<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Markdown on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/markdown/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Markdown on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Blog IDE Environment and Random Thoughts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:54:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article introduces the basic concepts of Markdown and its applications in various software. It recommends using VSCode as an IDE and lists recommended plugins. The author shares their experience switching from Hexo to Hugo, emphasizing Hugo&amp;rsquo;s flexibility and customization capabilities. Finally, it provides tips for quickly getting started with new technologies and shares a trick for resolving Hugo theme styling update issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lightweight markup language that allows people to write documents in an easy-to-read and write plain text format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed Markdown syntax is not elaborated on here; instead, an ebook is recommended: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://markdown-zh.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;点击此处&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many software programs already support md as a writing format. The CSDN blog system launched an online editor that supports md syntax, and it includes a helpful introductory article on md syntax when you first use it. Evernote added md note support in 2018, with various md markup options readily available, making the experience similar to editing regular articles and suitable for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-ides&#34;&gt;Recommended IDEs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By the time this article was written, it was 2020. You&amp;rsquo;ve likely heard of VS Code—after all, anyone considering using Git Page to build a blog system is an industry professional. While Sublime and Atom were good choices in earlier years, with two years of community support, VS Code has rapidly developed and become the preferred starting point for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s relationship with the open-source community has transitioned from a fractured state to a honeymoon period: embracing open source. The company I work for has also actively adopted the Java ecosystem in recent years; in other words, the current Java landscape is genuinely appealing within China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vs-code-plugin-recommendations&#34;&gt;VS Code plugin recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins typically include Readme files detailing basic usage, core features, and sometimes dynamic effect demonstrations provided by the plugin authors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It easily integrates images, complementing Hugo&amp;rsquo;s image plugin approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can&amp;rsquo;t remember the shortcuts, open the VS Code shortcut management menu, search for &amp;ldquo;md,&amp;rdquo; look at it several times; review the plugin instructions again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo&#34;&gt;hugo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m naturally restless; I can’t just sit still and write articles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo supports placing images and Markdown documents in separate folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic themes support various article styles in design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various convenient custom extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic&#34;&gt;academic
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The website defaults to ______&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The URL structure allows single-page navigation, avoiding scrolling on the homepage—a matter of personal preference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Formats: Essays, speeches, ebooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility: Customize overall style, customize CSS styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme&amp;rsquo;s support for Chinese is not yet fully mature, mainly from a visual perspective – the font size isn&amp;rsquo;t ideal for Chinese reading habits. However, it benefits from being developed by mostly Chinese developers, giving it an advantage over Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s best to do things yourself – inspect the browser elements. Once you’ve located an element, clicking on &lt;strong&gt;Insert Style Rule Below&lt;/strong&gt; in the sidebar allows you to easily retrieve the CSS style name, even for deeply nested styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Theme-specific syntax highlighting settings, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/#highlighting-options.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;官方链接&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The child is about to complain again – why are you being so vague from beginning to end, without mentioning any details?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to say that these things are enough for you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official Manual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugin Description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly get started with new technology, it&amp;rsquo;s recommended to first read the official documentation. Don’t feel pressured to understand everything in one go; at least aim for a general understanding. Search engine results may not always align with the latest version and could be misleading. The same applies to new books – start by looking at the table of contents to grasp what the author intends to cover. Sometimes, reading the preface first is helpful; in some foreign works translated into Chinese, the translator&amp;rsquo;s preface often summarizes the book’s core content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switching Hugo Academic&amp;rsquo;s built-in style and publishing to the site didn’t change the appearance. Clever users likely figured out that clearing the browser cache would solve the problem. And me, being ingenious: F12 developer mode, switched to &lt;code&gt;network&lt;/code&gt;BOLD_2&lt;code&gt;disable cache&lt;/code&gt;, refreshed, and it&amp;rsquo;s done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/2020-03-31-14-27-15.png&#34;
	width=&#34;399&#34;
	height=&#34;142&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;network&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;280&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;674px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
