<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Markdown on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/markdown/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Markdown on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:10:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/markdown/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Blog IDE Environment and Ramblings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:54:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article introduces the basic concepts of Markdown and its applications in various software, recommends using VSCode as an IDE, and lists recommended plugins. The author shares their experience switching from Hexo to Hugo, emphasizing Hugo’s flexibility and customization capabilities. Finally, it provides some suggestions for quickly getting started with new technologies and shares a trick for resolving the issue of Hugo theme styles not updating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lightweight markup language that allows people to write documents in an easy-to-read and -write plain text format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;markdown-1&#34;&gt;Markdown
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Detailed Markdown syntax will not be elaborated upon in this document. We recommend an ebook, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://markdown-zh.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;. Many software applications on the market now support MD as a writing format. The csdn blog system has launched an online editor that supports MD syntax; the first time you use it, there is a default introduction article about MD syntax, which I think is quite good. iNotes added support for MD notes in 2018, with various MD markers in the shortcut bar, and it&amp;rsquo;s almost as easy to use as editing a regular article. The overall interaction process is friendly to beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ide-recommendations&#34;&gt;IDE Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When writing this article, it’s already 2020 – you’ve undoubtedly heard of VS Code, after all, anyone thinking about using Git Page to build a blog system is an industry professional. In the early years, Sublime and Atom were also good choices. With two years of promotion from the open-source community, VS Code has developed rapidly and has gradually become the preferred choice for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Microsoft’s giant and the open-source community has successfully transitioned into a honeymoon phase: embracing open source. Our company has also actively introduced the Java ecosystem in recent two years, meaning that in business development, Java&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem is currently very fragrant domestically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vs-code-plugin-recommendations&#34;&gt;VS Code Plugin Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/2020-03-31-14-07-17.png&#34;
	width=&#34;310&#34;
	height=&#34;306&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Plugin List&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;101&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;243px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All plugins have their own Readme files, introducing basic usage, core functions, and some authors even provide dynamic effect demonstration images.
&lt;code&gt;Paste Image&lt;/code&gt;, combined with Hugo&amp;rsquo;s image plugin method, is very convenient for importing images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t remember the shortcuts, open the VS Code shortcut management menu, search for “md”, read it several times; review it again to look at the plugin usage instructions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I switched from Hexo to Hugo, as I love tinkering – it’s just my nature! Ultimately, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to quietly write articles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo supports placing images and Markdown documents in a single folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Academic theme supports various article styles in its design.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various convenient customization extensions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic&#34;&gt;academic
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The default website is &lt;code&gt;exampleSite&lt;/code&gt;, and menu introduction uses the &lt;code&gt;#component&lt;/code&gt; method, it’s recommended to use &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The URL pattern allows navigation links to jump to a single page instead of scrolling on the homepage – this is purely a matter of personal preference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Styles: Notebooks, Speeches, eBooks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility: Customization of overall style and custom CSS styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme’s Chinese support isn&amp;rsquo;t very complete; primarily from a visual perspective, the font sizes don’t align well with Chinese reading habits. The Hexo development team is largely comprised of Chinese developers, which is an advantage over Hugo in this regard. However, it’s rewarding to do things yourself and customize – browser element auditing. When you locate an element, to find out the CSS style name you need to modify, click &lt;strong&gt;Insert Style Rule Below&lt;/strong&gt; on the sidebar, even with nested CSS layers, you can easily get the node name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;[Introduce &lt;code&gt;custom.css&lt;/code&gt;](https://sourcethemes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic-1&#34;&gt;academic
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in syntax highlighting settings, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/#highlighting-options.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;official link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The kids are complaining again, saying you talk in such a vague and unclear way, without mentioning any details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I want to say is that with these things, you have enough to work with:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official Manuals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugin Documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When quickly getting started with new technologies, it’s recommended to first read the official website documentation, &lt;strong&gt;scanning through&lt;/strong&gt; – not necessarily reading it cover to cover, but at least having a general idea. Search engine results may not always be consistent with the latest version and could potentially mislead you. Similarly, when reviewing a new book, start by looking at the table of contents to understand what the author intends to discuss; sometimes, reading the introduction first is beneficial, especially with translated foreign books where the translator’s preface often covers the core content of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-eggs&#34;&gt;Easter Eggs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switching the Hugo Academic built-in style and theme, publishing to the site, and accessing it did not result in a change of style. A clever teammate already figured this out – clearing the local browser cache resolved the issue.  It was then that I, with my ingenuity, used Developer Mode (F12), switched to &lt;code&gt;network&lt;/code&gt;, checked “disable cache,” refreshed, and voila!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/2020-03-31-14-27-15.png&#34;
	width=&#34;399&#34;
	height=&#34;142&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;network&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;280&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;674px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
