<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>7x24 Hour Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/7x24-hour-trading/</link>
        <description>Recent content in 7x24 Hour Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:18:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/7x24-hour-trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Over-the-Counter (OTC) Clearing and Settlement of Digital Currencies: Unveiling the Mechanisms Behind 7x24 Continuous Trading</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:03:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional stock markets with defined opening and closing times, the digital currency market has attracted the attention of global investors due to its 7x24-hour continuous trading feature. This characteristic has also raised a core question: how are digital currencies cleared and settled in a world without a “market close” concept? Does it completely overturn these concepts in traditional finance? The answer is that digital currencies not only have clearing and settlement, but the way they are implemented and their system design are key to supporting all-day trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-difference-from-t2-to-real-time-settlement&#34;&gt;Core Difference: From T+2 to Real-Time Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional stock trading follows a “T+N” settlement system (e.g., T+1 in China, T+2 in the US), meaning that the actual transfer of funds and securities after a trade is executed (on day T) takes one or more business days to complete. During this period, clearing agencies conduct offsetting, calculate the receivables and payables of each party, and settle differences.
Digital currencies have completely changed this model. Its core settlement and delivery can be summarized as &lt;strong&gt;“Trade-to-Clear, Clear-to-Deliver,”&lt;/strong&gt; primarily due to its underlying blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-a-natural-real-time-full-settlement-system&#34;&gt;Blockchain: A Natural Real-Time Full Settlement System
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockchain itself can be considered a decentralized, immutable public ledger. Each transaction is recorded in a “block” and linked to the previous block through cryptographic methods, forming an irreversible “chain.” This process has the following key characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a transaction is validated by nodes on the network and packaged into a block, the transfer of assets is completed. Although confirmation times vary depending on the congestion and block generation speed of different blockchain networks (such as Bitcoin and Ethereum), ranging from seconds to several minutes, this is a qualitative leap compared to traditional finance’s “T+N.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike net settlement in traditional clearing systems, each transaction on the blockchain is independent and fully executed. When A transfers a bitcoin to B, it is clearly recorded in the ledger as A&amp;rsquo;s address decreasing by one and B&amp;rsquo;s address increasing by one, without any netting of multiple transactions before transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finality:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a block has been confirmed by enough subsequent blocks, this transaction is considered “final” and irreversible. This means that once settled, no one can undo or modify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, fundamentally, &lt;strong&gt;asset settlement occurs on the blockchain, automatically completed through network consensus, without the need for traditional central clearing counterparties (CCPs) or custodians.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-vs-decentralized-exchanges-different-clearing-and-settlement-pathways&#34;&gt;Centralized vs. Decentralized Exchanges: Different Clearing and Settlement Pathways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the underlying technology is decentralized, the primary venues where users conduct digital currency transactions – exchanges – are divided into two types: centralized (CEX) and decentralized (DEX), which have different clearing and settlement mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;centralized-exchanges-cex-internal-clearing--on-chain-settlement&#34;&gt;Centralized Exchanges (CEX): Internal Clearing + On-Chain Settlement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When users trade on centralized exchanges like Binance and Coinbase, they are actually operating within the exchange’s internal centralized ledger, rather than directly on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Clearing (Ledgering):&lt;/strong&gt; When users deposit digital currencies or fiat currency into an exchange, the exchange records corresponding balances in its database for the user&amp;rsquo;s account. All buy and sell actions a user takes on the platform, such as buying BTC with USDT, essentially just represents increases and decreases in numbers within different accounts in the exchange’s database. This process is completed quickly by the exchange’s &lt;strong&gt;“matching engine,”&lt;/strong&gt; which can be considered a real-time internal clearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Settlement (Withdrawal/Deposit):&lt;/strong&gt; The actual settlement that occurs on the blockchain only happens when users &lt;strong&gt;“deposit”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer from an external wallet into the exchange) and &lt;strong&gt;“withdraw”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer out of the exchange to an external wallet). At this point, the exchange initiates a chain transaction to truly transfer asset ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Performance Matching Engine:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures rapid order matching under high concurrency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold &amp;amp; Hot Wallet Separation:&lt;/strong&gt; Most user assets are stored in offline “cold wallets” to ensure security, while a small amount of assets is kept in online “hot wallets” to meet users’ daily withdrawal needs. This is the core design for ensuring 7x24 hours of asset safety operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Ledger Database:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizes a high-performance distributed database to ensure the accuracy and immediacy of internal transaction records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralized-exchanges-dexs-on-chain-atomic-swaps&#34;&gt;Decentralized Exchanges (DEXs): On-Chain Atomic Swaps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In decentralized exchanges like Uniswap and SushiSwap, the trading process is radically different. Users always maintain control over their own wallet private keys, and transactions are executed directly on-chain through “smart contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic Swap:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the core of how DEXs clear and settle trades. A smart contract is a program that automatically executes on a blockchain, ensuring that the exchange of assets is &amp;ldquo;atomic&amp;rdquo;—either both parties successfully exchange their assets, or neither does—preventing one party from sending assets without receiving confirmation from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing and Settlement Synchronized:&lt;/strong&gt; Users authorize interactions with smart contracts through their wallets. Once a transaction is triggered and confirmed on the blockchain, clearing and settlement are instantly completed in a single step. The entire process requires no trust in any centralized intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts:&lt;/strong&gt; The core logic of the exchange, including trading pairs, liquidity pools, and pricing algorithms (such as Automated Market Makers - AMMs) are all hardcoded into the smart contract, making them public and transparent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Oracles:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to securely feed external market price information onto the blockchain, providing price references for certain types of DEXs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a web or app interface that allows users to connect their wallets and interact with the backend smart contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-the-new-paradigm-for-digital-currency-clearing-and-settlement&#34;&gt;Summary: The New Paradigm for Digital Currency Clearing and Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In essence, digital currencies are not without the concepts of clearing and settlement; rather, they have transformed from a multi-party, time-consuming back-office process into an efficient, transparent, and even real-time automated one through blockchain technology and innovative system designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing Concepts Remain:&lt;/strong&gt; This is evident in CEXs as real-time matching and ledger accounting, and in DEXs, smart contracts incorporate clearing rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement is the Core Transformation:&lt;/strong&gt; Finality of settlement is guaranteed by blockchain consensus, enabling near real-time asset transfers – a cornerstone supporting 7x24 uninterrupted trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Serves Uninterrupted Operation:&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s CEX cold and hot wallet architectures or DEX automated smart contracts, the primary design objective is to achieve a transaction environment without manual intervention and never closed, while ensuring security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This disruptive clearing and settlement mechanism is not only a significant distinguishing feature of digital currency markets compared to traditional finance but also provides important insights into the future evolution of financial infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
