<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>The Seven Seconds of a Fish on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/the-seven-seconds-of-a-fish/</link>
        <description>Recent content in The Seven Seconds of a Fish on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 19:03:54 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/the-seven-seconds-of-a-fish/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Zhejiang financial circle collapsed, and the anti-corruption efforts over the past two years have not been limited to government departments.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/the-zhejiang-financial-circle-collapsed-and-the-anti-corruption-efforts-over-the-past-two-years-have-not-been-limited-to-government-departments/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:57:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/the-zhejiang-financial-circle-collapsed-and-the-anti-corruption-efforts-over-the-past-two-years-have-not-been-limited-to-government-departments/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I saw a report on Douyin about an anti-corruption investigation in the Zhejiang financial sector. I had written about the prelude to financial corruption once before, but didn&amp;rsquo;t follow up on related reports afterward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I still check financial news every day, and previously I rarely saw any reports about financial corruption. However, there have been increasing reports of financial corruption over the past two years, with more and more senior executives from banks, securities firms, and other financial institutions being investigated.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain-rise/&#34; &gt;Financial Anti-Corruption Curtain Rise&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recent systemic anti-corruption storm in the Zhejiang financial sector is one of the most iconic events in China’s financial field in recent years. This anti-corruption campaign, which began in 2023, centered around the collective downfall of the former presidents of Zhejiang branches of four major state-owned banks, exposing long-standing issues of power abuse and collusion between government and businesses within local financial systems. The following outlines the event timeline, core problems, underlying causes, and subsequent impacts from four dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-event-timeline-from-the-zhu-xiaoyu-case-to-the-collapse-of-the-gang-leaders-of-the-four-major-banks&#34;&gt;I. Event Timeline: From the Zhu Xiaoyu Case to the Collapse of the “Gang Leaders” of the Four Major Banks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Spark: The Zhu Xiaoyu Case Unearths a Rotten Financial System Case&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In May 2023, Zhejiang Provincial Vice Governor Zhu Xiaoyu was investigated, and his corrupt pattern of &amp;ldquo;eating off finance&amp;rdquo; became a breakthrough point. During his tenure, he obtained massive profits through interfering in corporate IPOs and loans, and formed an alliance of interests with financial institution executives. In November 2023, Zhu Xiaoyu was expelled from the Communist Party and public office, and the numerous clues provided during the investigation directly triggered subsequent seismic events within the financial system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anti-Corruption Storm Intensifies: Original Heads of Zhejiang Branches of the Four Major Banks Fall&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2024:&lt;/strong&gt; Guo XinGang, the former Chairman of the China Bank’s Zhejiang Branch, was investigated. After retiring, he made money through low-priced property purchases and equity premiums, abusing his authority in mineral loan approvals, resulting in significant losses of state assets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2025:&lt;/strong&gt; Gao Qiang, the former Chairman of the Construction Bank’s Zhejiang Branch, was investigated. During his tenure, he illegally approved loans leading to multiple projects going bankrupt and receiving “consulting fees” exceeding tens of millions of yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 2025:&lt;/strong&gt; Feng Jianlong, the former Chairman of the Agricultural Bank’s Zhejiang Branch, voluntarily confessed, and during his tenure, he transformed the Zhejiang branch of the Agricultural Bank into a &amp;ldquo;family industrial business,&amp;rdquo; with relatives holding illegal positions and serious misconduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 30, 2025:&lt;/strong&gt; Shen Rongqin, the former Chairman of ICBC’s Zhejiang Branch, was investigated. After retiring, he controlled institutions such as Changtang River Jinran Academy through “political rotation,” forming a network of interests with eight private enterprises.  Within 15 months, all the original heads of the four major banks&amp;rsquo; Zhejiang branches fell, creating a closed-loop anti-corruption effort.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory System Also Shakes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In January 2025, Pan Guang’en, former Deputy Director of the Zhejiang Provincial Party Committee’s Financial Bureau, voluntarily confessed, using his privileged position to facilitate corporate equity reforms and investments, illegally receiving massive amounts of money. This marked a shift in the anti-corruption campaign from financial institutions to regulatory departments, revealing the deep entanglement of the “regulatory-financial institution-private enterprise” three-party interest chain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-core-issues-credit-corruption-and-rotating-door-interest-chains&#34;&gt;II. Core Issues: Credit Corruption and Rotating Door Interest Chains
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Misappropriation of Lending Power: The Core Tool of Corruption&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All four former heads of the major banks utilized their lending power to transfer interests: Guo XinGang violated regulations by issuing mineral loans, Gao Qiang manipulated credit through “consulting fees,” Feng Jianlong’s family-style lending led to bad debts, and Shen Rongqin used the Golden Research Institute platform to channel funds to related enterprises. Data shows that 68% of individuals investigated within the banking system in 2024 were involved in illegal lending or loan approvals, highlighting a deeply concerning loss of control over lending power.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rotational Corruption: Retirement is Not a Safe Deposit Box&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All four individuals continued to wield power through “identity transformation” after retirement: Guo XinGang served as the president of an industry association to intervene in credit lending, Gao Qiang transitioned to a securities dealer director to manipulate capital, and Shen Rongqin established a “financial-academic-research” platform to connect with private enterprises. This “retire and continue” model allowed retired executives to evade regulation and form hidden interest chains. The 2024 Financial Anti-Corruption White Paper revealed that 68% of cases involved retired executives, with the Zhejiang case serving as a typical example.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blurred Boundaries Between Government and Business: Interest Transfer from Banks to Private Enterprises&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Changtang River Golden Research Institute, led by Shen Rongqin, was established with investments from eight private enterprises including Zhentai and Chuanhua, ostensibly an academic institution but in reality a political-economic nexus. Through this platform, Shen Rongqin directed banking resources towards related enterprises, forming a “banking institution – private enterprise think tank” binding model. Similar models were also evident in the cases of Guo XinGang and Gao Qiang, exposing the deep distortion of political-economic relations within local financial ecosystems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;three-root-causes-institutional-loopholes-and-regulatory-failures&#34;&gt;Three. Root Causes: Institutional Loopholes and Regulatory Failures
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term Absence of Local Financial Regulation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a major province for private economy, Zhejiang has been active in financial innovation, but the regulatory system hasn’t kept pace. Officials such as Zhu from Ju and Pan Guang&amp;rsquo;en have long dominated local financial policies, acting as both “athletes” and “referees,” leading to ineffective regulation. For example, during his tenure at the Financial Bureau, Pan Guang&amp;rsquo;en illegally interfered in corporate financing and share reform, but was not effectively restrained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Failure of Internal Controls within Financial Institutions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The internal supervision mechanisms of the four major banks’ Zhejiang branches were essentially empty. When Feng Jianlong served as the chairman of Zhejiang Branch of Agricultural Bank, his relatives quickly rose through the system, and the “one-voice” credit approval phenomenon was prominent. Shen Rongqin&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Employee Care Plan&amp;rdquo; ostensibly provided welfare, but actually consolidated power by controlling frontline employees to cover up corrupt behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weak External Supervision Mechanisms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The enabling of cross-provincial investigations (such as the Shen Rongqin case being handled by the Liaoning Provincial Supervisory Commission) demonstrated that local protectionism had severely hindered anti-corruption progress. Furthermore, the complex equity relationships between financial institutions and private enterprises (such as half of the top ten loan customers of Zhejiang Merchants Bank were real estate companies) made risk transmission hidden, making traditional regulatory measures difficult to penetrate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-subsequent-impacts-regulatory-upgrading-and-industry-restructuring&#34;&gt;Four. Subsequent Impacts: Regulatory Upgrading and Industry Restructuring
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normalization of Anti-Corruption and Systemic Plugging of Leaks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Provincial Supervision and Penetrating Regulation&lt;/strong&gt;: The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection adopted remote case handling to cut through local protection networks, and extended the scope of scrutiny from on-duty behavior to interest chains after retirement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technological Anti-Corruption Implementation&lt;/strong&gt;: Zhejiang piloted AI risk control models for credit approval, automatically identifying “people-based loans” and “political-business loans,” effectively curbing corruption at its source.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restrictions on Departing Executives&lt;/strong&gt;: Zhejiang Province is drafting the &amp;ldquo;List of Financial Executive Post-Employment Restrictions,&amp;rdquo; stipulating that bank chairpersons are prohibited from serving affiliated companies within three years after retirement, cutting off chains of power options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restructuring of the Financial Ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Systemic Risk Clearance in Banks&lt;/strong&gt;: Institutions such as Zhejiang Business Bank and Hangzhou Bank were initiated internal restructuring due to the downfall of senior executives, and high real estate loan ratios (such as Zhejiang Business Bank’s real estate non-performing asset rate reaching 2.48%) forced business transformation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Optimization of Financing Environment for Private Enterprises&lt;/strong&gt;: Following anti-corruption actions, Zhejiang Province launched policies such as “Zheke Loan,” providing 450 billion yuan in loans to 32,000 technology SMEs in 2024, driving finance back to its original purpose of serving the real economy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Warning Effect&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The collective downfall of former branch managers of the four major banks in Zhejiang shattered the illusion of “safety after retirement,” conveying a signal of “zero tolerance and no blind spots” in financial anti-corruption. This event also provides a mirror for the entire Chinese financial system: only by strengthening power constraints and improving regulatory systems can we safeguard financial security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The collapse of the Zhejiang financial circle was fundamentally a concentrated outburst of long-term loss of control over local financial power. This storm not only cleared out a number of “financial pests,” but also drove profound changes in regulatory models, institutional design, and industry ecosystems. In the future, how to balance financial innovation with risk management, and how to build “clean” government-business relationships will continue to be subjects of ongoing exploration for Zhejiang and even the entire Chinese financial sector.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2020-2025 Jiangxi Province Special Postdoctoral and National Civil Service Teacher Recruitment Data: Trends and Insights into Transformation</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/jiangxi-specialist-and-national-teacher-recruitment-trends-2020-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 18:59:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/jiangxi-specialist-and-national-teacher-recruitment-trends-2020-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;2020-2025 Years: The recruitment of teachers in Jiangxi Province shows a significant reduction trend: the number of specially appointed teachers decreased sharply from 6,617 to 32 (a decrease of 99.5%), and the number of national cadre teachers decreased from 11,324 to 2,146 (a decrease of 81.1%). The proportion of core subjects (Chinese, mathematics, and English) remained stable but declined in total volume; while the proportions of music, art, and physical education increased, the absolute number was limited (e.g., in 2025, they only recruited 2 people each). Policy-wise, &amp;ldquo;one withdrawal, one replacement&amp;rdquo; personnel adjustments have tightened, with teacher resources leaning towards vocational training and remote areas, traditional primary and secondary school positions have significantly reduced, and some subjects are planning for zero recruitment in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recruitment numbers of specially appointed teachers in Jiangxi Province over the past five years have been collected, with data sorted by subject and compiled into a table.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;— ——————&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on recruitment announcements and publicly available data released by the Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education, the Ministry of Human Resources and Social Security, and other official agencies, the following summarizes the recruitment situation for contracted teachers and civil servant teachers from 2020-2025. Please note that &lt;strong&gt;2025 data represents planned recruitment numbers&lt;/strong&gt;, and some years’ subject breakdowns are not fully disclosed; subjects marked as “unspecified” in the table represent total figures or missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unspecified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,617&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;900&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;317&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-1&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Specified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-2&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Specified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,835&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-3&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Specified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;650&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-4&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Specified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,008&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;380&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-jiangxi-province-special-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-5&#34;&gt;I. Jiangxi Province Special Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unspecified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-civil-service-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province Civil Service Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number of Recruitments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Undefined&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11,324&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;524&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-civil-service-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-1&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province Civil Service Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number of Recruitments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Undefined&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13,324&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;624&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-national-personnel-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province National Personnel Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number of Recruitments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Broken Down&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-civil-servant-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province Civil Servant Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number of Recruitments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Undefined&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7,821&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;421&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-civil-service-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-2&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province Civil Service Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number of Recruitments&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Specified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,957&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;257&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-civil-servant-teacher-recruitment-data-2020-2025-1&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province Civil Servant Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Number Recruited&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Moral &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Art&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Not Broken Down&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;380&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-data-explanation&#34;&gt;III. Data Explanation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Source&lt;/strong&gt;: Recruitment announcements and official statistics from the Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education and the Department of Human Resources and Social Security over the past years (actual recruitment numbers for 2020-2024, planned numbers for 2025).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject Categories&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special Teachers focus on subjects at rural primary and secondary education stages; in 2025, only a small number of core positions will be retained.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;National Personnel Teachers cover all academic levels, with a more comprehensive subject setting including preschool education and special education (due to data not being segmented, these were not listed separately).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trend Analysis&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharp Decline in Total Numbers&lt;/strong&gt;: The recruitment quota for Special Teachers decreased by 99.5% compared to 2020 in 2025, and the recruitment quota for National Personnel Teachers decreased by 81.1%, reflecting demographic changes and adjustments in educational resources.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subject Hotness&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proportion of core subjects (Chinese, Mathematics, English) remained stable but declined year on year in terms of recruitment numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subjects such as Music, Art, and Physical Education, as well as Information Technology, saw an increase in their proportions, but the absolute number was limited (e.g., in 2025, Music and Art each recruited only 2 people).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some subjects (such as English) experienced freezes due to a decrease in student numbers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Policy Background&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tightening of Personnel Quotas&lt;/strong&gt;: The “One Out, One In” policy is being implemented, strictly controlling the addition of new quotas; in 2024, the proportion of non-quota positions reached 68.6%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Structural Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt;: Teacher resources are leaning towards vocational education and remote areas, with significant reductions in recruitment to traditional primary and secondary schools.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-obtaining-complete-data-recommendations&#34;&gt;Four. Obtaining Complete Data Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Official Channels:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education Website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jyt.jiangxi.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://jyt.jiangxi.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security Website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://rst.jiangxi.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://rst.jiangxi.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended Tools:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Examination for Civil Servants Website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.jxpta.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.jxpta.com&lt;/a&gt;): Download of past job lists.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Smart Education Platform (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.jxedu.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.jxedu.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;): Data on Special Recruitment Teachers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Notes:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The number of posts for some subjects (such as Information Technology) is planned at 0 in 2025, and actual recruitment may be supplemented through adjustment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject classifications may vary from year to year (e.g., “Moral and Rule of Law” merged with “Ideology and Politics”), please refer to the official announcement for the specific year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you require more detailed subject post distributions or regional breakdowns, we recommend contacting your local education bureau directly or querying through the official recruitment system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The “Tiangong” (Heavenly Palace) incident in medical education and the Butterfly Effect of Dong Xi Ying’s case</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-and-the-butterfly-effect-of-dong-xiying-incident/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 01:08:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-and-the-butterfly-effect-of-dong-xiying-incident/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Beijing Children’s Hospital “4+4” project (4 years non-medical bachelor&amp;rsquo;s + 4 years medical doctorate) focuses on interdisciplinary elite cultivation. The exposure of Dong Xi Ying’s case in 2025 revealed her reliance on family background (medical/scientific research lineage) to gain entry into the program, raising concerns about the ambiguity of her qualifications, allegations of plagiarism in her dissertation, and exposing contradictions between its elite recruitment model and fairness, as well as ongoing debates regarding shortened study durations and clinical internship training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompts&#34;&gt;Prompts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog: Harmony 4+4 Origin and Development, Core: A Corner of Tian Gong, Seen by Mortals, Dong Xiaojie&amp;rsquo;s Family Background, Normal Medical Doctor Cannot Graduate in Eight Years, Dong Xiaojie’s Family Background &amp;amp; Educational Background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;harmony-44-deconstructing-medical-educations-tiangong-heavenly-palace&#34;&gt;Harmony 4+4: Deconstructing Medical Education’s “Tiangong” (Heavenly Palace)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “4+4” project at the Beijing Union Medical College, launched in 2018, has been viewed as China’s “Tiangong” (Heavenly Palace) in medical education. This project, designed to mimic the American medical education system, adopted the philosophy of “nurturing multidisciplinary individuals, those who love medicine, and talents from across the nation.” It aimed to create a rift within traditional Chinese medical education by focusing on: &lt;strong&gt;replacing the traditional 5+3+3 (five-year bachelor’s degree + three-year master’s degree + three-year doctoral degree) model with four years of non-medical undergraduate education plus four years of medical doctorate training,&lt;/strong&gt; to cultivate cross-disciplinary leadership talent in medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This model&amp;rsquo;s “Tiangong” attribute is reflected across three dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elite Recruitment:&lt;/strong&gt; Early on, applicants were required to come from universities ranked within the top 50 by QS/Times/US News or among the top 10 (e.g., Barnard College) in US News’s liberal arts and sciences rankings. Although later relaxed to the top 100, a GPA of 3.6 or higher, or ranking within the top 30 of their class, was still required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internationalized Training Pathways:&lt;/strong&gt; The project utilized American-style organ-system integrated courses and PBL (Problem-Based Learning) teaching methods. Students were expected to complete core courses such as anatomy and pathology within four years and participate in clinical internships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controversial Quality Output:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite a slightly lower passing rate on the physician licensing exam (95.2%) compared to the traditional eight-year model (98.5%), graduates predominantly entered Union Medical College hospitals, with their career development showing no significant difference from traditional pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dong-xiyi-incident-peering-through-the-heavenly-palace-crack--a-glimpse-of-privilege&#34;&gt;Dong Xiyi Incident: Peering Through the &amp;ldquo;Heavenly Palace&amp;rdquo; Crack – A Glimpse of Privilege
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 2025, the extramarital affair involving Xiao Fei, a thoracic surgeon at the China-Japan Friendship Hospital, triggered an investigation into the “mysterious veil” surrounding the Covariance 4+4 project. The background and credentials of Dong Xiyi, the central figure in the scandal, sparked three key questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambiguity Regarding Educational Background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispute Over Undergraduate Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Dong Xiyi claimed to have graduated from Columbia University, but her actual enrollment was at Barnard College (ranked 14th among top liberal arts colleges according to US News in 2025). Despite the college meeting Covariance’s requirement of “top 20 liberal arts schools,” her diploma simultaneously listed both &amp;ldquo;Barnard College&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Columbia University,&amp;rdquo; which could easily be misinterpreted as a Columbia University graduate within the domestic recruitment market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispute Over Professional Field:&lt;/strong&gt; An economics undergraduate degree combined with a clinical medicine doctorate is considered to align with the 4+4 project’s positioning of “multi-disciplinary background,” but it has been questioned for lacking foundational pre-medical courses. Her doctoral dissertation, &amp;ldquo;Research on Multi-modal Image Fusion Technology in Medical Imaging Analysis,&amp;rdquo; was alleged to closely resemble a patent developed by North Korea Tech, raising concerns about academic misconduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Special Characteristics of Family Background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monopoly of Academic Resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Her father served as Secretary of the China Metallurgical Construction Research Institute, and her mother was Deputy Director of the North Korea Tech Engineering Technology Institute. Her grandfather was a professor in Covariance’s imaging field, and her paternal grandparents were foreign professors in the materials field. This “medical + research + university” composite family background provided her with implicit resources such as recommendation letters (requiring recommendations from two biomedical associate professors) and research collaborations (such as North Korea Tech patents).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jump in Career Path:&lt;/strong&gt; She switched from thoracic surgery during internship to urology, and her research direction spanned bone and joint, digestive system, and imaging fields, raising questions about “paved the way for resources.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Magnified Dispute Over Length of Study:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rationality of Time Compression:&lt;/strong&gt; Traditional medical doctorates require 11 years (5+3+3), while the 4+4 project compressed this time to 8 years. Although Covariance emphasized “course integration” and “early clinical practice,” some doctors pointed out that her clinical internship period (12 months) was less than the traditional eight-year program (18 months), potentially hindering skill accumulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispute Over Reduced Internship:&lt;/strong&gt; Some internship bases allowed 4+4 graduates to reduce their internship by one year, raising concerns about disrupting industry fairness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-medical-education-quagmire-behind-the-controversy&#34;&gt;The Medical Education Quagmire Behind the Controversy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dong Xiying incident reflects deep contradictions within Chinese medical education:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conflict Between Elitism and Equity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “application-assessment” model of the 4+4 program is essentially a transplant of the American medical school model, but China lacks standardized exams like MCAT, relying instead on subjective evaluations such as letters of recommendation and research experience, which are susceptible to influence from family background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data shows that in the 2023 graduating class of 4+4 students, 30% came from Qingbei Fuzhou (Jilin, Beijing, Zhejiang), and 25% from overseas top universities; the impact of family background on applications is significant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reality of Curriculum Reform:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cost of Time Compression:&lt;/strong&gt; 4+4 students produce significantly fewer research outputs (such as the number of papers) than traditional eight-year programs, and are accused of “prioritizing clinical work over research.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Division in Industry Recognition:&lt;/strong&gt; Three-class hospitals prioritize the reputation of Covance (commonly known as &amp;ldquo;Kohe&amp;rdquo;), while基层医院 (jīchéng yīyuàn - primary care hospitals) maintain a cautious attitude towards the clinical abilities of 4+4 graduates.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Misguided Pursuit of International Alignment:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The American 4+4 model requires passing the MCAT exam and completing 3-7 years of residency, while China’s 4+4 program simplifies both admission and residency stages, leading to “form resembling substance but lacking true substance.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data from the Ministry of Education shows that in 2024, the national enrollment of medical doctors under the 4+4 program was less than 5%, and its large-scale promotion still faces resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-reconstructing-the-tiangong-order-for-medical-education&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Reconstructing the &amp;ldquo;Tiangong&amp;rdquo; Order for Medical Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controversy surrounding the Keho 4+4 project fundamentally represents a collision between elite education and public expectations. When a corner of “Tiangong” (the Palace of Heaven) was glimpsed by mortals, it exposed not just isolated instances of flaws, but deeper contradictions within the entire medical education system. Future reforms must focus on three levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implement Transparent Selection Mechanisms:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduce standardized exams (such as a Chinese version of MCAT) to reduce the influence of subjective factors like letters of recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extend Clinical Training Cycles:&lt;/strong&gt; Restore clinical training cycles for 4+4 graduates to 3 years, ensuring that clinical competence is achieved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengthen Process Oversight:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish an academic integrity review mechanism and conduct rigorous originality verification for interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical education’s “Tiangong” should not be the privilege of a few; it should truly be a cradle for nurturing medical elites. Only when fairness in selection mechanisms, rigor in the training process, and norms in professional development are comprehensively guaranteed will this “Tiangong experiment” in medical education truly take root and flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Long time no see bull market in stocks</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/long-time-no-see-bull-market-in-stocks/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:42:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/long-time-no-see-bull-market-in-stocks/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the 2024 National Day holiday, China’s stock market experienced a remarkable surge, attracting considerable attention. However, following the holiday, the market unexpectedly turned to a dramatic plunge. This “polarization” of the stock market – a rollercoaster ride between soaring highs and plummeting lows – not only subjected investors to a thrilling yet nerve-wracking experience, but also prompted deep reflection within the market regarding policy, economic conditions, and fundamental market rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-national-day-stock-market-surge-a-policy-driven-frenzy&#34;&gt;Pre-National Day Stock Market Surge: A Policy-Driven Frenzy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the five trading days leading up to National Day, China’s stock market surged from a slump into “boiling mode.” On September 30th, the A-share market saw a full-scale rally with all indices hitting historic highs. The Shanghai Composite Index rose by 8.06%, the Shenzhen Component Index increased by 10.67%, and the Innovation Board China Advanced Index soared by 15.36%, while the STAR 50 Index achieved its largest single-day rise in history, jumping 22.84%. Market sentiment was extremely exuberant, with daily trading volumes across the Shanghai, Shenzhen, and Northern Exchanges reaching RMB 2611.5 billion, a significant increase of RMB 11559 billion compared to the previous trading day. More than 5300 stocks on the main board rallied collectively, creating a “sea of red.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core driver behind this rally was the concentrated release of a series of unexpectedly positive policies by the government and the resulting changes in market expectations. On September 24th, the People’s Bank of China announced a cut in the reserve requirement ratio and interest rates, reducing existing mortgage loan interest rates and standardizing the minimum down payment ratios. The Politburo Standing Committee’s meeting on September 26th emphasized the need to intensify counter-cyclical fiscal and monetary policy adjustments to boost capital markets and actively guide medium and long-term funds into the market. On September 30th, a series of real estate support policies were released. These measures conveyed the government&amp;rsquo;s determination to stabilize the market and promote growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-national-day-stock-market-plunge-calm-and-adjustment-after-the-frenzy&#34;&gt;Post-National Day Stock Market Plunge: Calm and Adjustment After the Frenzy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, market sentiment plummeted sharply after the National Day holiday. On October 8th, the A-share market opened strongly with nearly a limit-up rise, but following a significant high opening, the market experienced violent fluctuations before closing down. Since then, the market’s center of gravity has continuously shifted downwards, and as of October 16th, the Shanghai Composite Index rose and fell by more than 15%, cumulatively falling by over 470 points. From October 8th to 10th, core A-share indices all declined, with the Shenzhen Component Index down 6.21%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this plunge are multifaceted. On one hand, it was a digestion of risks accumulated from the rapid rise in the previous period; on the other hand, it was also related to adjustments in market expectations regarding policy. Some investors believed that the short-term effects of policies were already evident, but the long-term effects still needed to be observed. Furthermore, volatility in global markets also impacted A-shares. On October 9th, the Hang Seng Index fell by 9.41%, and A50 futures fell by 10.4%, further exacerbating market declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection-and-outlook-on-the-market&#34;&gt;Reflection and Outlook on the Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dramatic volatility in the stock market around National Day highlighted a deep reflection among investors regarding policy, economics, and market fundamentals. On one hand, the short-term stimulus effects of policies were significant, but their long-term impact remains to be observed. On the other hand, the rapid rise and fall of the market served as a reminder for investors to maintain rationality and avoid emotional investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, whether A-shares can usher in a genuine “long bull” trend depends on whether policy can effectively transmit to the real economy and ultimately drive substantive improvements in economic fundamentals. Investors should closely monitor the specific implementation of policies and changes in economic data to rationally adjust their investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sharp rises and falls in the stock market around National Day were a game between policy and the market, and also a test of investors’ mentality. In this “two-pronged” market environment, we saw the power of the market and the influence of policy. How the market will unfold in the future remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Spring Festival box office *Ne Zha* goes viral/breaks out</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ne-zha-breaks-through-during-spring-festival/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ne-zha-breaks-through-during-spring-festival/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation of the provided Chinese text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Chinese people, every Spring Festival, we gather with our families for reunion dinners and watching movies has become an indispensable entertainment activity. This year’s Spring Festival box office hit, &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt;, exploded out of its niche, sparking discussions on streets and in alleys. The scale is impressive, reminiscent of the previous blockbuster, &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, carrying a strong patriotic theme that inexplicably evokes a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Write an article, topic: The explosive popularity of &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt; at the Spring Festival box office, the inexplicable sense of national pride, similar to older films like &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, with a patriotic theme. While there has been significant progress, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t reached this level. As gamers, many aspects seem greasy, and the combat scenes are heavily influenced by online games. There have already been people who bought movie tickets for &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt; but didn’t actually watch it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-combat-scene-lacked-texture&#34;&gt;The Combat Scene Lacked Texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a gamer, I’m usually immersed in various online worlds. Because of this, I didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for movies. However, with the huge popularity of &lt;em&gt;The Battle Between Heaven and Earth&lt;/em&gt;, everyone around me was talking about it, so I thought I’d take a look. When I entered the cinema, as soon as the scene came on screen, my heart sank. Although the visuals were noticeably improved compared to previous films, some scenes looked a bit greasy. Specifically, the combat scenes felt too heavily influenced by games; you know, like the style was too much like what I’ve seen in video games. Having played so many years of games, the visual style and certain scenes reminded me too strongly of those in games, lacking the texture that a film should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-fanatics&#34;&gt;Crazy Fanatics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie, I went out to see what was happening online. Turns out, quite a few people said they bought tickets for &lt;em&gt;The Soul of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; purely to boost its box office revenue. This is impressive – I have to admit I’m somewhat impressed! It seems that everyone&amp;rsquo;s enthusiasm and support for this film is incredibly high, and they were willing to do something for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;storyline&#34;&gt;Storyline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s reflect on it: back when “The Battle of Wukong” came out, Wu Jing shouted “Anyone who dares to harm China will be punished, no matter how far away,” and countless people felt a surge of patriotism, thinking our Chinese military was incredibly powerful and our country immensely strong. Although “The White Dragon” doesn’t have such a direct patriotic slogan, it vividly portrays traditional Chinese culture. Characters like Nezha and Ao Bing, figures we&amp;rsquo;ve grown up hearing stories about since childhood, are brought to life with their feuds, romances, and growth journeys in the film – this is precisely the charm of Chinese culture, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take Nezha as an example. He was misunderstood and ostracized from a young age, but he refused to give up, shouting “My destiny is not determined by heaven, but by myself,” which resonates so strongly with the resilience deep within every Chinese person. No matter what difficulties we face, we don&amp;rsquo;t bow down; we change our fate through our own efforts. Ao Bing is similar, carrying the burden of his family’s mission, appearing cold on the surface but possessing a kind heart, and sacrificing himself for his friends. This friendship, this sense of responsibility – aren’t we often able to see these things in real life too?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advancements-in-animated-films&#34;&gt;Advancements in Animated Films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;em&gt;The Fire on the Mountain&lt;/em&gt; (Nezha) had some imperfections, it effectively combined traditional Chinese culture with modern film technology, allowing us to see significant progress in Chinese animated films. Just as &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt; demonstrated China’s breakthrough in the action film genre. This kind of advancement makes us feel that Chinese cinema can rise to prominence on the international stage and allows foreigners to witness the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, no matter where we go, we carry our nation and culture within us. Films like &lt;em&gt;Nezha&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt; are like keys that unlock the deep-seated sense of national pride within us. They allow us to feel the strength of our country and the charm of our culture amidst laughter and joy, while also inspiring us to work hard in our respective roles to contribute to the prosperity and flourishing of our nation. That’s probably why these films went viral and were able to evoke a sense of national pride within us. In the future, we hope for more films like this to appear, allowing this feeling of national pride to remain full and abundant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Promoting Real Estate and Central Bank’s Four-pronged Measures</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promoting-real-estate-and-central-bank-four-measures/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 20:42:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promoting-real-estate-and-central-bank-four-measures/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancellation of Property Mortgage Interest Rate Floor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Housing Fund (Prudential Loan) Interest Rate Will Be Reduced by 0.25% Starting Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First-Time Homebuyers Down Payment Ratio Reduced to 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;300 Billion Yuan in Guaranteed Affordable Housing Repurchase Loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancellation-of-national-level-first-and-second-tier-commercial-personal-housing-loan-interest-rate-policy-lower-bounds&#34;&gt;Cancellation of National-Level First and Second-Tier Commercial Personal Housing Loan Interest Rate Policy Lower Bounds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Headquarters of the People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, branches of the People’s Bank of China in provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned cities; branches of all state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and all joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to implement the decision deployment of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council, adapt to the new supply and demand relationship in China’s real estate market and the new expectations of people for high-quality housing, and promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, the following matters regarding adjustments to commercial personal housing loan interest rate policies are hereby notified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. The lower bounds of interest rates on commercial personal housing loans for first-tier and second-tier housing nationwide are cancelled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;II. Branches of the People’s Bank of China at provincial levels will, in accordance with the principle of tailoring measures to local conditions, guide provincial market interest rate pricing self-regulatory mechanisms to determine independently whether to set lower bounds on commercial personal housing loan interest rates and their respective levels (if any), based on the real estate market situation within each jurisdiction and local government regulatory requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;III. Financial institutions in the banking industry shall reasonably determine the specific interest rate level for each loan, taking into account the interest rate limits determined by provincial market interest rate pricing self-regulatory mechanisms (if any) and factors such as the operating conditions of the institution and its customer risk profile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-personal-housing-mortgage-loan-interest-rates-by-025-percentage-points&#34;&gt;Reducing Personal Housing Mortgage Loan Interest Rates by 0.25 Percentage Points
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, Shanghai Headquarters, branches of the People’s Bank of China in provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned special-purpose cities; policy banks, state commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People’s Bank of China has decided to reduce personal housing mortgage loan interest rates by 0.25 percentage points, effective May 18, 2024. The interest rates for first-time and second-home personal housing mortgage loans with a term of less than 5 years (including 5 years) will be adjusted to 2.35% and 2.85%, respectively.  The interest rates for first-time and second-home personal housing mortgage loans with a term of less than 5 years (including 5 years) will also be no lower than 2.775% and 3.325%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;down-payment-ratio-adjusted-to-no-less-than-15&#34;&gt;Down Payment Ratio Adjusted to No Less Than 15%
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, Shanghai Headquarters, branches of the People’s Bank of China in provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned unitary cities; the Regulatory Bureau of the National Financial Supervision and Administration; all state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and all joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to implement the decision-making deployment of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council, adapt to the new supply and demand relationship in China’s real estate market and the new expectations of people for high-quality housing, and promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, the following matters regarding personal mortgage loans are hereby notified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For residential households purchasing commercial first-time home purchases, the minimum down payment ratio for commercial personal mortgages on first-time home purchases will be adjusted to no less than 15%, and the minimum down payment ratio for commercial personal mortgages on second-time home purchases will be adjusted to no less than 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this, the branches of the People’s Bank of China at each provincial level, and the派出机构 (outposts) of the National Financial Supervision and Administration will, according to the control requirements of local governments, independently determine the minimum down payment ratio limits for first-time and second-time home purchases in various cities based on a principle of tailoring policies to local conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-central-bank-will-establish-a-30-billion-yuan-guarantee-housing-re-loan&#34;&gt;The Central Bank Will Establish a 30 Billion Yuan Guarantee Housing Re-Loan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 4:00 PM, representatives from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the Ministry of Natural Resources, the People’s Bank of China, and the National Financial Supervision and Administration Commission gathered at a routine policy briefing by the State Council to introduce measures to effectively ensure contract fulfillment (保交房).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the meeting, People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Vice Governor Tao Ling announced that the central bank will establish a 30 billion yuan guarantee housing re-loan facility to support local state-owned enterprises in purchasing completed but unsold commercial properties at reasonable prices for use as self-built or rental-based affordable housing. This is expected to drive an additional 50 billion yuan in bank loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the People’s Bank of China, the guarantee housing re-loan term can be extended up to four times annually, with a rate of 1.75%, aimed at 21 nationwide banks. It incentivizes banks to lend to local state-owned enterprises selected by city governments to purchase completed but unsold commercial properties for use as affordable housing. The purchased properties are strictly limited to those commercially available properties built by real estate developers that have not yet been sold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding this policy, the central bank will soon issue the &lt;em&gt;Notice on Measures Concerning the Establishment of the Guarantee Housing Re-Loan Facility&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Starch noodles and roadside stalls: The new influence of capital’s news.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sausages-and-street-vendors-capital-news-influence/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:31:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sausages-and-street-vendors-capital-news-influence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;315 actually did not report on “chicken mud,” and this issue itself has been confusing the official exposure of CCTV’s 3·15 Gala with other food safety hotspots that occurred concurrently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zhihu-answer-journalismhttpswwwzhihucomquestion648967411answer3433834122&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/648967411/answer/3433834122&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zhihu Answer: Journalism&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 315 evening event mentioned nine manufacturers, and none of them included potato starch (daoniansan). Now, the major brands that were nominated have lost all heat, while this potato starch – which is a national staple (found on almost every street food corner across China with a large number of stalls, likely the most prevalent) – has been brought out to argue and it feels like potato starch is being entirely scapegoated. I’ve looked at online news sources; CCTV released a report on ham on 3.15, listing only a few manufacturers&amp;rsquo; ingredients, and none of those manufacturers were primarily producers of potato starch. There was nothing obviously wrong with their ingredients, and then this reporter used information from an employee at one factory who said they sometimes use chicken bone meal to substitute for meat – something that was rumored – and she went to inquire on Taobao about pet food suppliers selling chicken bone meal: “Can people eat it?” This isn’t a stupid question, is it? They dare to sell it to pets? Then rumors spread that potato starch contained chicken bone meal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, many factories are likely to close down, and tens of thousands of small street vendors across the country face the situation of having goods unsold and no business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-life-on-earth&#34;&gt;Real Life on Earth
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Xiaoxiang Morning News reports on March 17th, the day after the “stuck starch tube collapse” incident in Sanmenxia, Henan, an elderly woman set up a stall selling starch tubes two days later, but after two hours, she still didn’t attract any customers and ultimately quietly ate the starch tubes herself. The photographer said that he himself usually eats four or five starch tubes at once, but after learning that the starch tubes contained chicken bone mud, he refused to eat them. That day, out of curiosity about whether anyone would still buy her sausages after they were exposed, he saw that the vendor hadn’t sold a single tube in two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The aunt didn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about the starch tube incident; she only knew that suddenly no one was buying her grilled sausages today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The elderly woman was right; she was just trying to make a living, and the elderly woman didn’t even know if the product had any problems or whether it was qualified, nor did she know what bone mud was. She didn&amp;rsquo;t know about the internet; she was simply a bottom-level person finding ways to survive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The starch tubes collapsed, but the bill was paid by one after another of bottom-level vendors. It’s a painful process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;zhihu-answer-regulatory-issueshttpswwwzhihucomquestion648967411answer3433978475&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/648967411/answer/3433978475&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Zhihu Answer: Regulatory Issues&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, during an afternoon, my colleague who was working in Beijing and I went to have lunch. We passed by a small stall selling sausages and sizzling beef skewers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blurted out, “With all this black technology starch sausage and sizzling beef, are people even going to eat it?” Because in my view, the last time I ate a starch-based ham sausage was probably about fifteen years ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague hesitated and then said tactfully, &amp;ldquo;Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve been living in a big city. Actually, in our hometown, pickled cabbage, instant noodles, and ham sausages are everyday staples.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I was in school, my dad would only let me have a sausage on the road if I got full marks. It wasn’t because they were unhygienic; sausages simply cost 1.5 yuan, enough to buy two pounds of vegetables.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The way we call instant noodles, carbonated drinks, and spicy strips ‘junk food’ – I only learned about that after coming to Beijing for school.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized how arrogant my casual words had been and stopped talking. But this incident left a deep impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this is the daily life of most Chinese people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their lives don&amp;rsquo;t include fancy “Mediterranean diets,” “green organic vegetables,” or “non-GMO soybeans.” They only care about whether they can buy some cheap and delicious vegetables, meat, and snacks, and enjoy the few moments of happiness their families have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They’re curious about what ingredients make up the things on shelves, whether they might harm their health, and if there are any strange chemical components.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s simply not something they should be concerned with or understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They simply believe that if there’s a problem, someone should be in charge, and it shouldn’t appear on the shelves.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after watching a 315 episode, we realized that wasn’t the case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-tech modifications were found in electronic scales and gasoline pumps, requiring YouTubers to take videos risking beatings to expose them, allowing regulators to “suddenly realize” and investigate;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The pork belly and starch sausages sold on live streams and small stalls turned out to be made with rotten meat and bone meal, requiring CCTV reporters to go undercover and film before anyone verified the source and tracked it down;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Health wines” heavily promoted on television and airport advertisements needed someone to expose their entire backstory through videos before they were urgently removed overnight, disappearing from the public’s sight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once a year&amp;rsquo;s 315 event, every six or seven products are randomly pulled – is that enough?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How do you find those who have already eaten or bought them?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Oriental Zhentan Short Essay Incident: A Collision of Culture and Commerce</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/dongfang-zhenxuan-essay-controversy-culture-vs-commerce/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 18:57:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/dongfang-zhenxuan-essay-controversy-culture-vs-commerce/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Oriental Zen Selection short essay incident was a online uproar triggered by Oriental Zen Selection’s official account denying that anchor Dong Yufei was the author of all the short essays. The truth is now unrecoverable, and the company&amp;rsquo;s power struggles have pushed this matter into the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fish’s seven-second memory will be handed over to &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; for writing, having experimented with &lt;code&gt;Bing AI&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ChatGPT Plus&lt;/code&gt;. The former provided more complete information, while the search engine still obtained more data, but the output blog content was not as complete and had a rigid format; the latter generated content based on keywords, which wasn’t as complete but could obtain full blog content. If given the URLs of reference materials, it could optimize the generated article.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-text&#34;&gt;Main Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dongyu He incident, involving a short essay by Oriental Select, is a dispute centered around copyright and creative ownership. Beginning on December 5, 2023, it involved a series of interactions between anchor Dong Yuhe and Oriental Select. This storm not only revealed the complexities of commercial operations but also sparked profound reflections on contemporary commercial culture and online society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-5-2023-event-origin&#34;&gt;December 5, 2023: Event Origin
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dongyu Hui, a host from Oriental Zhentan, quickly went viral after reciting “short essays” in a pre-release video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oriental Zhentan stated in the video comments that most of these short essays were created by the copywriting team and not entirely from Dongyu Hui’s own hand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-13-2023-dong-yufeis-response&#34;&gt;December 13, 2023: Dong Yufei’s Response
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dong Yufei published a lengthy article opposing the defamation of anyone under the guise of “fan circles,” stating her position on the matter.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-14-2023-management-response&#34;&gt;December 14, 2023: Management Response
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dong Xuhe (CEO of Oriental Zhensheng) released an apology video, admitting to management loopholes within the company.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yu Minhong (Chairman of Oriental Zhensheng) also responded to the incident, expressing apologies to Dong Yuhui.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-16-2023-major-decisions&#34;&gt;December 16, 2023: Major Decisions
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oriental Zhentan officially removed Sun Dongxu from the CEO position, with Yu Minhong assuming the role.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the same day, Yu Minhong published an apology letter, stating that he would unblock users who had been banned from live streams.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-18-2023-dong-yufeis-new-role&#34;&gt;December 18, 2023: Dong Yufei’s New Role
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental Education &amp;amp; Technology Group appoints Dong Yufei as Chairman and Cultural Assistant of New Oriental Education &amp;amp; Technology Group, concurrently serving as Vice President of New Oriental Culture &amp;amp; Tourism Group.
-俞敏洪 (Yu Minhong) revealed that he will establish a studio with Dong Yufei to open new live broadcast accounts and live rooms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-and-reflection&#34;&gt;Conclusion and Reflection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This storm was not only a dispute over copyright and creative ownership, but also deeply reflected the collision between culture and commerce. In today’s digital and fragmented era, the ownership of content copyrights has become a topic worthy of deep consideration. The Oriental Sanshifen Incident, not only a media storm, but also a profound reflection on contemporary commercial culture and online society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As observers, how should we view this collision between culture and commerce? While pursuing commercial interests, how can we protect and respect the creative labor of creators? These questions are worth deep consideration for each of us.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Opening of Financial Anti-Corruption</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain-rise/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain-rise/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Committee of the Communist Party of China: will intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, and thoroughly rectify “the four prevailing tendencies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;communist-party-of-china-central-politburo&#34;&gt;Communist Party of China Central Politburo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China held a meeting on September 27, reviewing the Comprehensive Report on the First Round Supervision of the First Session of the Twentieth Party Congress. Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Communist Party of China, chaired the meeting. The meeting emphasized that the supervision and oversight work should be used as an opportunity to further strengthen the leadership of the Communist Party in all aspects, urging supervised party organizations to raise their political stance, conscientiously fulfill the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Central Committee, continuously enhance the core functions and competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, intensify financial institutions&amp;rsquo; service to the real economy and national strategies, and promote high-quality development. It was stressed to coordinate development and security, firmly establish bottom-line and limit thinking, adopt effective measures to prevent and mitigate major risks, and safeguard the safety line.  It was also necessary to advance comprehensive Party self-discipline to greater depths, consolidate the responsibility of the secretary of the党委 (party committee) as the first person, strengthen the responsibilities of leadership committees members “dual duties in one position,” and enhance the supervision responsibilities of disciplinary and supervisory organizations, highlight strengthening supervision of all levels’ “one leader”, intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and financial sectors, deeply rectify “four prevailing styles,” deepen reform, improve systems, promote source governance, and facilitate treatment of problems comprehensively. (Xinhua)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating Major Financial Risks! Liu Liange, former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Merchants Bank, has been expelled from the Communist Party.
According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, with the approval of the Communist Party of China, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision initiated an investigation into Liu Liange’s serious violation of disciplinary and illegal acts as the former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Merchants Bank Co., Ltd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideological conviction, betrayed his original mission, was firm and resolute in implementing the decisions and plans of the Communist Party Central Committee, failed to guard against financial risk prevention responsibilities, recklessly intervened in loan projects and issued loans illegally, causing major financial risks, was ineffective in fulfilling his role as the main body of comprehensive self-discipline of the Party, seriously damaged the political ecology of his unit, privately brought prohibited books into the country, plotted against organizational scrutiny; ignored the spirit of the Eight Rules, accepted gifts and valuables illegally, visited private venues, and received skiing and tourism arrangements; failed to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, did not truthfully explain when questioned by the organization, showed favoritism in appointing and promoting personnel; violated regulations regarding commercial operations; illegally interfered with capital lending, secretly retained confidential materials; was morally corrupt, had an improper family style, failed to properly manage his relatives and educate them; lacked a bottom line of discipline and law, abused power, “ate from finance,” used his position for the benefit of others in loan financing, project cooperation, and illegally accepted huge amounts of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu Liange seriously violated the Party’s political conduct, organizational conduct, integrity conduct, work conduct, and lifestyle conduct, constituted serious disciplinary violations and was suspected of criminal offenses related to illegal loan issuance and fraud, and did not curb or restrain himself after the 18th Party Congress, had a severe and adverse impact, warranted serious handling. In accordance with relevant provisions of the &lt;em&gt;Disciplinary Punishment Code of the Communist Party of China&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Law of the People’s Republic of China on Supervision&lt;/em&gt;, and after deliberation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision Committee and approval by the Communist Party of China, it was decided to expel Liu Liange from the Communist Party with a dismissal sanction; cancel his benefits in accordance with regulations; terminate his representation in the Nineteenth National Congress; recover illegally obtained income; transfer his suspected criminal issues to the Public Prosecutor’s Office for investigation and prosecution, and related property to be transferred to the Public Prosecutor’s Office.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li Xiaopeng, former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Everbright Bank, has been expelled from the Communist Party and public office due to serious violations and illegal acts (CCTV News).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision reported: According to a report from the Guiyang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China, Li Zhi Ming, former Party Secretary and Chairman of Guiyang Rural Commercial Bank, was suspected of serious violation of discipline and law and is currently under investigation by the Guiyang Municipal Committee of the Communist Party of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-an-eight-year-hiatus-huijin-boosts-holdings-in-four-major-banks&#34;&gt;After an Eight-Year Hiatus, Huijin Boosts Holdings in Four Major Banks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, Industrial Bank, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, and Construction Bank – the four major state-owned commercial banks – respectively announced that Huijin Company had increased its holdings, totaling 276.1 million shares, 372.7 million shares, 248.9 million shares, and 183.8 million shares, respectively. Huijin Company plans to continue increasing its holdings in the four major banks on the secondary market over the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>China’s COVID-19 lockdown easing</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-coronavirus-end-lockdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 19:22:04 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-coronavirus-end-lockdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The policy announcement was incredibly sudden, and its implementation was swift – the Health Code QR code was lifted, and checks for green codes in public places ceased. Browsing the Chinese-language version of The New York Times, the entire front page was dominated by discussions about China’s reopening.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I won&amp;rsquo;t comment on the policies; I’m simply recording what’s happening around me. Originally, Beijing had no zero-COVID policy, but the relaxation of restrictions spread rapidly, resulting in widespread infections. Among my friends, none were seriously ill. Shenzhen, bordering Guangzhou, also began to develop quickly. As I write this, with colleagues based in the suburbs of Shanghai, there haven’t been any large-scale outbreaks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back home, the protective measures were minimal, and they spread rapidly. Most people likely experienced a similar feeling – suddenly, restrictions were lifted, with new policies announced weekly until a full reopening was achieved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s undeniable that the three years of zero-COVID policy had an effect; we must adapt to the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pelosi Visits Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 22:57:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t know politics, don’t make comments, record this “carnival” on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;musings&#34;&gt;Musings
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tangshan Assault Incident&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Primary School Textbook Cultural Invasion Incident&lt;/strong&gt; – I wonder how many people even remember them anymore. These trending news stories have become numbingly commonplace, without much feeling, and I just watch TV as usual after work, observing the spectacle. The economic situation is already dire; a war wouldn’t make things any better.  I don&amp;rsquo;t understand politics or offer commentary, simply recording this internet-fueled “carnival.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wiki-overviewhttpszhwikipediaorgwiki2022e5b9b4e58d97e8a5bfc2b7e8a3b4e6b49be8a5bfe8a8aae5958fe58fb0e781a3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022%E5%B9%B4%E5%8D%97%E8%A5%BF%C2%B7%E8%A3%B4%E6%B4%9B%E8%A5%BF%E8%A8%AA%E5%95%8F%E5%8F%B0%E7%81%A3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wiki Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Nancy Pelosi visit to Taiwan, also known as the Pelosi visit to Taiwan, refers to U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s 2022 visit to Asia, specifically her itinerary which included a stop in Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the U.S. House Speaker being considered the third-highest official in the United States and plans to visit Taiwan, the date was approaching shortly before the Chinese People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army&amp;rsquo;s (PLA) 70th Founding Day on August 1st, and long-term it approached the Communist Party of China’s Twentieth National Congress, the 2022 U.S. elections, and the 2022 Taiwan local elections. The government of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China issued a strong protest, dispatching destroyer task forces to the northeast waters of the Taiwan Strait and mobilizing the Shandong and Liaoning aircraft carrier strike groups, with the Eastern Theater Command and Southern Theater Command conducting large-scale live-fire exercises in the East Sea and South China Sea respectively. On the U.S. side, the Ronald Reagan aircraft carrier strike group arrived around the Taiwan Strait to guard Pelosi’s possible visit itinerary, and multiple waves of reconnaissance aircraft and aerial refueling tankers were deployed on standby at Japan&amp;rsquo;s Camp Hikawa Air Base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden had a video meeting before the visit, which covered the issue of Taiwan. Taiwanese and international media reported that Speaker Pelosi and the House delegation would arrive at Songshan Airport in Taipei on the 2nd, stay overnight, and meet with Taiwan’s Presidential Office level officials including President Tsai Ing-wen on the 3rd. Some analysts believe this visit could potentially lead to a new crisis in the Taiwan Strait, similar to the 1996 Taiwan Strait Missile Crisis, after 26 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-11&#34;&gt;08-11
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;By today, this has pretty much settled down. During this time, the headlines were dominated by various naval exercises, and Zhihu was putting in a lot of effort to update its trending charts every day, talking about all of this. Let the reporters work hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Shanghai Fen Yong Guo (Shuang Yang Pot) Lockdown</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/shanghai-yuanyang-pot-sealed/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:03:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/shanghai-yuanyang-pot-sealed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The leadership team insisted for two days that Shanghai wouldn’t be locked down, that Shanghai was important. But in the end, facing the reality or to preserve their own prestige, they came up with a strategy of closing across the Huangpu River first for a period of time, and then locking down this side of the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lockdown&#34;&gt;Lockdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I experienced the SARS epidemic and have very little memory of it. After seeing related materials, it ended because its incubation period was short and there wasn’t a nationwide spread yet. I remember being in primary school back then, with classes ending early every day, and the smell of disinfectant always lingering in the air.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the end of 2019, COVID-19 has been raging for almost three years. Workers who travel abroad have become accustomed to it, wearing masks when they need to. The recent wave of outbreaks in Shanghai has repeatedly fluctuated, originating from Hong Kong and then spreading across the border into Shenzhen, and here in Shanghai was due to a surge of imported cases from Hong Kong. The official announcement stated that the spread of the epidemic was caused by inadequate protection measures at quarantine hotels, and the mutated virus had reduced its toxicity but increased its transmission speed through ventilation systems in hotels. Initially, it wasn’t very serious and could be contained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are often confident. Shanghai&amp;rsquo;s leaders were like that too. They would choose to implement grid-based risk control with us for precise containment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lockdown-1&#34;&gt;Lockdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can all see from the results, the new cases have already exceeded 20,000, leaving us with no choice but to implement a lockdown. Notably, it didn’t use the word “lockdown” externally, as it had previously stated during a press conference that Shanghai did not need a lockdown, in order to preserve its last shred of face.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;grocery-shopping&#34;&gt;Grocery Shopping
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The delivery industry is a new emerging sector driven by the internet. The core of it relies on someone delivering groceries for you, right? However, due to widespread lockdowns in many areas during the pandemic, merchants could operate but no one was available to deliver, which removed the final link in the chain. People outside of this may not fully understand – how could a cosmopolitan metropolis like Shanghai, with its residents going everywhere, all rush out to buy groceries together en masse? In reality, most people are also migrant workers who come here to work and live in rented apartments, typically eating at company canteens or restaurants, rarely cooking at home. When this route becomes blocked, those with the means will start buying groceries. Because this lockdown announcement was not made in advance, people didn&amp;rsquo;t have much food or vegetables stored up, which led to the chaotic rush to buy groceries seen in the video. In that situation, gathering together directly resulted in a resurgence of the epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industry&#34;&gt;Industry
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;All of us are working in the IT industry. I experienced the impact of the pandemic, getting a taste of remote work. Back in 2019, I stayed at home for almost a month, changing my train tickets back and forth ten times, with no certainty about when I would be able to return to Shenzhen.  I can’t even imagine how those people in the catering, tourism, or many service industries have been getting by these past few years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Capital Monopoly and the Demise of the Online Education Industry</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent two trading days have seen a significant downturn in the stock market, exposing newcomers to the risks of the market. China is about to enter an aging demographic phase, and birth rates are dismal, with the decline exceeding the estimates of relevant experts, hindering industries that obstruct declining birth rates; the Party will take decisive action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-burden&#34;&gt;Reducing Student Burden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 1990s didn’t have as many interest classes or tutoring sessions; after school, we would run wild playing. This was first due to the limitations of our families&amp;rsquo; conditions and second because tutoring centers hadn’t yet established a brand effect, convincing parents to trust them. Twenty years have passed in a flash, and since 2019, the capitalization of K12 education has seen the rise of online tutoring companies like猿辅导 (Yuancu Tu), bolstered by capital, which have created various high-end tutoring centers by concentrating excellent resources. Despite exorbitant fees, parental enthusiasm remains unstoppable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process of urbanization, many parents see education as a path to escape the constraints of the peasantry and achieve a social class leap. As cogs in the machine themselves, they don’t have much time to care for their children, not only because they are highly competitive but also because they don&amp;rsquo;t want their children to fall behind their peers. “It’s difficult for nobles to become commoners,” and with ordinary education levels, it is hard for families in China to maintain their current social standing or make another class leap. If they enter vocational high schools, in today’s society, they believe this represents a downward slide in social status, which is something most parents cannot accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-burden-1&#34;&gt;Reducing Student Burden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the reasons behind extracurricular tutoring and why parents seek it out. Textbook knowledge and example problems are straightforward – many students can understand them easily. However, many subjects cover broad concepts superficially without delving deeply. The talent selection mechanism requires differentiation, leading to a contradiction: exam questions based solely on textbook knowledge cannot effectively filter candidates. This necessitates horizontal and vertical expansion of learning. These areas are aspects that teachers simply cannot cover in the classroom, creating the fertile ground for extracurricular tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document contains numerous clauses and specifications, outlining multiple aspects and providing a summary of the guiding document’s outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Completely reduce the total amount and duration of homework assignments to alleviate students&amp;rsquo; excessive workload.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the level of after-school services offered by schools to meet diverse student needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly govern extracurricular training activities and comprehensively standardize their behavior.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly enhance teaching and learning quality to ensure that students master what they learn at school.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen supporting governance and improve support capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully organize and implement it, aiming for tangible results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elite-education&#34;&gt;Elite Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s also a phenomenon in the education sector – the increasing prevalence of powerful private schools. Public schools are struggling to provide sufficient high-quality resources (leading to enclaves/gated communities). Various sized educational groups are attracting excellent teachers with high salaries, establishing quality learning environments, and gradually building their own brands, most notably: &lt;strong&gt;Hen Shuai Model&lt;/strong&gt;. Old Home Corporation averages over 3000 RMB, powerful private primary schools charge between 9000 and 10000 RMB per year. Educational groups form a virtuous cycle – my tuition is expensive, but the teachers are excellent, students achieve good grades, I raise tuition fees, and parents will still send their children here. Public resources (teachers) are gradually being drawn to private schools, ultimately becoming synonymous with substandard education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithmic-optimization&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Optimization
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is data showing that Meituan’s contracted delivery riders have approached 4 million, with approximately 400,000 active riders. Many people rely on this job to support their families and livelihoods. The relentless algorithmic pressure to minimize delivery times reduces individuals into measurable units, feeding them into algorithms for constant calculation, continually exploring the boundaries of delivery rider collapse. Believing themselves clever, &lt;strong&gt;they violate human nature and serve capital.&lt;/strong&gt; The market operates here, allowing everyone to play and enjoy sustainable play, rather than &lt;strong&gt;monopolizing, wielding privileges, the gameplay of capitalism, a reckless and brutal growth that will ultimately come to an end&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility&#34;&gt;Stock Market Volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 2021, education stocks represented by New Oriental performed a dramatic plunge, followed by Hao Pai Futures in the pre-market session. &lt;strong&gt;Stock prices plummeted by half.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China has gradually entered an aging population, and various social phenomena affecting family planning must be rectified; monopolistic and overtime internet companies were fined, and the capital-concentrated education industry was also scrutinized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility-1&#34;&gt;Stock Market Volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The education industry is not allowed to be capitalized on; a single vote directly negated related industries&amp;rsquo; IPO financing, and there was wailing everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental &amp;ldquo;Takes a Plunge&amp;rdquo;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/new_oriental_stock_price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;New Oriental &amp;ldquo;Takes a Plunge&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan Crashes
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/new_oriental_stock_price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Meituan Crashes&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.infoq.cn/article/9Q1O2vWYNE8Mfhkzuyzs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Regulatory Intensive Efforts Cause Online Education to “Brake Suddenly”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.moe.gov.cn/jyb_xxgk/moe_1777/moe_1778/202107/t20210724_546576.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;The State Council Office issued the &amp;ldquo;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Extracurricular Training Burden of Students in Compulsory Education Stages&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points, the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism. From the mouths of the older generation, we heard that to get rich, you first needed to build roads. China&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure construction – these things are all funded by the state, and in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there’s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. Talking too much is getting off-topic, and ordinary people might feel that trade wars don&amp;rsquo;t have much impact on their lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. The IT industry I work in – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – the core configuration of assembling a computer comes from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost, and high-end manufacturing is undoubtedly essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war (often referred to as the “China–United States trade war,” “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” or “US-China trade war”) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China is stealing US intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, imposing tariffs on goods imported from China totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States. The Ministry of Commerce of China retaliated in kind with a 25% additional tariff on $340 billion worth of U.S. goods exported to China, including soybeans, the largest export product from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides had temporarily reached an agreement to pause the trade war in May 2018 and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative subsequently released its first list of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States on June 16, raising the existing 10% tariff to 25%. The China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) then retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S. products exported to China. On July 6, the Trump administration formally implemented tariffs on the first list of $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, marking the formal implementation of Trump’s trade policy towards China (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently added with a 25% tariff on August 23). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; The General Administration of Customs of China (GACC) indicated that China’s counter-measures were implemented immediately after the U.S. imposed tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump agreed to hold a nine-month negotiation and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the U.S. side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on approximately $200 billion, totaling $250 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, which took effect on June 1. On May 13, the China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) announced that tariffs on $600 billion worth of imported U.S. products would be raised to a range of 5% to 25%, starting from June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced that the implementation date for tariffs of 25% on U.S. goods would be postponed to June 15, and SAFE stated that China’s tariff measures took effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Trump held a meeting at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart economic consultations, with the United States ceasing to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to concerns about China’s purchasing process of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that tariffs of 10% would be imposed on the remaining $300 billion worth of all Chinese goods shipped to the United States starting September 1, 2019. On August 5, the Renminbi exchange rate against the US dollar fell below 7 yuan. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that China was designated as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and parts, while the U.S. side responded by increasing the tariff rates on its existing $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and its current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as retaliation, but these measures were subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
