<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Dong-Xi-Ying on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/dong-xi-ying/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Dong-Xi-Ying on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/dong-xi-ying/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The “Tiangong” (Heavenly Palace) incident in medical education and the Butterfly Effect of Dong Xi Ying’s case</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 01:08:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Beijing Children’s Hospital “4+4” project (4 years non-medical bachelor&amp;rsquo;s + 4 years medical doctorate) focuses on interdisciplinary elite cultivation. The exposure of Dong Xi Ying’s case in 2025 revealed her leveraging family background (medical/scientific research lineage) to enter the program, raising concerns about the ambiguity of her qualifications, allegations of plagiarism in her dissertation, and exposing a conflict between the project&amp;rsquo;s elite recruitment model and fairness. Issues regarding shortened study durations and internship training remain unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompts&#34;&gt;Prompts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog: Harmony 4+4 Origin and Development, Core: A Corner of Tian Gong, Seen by Mortals, Dong Xiaojie&amp;rsquo;s Family Background, Normal Medical Doctor Cannot Graduate in Eight Years, Dong Xiaojie’s Family and Educational Background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;harmony-44-deconstructing-medical-educations-tian-gong&#34;&gt;Harmony 4+4: Deconstructing Medical Education&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Tian Gong&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “4+4” project at the Beijing Union Medical College, since its launch in 2018, has been viewed as China’s “Tian Gong” – or celestial palace – in medical education. This project, designed to mimic the American medical education system, adopted the philosophy of “cultivating multidisciplinary individuals, nurturing loving doctors, and attracting outstanding talents from across the nation.” It aimed to create a rift within traditional Chinese medical education by: &lt;strong&gt;replacing the traditional 5+3+3 (five-year bachelor’s degree + three-year master’s degree + three-year doctoral degree) model with a four-year non-medical undergraduate program plus a four-year medical doctorate training.&lt;/strong&gt; This was intended to cultivate cross-disciplinary leadership talent in medicine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project&amp;rsquo;s “Tian Gong” attributes are reflected across three dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elite Recruitment:&lt;/strong&gt; Early requirements stipulated that applicants must come from QS/Times/US News top 50 universities or US News’s top 10 liberal arts colleges (such as Barnard College), later relaxed to the top 100, but still requiring a GPA of 3.6 or being within the top 30% of their class. &lt;strong&gt;Internationalization of Learning Pathways:&lt;/strong&gt; Adopting an organ-system integration curriculum in the American style, PBL (Problem-Based Learning) methodology, students must complete core courses such as anatomy and pathology within 4 years, and participate in clinical internships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Controversy Regarding Export Quality:&lt;/strong&gt; Although the pass rate for practicing physicians (95.2%) is slightly lower than that of traditional eight-year programs (98.5%), graduates predominantly enter affiliated hospitals, and their career development shows no significant difference from traditional pathways.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dong-xiying-incident-a-celestial-realm-crack-revealed-by-ordinary-eyes&#34;&gt;Dong Xiying Incident: A &amp;ldquo;Celestial Realm&amp;rdquo; Crack Revealed by Ordinary Eyes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 2025, the extramarital affair involving Xiao Fei, a thoracic surgeon at Zhongdayu Hospital, and his wife was reported, inadvertently exposing the “mysterious veil” of the 4+4 project at Xinhua Hospital. The background of Dong Xiying, the person involved, sparked three key questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambiguity Regarding Educational Background:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispute Over Undergraduate Institution:&lt;/strong&gt; Dong Xiying claimed to have graduated from Columbia University, but actually attended Barnard College (ranked 14th in US News &amp;amp; World Report for liberal arts colleges in 2025). Although the school met Xinhua Hospital’s requirement of “top 20 liberal arts colleges,” its diploma simultaneously listed &amp;ldquo;Barnard College&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Columbia University,&amp;rdquo; which could be easily misinterpreted as Columbia University&amp;rsquo;s main campus in the domestic recruitment market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispute Over Professional Field:&lt;/strong&gt; An economics undergraduate degree combined with a clinical medicine doctorate path, while aligning with the 4+4 project’s positioning of “multi-disciplinary background,” was questioned for lacking foundational courses in pre-medical studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dong-xi-ying-incident-peering-through-the-heavenly-palace-crack--a-glimpse-for-ordinary-people&#34;&gt;Dong Xi Ying Incident: Peering Through the &amp;ldquo;Heavenly Palace&amp;rdquo; Crack – A Glimpse for Ordinary People
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unique Family Background:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic Resource Monopoly:&lt;/strong&gt; Her father was the secretary of the China Metallurgical and Research Institute, her mother was a deputy director of the North Science University Engineering Technology Research Institute, her grandfather was an academician in the imaging field of Xinhua Medical Institution, and her uncle and aunt were foreign academicians in the materials field at North Science University. This “medicine + research + university” composite family background provided implicit resources such as recommendation letters (requiring recommendations from two biomedical associate professors) and research collaborations (such as North Science University patents).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Career Path Leaps:&lt;/strong&gt; She transitioned from cardiac surgery during residency to urology, with research spanning orthopedics, gastroenterology, radiology, and other fields. This was questioned as “paved road” due to the rapid changes in her career path.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exaggerated Controversy Over Study Duration:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasonableness of Time Compression:&lt;/strong&gt; Traditional medical doctorates require 11 years (5+3+3), while the 4+4 program compressed the time to 8 years. Despite Harmony emphasizing “curriculum integration” and “early clinical exposure,” some physicians pointed out that its clinical internship period (12 months) is still less than the traditional eight-year program (18 months), potentially impacting skill accumulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Controversy Regarding CCT Reduction:&lt;/strong&gt; Some CCT bases allowing 4+4 graduates to have a year of CCT reduced are being questioned for undermining industry fairness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-medical-education-quagmire-behind-the-controversy&#34;&gt;The Medical Education Quagmire Behind the Controversy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dong Xiying incident reflects deep contradictions within Chinese medical education:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conflict between Elitism and Equity:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The “application-assessment” model of the 4+4 program is essentially a transplant of the American medical school model, but China lacks standardized exams like MCAT, relying instead on subjective evaluations such as recommendations and research experience, which are significantly influenced by family background.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data shows that among graduates of the 4+4 program in 2023, 30% came from Qingbei Fuzhou (the top universities), and 25% from overseas prestigious schools. The influence of family background on applications is significant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Reality of Curriculum Reform:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Cost of Time Compression:&lt;/strong&gt; 4+4 students produce significantly fewer research outputs (such as the number of publications) than traditional eight-year programs, and are accused of “prioritizing clinical work over research.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Divergence in Industry Recognition:&lt;/strong&gt; Three-tier hospitals prioritize the reputation of Covance (the name of the top medical school), while基层医院 (jīchéng yīyuàn – primary hospitals) maintain a cautious attitude towards the clinical abilities of 4+4 graduates. - &lt;strong&gt;The Confusion Surrounding the International Integration of Medical Education&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US 4+4 model requires passing the MCAT exam and completing a 3-7 year residency, while China’s 4+4 programs have simplified the entry and residency stages, leading to “form resembling but not being” the real thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data from the Ministry of Education shows that in 2024, 4+4 programs accounted for less than 5% of national medical doctorate admissions, and their large-scale promotion still faces resistance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-reconstructing-the-tiangong-order-of-medical-education&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Reconstructing the &amp;ldquo;Tiangong&amp;rdquo; Order of Medical Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controversy surrounding the CoHo 4+4 project fundamentally represents a clash between elite education and public expectations. When a corner of the “Tiangong” (Heavenly Palace) was glimpsed by mortals, it exposed not just isolated instances of flaws, but deeper contradictions within the entire medical education system. Future reforms must focus on three levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transparent Selection Mechanisms:&lt;/strong&gt; Introduce standardized exams (such as a Chinese version of MCAT) to reduce the influence of subjective factors like letters of recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extend Clinical Training Cycle:&lt;/strong&gt; Restore the clinical training cycle for 4+4 graduates to 3 years, ensuring that clinical competence is achieved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strengthen Process Oversight:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish an academic integrity review mechanism and conduct rigorous originality verification for interdisciplinary research.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical education’s “Tiangong” should not be a privilege reserved for a select few, but rather a true cradle for nurturing medical elites.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
