<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Buy Tickets Online on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/buy-tickets-online/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Buy Tickets Online on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/buy-tickets-online/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Mystery of Spring Festival Movie Ticket Prices: Differences Between Online and Offline Sales</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight people wanted to go see a movie. We initially planned to buy tickets on Taopihao and Maoyan, but saw the price was 60 yuan. Luckily, we had a cinema recharge card that required purchasing tickets at the front desk in person. Thinking to ask if there were any discounts, we were surprised to find that the same showing only cost 35 yuan when bought at the front desk – quite a difference in price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hidden-markups-on-platform-service-fees&#34;&gt;Hidden markups on platform service fees
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While online ticketing platforms offer convenience, their service fees are not insignificant. They create a user-friendly ticket purchasing experience, such as precise seat selection and the ability to view purchase history at any time, all of which require financial investment for maintenance. These costs are added to the ticket price in the form of platform service fees, resulting in higher online ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinema-differentiation-operating-strategy&#34;&gt;Cinema Differentiation Operating Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demand for moviegoing during the Spring Festival season is surging, and theaters are using tiered pricing to maximize profits. Online platforms have high traffic, and many people are accustomed to buying tickets in advance online, so theaters set higher prices for those tickets; however, they offer lower prices to attract walk-in customers who purchase tickets directly at the front desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pricing-logic-behind-profit-sharing-cooperation&#34;&gt;The pricing logic behind profit sharing cooperation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The split of revenue between online platforms and cinemas affects ticket prices. Online platforms need to take a share from the box office, so they raise ticket prices to ensure profitability. Cinema counters sell tickets directly without any intermediary links, reducing costs, and naturally offering more affordable prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-consumers-buying-tickets&#34;&gt;Tips for Consumers Buying Tickets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just focus on online platforms when buying tickets in the future. Try calling the cinema front desk to ask about prices, or go directly to the front desk for inquiries – you might be surprised. If you’re a frequent moviegoer, getting a cinema membership card and enjoying member benefits can save you quite a bit of money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
