<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Movie on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/movie/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Movie on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/movie/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Spring Festival Blockbuster Movie Ticket Price Mystery: The Difference Between Online and Offline Prices</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-movie-ticket-price-mystery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-movie-ticket-price-mystery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight people wanted to go see a movie. They originally planned to buy tickets on Taopiaopiao and Maoyan. When they looked at the price, it was 60 yuan. Luckily, they had a cinema recharge card that required them to purchase tickets at the cinema’s front desk. They thought about asking the front desk if there were any discounts, but unexpectedly, the same showtime cost only 35 yuan when purchased at the front desk. The price difference was quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hidden-add-on-of-platform-service-fees&#34;&gt;The “Hidden Add-on” of Platform Service Fees
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While online ticketing platforms are convenient, platform service fees cannot be ignored. They provide users with a seamless booking experience, such as precise seat selection and the ability to view purchase history at any time – all of which require investment in maintenance. These costs are then passed on to consumers through increased ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinema-differentiation-operation-strategies&#34;&gt;Cinema Differentiation Operation Strategies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the explosive demand for movie-watching during the Spring Festival, cinemas adopted differentiated pricing strategies to maximize revenue. Online platforms have a large volume of traffic, and many people are accustomed to purchasing tickets online in advance; therefore, cinema ticket prices were set higher on these platforms. Conversely, those buying tickets directly at the box office – walk-in customers – received lower prices to attract this segment of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-price-logic-behind-revenue-sharing&#34;&gt;The Price Logic Behind Revenue Sharing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Revenue sharing models between online platforms and cinemas impact ticket prices. For an online platform to take a slice of the box office revenue – in order to maintain profitability – they will typically raise ticket prices. Meanwhile, cinema box offices have no intermediary costs, leading to lower prices and more affordable tickets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consumer-ticket-buying-tips&#34;&gt;Consumer Ticket Buying Tips
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t just look at online platforms when buying tickets. Call the cinema&amp;rsquo;s front desk to inquire about prices, or go directly to the front desk and ask – you might find a surprise. If you frequently watch movies, get an auditorium membership card to enjoy member discounts and save money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Analysis of Political Elements in 2025 Spring Festival Film Releases</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-films-spring-festival-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:49:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-films-spring-festival-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I went to the Spring Festival movie release to join in the crowds, and this time I watched two films that felt quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the new changes in the 2025 Spring Festival movie releases, focusing on &lt;em&gt;Dwelling in the Fuchun Pavilion&lt;/em&gt; (Tangrenjie Tanjian 1900) and &lt;em&gt;Nezha: The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Child&lt;/em&gt;. The former utilizes the backdrop of San Francisco’s Chinatown in 1900 to depict the discrimination and oppression faced by Chinese people, reflecting social and political conditions. As an animated film, the latter employs rich metaphorical elements to subtly critique the current international political landscape – such as the Jade Palace resembling the Pentagon mirroring the American political system, the dollar symbol on the Heavenly Mandate Throne symbolizing U.S. dollar hegemony, the jade amulet similar to American green cards representing status levels, and the Soul-Devouring Elixir resembling biological weapons reflecting malicious actions. Both films offer a new viewing experience and prompt reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovation-in-the-style-of-chinese-new-year-film-releases&#34;&gt;Innovation in the Style of Chinese New Year Film Releases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, films released during the Spring Festival often featured lighthearted entertainment and family-friendly themes, aiming to allow audiences to relax and unwind during the holiday season, rarely addressing sensitive political topics. However, in 2025, the Spring Festival release broke with convention; &lt;em&gt;The Mystery Down South 1900&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Nezha: Part One&lt;/em&gt; incorporated rich political elements, sparking widespread discussion among viewers and bringing a new atmosphere to the Spring Festival film slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shanghai-noon-1900-a-vivid-depiction-of-political-times&#34;&gt;“Shanghai Noon 1900”: A Vivid Depiction of Political Times
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Shanghai Noon 1900” is set in San Francisco’s Chinatown in 1900, when Chinese immigrants overseas faced severe racial discrimination and oppression. The protagonists not only have to solve the mystery of the case but also confront discrimination and unfair treatment from all sides of society. The film&amp;rsquo;s portrayal of racism and power struggles accurately reflects the social political environment of that time, allowing us to see the difficult struggle of Chinese immigrants for survival and dignity, and the underlying political issues worth deep consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This historical background inevitably reminds one of the current predicament faced by overseas Chinese in the business sector, such as the TikTok and Zhou Jiayu incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 6, 2024, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit rejected TikTok’s request, ruling that the legally mandated sale law passed by Congress under national security grounds had withstood constitutional scrutiny. TikTok CEO Zhou Jiayu wrote in a memo to employees that the next step would be “seeking an injunction and awaiting review by the U.S. Supreme Court.” The source of this event is the U.S.’s “Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversarial Control of Applications” law, which requires ByteDance to divest its TikTok business within 270 days after the law’s passage, with a final deadline of January 19, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During various hearings, Zhou Jiayu was subjected to numerous difficulties. On January 31, 2024, the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee held a hearing on “The Big Tech Companies and the Online Child Sexual Abuse Crisis,” with anti-China lawmaker Tom Cotton confronting Zhou Jiayu, repeatedly posing eight questions about his nationality, including asking him what country he was from, whether he had applied for Chinese or American citizenship, even sparing his wife and children’s nationalities. Despite the hearing&amp;rsquo;s theme being “online child sexual abuse,” the lawmakers shifted the topic to TikTok being owned by Chinese company ByteDance, forcing Zhou Jiayu to answer irrelevant questions. Just as in “Shanghai Noon 1900,” Chinese people overseas faced unwarranted discrimination, Zhou Jiayu also suffered from unfair treatment and questioning due to the background of TikTok, which is owned by ByteDance. This series of events reflects how, across different eras, overseas Chinese face numerous obstacles when pursuing their own development and safeguarding their rights – whether it’s racial discrimination a century ago or political manipulation in business today, all deserve our deep reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-deer-and-the-phoenix-political-metaphors-hidden-behind-mythology--an-analysis&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Deer and the Phoenix&amp;rdquo;: Political Metaphors Hidden Behind Mythology – An Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite appearing as a typical animated film, “The Deer and the Phoenix” is replete with political metaphors through its numerous settings and plots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mapping of Power Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; The Yuhuang Palace is molded into the center of supreme power in the celestial realm, with architectural styles resembling the Pentagon, primarily using white tones to symbolize Western hegemony disguised under the banner of “universal values.” The “Monster Hunting Squad” led by Wuliangxian, with its subordinates Lu Ban and He Feizi, are believed to correspond to the US alliance system, including Japan and South Korea. The Yuhuang Palace’s “online meeting” scene, with twelve golden immortals discussing the “Battle of Sovereigns,” is similar to NATO meetings led by the United States, suppressing other countries under the guise of “maintaining order.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hints of Economic Hegemony:&lt;/strong&gt; The Taiyuan Ding used for alchemy in the Yuhuang Palace has a dollar sign at its entrance, symbolizing America’s use of economic hegemony to “refine” and exploit resources from other nations. Wuliangxian’s act of refining dragons into the Ding with the justification of “upholding heaven and earth” is like certain countries using “international rules” to pursue their interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metaphors of Identity and Hierarchy:&lt;/strong&gt; The celestial identity amulet granted to Nezha, with its color and pattern design resembling a US green card, symbolizes the celestial realm’s rejection and hierarchical division of “foreign races,” reflecting real-world differences in identities and unequal treatment between different countries and groups.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Allusions to Malicious Actions:&lt;/strong&gt; Wuliangxian forcing Nezha to take the Dan of Soul Annihilation, which resembles a bioweapon, darkly alludes to certain countries using the guise of “saving the world” to carry out destructive and devastating actions against other nations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbolism of Resources and Development:&lt;/strong&gt; The Seven Colored Lotus is crucial for reshaping Nezha and敖 Peng’s bodies, symbolizing key energy and technological lifelines monopolized by major powers. Its “jade nectar and elixir” must be obtained through the Yuhuang Palace&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;celestial examination,&amp;rdquo; mirroring developing countries’ dependence on core resources and being subjected to “rule-based plunder” under a hegemonic system. The Lotus’ temporary failure and restoration conditions reflect the plight of small nations in energy crises.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-reflections-on-cinematic-art-and-political-expression&#34;&gt;Deep Reflections on Cinematic Art and Political Expression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These films, amidst the nationwide viewing craze during the Spring Festival, incorporated political elements, offering audiences a new cinematic experience – one that moved beyond simple entertainment and served as a mirror reflecting political issues within history and reality. This has prompted us to delve into the relationship between cinematic art and political expression. Will directors in future film creations increasingly convey their perspectives on social and political matters through cinema? As a powerful cultural transmission medium, can film simultaneously engage in artistic expression while also taking greater notice and consideration of societal realities? These questions are worth exploring as we appreciate films, and we look forward to the film industry bringing more exciting integration of art and real-world expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter Egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boabab large model, wasn&amp;rsquo;t performing very well today, it froze several times, the article stopped halfway and couldn’t continue, so I had to restart the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
