<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Random Thoughts and Musings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/random-thoughts-and-musings/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Random Thoughts and Musings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/random-thoughts-and-musings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Too much AI, some side effects</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the establishment of &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s been a surge in recording and publishing trivial things using AI. Consequently, time for quiet reflection has diminished. It would be better to slightly control the output of this column and consolidate it into a monthly publication, releasing one article per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a lingering effect or side effect – efficiency increases, but depth and breadth of thought decrease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-improvement-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency improvement: Undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, this column wasn&amp;rsquo;t well-maintained. Due to laziness, I didn’t search for information or compile records on some trending events. Now, with various AI tools, outlining is sufficient; the AI can automatically search and record related events, generate articles, and after simple formatting, they can be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is like a dream come true for those who don&amp;rsquo;t want to put in too much effort; it significantly boosts efficiency, almost achieving results with half the work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficiency significantly improves when coding instead of writing articles. Many code sections previously required detailed review of API documentation; now, this step can be skipped – a necessary shortcut. Familiarity with APIs is best left to AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;junk-content&#34;&gt;Junk content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the submissions lack substance; they feel lifeless and stale, like chewing wax—not a style I previously enjoyed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, AI-generated content often feels like mass-produced work, lacking soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet junk of the new era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetfulness&#34;&gt;Forgetfulness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of article is AI-generated. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the readers, and over time, my own memory will fade or even disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar issues arise when coding – without reviewing the commit history, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know your original thought process or rationale for a particular implementation. This is especially true with code generated after extensive revisions and discussions with AI, which can significantly diverge from the initial idea, even becoming entirely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant decrease in how often I use Google and Baidu recently; searching with AI is much better than traditional search engines, both in terms of interaction and results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s commemorate &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the earliest AI tools connected to the internet released by a major company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are using Google less; visits to &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; have decreased as well. Many questions can now be answered directly by AI, and this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blog I&amp;rsquo;m still maintaining doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much traffic anyway, and certainly won&amp;rsquo;t now; it’s more of a personal journal for my own reference&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>County-level Brahmin: Big Shots in Small Towns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Teacher Da Bing has become very popular on Douyin. You often see accounts sharing clips from her livestreams. During one livestream, a listener asked, &amp;ldquo;Teacher Da Bing, I want to sell my house in Xi&amp;rsquo;an and return home to relax.&amp;rdquo; Da Bing replied, &amp;ldquo;At your age, in your thirties, you can’t just ‘lie flat.’ Your parents are aging, your children aren&amp;rsquo;t established yet, and even returning to your hometown, you’ll still have to deal with the complexities of a small county town.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether the view is right or wrong, what does this word mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many small county towns, people often talk about &amp;ldquo;county Brahmin&amp;rdquo; – their existence feels like a symbol of the local society. They are not necessarily religious figures or individuals with impressive titles, but rather seemingly ordinary yet influential people. They represent “power, status, and voice” in a small place, symbolizing a certain stratum within that county town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-1&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, we need to understand that &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; originally referred to the highest stratum of Indian society, representing wisdom, authority, and spiritual supremacy. However, in Chinese county towns, the term “county town Brahmin” lacks such complex religious connotations; it&amp;rsquo;s more a metaphor for a social phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmin&amp;rdquo; refers to individuals who hold cultural authority within a county, such as teachers, doctors, prominent local merchants, and officials. Although their positions may seem ordinary, in the relatively closed environment of a county, they possess a comparatively high social status or, more accurately, considerable influence on local opinions and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-2&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the county town, almost every industry has these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins.&amp;rdquo; They might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Especially teachers with decades of experience in local areas, who may not be graduates of prestigious universities, but deeply understand how to build credibility through knowledge and are widely respected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officials in county-level cities, such as deputy county commissioners and section chiefs, control certain resources and power. Despite their relatively low positions, due to the limited scope of their authority, they can become influential figures within their localities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owners in some county-level cities, though their businesses may not be large, hold considerable wealth and local influence. They might run a couple of well-known small enterprises and have significant sway within the county.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These individuals, though not prominent compared to elites or officials in big cities, hold a status almost equivalent to &amp;ldquo;cultural elders&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;power centers&amp;rdquo; within this small county-level society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-3&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the meaning of &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins,&amp;rdquo; we must consider the unique environment of county towns. Here, information flows more slowly than in big cities, and social mobility is relatively fixed. These &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; often gain influence through long-term engagement with the locality, accumulating reputation, knowledge, and networks. They impact various aspects of local politics, economy, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In smaller areas, particularly where the education system may not be well-developed and ordinary people have limited choices, local &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; figures subtly shape the cultural atmosphere through knowledge imparted in classrooms, media explanations, and even social interactions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the limited population and resources in county-level towns, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often key controllers of local resources. Their influence is pervasive, affecting everything from social welfare and policy implementation to project approvals. Their power of speech and decision-making allows them to hold a significant position within the local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a relatively closed small society, interpersonal relationships are often crucial. These &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; control the flow of information and allocation of resources by establishing strong social networks, allowing them to play a decisive role at critical moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-4&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often respected and revered, this elevated status is not without its problems. In modern society, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see that many of these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may lack genuine ability and innovative spirit, instead maintaining their position through hereditary relationships and resource monopolies. With the development of informatization, their power is gradually being eroded, and new social mobility is beginning to reshape the landscape of small counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;ldquo;County-Level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; is a fascinating social phenomenon that reflects the power and cultural structures within local societies. While their “power” may not directly threaten national governance, they are undoubtedly influential figures within their localities. In this era of rapid information flow and accelerating social change, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may be facing unprecedented challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-5&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have existed at all, but out of curiosity—and that’s how this article came to be&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Getting out and about is generally good</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had followed my family&amp;rsquo;s plans and stuck with studying electrical engineering instead of writing code, I probably would have been a typical obedient son&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dusting off memories, sparked by the approaching Spring Festival and a conversation with my roommate, prompting a review of these past years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gaokao results weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly good or bad. I graduated from a 211 university, but according to my father’s original plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work at the local electricity bureau. As mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly touch on how I ended up in IT—I forgot to mention one key factor: my values and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still in a rural school during my first year of junior high, my family arranged for me to transfer to a city school by my second year. It felt like Liu姥姥 visiting the Grand View Garden – I struggled to adapt to the city&amp;rsquo;s vibrancy. I hadn’t gone to the cinema many times as a child, certainly not with my parents; relatives had taken me occasionally. Fortunately, I made friends with several like-minded guys. Though we don&amp;rsquo;t keep in touch much now, those youthful days were still good. After tutoring on weekends, we would collect plastic bottles from the classroom, expertly crushing them with our feet and packing them into bags to take home for my mom to save. Once we had enough, we’d find someone to recycle them. We played chess, badminton, and Dou Di Zhu (a card game), and the losers had to do push-ups. I was even a little grateful then that my dad had been getting me involved in various sports since I was young. That&amp;rsquo;s when my perspective on money started to shift, and I felt slightly inferior. But these minor misfortunes were fleeting. My family wasn’t wealthy; we didn’t have much pocket money, and sometimes I couldn’t play with the other kids, especially on weekends. My parents’ hard work was visible – we moved from the village to the city. The seeds had been planted, waiting to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being a simple person, I was generally very happy during my studies—a feeling many don&amp;rsquo;t experience until after graduation. Studying isn’t particularly difficult; the conversion of effort to results is relatively straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining childhood memories of the imperial era with university life, encountering a laptop felt like opening Pandora&amp;rsquo;s Box. I was introduced to games and connected with the role of a game merchant. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, purchasing goods upstream and selling them through my own network, earning small sums. Gradually, I understood the entire operational logic of the chain. The goods we sold were essentially batch-incubated by upstream programs with near-zero costs. At this point, things started to veer off course. My major had specialized branches – electrical grids on one side, and automation (a broad field including chip programming and factory electrical automation) on the other. Realizing that programming could make significant money, and seeing how much profit was made upstream, combined with my existing programming background, I began experimenting and earning small amounts of money. During major selection, I naturally chose automation. I skipped many required courses in my junior year, constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s article mentioned that, driven by a romanticized view of hackers and with the kindness of IT experience, I delved into assembly, penetration testing, game hacks, DLL hijacking, and account theft, becoming familiar with various black and gray industries. My parents taught me ethics, and the law still guided me; I didn&amp;rsquo;t go completely astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous article link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During university, I had one relationship. Looking back, it was more about longing for the kind of love seen in TV dramas. At that time, my emotional maturity wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to understand how to truly love someone, let alone build a family and establish a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been fortunate. My university years didn&amp;rsquo;t lead to graduate school; I started working right after graduation and benefited from the boom in the IT industry. It’s been eight years now, but the hype has faded and the era is coming to a close. Sometimes I wonder if I made the wrong choice, perhaps entering the power grid as my father suggested would have been better. That thought lingered for the first five years, but gradually disappeared. Joining HSBC through campus recruitment, I didn’t switch companies for five years – this left gaps in my technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following instructions from headquarters in Hangzhou, I went to Shenzhen, experienced a workplace power struggle (which I later realized was a loss for everyone involved, with the board ultimately winning), and returned to Hangzhou fueled by a passion for technology. With a touch of youthful naivete, I left Hangzhou and moved to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle, register residency, and buy a home in Hangzhou. With interest rates at their peak and housing prices at their highest, entering the market would likely lead to being stuck with a mortgage; my family savings are too thin to handle it. The thought of marrying under that kind of financial pressure, compounded by industry downturns, makes me emotionally unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After so many years, witnessing so much, experiencing my own foolishness and recklessness, I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing well. Through experiences and encounters with people, I’ve gradually matured. Staying at home would have left those personality flaws to erupt in some unknown way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Monetization Model: Raffles/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Host giveaways of iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift lotteries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These seemingly unrelated things are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic, with a hint of financial engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;win-gifts-through-platform-lottery&#34;&gt;Win gifts through platform lottery
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users obtain platform currency to purchase gifts for their favorite streamers. Platforms also offer another approach: instead of directly gifting, users can spend the acquired currency to enter raffles and win exclusive, high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s already a problem – online lotteries are essentially platforms running casinos. With enough participants, they’re guaranteed to be profitable. &lt;strong&gt;屌丝&lt;/strong&gt; Users participate hoping for a big win, intending to show off and gain status!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gift-from-streamer-physical-item&#34;&gt;Gift from streamer (physical item)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The platform&amp;rsquo;s lottery focuses on user content. Hosts have monthly activity and popularity tasks. Enabling the gifting lottery allows fans who send designated gifts or amounts to participate, with prizes like high-end phones or cash rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular streamers, this event is quite profitable – essentially a zero-cost purchase with enough participants to generate income. It tests the streamer&amp;rsquo;s operational skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another way to play—with high rewards (cash value)—and many outdoor streamers use this method, essentially a form of online gambling. People don’t care about the content; users only care if they can win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from show-focused hosts, ordinary game streamers struggle to drive player spending through PK mode. Gaming and watching streams are leisure activities; people don&amp;rsquo;t typically want to spend extra money. Especially lotteries can cultivate users’ charging habits and consumption habits, occasionally leading to impulse purchases (with generous prizes, creating a desire to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini-program ranking rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini-program with trivial processes or offer limited gaming support. These are all cover tactics to pass Tencent&amp;rsquo;s review; the gameplay should include a ranking system. Users earn points by viewing incentivized ads and completing tasks, and the backend uses these points to determine rankings. High-ranking users receive designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core logic: Advertising revenue &amp;gt; Operating costs + Reward expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even small programs can operate effectively, providing reasonable services and earning income through appropriate advertising. The earnings may not be substantial, but a steady trickle can still work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>At that time, he was young; perhaps he had talent, but not much</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my seventh year of working, the positive feedback from coding isn&amp;rsquo;t as frequent anymore. Looking back on how I ended up down this path.
The choices we make, especially in childhood, tend to follow positive feedback – proactively avoiding harm and seeking benefit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-childhood&#34;&gt;One, Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving downtown, encountering computer books? Hacker resources? Becoming familiar with Windows systems? Those are later stories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother&amp;rsquo;s uncle runs a shop in the computer market
We started using computers early on, so we developed a basic understanding of them. Later, in school and during computer classes, I remained quite interested.
I heard about the computer competitions in junior high, thought they were really cool, but then after transferring schools, I put that idea aside
During my first year of junior high, I was familiar with basic computer operations and often stood out in computer class
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with it – yes, you read that right, not proficient, but familiar – with Microsoft Office suite, that would be even better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving&#34;&gt;Moving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the move, once I got into the city, I ended up frequenting the library due to my neighbors. While I read a lot of novels, I also looked at many magazines.
Computer News, Popular Software
Increasingly interested in computers, with childhood admiration for hackers and actively learning related knowledge at school
Understanding the basics of operating systems: Control Panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This magazine is quite suitable for beginners; it explains operations systematically using case studies
software reviews, industry news, and more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;high-school&#34;&gt;High school
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my second year of high school, [this competition], the school leaders also paid it considerable attention
There&amp;rsquo;s also a foundational hardware aspect – an alumnus donated a building to the university, including a new library and computer lab. It’s all so coincidental.
With Bo&amp;rsquo;s explanations, he would be considered a computer expert in the class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic whiz + computer expert, knows how to hack computers and disable classroom surveillance software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition, despite its challenges, reached the finals. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully grasp everything, the questions focused on basic algorithms, but I did gain some valuable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still just half a bucket, like taking a trip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-college&#34;&gt;Four. College
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it came time to choose a major in college, I followed my family&amp;rsquo;s suggestion and chose automation. I actually wanted to study high-voltage electricity, hoping to work for the power company after graduation, but I didn’t learn much of the coursework.
Self-directed learning is scarce in professional courses, but computer science courses within those programs come naturally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping required courses, studying computer science diligently, and spending time daily on forums like &amp;ldquo;Jingyi Forum&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;52PoP.&amp;rdquo;
Combining knowledge of assembly language and C++,
Ultimately, Xiao Zheng&amp;rsquo;s choice was to write code for chips, and my family didn&amp;rsquo;t interfere; they let me choose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, [name redacted], with a high level of education, joined Baidu
My older sister understands me; she knows I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a state to think or research, so she told me to talk it over with my cousin
Finalize the future development path; skip going home for summer vacation, stay with the mentor, work on projects, and gain experience
Entered Hengan Electronic based on a still-acceptable academic record&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;graduation&#34;&gt;Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the key – I took courses in information retrieval, knowing how to quickly find and locate materials and issues
A helpful mentor appeared at work, gave me time to learn independently, troubleshoot issues thoroughly, and introduced me to experts at the R&amp;amp;D center
This laid the groundwork, and now Shenzhen branch believes I&amp;rsquo;m impressive – I successfully took charge of the trading channel team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here lies a problem; my foundational knowledge of computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design…
Without systematic study, it&amp;rsquo;s all based on personal experience
Frequently redesigning code, lacking a consistent approach to module design – after seven years, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel burnt out&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>nights-naming-art</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character for &amp;ldquo;fate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;life,&amp;rdquo; 命, stands alone – it has no homonyms. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life is unique and unrepeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flipping through the rankings on Qidian Chinese, &amp;ldquo;Night&amp;rsquo;s Naming Technique&amp;rdquo; is dominating with its monthly votes, far ahead of second place by a huge margin – practically unattainable. I’ve mostly read works from established authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Er Gen in the past, but this time I decided to try a new author and experience a different kind of reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, &amp;ldquo;Night&amp;rsquo;s Naming&amp;rdquo; had reached two million monthly tickets, significantly surpassing the second-place novel with only eighty thousand, a remarkable difference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lack the expertise to evaluate the writing of this book. However, having read through more than ten chapters, the plot is tightly paced and intricately connected, captivating the reader. The high number of votes it received is well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, like the character for &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo; (命), the character for &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; (死) also has no homophones in Chinese. Does this perhaps suggest that the end of life is equally unique and irreplaceable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right – you are a person, and also an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; possessing feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your essence. We won’t discuss the great individuals who willingly sacrifice themselves for society or for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;right-now&#34;&gt;Right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering average wages, or even those in my hometown, my current income is already significantly above average. What more could I possibly want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning a million; once you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning ten million. This is human nature, and one must confront their own inner desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s causing all the envy? It’s the easy money of short videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see is this short video, but you don’t see the scriptwriting and filming behind it. Yet, everyone dreams of being a genius, believing they are naturally suited for that field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-contact&#34;&gt;Begin contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching so many videos, a little analysis reveals clear professional editing and a strong cinematic feel. This suggests they have formal training. While there&amp;rsquo;s logic to grassroots success stories, it doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, you&amp;rsquo;ll find countless videos teaching you how to make videos. That’s when reality sinks in: if this could really make money, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime edits, which were enjoyable to watch. But when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began relentlessly recommending instructional videos, flooding my feed. As someone in the IT industry myself, I couldn’t help but wonder if the team behind the algorithm had lost their minds. Is this recommendation strategy meant to imply that users are foolish? And the fact that they keep suggesting ways to earn money through Douyin, from various angles and types… This piece is being written at 3 AM, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even intend to write it. I just question how long this business model can last and how much time it will consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preaching one thing when instructing others, but failing to control oneself – that&amp;rsquo;s a joke. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven’t published much domestically. Here, I’m just casually complaining. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least currently, it actively assists with the spread of real-time news and the promotion of state policies. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to my school days now. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In today’s era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology. If you can see this line, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the entire draft is very conversational. Honestly, I just read it aloud and wrote it down. I used Sogou Input Method for years, but when it comes to voice input, iFlytek is undoubtedly more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 was changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? It&amp;rsquo;s a dream that the number of entries this year could exceed one hundred – it really is a dream. They aren’t exactly articles, more like records. I examine myself three times a day; you surely can think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>lost-and-confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at some point in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose sight of their pursuit of meaning. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations; back then, I would have confidently said that I longed to write code—remarkable, exceptional code. However, in my current role, I’ve primarily dealt with operational matters, largely benefiting from the dividends of industry growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t considered marriage, having children, or establishing a career. My mind is mostly blank, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. On weekends, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day at home, immersed in my own world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to in life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-house&#34;&gt;Buy house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was determined to save enough money to buy my own home and meticulously planned every expense. However, seeing house prices continually rise, I went from anxiety and resentment to numbness. Eventually, I realized that even if I bought a property, it would just be another heavy burden, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving small goals – like building a powerful desktop computer, buying a camera I&amp;rsquo;d long wanted, or taking an impromptu trip. Now, I approach saving with a more relaxed attitude, worry less about daily expenses, indulge in what I want to eat, and boldly try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I truly longed for was simply to go home. No special occasion needed, just returning to a familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
