<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>“Increased scrutiny of third-party advisor regulation, and the beneficiaries behind the ‘Douyin (TikTok) stock trading’ phenomenon face a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.
Following the wind of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.
In late September this year, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, recommendations on Douyin (TikTok) have attracted attention from various parties.
Several financial commentators have risen to prominence on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in the capital markets.
However, the rapid rise of these commentators is not to be ignored – it’s largely driven by third-party investment advisory firms.
It&amp;rsquo;s understood that many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (投流) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding advisory products.
There are even rumors that one third-party investment advisory firm generated 10 billion yuan in revenue in October alone, exceeding its first-half earnings this year.
But “good times” are facing more uncertainties. Since November, multiple departments have successively issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliant management of their self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 15th, Tianhong Securities (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in behavior such as hinting at recommending stocks through livestreaming operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be signaling to the market a stricter regulatory approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion prospects of third-party investment advisory service institutions, such as JiuFang Zhitu (9636.HK), are also likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tight-regulation-monitoring&#34;&gt;Tight Regulation Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant League of Finance’s monitoring, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under such circumstances, the “pushing and pulling” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of investment advisors recommending individual stocks through various methods during live broadcasts is a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend new clients for a company that was found to be “hinting at stock recommendations” during a live broadcast. On November 14th, the Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 (Guangdong Securities and Futures Association) issued a notice titled “Live Streaming Control Issues Lead to Suspension of Business for Institutions,” directly addressing instances where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications exhibited inadequate control during live streaming operations. The notice also cited instances of recommending individual stocks within the live streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The practice of recommending stocks through live streaming is strictly prohibited. Given that live streaming constitutes public media dissemination, all individuals, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, shall not recommend individual stocks during live streams.” The Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 stated this clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Commission (SRRC) disclosed a penalty notice that also involved illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.  An investigation by regulators revealed that Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, used WeChat Video No. to publicly disseminate misleading video content, violating professional conduct.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stringent-supervision-in-place&#34;&gt;Stringent Supervision in Place
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to information obtained by Wind (ID: TradeWind01), some ineligible investment advisory firms were using “front-running” brokers (ID:TradeWind01) on Douyin (TikTok) to recommend stocks, and they have since been suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Individuals in the industry are livestreaming, but they are actually operating under the umbrella of a broker-dealer, which allows them to obtain investment advisor qualifications. They then use these livestreams to generate leads and sell advisory product bundles,” said a consultant based in South China to Wind (ID: TradeWind01). “However, because they were recommending stocks during the livestream, it was discovered, leading to their suspension. Regular broker-dealers typically discuss sector trends during investment education livestreams but do not delve into individual stock recommendations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are maintaining a high level of vigilance regarding illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms. For example, recent notices from the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Commission have revealed that some individual institutions or individuals are engaging in illegal stock promotion through self-media, among other violations. To further regulate self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies within its jurisdiction, all institutions must strengthen their company’s self-media management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for third-party wealth management service providers&amp;rsquo; business expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-a-scam&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is a Scam
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors attracted by short videos have made money remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As China’s “first online investor education stock,” JiuFang Intelligence’s market capitalization rose from 2878 million yuan on September 9th to 12464 million yuan on November 13th, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report shows that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by June 30th, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhu” (a nickname) has 2.26 million followers on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We deeply cultivate MCN operations, focusing on the user-centric approach, and synergistically promote the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products.” “Nine Fang Intelligence Investment pointed out, “By deeply integrating new media tools such as live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant course packages cover a price range from several hundred yuan to over ten万元 (approximately $1.5 million). The most expensive package, “Super Investor,” priced at 13.96万元 ($2.0 million) for six months, includes exclusive insights and private consulting services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant products have a return rate exceeding 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the return rates for the flagship series and “Nine Fang Intelligent Dragon” series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the impact of regulatory headwinds on Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s business expansion remains to be observed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports have stated that accounts belonging to third-party custodians such as Jiu Fang Zhi Tu (Nine Wise Investment) have been affected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a report by a media outlet claimed &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; (a popular livestreamer) was suspended from streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th at 3:00 PM, Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the “Hong Bangzhu” livestream interface still allowed bookings for a live stream on November 18th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market news indicated that relevant authorities have intervened to inspect Jiu Fang Zhi Tu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a source close to Jiu Fang Zhi Tu told Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) that the inspection was a routine check and had already concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company embroiled in rumors surrounding this regulatory storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities has been investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may be suspended from operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th that “there were no illegal stock recommendation cases and no investigation was initiated.” “However, that evening, Tianhe Securities announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tianhe Securities Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau for violations during its livestreaming promotional activities, specifically due to inadequate compliance controls and instances of hinting at recommended stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also signify a further escalation in regulatory scrutiny regarding stock recommendations on social media platforms like Douyin (TikTok) Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the short video market is attracting many brokerage firms, but due to compliance requirements, brokers are currently being cautious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-forbidden&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is Forbidden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told Wind Info (ID:TradeWind01) that the company was exploring short video operations and lead generation methods, and had organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning. However, due to regulatory compliance requirements, it is currently in an exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements, is because short video content has a distinctly emotional color. But investors need to maintain rationality when dealing with it, and there is a natural conflict between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If emotional forces influence capital markets, it can easily trigger violent market fluctuations, which goes against the long-term healthy development of capital markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What way should securities firms embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “crossing the red line”? It’s clearly a difficult question for all parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, but also a bipedal animal, complete with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everyday sensibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is far above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you think about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you think about earning one billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but what you don’t see is the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are becoming more aware. If they could really earn money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling. It felt surprisingly engaging, to the point where you’d start to find it interesting yourself. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone who also works in the IT industry, this made me feel like the algorithm overlords were having a bit of a problem – you know, recommending things in this way. They’d constantly find new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they were trying to figure out whether I was stupid or they were. The question is, how long can this business model last? How much time can you drain from people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, just quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet down and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must always come up with something, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
