<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>“Increased scrutiny of third-party advisor regulation, and the beneficiaries behind the ‘Douyin (TikTok) stock trading’ phenomenon face a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following the surge of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In late September, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, Douyin (TikTok) recommendations for stocks garnered attention from various parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous financial commentators have risen to prominence on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behind these rapidly rising financial commentators lies a significant force: third-party investment advisory service companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s understood that many third-party advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (投流) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are even rumors that one third-party advisory firm achieved revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, “good times” are facing more uncertainties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since November, multiple departments have issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliance management of self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On November 15th, Futu Securities (300033.SZ) announced that a subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in suggestive stock recommendations through livestreaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be signaling a stricter regulatory environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The expansion of third-party investment advisory service firms like Fangyuan Intelligence Investment (9636.HK) is likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring-by-regulators&#34;&gt;Close Monitoring by Regulators
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant Network, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the “stirring up” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulatory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment advisors recommending stocks through live broadcasts constitutes a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took measures to suspend new clients for a company’s livestreaming that presented “implicit stock recommendations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14th evening, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued an announcement titled &amp;ldquo;Live Streaming Control Lacking Effectiveness, Institutions Suspended Business,&amp;rdquo; directly addressing situations where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate controls during live streaming operations and engaged in recommending stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association stated: “Strictly prohibit livestreaming stock recommendations. Livestreaming is a public media dissemination platform, and livestreaming personnel, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, shall not recommend stocks during live broadcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau disclosed a penalty notice involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated professional norms by publishing misleading videos through WeChat Video No., which contradicted industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau subsequently issued a supervisory management measure to issue a warning letter to Wang Yong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wind (ID:TradeWind01) information, some unqualified investment advisory firms have been using “rented” brokerage accounts to promote stocks on Douyin and have since been suspended from broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people are livestreaming in the industry, but they are actually renting under a brokerage firm, which gives them investment advisor qualifications, then they use live streaming to generate leads, and sell investment advisory product bundles offline,” said a consultant from South China to Wind (ID:TradeWind01). “However, because they recommended stocks during the livestreaming, they were discovered and subsequently suspended.” Regular brokerages typically discuss sector trends but do not involve individual stock recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that some institutions or individuals were using self-media to illegally recommend stocks, in order to further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies in the辖区, all institutions should further strengthen company self-media operation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for the business development of various third-party investment advisory service firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors who were attracted by short videos made a profit remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “China’s first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence’s market capitalization rose from 2.878 billion yuan at the beginning of September to 12.464 billion yuan on November 13, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report showed that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by the end of June, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhuxi” has 2.26 million fans on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on users, and synergistically promote the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products,” JiuFang Intelligence stated. “By deeply integrating live streaming, short videos, and other new media tools, leveraging AI technology to build a fan network, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory course packages cover price ranges from tens of yuan to more than ten万元. The most expensive package, “Super Investor,” is priced at 139,600 yuan per six months, including exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory product refund rate is above 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for JiuFang Intelligence’s flagship series and JiuFang Intelligence’s Qionglong Series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, under regulatory scrutiny, whether JiuFang Intelligence&amp;rsquo;s business development will be affected remains to be further observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports said that accounts belonging to third-party investment advisory companies such as JiuFang Intelligence have been impacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a media report stated that “Hongbangzhuxi” was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th, XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the appointment for “Hongbangzhuxi’s” livestream on November 18th was still available in the livestream interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market sources said that relevant departments have entered JiuFang Intelligence for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a close source to JiuFang Intelligence told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection belonged to routine inspections and had already ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company involved in this round of regulatory storm rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities was investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may suspend business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th, “There were no illegal stock recommendation cases, and there was no investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that same evening, Tianhong Securities announced that its subsidiary Zhejiang Tianhong Cloud Software Co., Ltd. was penalized with a three-month new customer suspension due to inadequate compliance controls in the promotion of livestreaming business and the existence of scenarios suggesting recommendations of stocks, by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also mean that regulatory departments are further focusing on荐股 (recommendation of stocks) content on social media platforms such as Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the cake of short videos has also attracted many securities firms, but due to compliance requirements, securities firms are currently cautious about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the company is exploring methods for short video operations and lead generation, and it has organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning, but due to compliance requirements, it is still in an exploratory stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements is because the content on short video platforms has a distinct emotional color, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality, and the two exist in a natural conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If uncontrolled emotions influence the capital market, it can easily trigger violent fluctuations in the market, which goes against the long-term healthy development of the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What manner should securities holding institutions embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “stepping on red lines”? This is clearly a difficult question for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, and also a bipedal animal, with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everydayness&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is significantly above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you start thinking about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you start thinking about earning a billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but you don’t see the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are starting to wake up. If they could really make money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling – you’d start to find them interesting. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone in the IT industry myself, I began to feel that the “big brothers” behind these algorithms were having a bit of a problem – you recommend like this, are you thinking I’m stupid or are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; stupid? Crucially, they keep finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they&amp;rsquo;re constantly trying to figure out the most effective way to exploit my time. I started wondering how long this business model could last, and how much time they could drain from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet their minds and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It&amp;rsquo;s not really articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must be able to think of some things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
