<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Douyin on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/douyin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Increased scrutiny of third-party investment advisors; will those behind the TikTok stock trading scheme face repercussions?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sledgehammer is falling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage services, boosted by short videos, may be entering a period of rapid growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late September, following a surge in A-share market performance, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s stock recommendations received widespread attention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several financial commentators, including &amp;ldquo;Da Lan,&amp;rdquo; gained popularity on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of popular financial commentators is also supported by third-party investment advisory firms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using traffic strategies to attract viewers to watch their educational videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing related investment advisory products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumors suggest that a certain third-party investment advisory firm earned 1 billion yuan in revenue this October alone, exceeding its earnings for the entire first half of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &amp;ldquo;good times&amp;rdquo; are facing more uncertainties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since November, various departments have issued documents requiring securities service providers to strengthen compliance management of social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 15th evening, Tonghua Shun (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the securities regulatory commission for livestreaming activities involving implied stock recommendations
This could be signaling that regulators are tightening their oversight
The promotion of third-party investment advisory firms, including Nine Square Wisdom Investment (9636.HK), may face increased pressure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring&#34;&gt;Close monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin has amplified emotional expression and indirectly influenced trading behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from Jullian Analytics, during the period of September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volume reached a new high, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, more than doubling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actions of third-party investment advisors are attracting regulatory attention amid this situation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage employees recommending individual stocks during livestreams is a frequent violation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend the acceptance of new clients from a company due to instances of &amp;ldquo;suggesting stock recommendations&amp;rdquo; during its livestream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 14th, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued a notice titled &amp;ldquo;Inadequate Live Stream Control Results in Business Suspension,&amp;rdquo; directly pointing out that certain institutions with securities advisory qualifications had inadequate controls during live stream promotional activities, including recommending specific stocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live stock recommendations are prohibited. Live streaming falls under public media dissemination, and live streamers, regardless of whether they are registered securities investment advisors, are not permitted to recommend individual stocks during broadcasts. - Guangdong Securities &amp;amp; Futures Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a penalty notice disclosed by the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau also included one case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An investigation by regulators revealed that Wang Yong, an investment consultant at Haitun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd. Shanghai Branch, published misleading video content on WeChat Video Number, which violated professional conduct guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau took supervisory measures, issuing a warning letter to Wang Yong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, some unqualified investment advisors who were recommending stocks on Douyin (TikTok) by affiliating with brokerages have been suspended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some individuals in the industry are doing livestreams on Douyin, operating under brokerage firms to obtain investment consultant qualifications. They then use these livestreams to attract customers and sell investment consultant product packages offline. However, they were suspended after being caught recommending specific stocks during a livestream. Reputable brokerages typically only discuss sector conditions in their educational livestreams, but avoid mentioning individual stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau has notified that some institutions or individuals within the industry have been found to be engaging in illegal stock recommendations and other violations through self-media. To further regulate the operation and management of securities investment consulting agencies&amp;rsquo; self-media within its jurisdiction, each agency should strengthen their own self-media operations management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may bring more challenges to the promotion of third-party wealth management services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;traffic-businesses-are-illegal&#34;&gt;Traffic businesses are illegal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether investors lured into the market by short videos have made money remains to be seen, but as &amp;ldquo;water sellers,&amp;rdquo; third-party investment advisory firms are already seeing their value rise in the secondary market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leading player in online investment education, Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s market capitalization has surged from 287.8 million yuan in early September to 1.2464 billion yuan as of the close on November 13th, representing a gain of 333.08% over 49 trading days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mid-year report shows that in the first half of this year, Jiufang Zhi Tou conducted brand exposure on social media platforms like Douyin and Xiaohongshu, reaching 488 accounts and 0.46 billion followers by the end of June&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; (Mr. Hong), as Chief Investment Consultant for Jiufang Zhito, has 2.26 million followers on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focus on MCN operations, prioritizing users and collaboratively driving the comprehensive development of traffic, brand, and product. Jiu Fang Zhi Tou notes that by deeply integrating new media tools like live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we can effectively achieve efficient conversion of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiufang Zhitu&amp;rsquo;s advisory courses range in price from several thousand to over ten thousand yuan. Their most expensive package, &amp;ldquo;Super Investor,&amp;rdquo; is priced at 139,600 yuan/six months and includes exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Jiumfang Intelligence Investment&amp;rsquo;s advisory products have a refund rate exceeding 10%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for Jiu Fang Zhi Tou&amp;rsquo;s flagship series and Qinyulong series were 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s business expansion will be affected remains to be seen amidst regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent media reports indicate that accounts under third-party investment advisors like Jiufang Zhi Tou have been affected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, media reported that &amp;ldquo;Hong Tou&amp;rdquo; was suspended from streaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 15th, TradeWind01 searched for the account and found that appointments for the livestream on November 18th were still available on &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; live broadcast page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market news also indicates that regulatory authorities have inspected Jufeng Intelligent Investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources close to Nine Square Exit confirmed to TradeWind01 (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection was a routine check and has concluded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company recently rumored to be caught up in this round of regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports indicate that Tonghua Shun is under investigation for alleged illegal stock recommendations, potentially leading to a suspension of its business operations
Tonghua Shun responded on November 15th, stating that &amp;ldquo;there is no illegal stock recommendation situation and there has been no investigation.&amp;rdquo;
That evening, however, Tonghua Shun announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tonghuashun Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau with a three-month suspension of acquiring new clients due to inadequate compliance management during live streaming promotions and instances of implied stock recommendations
This may also indicate that regulatory bodies are increasing their scrutiny of stock recommendations on platforms like Douyin Live&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, short video platforms are also attracting investment firms, but their involvement is currently limited by regulatory requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A source from a securities firm told TradeWind (ID: TradeWind01) that the company is exploring short video operations and traffic acquisition methods, and has even sent personnel to learn from short video platform companies. However, due to compliance requirements, it remains in the exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, regulatory compliance requirements stem from the emotional nature of short video platform content, while investment requires a rational approach – a conflict inherent in their natures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allowing emotions to influence the capital market can easily trigger sharp fluctuations, which is detrimental to its long-term healthy development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How securities firms can navigate the rise of short videos while avoiding regulatory breaches remains a challenging question for all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right – you are a person, and also an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; possessing feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your essence. We won’t discuss the great individuals who willingly sacrifice themselves for society or for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;right-now&#34;&gt;Right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering average wages, or even those in my hometown, my current income is already significantly above average. What more could I possibly want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning a million; once you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning ten million. This is human nature, and one must confront their own inner desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s causing all the envy? It’s the easy money of short videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see is this short video, but you don’t see the scriptwriting and filming behind it. Yet, everyone dreams of being a genius, believing they are naturally suited for that field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-contact&#34;&gt;Begin contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching so many videos, a little analysis reveals clear professional editing and a strong cinematic feel. This suggests they have formal training. While there&amp;rsquo;s logic to grassroots success stories, it doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, you&amp;rsquo;ll find countless videos teaching you how to make videos. That’s when reality sinks in: if this could really make money, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime edits, which were enjoyable to watch. But when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began relentlessly recommending instructional videos, flooding my feed. As someone in the IT industry myself, I couldn’t help but wonder if the team behind the algorithm had lost their minds. Is this recommendation strategy meant to imply that users are foolish? And the fact that they keep suggesting ways to earn money through Douyin, from various angles and types… This piece is being written at 3 AM, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even intend to write it. I just question how long this business model can last and how much time it will consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preaching one thing when instructing others, but failing to control oneself – that&amp;rsquo;s a joke. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven’t published much domestically. Here, I’m just casually complaining. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least currently, it actively assists with the spread of real-time news and the promotion of state policies. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to my school days now. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In today’s era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology. If you can see this line, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the entire draft is very conversational. Honestly, I just read it aloud and wrote it down. I used Sogou Input Method for years, but when it comes to voice input, iFlytek is undoubtedly more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 was changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? It&amp;rsquo;s a dream that the number of entries this year could exceed one hundred – it really is a dream. They aren’t exactly articles, more like records. I examine myself three times a day; you surely can think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
