<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Bewilderment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bewilderment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Bewilderment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bewilderment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Lost</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at a certain stage in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. In the mundane routine of work, they gradually lose sight of the pursuit of meaning in their profession. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations. Back then, I would have said without hesitation that I longed to write code—code that could amaze and be incredibly impressive. However, since starting work, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed more to business-related matters, much of which is thanks to the benefits brought about by industry development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t included marriage, having children, and establishing a family or career within my sphere of thought. My mind is almost empty, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. Every weekend, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day staying at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something in their life that they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-house&#34;&gt;Buy a house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was still thinking about saving up to buy my own house and carefully calculating every expense towards that goal. However, seeing the prices of houses continue to rise, I went from initial anxiety and resentment to eventually becoming numb. I gradually felt that even if I bought a house, it would just be another heavy burden on me, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was to achieve small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, buying a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. But now, I approach saving money with a more relaxed attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses, eating what I want when I see it, and daring to try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I longed for most in my heart was simply to go home. It didn&amp;rsquo;t require doing anything special, just returning to that familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
