<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mindset on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mindset/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mindset on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and even if you’re anxious, it won’t help.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs. My ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Write an article: Addressing the mental issues in stock trading finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the initial entry into the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my investments focused primarily on blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, HK Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Expecting an annualized return while hearing bullish calls about matching a bank&amp;rsquo;s three-year fixed deposit,” in reality, it was driven by greed wanting more, leading to hasty increases in positions followed by depletion of cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represented significant capital outflows, and overall, there wasn’t enough liquidity allocated for these investments, resulting in insufficient funds later on. Buying blue chips is like aligning with “old money”—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Evergrande ran into trouble, bank stocks plummeted dramatically, successfully capitalizing on the opportunity to clear out positions. This reflects a lack of understanding regarding the impact on the broader economy. The real estate sector’s dominance within China&amp;rsquo;s economic landscape necessitates avoiding a hard landing; consequently, continued stock market declines affected red-chip stocks like &lt;strong&gt;Industrial Bank&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose for about two years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, &lt;strong&gt;Zhongxing&lt;/strong&gt; was severely impacted, and its share price also fell sharply. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HSPE (Hubei Hongyu Electronic)&lt;/strong&gt; is a legacy company; after Ant Group’s departure, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock benefits from market manipulation by a major shareholder, which allows it to surge several times per year. With reasonable position control, losses can be minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-devouring-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The “Monster” Devouring Reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greed is the most common problem in a stock trading mindset.&lt;/strong&gt; When stock prices rise steadily, and investors’ account profits continuously increase, greed quietly takes root. Many people still fantasize about continued upward movement of stocks even when they are already at high levels, craving more gains, and refusing to cut their profits. They are blinded by greed, forgetting the existence of market rules and risks. For example, during the hype of certain hot-topic stocks, some investors see a doubling or even several times increase in prices over a short period, and become trapped, constantly adding to their positions, hoping to be the last winner. However, the market will not always go crazy; when the bubble bursts and stock prices plummet sharply, these investors driven by greed often suffer heavy losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-the-chains-that-restrict&#34;&gt;Fear: The “Chains” That Restrict
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the counterpart to greed. It possesses a powerful destructive force in the stock market as well. When market conditions suddenly reverse and stock prices plummet dramatically, investors are prone to panic. This fear erodes their confidence in the market, even when the fundamentals of their holdings are sound, leading them to hastily sell off their shares out of a fear of further losses. For example, during periods of global financial crises, even high-quality blue-chip stocks saw significant declines alongside the broader market. Some investors were consumed by fear and failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies, selling their stock at extremely low prices and missing out on the substantial returns that came with subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses for investors but can also create a lasting psychological shadow over the stock market, making them hesitant to re-enter investments and thus losing out on investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blind-following-losing-direction-in-the-fog&#34;&gt;Blind Following: Losing Direction in the &amp;ldquo;Fog&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In stock trading and wealth management, blindly following trends is another psychological pitfall that investors easily fall into. In an era of information overload, various investment suggestions, market rumors, and hot topics are rampant. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment abilities, blindly following others&amp;rsquo; operations. When they see their peers making money by buying a particular stock, they immediately follow suit without further thought; when they hear so-called &amp;ldquo;insider news,&amp;rdquo; they readily share it. This blind following behavior ignores the research and analysis of the underlying stocks, causing investors to be like lost ships in the fog, losing their own direction. For example, some momentum stocks can generate short-term gains for followers during the initial market hype. However, as the hype fades and stock prices plummet, those investors who lack understanding and blindly follow become “pickup operators.” They fail to realize that each investor’s risk tolerance, investment objectives, and investment horizon are different; an investment strategy suitable for one person may not be suitable for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-the-hidden-rocks&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: The Hidden “Rocks”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is also a significant issue in the investment and financial mindset. Some investors, after achieving several successful investments, begin to inflate their egos, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict stock movements. They ignore the complexity and uncertainty of the market, engage in excessive trading, blindly expand their investment scale, and even use high leverage for speculation. However, the market is ever-changing, and overconfident investors often suffer severe setbacks in a single unexpected market fluctuation. For example, some investors with limited experience who achieved an initial victory believe they possess professional investment capabilities and begin to frequently buy and sell stocks, continuously increasing their investment amount. When systemic risks or sudden negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to cut their losses promptly due to overconfidence, leading to a significant reduction in their principal amounts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-stable-investing&#34;&gt;How to Adjust Your Mindset for Stable Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish the Right Investment Philosophy: Investors should clearly understand that stock investing and wealth management are aimed at achieving long-term, stable asset appreciation, not overnight riches. By learning investment knowledge, understanding market rules, adopting value investing and long-term investment philosophies, and avoiding being swayed by short-term profits and market sentiment, you can make informed decisions. For example, thoroughly research a company’s fundamentals, paying attention to its profitability, industry position, management team, and other relevant factors, choosing stocks with long-term investment potential rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a Reasonable Investment Plan: Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable investment plan. Clearly define key elements such as the amount to invest, the investment timeframe, expected returns, and stop-loss points, and strictly execute according to the plan. This can help avoid impulsive decisions made due to emotional fluctuations during investment. For example, set the investment proportion of each stock to no more than a certain percentage of total assets, and promptly take profits when the price rises to reach the expected return, and decisively cut losses when it falls to the stop-loss point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control emotions and remain calm: When facing market volatility, you need to learn to control your own emotions, maintain calmness and rationality. You can relieve investment pressure by diverting attention, engaging in physical exercise, or communicating with others, avoiding negative impacts of emotion on investment decisions. When the market experiences a significant fluctuation, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine them with your investment strategy and stock fundamentals, and make rational judgments instead of blindly following trends or panic selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-steady-wealth-management&#34;&gt;How to Adjust Your Mindset for Steady Wealth Management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Learning and Reflection: The stock market is constantly evolving, and investors need to continuously learn new investment knowledge and skills, paying attention to macroeconomic trends, industry dynamics, and company information, and constantly improving their investment level. At the same time, it’s important to regularly reflect on your investment behavior, summarize experiences and lessons learned, identify problems in your mindset and decision-making, and promptly adjust and improve them. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze the reasons for success and failure, and think about how to avoid similar mistakes in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in stocks and wealth management is a long and challenging journey, and mindset plays a crucial role. Only by maintaining a rational, calm, humble, and independent-thinking mindset can you steadily progress through the stock market’s fluctuations and achieve the preservation and appreciation of your wealth. ## How to Adjust Your Mindset for Steady Financial Planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Learning and Reflection: The stock market is constantly evolving, and investors need to continuously learn new investment knowledge and skills, paying attention to macroeconomic trends, industry dynamics, and company information, and constantly improving their investment level. At the same time, it’s important to regularly reflect on your investment behavior, summarize experiences and lessons learned, identify problems in your mindset and decision-making, and promptly adjust and improve them. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze the reasons for success and failure, and think about how to avoid similar mistakes in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in stocks and financial planning is a long and challenging journey, and mindset plays a crucial role. Only by maintaining a rational, calm, humble, and independent-thinking mindset can you steadily move forward in the stock market’s waves and achieve the preservation and appreciation of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
