<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mindset on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/mindset/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mindset on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/mindset/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Making money takes time; rushing it wont help</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading, while I haven&amp;rsquo;t made a fortune, I also haven&amp;rsquo;t lost too much. The biggest issue is an unreasonable cash flow plan and unstable mindset. Currently, my primary income comes from work – a fixed salary. My tolerance for financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; buying too little means you won’t profit when prices rise, while buying too much leads to losses when they fall. A stable mindset is therefore crucial; it helps steady our ship of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing through stock trading: The importance of mindset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides dabbling in small-cap and newly listed stocks when I first started, the investments I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on since have been primarily blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hengan Electronics, ZTE, and various large-cap index funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it stemmed from greed wanting more—rushing to increase holdings at the start, then facing a cash flow crisis. Expenses like insurance, buying property, and getting married were major drains on funds; the overall plan lacked sufficient financial buffer, leading to later shortages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy blue-chip stocks, it&amp;rsquo;s like relying on [someone] dependable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Evergrande ran into problems, bank stocks plummeted, allowing for a successful opportunity to sell off. However, this demonstrates a flawed understanding of the broader economy – real estate&amp;rsquo;s share in the national economy is too significant, with far-reaching implications that cannot be ignored. The subsequent market decline and the sustained rise of dividend stocks over roughly two years reflect this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The early stages of the trade war saw significant damage, with stock prices falling sharply, but they gradually recovered afterward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This stock belongs to the former employer. After Ant Financial&amp;rsquo;s divestiture, the price dropped significantly, but it has market makers who can push it up several times a year. With proper position sizing, losses will be minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-that-devours-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The &amp;ldquo;monster&amp;rdquo; that devours reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When stock prices rise steadily and investors&amp;rsquo; paper profits increase, greed quietly takes root. Many, seeing prices already at high levels, still fantasize about continued upward trends and seek greater returns, unwilling to take profits. Blinded by greed, they forget market rules and the existence of risk. For example, during speculative surges in certain hot-topic stocks, some investors, witnessing short-term doubling or even multiple times increases, become deeply involved, continuously adding positions with the hope of being the last winners. However, markets don&amp;rsquo;t stay exuberant forever; when bubbles burst and prices plummet, these greed-driven investors often suffer heavy losses. Greed robs them of their ability to analyze and decide rationally, turning them into &amp;ldquo;gamblers&amp;rdquo; rather than wise investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-shackles-binding-your-hands-and-feet&#34;&gt;Fear: Shackles binding your hands and feet
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the opposite of greed. Fear is equally destructive in the stock market. When market conditions turn sharply downward and prices plummet, investors easily panic. This fear erodes their confidence; even with fundamentally sound stocks, they rush to sell to avoid further losses. For example, during the global financial crisis, many high-quality blue-chip stocks also fell dramatically. Some investors, overwhelmed by fear, failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies and sold their shares at rock-bottom prices, missing out on substantial returns from subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses but can also create a lasting psychological shadow, deterring them from re-entering the market and causing them to miss investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blindly-following-trends-a-fog-that-obscures-direction&#34;&gt;Blindly following trends: A &amp;ldquo;fog&amp;rdquo; that obscures direction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blindly following the crowd is another common psychological trap for investors in stock trading and wealth management. In an era of information overload, investment advice, market rumors, and trending news abound. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment skills, blindly imitating others&amp;rsquo; actions. Seeing others profit from buying a particular stock, they rush to buy without careful consideration; hearing so-called &amp;ldquo;insider tips,&amp;rdquo; they invest everything they have. This blind following neglects the necessary research and analysis of individual stocks, leaving investors lost like ships in fog, losing their direction. For example, some concept stocks may generate short-term gains for followers initially, but as hype fades, prices plummet, turning those unaware and blindly following into &amp;ldquo;bag holders.&amp;rdquo; They fail to realize that each investor has different risk tolerance, investment goals, and time horizons; what works for others might not work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-a-hidden-shoal&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: A Hidden &amp;ldquo;Shoal&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is a significant issue in the mindset of stock and financial investments. After experiencing initial investment successes, some investors become inflated with pride, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict price movements. They disregard the complexity and uncertainty of the market, leading to excessive trading, blindly expanding their investment scale, and even using high leverage for speculation. However, the market is unpredictable, and overconfident investors often suffer significant losses from unexpected market fluctuations. For example, inexperienced but initially successful investors may believe they possess professional investment skills and begin frequent buying and selling while continuously increasing their investments. When systemic risks or negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to stop their losses in time due to their overconfidence, resulting in substantial capital erosion. Overconfidence is like a submerged reef, appearing calm and harmless on the surface but capable of wrecking an investor&amp;rsquo;s financial ship unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-sound-financial-management&#34;&gt;How to adjust your mindset for sound financial management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a correct investment philosophy: Investors should understand that stock trading and wealth management are for the long-term, stable growth of assets, not for getting rich quick. Through learning investment knowledge, understanding market patterns, and adopting value investing and long-term investment principles, avoid being swayed by short-term gains and market sentiment. For example, thoroughly research a company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals – its profitability, industry position, management team, etc. – to select stocks with long-term investment value, rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a sound investment plan: Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable plan. Clearly define key elements such as investment amount, timeframe, expected return, and stop-loss point, and adhere to the plan strictly. This helps avoid impulsive decisions driven by emotional fluctuations. For example, limit each stock&amp;rsquo;s allocation to a certain percentage of your total assets; take profits when prices reach your target gains, and cut losses decisively when they hit your stop-loss level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control your emotions and stay calm: When facing market volatility, learn to manage your emotions and remain calm and rational. Relieve investment pressure through methods like distraction, exercise, and communication. Avoid letting emotions negatively impact your investment decisions. When the market experiences significant fluctuations, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine your investment strategy with the fundamentals of the stocks, and make a rational judgment instead of blindly following trends or panicking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous learning and reflection are essential in the ever-evolving stock market. Investors must consistently acquire new knowledge and skills, stay informed about macroeconomic trends, industry developments, and company information to improve their investment capabilities. Regularly reflecting on investment behavior, summarizing lessons learned, identifying issues with mindset and decision-making, and making timely adjustments are also crucial. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze successes and failures, and consider how to avoid similar errors in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in the stock market is a long and challenging journey where mindset plays a crucial role. Maintaining rationality, composure, humility, and independent thinking are essential for navigating market volatility and achieving wealth preservation and growth. Investors should consider cultivating a positive mindset as a fundamental part of their investment process, enabling them to steer their financial future successfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
