<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Nezha on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/nezha/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Nezha on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/nezha/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Nezha breaks out during Spring Festival season</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, we always gather as a family during the Spring Festival and watching movies has become an essential form of entertainment. This year&amp;rsquo;s Spring Festival season, &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; was incredibly popular, sparking discussions everywhere. The buzz is quite similar to that of &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; both films exuding a patriotic theme, which unexpectedly stirs up a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpected success of &amp;ldquo;Nezha&amp;rdquo; during the Spring Festival season, a surge of inexplicable national pride, reminiscent of previous films like &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; with patriotic themes. While acknowledging significant progress, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as it’s being made out to be. As a gamer, many aspects feel greasy. The fight scenes are heavily influenced by online games. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen numerous posts about people buying tickets for Nezha but not actually going to see the movie due to its box office performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fight-scenes-lack-texture&#34;&gt;The fight scenes lack texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a gamer, and I usually spend my days immersed in various online game worlds, so I didn’t have high expectations for movies. But I couldn’t resist the hype around 《Moana》, everyone was talking about it, so I thought, why not take a look? When I walked into the theater and the visuals came on, I felt a “thud” in my heart. Although the production quality has improved considerably compared to before, some of the scenes looked quite greasy. And the fight scenes? They were too heavily influenced by online games. Having played games for so many years, this visual style is too similar to some game scenes, lacking the texture that a movie should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-movie-fans&#34;&gt;Crazy movie fans
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie, I came out and saw that quite a few people online said they bought tickets for &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually watch it, all to boost its box office. I’m truly impressed by this move; it seems everyone is incredibly enthusiastic about this film and willing to do anything for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think back to when &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; came out, when Wu Jing shouted, “Whoever dares offend China will be punished no matter how far away they are,” so many people were filled with excitement, feeling that our Chinese military was so powerful and our country so strong. Although &amp;ldquo;The Devil’s Bond&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t have such direct patriotic slogans, it vividly showcases the essence of traditional Chinese culture. Nezha and Ao Bing, these mythological figures, we grew up listening to their stories, and the film portrays their grievances, love-hate relationships, and growth process with depth and emotion – isn’t that the charm of Chinese culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Nezha. Misunderstood and looked down upon since he was a child, yet he refused to give up, shouting &amp;ldquo;My fate is my own, not the heavens’.&amp;rdquo; This spirit is so much like the resilience ingrained in our Chinese people. No matter how great the difficulties we face, we won&amp;rsquo;t bow down, but rely on our own efforts to change our destiny. Ao Bing also exemplifies this – burdened with a family mission, seemingly cold but actually kind-hearted, willing to sacrifice himself for his friends. We often see such friendship and responsibility in real life, don’t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-progress-of-animated-films&#34;&gt;The progress of animated films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect in some aspects, it combines traditional Chinese culture with modern film technology quite well, allowing us to see the progress of Chinese animated films. Just like how &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; showed everyone China’s breakthrough in the action genre. This kind of progress makes us feel that Chinese cinema can shine on the international stage and allow foreigners to appreciate the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, no matter where we go, we carry our country and culture in our hearts. Movies like &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; are like keys, opening the door to a sense of national pride deep within us. They allow us to feel the strength of our nation and the charm of our culture amidst laughter and joy, also inspiring us to work hard in our respective positions and contribute our share to the prosperity and development of our country. This is probably why these films have become so popular and resonate with a sense of national pride. In the future, I hope there will be more movies like this, keeping this feeling of national pride full and overflowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
