<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Reprint on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/reprint/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Reprint on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/reprint/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is modern monetary theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The continued bull market in US stocks, aside from America&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;hard power,&amp;rdquo; is largely due to the excessive liquidity of the dollar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system, following the &lt;strong&gt;2008 financial crisis&lt;/strong&gt;, has gradually become a key theoretical underpinning that multiple economies tacitly refer to. Its main feature is an increased emphasis on the initiative of government intervention in the market, utilizing government fiscal deficits as its primary tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with &lt;strong&gt;Keynesianism&lt;/strong&gt;, which emphasizes the government&amp;rsquo;s role in &lt;strong&gt;smoothing economic cycles&lt;/strong&gt; – suppressing during overheating and stimulating during contractions. It places great importance on the multiplier effect of government spending, that is, how much consumption can be stimulated by a given amount of money. Government spending of 1 unit of currency leads to an increase of 1 unit of income for businesses and individuals, which expands production, increases employment, and boosts consumption, thereby mitigating economic contraction. It also tends to be relatively conservative regarding fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. The &lt;strong&gt;multiplier effect&lt;/strong&gt; can drive market recovery and thus increase government revenue, especially in suppressing overheating cycles, allowing the accumulation of stimulus resources for the next cycle, such as government debt potential and interest rate levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system is more like an extension of extreme Keynesianism, but with a key difference: the limitation on government debt. Central banks should not be independent and their primary goals are &lt;strong&gt;inflation and full employment&lt;/strong&gt;, specifically inflation related to limited resources and productivity. The idea is that the government, through unlimited fiscal deficits, increases purchasing power in the market as technological advancements improve production efficiency, until it reaches an ideal state of full employment and a production bottleneck. Further increases in money supply will then lead to inflation, at which point controlling the upper limit of the fiscal deficit becomes necessary. As long as there are idle productive resources in the market, increasing the deficit will not cause inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the financial crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, reality is not an ideal world. The execution of each link involves human participation, and Keynesianism is selectively applied, leading to a situation where economic downturns are stimulated more than overheating is suppressed. Stimulus for a poor economy brings political achievements, and even overheating can be seen as such, making it fundamentally difficult to curb. This results in numerous economic problems, new financial crises that may not be inferior to the economic impact caused by traditional overcapacity. The 2008 global financial crisis was actually a bubble resulting from market self-reinforcement under extreme Keynesianism. It produced a large number of Ponzi scheme financial investment products, such as real estate and financial investment products derived from real estate as underlying assets. Even before the crisis erupted, there was insufficient risk awareness at academic, political, and market levels. They considered prosperity supported by debt to be achievements, and many benefited from it – for example, the massive financial system, where losses were borne by participants while dividends were enjoyed. It was a case of profiting handsomely even in bankruptcy; the money is impossible to return, ultimately leading to numerous participants bearing the gains from each link of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the shadow of the modern monetary system emerges after the financial crisis, characterized by rapid &lt;strong&gt;fiscal deficit monetization and unlimited quantitative easing by the central bank&lt;/strong&gt;, along with so-called emergency lending policies. The central bank acts as a lender of last resort, providing an endless supply of liquidity, while governments can continue to accumulate debt. With coordinated cooperation between the central bank and fiscal policy, the central bank supports government fiscal deficits through measures such as purchasing government bonds, ensuring consistency in policy objectives. This is why the boundaries between modern monetary policy and fiscal policy are becoming increasingly blurred, with money base issuance heavily reliant on the central bank&amp;rsquo;s direct participation in buying government debt – printing money with one hand and spending it with the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eurozone and the United States show similar trends. In 2008, EU government debt was approximately €6.7 trillion, with a leverage ratio of around 66%, slightly above the generally accepted warning line of 60%. By 2014, during the 5-year period of rescue measures, the debt scale reached €9.5 trillion and the leverage rose to 93%. The United States is even more exaggerated; in 2008, US government debt was approximately $10 trillion, reaching around $18 trillion by 2014, and recently again raised the government debt ceiling. Of course, each drama uses the threat of a government shutdown as leverage, but each time it breaks the government debt limit, now exceeding $36 trillion – a growth of $26 trillion compared to 2008. Considering GDP growth factors, the government leverage has also increased from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as lender of last resort, plays an important role in multiple rescue operations and is one of the main purchasers of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-drawbacks-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;The drawbacks and limitations of the modern monetary system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led economic stimulus plan, although not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the omniscience of the market and the selfless courage of all participants in every link? Take a simple example: suppose a government department increases the budget for a certain direction by 1 million – does it go to the leader’s nephew or to the more cost-effective market bidding process? Of course, in reality, interests will be transferred in more complex ways, resulting in the situation where the government expands its debt and expenditure, but the flow is completely uncontrollable. The recent uproar over establishing a government efficiency department in the United States is actually an extension of this kind of problem. Naturally, these vary across different economies with corruption indices, and we are discussing the common issues more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-issues&#34;&gt;Inflation issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of modern information networks, governments now have a far greater grasp on market information than in the past. However, this is not omniscience; the market itself contains variables, and it always changes due to expectations, entering a self-reinforcing loop. I anticipated your anticipation. Consider actual performance as an example: although Modern Monetary Theory performed well between 2008 and 2020, genuinely achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stability—even leading to temporary deflation in the Eurozone and keeping US inflation largely within the expected range of 1–3%—it led people to believe in a more extreme tool as they once believed in Keynesianism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, the main reason is that manufacturing in developing countries continued to show a high growth trend after 2008. For example, China, which gradually secured its position as a global production powerhouse during this period, along with emerging economies like Southeast Asia and India, maintained relatively high manufacturing value-added, effectively offsetting the biggest limitation of Modern Monetary Theory – resource constraints. This allowed Europe and America to maintain relatively stable inflation even amidst deindustrialization, over-financialization, and surging government debt and money supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the use of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States experienced significant inflation, reaching around 10% at their peaks. Even today, nearly three years after interest rate hikes began, the US job market continues to show unusual overheating, and financial markets have seen excessive prosperity diverging from economic growth due to monetary support. As the base effect fades, US inflation is heading towards 3% again. This overheating during interest rate hikes is closely related to fiscal deficits. Interest rate hikes are a contractionary measure in monetary policy, while fiscal policy has been expansionary. Combined with the massive money supply of 2020, this has made US inflation unusually persistent. A major limitation of Modern Monetary Theory is high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-debt-issues&#34;&gt;Government debt issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, the government can indefinitely finance debt repayment through borrowing to repay debt, but the prerequisite is that the central bank must completely become a puppet – that is, &lt;strong&gt;fiscal and monetary policy alignment&lt;/strong&gt; in modern monetary systems. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that the Federal Reserve isn’t prepared to fully relinquish authority to the government. Considering the accumulated government debt balance over decades, especially interest expenses, high-interest debt on top of existing debt has gradually become a massive fiscal burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal year 2023: The U.S. federal government’s fiscal revenue for fiscal year 2023 was $4.439 trillion, with interest payments on debt accounting for approximately 15% of that revenue. This high-interest trend continued in 2024, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.
For fiscal year 2024: the U.S. federal government&amp;rsquo;s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments on debt totaling $882 billion, accounting for approximately 18% of U.S. federal revenue—even exceeding Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sustainability issue of fiscal policy. If low interest rates and low inflation are maintained for a long time, with high debt (like Japan), it can indeed create an application of quasi-modern monetary theory over the long term. According to the Rule of 72, as long as the interest rate is sufficiently low, incremental borrowing under debt-funded finance is very slow. If the cost of funds is 1%, pure debt-funding can double the debt in 72 years. Assuming inflation disrupts this delicate balance, the accumulation of interest payments on the debt could lead to an uncontrolled trajectory of future debt; compound interest becomes a more significant factor than the principal itself. These issues will become even more acute if the central bank’s actions are inconsistent with the goals of the ruling party. The political agenda of the Trump administration, for example, sharply contrasts with the current hawkish stance of the Federal Reserve, which is an important source of the escalation in relations between the US government and the Fed during this term. What everyone is most concerned about is whether the current chairman can successfully reach the end of his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;Financial bubbles and monetary credit issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, government spending increases would flow to households and businesses, prompting them to increase their own spending and boosting effective demand. However, having firsthand experience of numerous financial bubbles since 2000, people will clearly show a strong preference for investment over consumption, especially when products with extremely high expectations of appreciation emerge. People rush to the financial markets seeking higher returns, even at the expense of quality of life and taking on leverage. This is similar behavior observed during periods of rapid growth in real estate in Japan, the United States, and our country. Combined with policy stimulus and practitioners pursuing their own interests, there are many issues like subprime loans. Many so-called market-saving policies actually encourage borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History consistently shows a striking pattern: when monetary and fiscal policies are aggressively implemented, they often lead to &lt;strong&gt;a boom in asset bubbles and wealth redistribution&lt;/strong&gt;. Asset bubbles come first, followed by wealth redistribution, which then leads to another problem – the economic Ponzi scheme that arises from extreme Keynesianism or prolonged use of Modern Monetary Theory (Minsky moment). As long as there is hot money, asset prices continue to rise, and as long as they continue to rise, it attracts newcomers with cash. Meanwhile, the CPI measuring changes in basic living expenses remains relatively unchanged; money stagnates in specific sectors. Newcomers eventually run out of funds, and &lt;strong&gt;after the revelry comes the crash&lt;/strong&gt; – the Minsky moment’s judgment – a pattern that has never failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, currency itself is subject to supply and demand. When the market supply is excessive, traditional investment assets cannot absorb it, or when it fails to attract capital after repeated cycles—such as real estate bubbles that have collapsed repeatedly (something Japanese people haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to touch in decades)—and policies like taxation suppress speculation, increasing taxes on property ownership to reduce speculative demand will all increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation where currency supply is excessive, the market urgently needs investment assets that are both capital-attracting and tax-free. Various virtual investment products emerge as a result. Even the U.S. President and First Lady have come in for a share. One explanation is poaching from the dollar&amp;rsquo;s domain, but it’s more accurately seen as an inevitable consequence of global currency overissuance and financial churning leading to erosion of fiat currency credit. The credibility of modern monetary theory, which relies heavily on the state&amp;rsquo;s monopoly rights over credit-based currency, may even be challenged. What kind of environment gives rise to what kind of financial games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Modern Monetary Theory and Keynesianism are more like a progressive and substitutional relationship. It places greater emphasis on government intervention in the market and adopts a more radical attitude towards fiscal deficits and central bank independence. The overuse of Keynesianism led to stagflation and financial crises. In response to this artificially overheated economy&amp;rsquo;s clearing, Modern Monetary Theory quietly took over after 2008. Amidst continued productivity gains in economic globalization, it quickly restored growth and maintained inflation levels in the countries using it in the short term, but also accumulated large government debt and financial bubbles. When inflation rebounded, and the central bank’s goals diverged from the government&amp;rsquo;s, high interest rates and high leverage exacerbated the fiscal burden caused by government debt repayment, significantly weakening fiscal sustainability. At the same time, excessive government involvement in base money issuance led to financial bubbles, while unlimited printing weakened the currency&amp;rsquo;s creditworthiness itself. The strength of the dollar appears impressive, but it is actually supported by the weakness of others. A huge demand for investment has spawned various new financial investment and speculative tools, even escaping the tax restrictions on traditional financial investment products. This is a microcosm of the global economy. Modern Monetary Theory may not be the future; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s a relic of the past, starting in 2008. Coupled with reverse globalization, the greater the financial bubbles blown, the higher the accumulation of government debt, and the more reckless the financial speculation, the higher the efficiency of distorted wealth distribution, and the greater the risk of a hard landing – including economic and social risks. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s Keynesianism or Modern Monetary Theory, no matter how much money is supplied, it cannot truly solve the problem of wealth structure; instead, it exacerbates risks in asset bubbles and moral hazard. People repeatedly fall into the same pit in different poses but never learn from their mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fees have been reduced, fees have been reduced; several large domestic ETFs have lowered their fees</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 03:08:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Huatai Pioneer’s CSI 300 ETF and related announcements have lowered the comprehensive fee rate to the lowest tier among its peers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 19th, China Tai Ping Fund announced that to better meet the investment and financial management needs of a wide range of investors, starting from November 22nd, it will adjust the management fees and custody fees for China Tai Ping Huatai Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its linked funds, and revise relevant content in the corresponding fund contracts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After adjustments, the annual management fee for China Tai Ping Prudential Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its linked funds has been reduced to 0.15%, and the annual custody fee has been reduced to 0.05%, both adjusted to the lowest tier of fees for index funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost simultaneously, leading ETFs in the industry such as ChinaAMC CSI 300 ETF, ChinaAMC SSE 50 ETF, NFAT Zhongcai 500 ETF, JIA SHI CSI 300 ETF, and Yifangda Growth Enterprise ETF also announced reductions in management fees and custody fees, with rates all lowered to 0.15% and 0.05%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most ETF fee reductions in the past, this one was driven by proactive action from a product with scale advantages within the market, and will have a greater impact on the industry going forward. Exchange data shows that as of November 18th, the size of Caitong B&amp;amp;R CSI 300 ETF exceeded 370 billion yuan, making it the largest ETF in the current market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest group of super ETFs has taken the lead in reducing fees, demonstrating a willingness to benefit investors and allowing them to invest in popular and liquid funds with higher value for money&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry experts believe that fee reductions for ETFs with economies of scale will, on the one hand, help to fulfill the role of mutual funds in providing inclusive financial services, benefiting a wider range of investors by reducing holding costs, increasing potential returns, and enhancing their investment experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, low fees also help to further enhance the competitiveness of the product itself. With the support of liquidity absorption and cost operation advantages, the product is expected to attract more long-term incremental capital into the market, helping to build a good ecosystem for &amp;ldquo;long money, long investment.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, thanks to its unique advantages such as flexible trading, high transparency, strong liquidity, and low investment threshold, broad-based ETFs have become a primary channel for investors entering the market with modest capital and pursuing long-term investments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This price reduction could become a sort of &amp;ldquo;accelerator,&amp;rdquo; making it easier for large investors to enter the A-share market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The fixed-investment fund I chose, Tianhong Fund, hasn&amp;rsquo;t released an announcement yet, but it should follow suit. If there’s no update, I’ll have to consider switching funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Original management fee: 0.5%, custody fee: 0.1%. New management fee: 0.15%, custody fee: 0.05%. This is still a significant reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Increased scrutiny of third-party investment advisors; reckoning for those behind TikTok stock trading</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sledgehammer is falling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage services, boosted by short videos, are likely entering a fast track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late September of this year, after a period of strong performance in the A-share market, Douyin stock recommendations received attention from various parties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several financial news anchors, including &amp;ldquo;Da Lan,&amp;rdquo; have gained popularity on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of popular financial news anchors also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t overlook the power behind them – third-party wealth management firms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using traffic allocation to attract users to watch investment education videos and boost their enthusiasm for purchasing related investment advisory products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumors also suggest that a certain third-party investment advisory firm earned 1 billion yuan in revenue this October alone, exceeding its income for the entire first half of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &amp;ldquo;good times&amp;rdquo; are facing more uncertainties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since November, various departments have issued documents requiring securities service institutions to strengthen compliance management of their social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 15th, Tonghua Shun (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission due to live streaming activities involving implied stock recommendations and other behaviors
This could be signaling that regulators are tightening their oversight of the market
The promotion of services by third-party investment advisory firms, including Nine Square Wisdom Investment (9636.HK), may also face increased pressure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strictly-monitored-and-watched-closely&#34;&gt;Strictly monitored and watched closely
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin has amplified emotional voices and indirectly influenced trading behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from Jiali Digital, during the period of September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volume reached a new high, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, more than doubling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the actions of third-party investment advisory firms that are &amp;ldquo;adding fuel to the fire&amp;rdquo; are attracting the attention of regulatory authorities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage employees recommending individual stocks through live streams is a frequent violation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend the acceptance of new clients from a certain company due to instances such as &amp;ldquo;implying stock recommendations&amp;rdquo; in their live broadcasts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 14th, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued a document titled &amp;ldquo;Inadequate Live Stream Control, Institutions to be Suspended,&amp;rdquo; directly pointing out that some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate control during live stream promotional activities and engaged in recommending individual stocks during broadcasts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live stock recommendations are prohibited. Live streaming falls under public media dissemination, and live streamers, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, are not permitted to recommend individual stocks during broadcasts. This was stated by the Guangdong Securities Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau’s penalty notice also included a case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, an investment consultant at the Shanghai branch of Haisun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd., published misleading video content through WeChat Video Number, which violated professional conduct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau took supervisory management measures of issuing a warning letter to Wang Yong regarding this matter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to information obtained by Feng (ID: TradeWind01), some investment advisor firms that do not meet the qualifications have been recommending stocks on Douyin through brokerage affiliations and have now been suspended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people in the industry are doing live streams on Douyin, but they’re actually affiliated with brokerages, which gives them investment consultant qualifications. Then they use online live streams to attract customers and sell investment consultant combination products offline.” A wealth manager from South China told Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01), “But later, because they were recommending stocks during the live stream, it was discovered, so they were suspended. Reputable brokerages generally have educational live streams that discuss sector conditions but don’t involve individual stocks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are paying close attention to illegal stock recommendations on social media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that individual institutions or individuals within the industry have been found to be engaging in illegal stock recommendations and other violations through self-media. To further regulate the operation and management of securities investment consulting agencies&amp;rsquo; self-media within its jurisdiction, each agency should strengthen the management of their own self-media operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may bring more challenges to the promotion of various third-party wealth management service providers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;traffic-businesses-are-illegal&#34;&gt;Traffic businesses are illegal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether investors lured into the market by short videos have made money remains to be seen, but as &amp;ldquo;water sellers,&amp;rdquo; third-party investment advisory firms have already seen their value rise in the secondary market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leading player in online investment education, Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s market capitalization has surged from 287.8 million yuan in early September to 1.2464 billion yuan at the close of trading on November 13th, representing an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report shows that in the first half of this year, Jiufang Zhi Tou conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, reaching 488 accounts and 0.46 billion followers by the end of June this year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as the chief investment consultant of Jiufang Zhito, &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; has 2.26 million followers on Douyin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are deeply engaged in MCN operations, focusing on users and collaboratively driving the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products. Jiufang Zhi投 (Jiufang Investment) pointed out that &amp;ldquo;By deeply integrating new media tools such as live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we can effectively achieve efficient conversion of traffic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiufang Zhitou&amp;rsquo;s consultant courses cover a range of prices from several thousand yuan to over 130,000 yuan. The most expensive package, Super Investor, is priced at 139,600 yuan/six months and includes exclusive insights and private consultant services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JIAF’s investment consultant products have a refund rate of over 10%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for Jiu Fang Zhi Tou&amp;rsquo;s flagship series and Jiu Fang Zhi Tou’s Qinlong series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Jiufang Zhitu’s business development will be affected remains to be seen amid regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent media reports indicate that accounts under third-party investment advisory firms such as Jiufang Zhi Tou have been affected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, media reported that &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rdquo; had been suspended from streaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th in the afternoon, Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) searched for the account and found that the livestream appointment for November 18th was still available on the &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rdquo; livestreaming interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market news also indicates that relevant authorities have inspected Jufang Intelligence Investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But individuals close to Nine Square Intelligence have told TradeWind (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection is a routine check and has concluded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company rumored to be caught up in this round of regulatory storm recently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports indicate that Tonghua Shun is being investigated for allegedly illegally recommending stocks, and business operations may be suspended
In response, Tonghuashun stated on November 15th that &amp;ldquo;there is no illegal stock recommendation situation and there has been no investigation.&amp;rdquo;
However, that same evening, Tonghua Shun announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tonghuashun Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau with a suspension of acquiring new customers for three months and other penalties due to inadequate compliance management during the promotion of its live streaming business and instances of implying stock recommendations
Behind this, it may also mean that regulatory authorities&amp;rsquo; attention on promotional stock content on social media platforms like Douyin Live is being further upgraded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the short video market is also attracting many brokerages, but they are currently still cautious due to regulatory requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person from a securities firm told Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) that the company is exploring short video operations and methods for attracting traffic, and has also organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning. However, due to compliance requirements, it is still in the exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the various compliance requirements of regulation stem from the evident emotional coloring of content on short video platforms, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality; the two are inherently in conflict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If emotions influence the capital market, it can easily lead to sharp market fluctuations, which is contrary to the long-term healthy development of the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How securities firms should embrace the arrival of the short video era while avoiding regulatory breaches is a difficult question for all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why do computers generally use little-endian storage?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:43:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An Explanation of Byte Order [Host Order, Network Order, Observing Directly Through a Debugger]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some design habits formed due to historical reasons in the computer field are like the principle that the width of a horse&amp;rsquo;s rear end determines the width of a rocket engine – there’s no need to analyze their “advantages” and “disadvantages”; they’re simply historical conventions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-link&#34;&gt;Original link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author: Arctic
Link: [https://www.zhihu.com/question/637413724/answer/3346032134]
Source: Zhihu
Copyright belongs to the author. For commercial reproduction, please contact the author for authorization; for non-commercial reproduction, please indicate the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reprint-of-the-main-text&#34;&gt;Reprint of the main text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The current endianness situation is a result of historical habits and commercialization, not really related to the technology itself. ARM can be configured as either big-endian or little-endian. The TCP/IP header still uses big-endian (network byte order). There are also many storage protocols/specifications in the storage field that save data in big-endian format.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the three questions raised by the original poster, looking back today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do computers generally use little-endian storage? &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; Incorrect&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiency is not necessarily higher&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any attempt to justify these three issues based on current technology is like drawing a target before shooting an arrow&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, when it comes to the choice between big-endian and little-endian, there were indeed certain objective factors in the history of computer development: Advantages of host byte order (little-endian): Little-endian adders are easier to implement. If you want to build an 8-bit * 4 adder, you only need one 8-bit adder and can simply loop through all bytes from low to high and add them. The carry circuit is very simple. However, with big-endian, you need to load 32 bits at once, otherwise the calculation cannot be performed. Looking at it now, there’s not much difference between loading 8 bits or 32 bits, but decades ago, memory was expensive, so simplicity was preferred. Therefore, the choice of little-endian for host byte order was based on cost considerations. Advantages of network byte order (big-endian): Early devices had very small caches, and receiving the high byte first allowed for quick determination of packet information: package length (how much cache to prepare), address range (IP addresses are matched from front to back). Early networking devices used bytes as their unit, so taking the high byte first was indeed faster. Therefore, network devices use big-endian, also based on cost considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the choice of byte order has historically been driven more by application scenarios and cost considerations (such as PPC/MIPS being better suited for network devices), and later, due to compatibility reasons, the endian configuration has continued to be used until today&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking at it today, these advantages no longer exist at all; they are merely historical habits&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is it that we spend our whole lives pursuing?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Master Wang Xizhi said: A woman&amp;rsquo;s companionship, over a lifetime of looking up and down, may be found in the depths of one’s heart through understanding her words; or it may be entrusted to someone and exist beyond the confines of the body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s life is like a flash of lightning, fleeting and ephemeral. Like grass and trees flourishing in spring and withering in autumn, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, in this life, I have so many desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lying by the stream as a child, peeling lotus pods, busily releasing kites in the east wind, chasing after yellow butterflies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also leaned against mulberry trees to learn how to grow melons; returning with a full meal after dusk, he would still lie beneath the bright moon without taking off his raincoat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I hope to achieve distinction in the imperial examinations, have a beautiful companion by my side, enjoy endless wealth, rise through the ranks steadily, be surrounded by esteemed guests, and celebrate every night with music and revelry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing old, yet desiring health and longevity – welcome servants, await children, a game of chess, a close friend, a pot of wine, a courtyard, and enjoying family life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see how people rush about, all for a few pieces of silver. Yet those few pieces of silver can resolve countless sorrows in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large number of people are still struggling to make a living, where do they have time to pursue meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a person&amp;rsquo;s life is just an experience, like grass, trees, and the sun and moon, experiencing the cycle of desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not understanding life leads to the feeling that one is like a mayfly adrift in the universe, a grain of sand in the vast ocean. Sorrow for the brevity of my existence, envy of the endlessness of the Yangtze River. Understanding life brings joy in what you encounter, satisfaction with what you gain, contentment and self-sufficiency, unaware of approaching old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, you can pursue poetry, wine, flowers, and tea; you can pursue the clear breeze on the river, or the bright moon in the mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;rsquo;t be overly concerned with the outcome, as outcomes are fleeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To exhaust a lifetime, arriving in this world, striving to experience as much of life’s joys and sorrows, birth, aging, sickness, and death as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this line from Big Fish &amp;amp; Begonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are very short, and we will eventually lose them, so why not be a little bolder? Love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream. There are many things in life that have no answers, so why not be a little bolder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like “The Pavilion of Prince Shaobo” and “Ode to the Red Cliffs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of the feeling that arises when recalling people of the past is as if it were a contract. I have never failed to feel grief and regret upon contemplating literature, unable to fully grasp it in my mind. Indeed, I know that life and death are vain conceits, and equating all lives is a foolish fabrication. Those who come after will view us as we now view those of the past. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>China&#39;s good future will be a China with good elders</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-good-china-with-elderly/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-good-china-with-elderly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that in twenty years, I’ll be a lovely old man, accompanied by a lovely old lady. Not seeking great wealth or status, just good health and the ability to travel around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search, no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I say that in 10 years, the charming old man will be me. I must work hard to become a charming old man. The good future of China will surely be one with kind old men and women. Even if I am 60 years old in 10 years, I will still be the youngest in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, people think it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good for a 50-year-old Chinese man to have this physique. But behind this body is the motto I believe in: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! When the rain stopped, I wanted to go running, and I’ll play soccer tomorrow afternoon. At 50, I can still play big games – I&amp;rsquo;m not kidding, and often play with professionals. But what&amp;rsquo;s behind it? Discipline. I spend my remaining days running, and some people find running very monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I am free to run, never listening to music, because I think listening to my own breath is the most beautiful music for running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Otherwise, I rarely use the treadmill. And a lot of people say Beijing&amp;rsquo;s smog is so bad, but I run five days a week – two days are already reserved for the smog. What’s different about me, though, is that I never stop. Every month, I mark a day in my journal—in my experiences—for each day I run; there are never fewer than 18 days a month. Running just flies by. And when I run, I don&amp;rsquo;t wear glasses, but more importantly, I’m still playing soccer every week. The last class I teach my graduate students will be at my house, and the theme is fun. I think fun is so important; I never deal with people who have no joy or hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To treat them with respect and keep a distance – such people are too frightening. If you don’t find joy, what joy do you have? I really don&amp;rsquo;t have much either. What kind of work do you like? This year, early on, one of my graduate students was assigned to China News Weekly. We had a special series called &amp;ldquo;To…&amp;rdquo; Every year when my graduate students graduated, their final assignment was to write an article about 10 years from now, which I would keep. Then, 10 years later, I would unfold them one by one. I also wrote about turning 50 and writing to 60 – a distant place I never thought I’d reach, far beyond the map, but suddenly it&amp;rsquo;s my next stop. My students, when they were 20 writing to 30, that was a love letter from spring to summer. But when I turned 50 writing to 60, it just became the murmuring of late summer to autumn. Now, I’m writing to 10 years from now – writing about myself, slowly, about my bed, a meal, and the people around my family. That&amp;rsquo;s perfectly normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what kind of person should one be at 60 years old? My premise is very clear. In the preface, this article is quite long. I said that in 10 years, a lovable old man will be me, and I want to work hard to become a lovable old man. For China to be endearing, it depends not only on having more young people who must become citizens, no longer just ordinary folks, energetic young people, and young people who understand the rules. A good future China must have good old men and good old women. Currently, there are already over 230 million people in China over 60 years old. In 10 years, it will definitely exceed three hundred million. That is to say, just considering the population aged 60 and above, if China were a country on its own, it would be among the top five in the world, or even potentially the third largest. Just think about how terrifying that is?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I don’t know if everyone has seen a table online today showing the average life expectancy of various provinces and municipalities in China; Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years old, counting both men and women on average. The average lifespan certainly gives men a significant advantage over women. That means that even when I&amp;rsquo;m 60 in ten years, I’ll be one of the youngest in this third stage of life. As for the future, women retire at an average age of 55, with 25 years remaining until their average lifespan of 80; men retire at 60, with 20 years remaining until their average lifespan of 80! You can’t just spend your time dancing square dances. And I can say that the older sisters and brothers dancing square dances today are a cultural habit and entertainment form brought to them by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another 20 years, the next generation may still have square dancing, but there will be a significant decrease. The younger generation is no longer an active participant in group activities. Just as older people prefer to travel in tour groups, young people are increasingly opting for independent and self-guided trips. Square dancing will continue, but its scope will certainly shrink. There&amp;rsquo;s nothing good or bad about this; it’s simply the times changing, constantly evolving. When I was 60, I was the youngest member of the team. What kind of person should I be? Chinese painting says that at 60, your ears are attuned – but I definitely wouldn’t listen then, still easily annoyed by things I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered by, and even getting upset when happy. More importantly, what can I do for the younger generation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you do for a good cause? Don&amp;rsquo;t be lazy, don&amp;rsquo;t give in easily, oppose what needs opposing. If someone young might harm your interests, can you stand in front of them? I often have to look at this mirror now, back and forth. A good friend of mine has passed away. Tao Wei used to gather with us frequently at our house, and once told me a true story. We all felt the pain together. The older generation, like Chen Lao, kept everything in their homes – you break open a box, and there are 30-something items tucked under the bed. You tell him, &amp;ldquo;This shirt cost over 500 to buy, now it&amp;rsquo;s being offered as tribute,&amp;rdquo; lighting incense every day. Therefore, our generation is accustomed to battling wits with our parents. How much would something costing 700 bring back?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;220&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it’s easy to cause trouble. Tao Wei once spent over 400 yuan buying a T-shirt for his dad. The T-shirt was really nice, how much did it cost? 99. I wore that style. The next day, things went badly. When he came back in the evening, he asked Tao Wei for 400 yuan and wanted him to buy four more. Today, when I wore it out, Uncle Li and many others praised it. They said that this kind of deception carries a great risk, and you shouldn’t do such things as you get older. I won&amp;rsquo;t mention the specific person in the hospital orthopedic department; elderly people fracture their bones, and the crucial reason is often the shoes bought from street vendors. Of course, this is just about the material aspect. Even when you&amp;rsquo;re old, you still need a spiritual life, you still need curiosity, and you still want to shield young people from the wind and rain – live each day happily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel curious and excited, looking forward to the moment I turn 60, feeling that it will be a beautiful beginning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18th birthday might be a little different from yours</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very common term &lt;strong&gt;information fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt;. Since graduating from high school and abandoning the time spent reading novels, it’s been a long time since I&amp;rsquo;ve sat down to read a book seriously and quietly. Sometimes when I look back, after working for so long, do I even remember what I did each year? Often, by mid-year, I’ve already forgotten many things from the first half of the year. Writing blogs is a good habit; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if much of what I write isn&amp;rsquo;t public – it was originally meant to be read for myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal reader is myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search, no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s 18th birthday is like a gaze filled with anticipation and questioning. Each person occasionally asks themselves, are you the way you wanted to be back then? I worry that nowadays everyone has countless social media circles but no real friends, chatting every day but never having heartfelt conversations, acquiring endless knowledge but remaining far from wisdom. Everyone should ask themself on their 18th birthday: deceiving others is easy, but deceiving yourself is difficult!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think everyone&amp;rsquo;s 18th birthday is like a gaze of expectation and inquiry. You can deceive others, but you can’t deceive your own 18-year-old self. Is today the way you wanted to be when you were 18? I think it&amp;rsquo;s alright. Today, there are so many things that matter more than what I thought about at 18 – material possessions, fame, and so on. I’ve gained them, but on the other hand, I’m still on the journey. When I was 18, I studied journalism at the broadcasting academy, hoping to become a journalist like Farahachi, the best. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path. That&amp;rsquo;s why people often ask me, Bai Lao (Teacher Bai), why are you still at CCTV? Because I want to be a good journalist. Journalism is still ongoing. It’s the gaze of my 18-year-old self. So I think everyone should occasionally ask their 18-year-old self: Are you living the way you wanted to back then?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that truly can&amp;rsquo;t be faked. This is what I looked like when I was 18, and in the blink of an eye, 32 years have passed. Everyone who came to Beijing to go to university would have a photo like this. Back then, there were wrinkled suits on Tiananmen Square, with school badges pinned to their chests. Because there were so few college students at that time, not wearing a badge felt especially proud. My hair was long back then, but I still really like how I looked when I was 18. So many years have passed, and suddenly I realized I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for what I faced at 18 because it quietly shaped me. On May 8th, 1986, I bought a collection of Misty Poetry at the Wangfujing Bookstore. That year, I listened to Cui Jian’s “Nothing To My Name” at the Workers’ Stadium. And today, I suddenly realized that my writing style has been most influenced by Misty Poetry, rock music, and Gu Long&amp;rsquo;s martial arts novels – including my personality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you experience at 18? What might you carry with you on your journey as a result? I&amp;rsquo;m particularly curious about what 18-year-olds are experiencing today. Is it like being carved by knives and axes? But what tools are they using? And what kind of shape has it molded you into? I worry that now everyone has countless social media friends but no real friends, chatting every day without anyone to confide in, with limitless access to knowledge yet so far from wisdom—knowing everything but understanding nothing. It seems like everyone is talking about individuality. But as an observer, I find that today&amp;rsquo;s young people are very much the same. What should you let him experience at 18? I really liked 1986 because it was the best way to resolve 1966.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cultural Revolution ended in 1976, a result of chance. It can only truly eliminate the underlying concerns if we experience enlightenment and a resurgence of humanity, along with the growth of each individual – something that happened in 1986. We still need to undergo this enlightenment, and we must further develop a thorough understanding of human nature. Regardless of how much economic progress or change occurs in Chinese society, without genuinely addressing and understanding human nature—controlling its negative aspects while activating its positive ones—there will continue to be many things that concern us. My 18-year-old experience is the same as this generation&amp;rsquo;s; we’ve strayed too far. Don&amp;rsquo;t forget why we started out, now condensed into these four characters: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t lose your original intention.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think no matter how far you go, everyone should ask themselves at 18 years old. It&amp;rsquo;s good to have a photo from your 18th birthday and look at it often to question yourself. What others say is useless. It’s too easy to deceive others, but deceiving yourself is very difficult. I said earlier that when I was 18, I would tell someone who is now 20 years old: you should always let your 18-year-old self be a pair of eyes watching you. And in your twenties, as I mentioned before, try opening many doors; you don’t know which one suits you best. Behind which door… It&amp;rsquo;s quite common in China now to see people in their twenties who are like elderly people, and many young people who are in their seventies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalists does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It recounts the author&amp;rsquo;s views on the journalistic profession, emphasizing that journalists should possess a social conscience, knowledge base, and perseverance. The author also shares their reflections at age 50, including maintaining curiosity, balancing material and spiritual needs, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search, no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The best journalist first has a social conscience, then knowledge reserves, and finally perseverance. It can’t be that you run 100 meters and aren&amp;rsquo;t satisfied, so you just run. I think these three combined—people expect the hidden dangers of vaccine safety to be completely resolved. This is like the milk powder incident – it always progresses through a cycle of problems arising, problems being solved, and thoroughly resolving those problems. Otherwise, what’s the point of journalists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best journalists first have a social conscience, second have a knowledge base, and third, they can’t just run 100 meters for fun; they need to keep running. I feel that these three combined with my turning 50 this year will make it clear that I seem suited for journalism. I am naturally closely linked to China&amp;rsquo;s 40 years of reform. When I turned 30, I stood on the bank of the Songhua River; when I turned 40, my birthday was entering and exiting the Olympic broadcast in 2008. Turning 50 this year, with the whole country commemorating the 40th anniversary of reform and opening up, there is indeed a correspondence. If we talk about a great era turning 40, does China’s 40 years of reform represent enlightenment or confusion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I feel that after 40 years of development, China has provided enough material wealth for both the people and the country. However, anxiety and confusion have increased instead of decreased. We thought that becoming strong and prosperous would solve everything, but we discovered that material comfort is just a foundation. It’s relatively easy to escape poverty materially, but it&amp;rsquo;s truly difficult to achieve spiritual richness and become a great nation. The United States is already attacking our high-tech industries; we need to focus on agricultural products. There has always been a saying in this world: it&amp;rsquo;s not easy being number two! How many number twos have there been in the US? Therefore, we will inevitably go through a long period of time to transform this &amp;ldquo;number two&amp;rdquo; mentality into something that surpasses ourselves. I can’t expect to get everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was lucky to start in television at 25, and it began with interviews of people. I came into contact with thousands of figures carrying various auras. When I was young, I thought these auras would surely make them happy. But when you get close to them, no, there’s not much connection between the aura and their happiness; sometimes they&amp;rsquo;re even inversely proportional. Just recently, I finished reading “The Last 29 Years of Guo Moruo.” Despite holding high positions like Vice Premier of the State Council, various CPPCC vice-chairmanships, and deputy committee chairmanships without ever being officially criticized, his two sons both died – one committed suicide, and the other likely fell to his death from a height. Could he have been happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? When she was in her sixties or seventies, having two sons leave her within a few years couldn&amp;rsquo;t make a former vice premier happy. Many famous calligraphy and paintings can bring happiness, being safely through many years can bring happiness. What more is needed? So I think looking at people’s reading habits is the best mirror. To put it slightly seriously, I feel that the anxiety of many people now comes from thinking too much and reading too little. This is a reply from Mr. Yang Jiang to a young person. Without reading, everyone expects fast food, hoping to find a remedy with just a mobile phone. How could that be possible? I learned to be clever through a clumsy process of studying, and subtraction is done when you read more and more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I don&amp;rsquo;t want to expect everything from everyone, but I hope the proportion increases – that more and more Chinese people can find a better version of themselves through education. That’s what matters most. No one sits on the ground staring at the stars and figures everything out; I can’t do that. But I can look in the mirror. A few years ago, a BBC news anchor came to Beijing, claiming to be their best news anchor. Then some well-meaning person organized a dialogue between Chinese news anchors and him. We had a conversation. During the conversation, he asked me a question: what should BBC learn from CCTV? I joked around first and said, of course, they should start by learning Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I joked that the BBC should learn from CCTV about their curiosity towards the world. I said, haven&amp;rsquo;t we rapidly expanded our presence globally in recent years? We now have over 70 foreign bureaus. Our reporters feel like students, and whenever they see something new abroad, they’re incredibly curious, observing the world with a great sense of wonder. The BBC has already treated Britain as the whole world; you’ve lost your curiosity. My friend slapped the table and said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;ve hit the nail on the head! That&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we lack.&amp;rdquo; In 2007, when I interviewed an author in Japan, he told me a sentence: “This country has everything except hope.” Later, I understood how profound that statement was. Looking at it from another angle, more than ten years ago, I felt like China lacked everything except hope; everyone felt there was something to look forward to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I worry about the day we become a prosperous nation that has everything except hope. To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m very concerned that China will reach a point where it feels truly poor only when it has everything. When I was 50, I feared becoming someone who could satisfy all material conditions but remained a very impoverished person. In our reality, there are many highly educated people lacking in culture, and many poor people with countless numbers in their bank accounts. This is the problem of this era. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t scary because it has momentum and hope ahead. That’s why I say we have a moral deficit and a loss of humanity – that&amp;rsquo;s the reason. I think scientists invent so many things not necessarily because they initially carried some grand mission, but out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I was curious whether I could pull it off, so I started pushing myself to be better around the age of 50. That makes me happy. One thing that bothers me now is persistence. We were just talking about you still persisting, and I said don&amp;rsquo;t – once you persist, you’re not far from death. In the past, we always said persistence equals victory. Chinese football would say “persist for three minutes, grit your teeth,” there’s no fun left, no methods left, so it relies on persistence. Persistence is sometimes important, but quite often this statement has two sides to it. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that when I&amp;rsquo;m persisting in doing something, like chatting with everyone now, I insist on finishing everything I have left to say. Actually, my time is up now, but I’m curious, what will the conversation turn out like?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give yourself a very small keyword, but engage in conversation with everyone. I think that at 50 years old, as long as you can still maintain great curiosity, there’s no problem. I like all fun things, but not necessarily the most fun things right now; today&amp;rsquo;s trends might disappear in an instant. There are yearly buzzwords – do you remember any? Could today’s internet media possibly be what traditional media dreamed of 10 years ago? So fun things always have their own inherent appeal. I respect everyone’s preferences, there must be a reason for that, but looking at the long term, people still prefer playing mahjong. When you also like eating fast food, restaurants serving elaborate meals will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things can’t just be passed with a sigh. How much fragmented reading do you have on your phone every day? How many longer readings do you have? But this is also a process, and the phone is becoming our handcuffs. So I think that the more short things you see, the more nearsighted people will gradually become, but this is also a process. I never worry about content being king. You’ll come back. You&amp;rsquo;ll entertain yourself to death every day until you reach 40, just like seeing teenagers drinking cola—you tell them to drink less, but you know they’re going to drink it anyway. But on the other hand, I’m optimistic; at 40, he will definitely return to the world of tea. That&amp;rsquo;s a Chinese person&amp;rsquo;s life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite normal, but I hope the next change will be a little faster. We’re just expressing our feelings – there are so few investigative journalists these days; you don’t even look at investigations anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will China&#39;s football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These supplementary reading responses were mostly written spontaneously in 2021, and the transcription of Bai Yansong’s speech was done when the pandemic had just begun. Don&amp;rsquo;t talk about twenty years later, even a year or two later—the changes in the world always exceed people&amp;rsquo;s expectations. Now the pandemic in China is nearing its end, but overseas it continues to rage on. Regarding soccer, the national team has been playing quite well in recent years, and the coach dares to play offensively. Compared to those clueless days of old, watching the games with my grandfather is actually a bit interesting now. What kind of experience is it that you’re so bored by a national team game that even an elderly person wants to change channels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search, no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Curious, very curious. How could it have gotten so bad? So you find there are many reasons why Chinese football doesn&amp;rsquo;t play well, and one of the reasons is that everyone is afraid to lose the ball on their own side, pass it to someone else – they don’t even do that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one of many reasons. Talking about 20 years of football, after 20 years, Chinese football feels so distant. The first expansion brought the number to 48. China might go, but it still might not. The best age for a national team is 26~30 – that’s today&amp;rsquo;s 6-10 year olds. Twenty years will make you feel very optimistic; in 20 years, it will definitely work. But when I mention today&amp;rsquo;s 6-10 year olds, your expression immediately becomes serious. So, cause and effect are intertwined. What are we planting today? We almost planted soybeans to have the national team play in a league – what will grow from that? Whoever initiates this action needs to prepare for dismissal; it violates the rules, so I haven’t thought about it too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we really should think about today&amp;rsquo;s children, aged 6-10 – are they playing soccer? Then you’ll know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Moral deficit, human deficiency</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When doing things, the first thing you need is a clear conscience. This will allow you to sleep soundly and avoid making mistakes on matters of principle. If you truly make a mistake, you should do your best to rectify it, not hide or try to forget. Humans are easily forgetful, but also a species with good memories. Peace of mind is the ultimate destination; being able to answer yourself honestly leads to a more relaxed life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Click here for the original video link [https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjQ4NA==.html]. If there is any copyright infringement, please contact me to delete it. This article is only a translation of the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight characters that carry a lot of weight: I feel we currently have a deficit in morality, a loss of humanity. Times always progress through a cycle of identifying and solving problems, a logic loop of thoroughly resolving issues. You need to be patient and wait for its reshuffling. For a country like China, many things are a slow process of reshuffling, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic during the change and the reshuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These past few days, China has been battling two typhoons – one invisible and the other visible. The invisible typhoon is the vaccine, which impacts the dams of our inner security. The visible typhoon rarely lands in Shanghai and then affects Beijing and Tianjin; it&amp;rsquo;s unprecedented for three municipalities to face a typhoon together in decades. That’s beside the point. What you need to think about now is whether you can thrive on your own – you’ve undergone significant changes, you have many answers, but if the surrounding environment doesn’t change, will you be happy? I have eight words that are quite weighty: we currently have a moral deficit and a loss of humanity; this is the biggest deficit and the greatest loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what people expect is for the safety concerns of the vaccine to be completely resolved, just like the milk powder incident back then. So sometimes you need to look at history and understand how the establishment and formation of a complete legal framework for the US FDA is also closely related to the unsafe milk powder and dairy products. The Sanlu milk powder incident forced China to make great changes in the dairy industry. While I can’t say the vaccine situation will be continuous, I hope this one will bring it to a halt. You need to know that progress always moves forward through a cycle of problems arising, being solved, and then completely resolved – otherwise, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of journalists? What&amp;rsquo;s the point of citizens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think the only thing each of us can do is to care. But the problem is that Chinese people are too easily forgetful. Like what I just said, after hitting someone&amp;rsquo;s car, we stop on the side of the road and run away; no one stops us. A large proportion of our neighbors and colleagues are like this. So it needs to be changed slowly. And as ordinary citizens, all we can do is pay attention and not forget. It’s not that there’s a lack of something – when people aren&amp;rsquo;t able to eat enough or wear warm clothes, talking about ideals doesn’t have much persuasive power. But once they are well-fed and clothed, and we’ve become the world’s leading diabetes nation, the leading high blood pressure nation, and many other “number one” nations, you see Chinese people starting to run (exercise), Chinese people starting to lose weight. I ask the ladies here, how many of you haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced the harsh reality that if I don&amp;rsquo;t eat a big meal, I won’t have the energy to diet? That’s a small transformation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the same with the spiritual level we talked about. When you’re well-fed and warmly clothed, and you start exercising or dieting, your spiritual needs gradually increase. For example, I used to smoke, but when I started running, it just happened that one day I realized I hadn’t smoked in over 20 days, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t smoked since. Of course, I won’t say I completely quit—that feels too ceremonial. It’s not excluded that I might still have two or three cigarettes within a year. When your lifestyle changes, many things will change along with it. I think for Chinese people, you need to be patient and wait for the reshuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more people feel unhappy, but they won&amp;rsquo;t indulge in their unhappiness. While depression is on the rise, isn’t it also true that more and more people are seeking positive ways to live? This leads to a growth in things related to the spirit. So don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic; look at how you see the same thing. I often see drivers cutting in line on the street, which makes me frustrated. But then, in an instant, I become optimistic because the queue on the other side is much longer than before. This is just such a process. All of you here are willing to come to this place and chat about so many useless things on a rainy evening – isn’t that also a fun thing?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this also a kind of transformation, so there are many things that need to be thought about in a different way. Of course, I think there will be many things that need to grow slowly in the future. For example, you said entrepreneurship – who isn’t an entrepreneur throughout their life? Everyone’s life is essentially entrepreneurial. We&amp;rsquo;ve imbued &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurship&amp;rdquo; with too much of a sense of trendiness. In reality, entrepreneurship has always existed. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Su Shi an entrepreneur? Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Li Bai an entrepreneur? There will be many creations throughout one&amp;rsquo;s life, ultimately creating their own brand. It doesn’t matter if most don’t succeed; as long as you live a life with enough flavor and feel it was worthwhile. What I think China particularly lacks now is a good value system that views failure as another form of success. Chinese people only accept successful outcomes but don&amp;rsquo;t accept a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; failure as a kind of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s very difficult. So you find many reasons why Chinese soccer doesn’t play well, and one of those reasons is that everyone is afraid to lose the ball if they pass it to someone else, even if it’s just themselves. Without that kind of approach, of course, this is only a small reason. So I feel that after reaching my age, past 30, I wrote about not being in a hurry in the preface, but now at 50 there&amp;rsquo;s a little bit of urgency because time goes by so quickly, so fast, and many things you expect haven’t become reality yet. But on the other hand, it is understood that for a country like China, many things are a slow process of shuffling. You see your parents; some were like traffic lights didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, but occasionally you see their children pulling them along. It&amp;rsquo;s changing, it&amp;rsquo;s shuffling. So I think you need to have some patience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>It takes a lot of reading to find the answer regarding time</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country is getting better and stronger. If people&amp;rsquo;s vanity didn’t exist, it wouldn’t be so strong. Looking back from the 1990s to now, in the families I have interacted with, everyone&amp;rsquo;s life has gotten much better than before. At the same time, there are more wealthy individuals. In the process of market-oriented economic development, an increase in income inequality is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issues of social stratification and blocked upward mobility that are commonly discussed are systemic problems in the world today. The contributions made by our party regarding the basic welfare and social security of the people should be recognized. Life will get better and better; if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy a house, you can rent one. There are also issues with unequal distribution of educational resources when it comes to children’s education, sometimes requiring trade-offs. Do you prioritize better job opportunities and work environment or more time spent with your family? Don&amp;rsquo;t impose your own ideas on others, including your children and family. Sit down and have a good talk; life will always get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-original&#34;&gt;Video original
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Click here for the original video link] (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA%29&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA)&lt;/a&gt;. If there is any copyright infringement, please contact me to delete it. This article is only a translation of the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;30 years old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve turned 50 this year, and I never thought about it before. I thought, &amp;ldquo;This is an old man.&amp;rdquo; Now I realize I really am an old man. This is what I looked like at 30. Didn’t feel very young or handsome at 30, but looking back now at 50, not bad at all. What&amp;rsquo;s the biggest life feeling at 30? Looking back. I think it’s subtraction; the keyword is subtraction. In a sense, experiencing and thinking about things, writing them out and leaving them behind to start fresh on a new blank page – like going for a run. But for me, doing subtraction, whether from myself or as a reminder to all of you, was truly very important at 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently guiding students at United College. I often remind them that before 30, you need to work your hardest on addition – try everything, because you don’t know how many possibilities you have, and you don’t know what opportunities fate will bring. It’s not about knowing &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do it, but some people in their twenties relentlessly pursue various additions, but forget subtraction, forget that there&amp;rsquo;s a time when you need to subtract. I think around 30 is a very important period in life – after doing a series of additions and running around everywhere, it’s crucial to do a subtraction. Otherwise, it will be too late. Why should you subtract? Not everything suits you, not everything is for you. You shouldn&amp;rsquo;t do everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight lines bind you, how far can you run? They may restrain each other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cheap&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I turned 30, I was promoted exceptionally – in academia that would be a professor, and for a journalist, a senior reporter. I was recognized at 29, and such things are rare now, but it started to bring about a huge confusion. When I worked on the Sydney Olympics in 2000 and received a lot of applause, I suddenly felt something wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite right. I began asking myself, what do you really want to do? What needs to be discarded? That year, I made a very important subtraction – I stopped my program for a year, without appearing overseas. Someone advised me that in the hosting profession, if you don’t appear on camera for just a month, it&amp;rsquo;s manageable, but six months and people will forget you. I said, &amp;ldquo;My face must be pretty cheap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, we started developing new programs. After going through a period of pain and joy, I took a full year off in 2001. Everything I&amp;rsquo;m doing today is really thanks to the subtraction I did back then. At that time, I could have done so many things – sports, E, lots of other fun stuff, producing, etc. But I said no. I realized I could only do news, and that’s what I should be doing most. So, I was the producer for three programs at the time, and I quit them all overnight, which led to who I am today. I simplified things. Just a few days ago, chatting with colleagues, I said that one very important decision I made in my late 20s wasn’t about having many options; it was about focusing on news. It&amp;rsquo;s like a deep well – there were opportunities for promotion, possibly to become deputy director, but I turned them down and returned to the foundation of an ordinary person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Undergraduate student&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a senior-level cadre with China Central Television, and not even definitively graduated with a bachelor’s degree. You understand our system, but I rejected it. I just wanted to see how far a bachelor’s degree could go. Why can’t someone with a bachelor’s degree continuously learn and lead graduate students? Yes, now I supervise graduate students, 11 every year – this is the result of a subtraction. I think that&amp;rsquo;s certainly a reflection on looking back. Also, when you’re young, it’s especially easy to feel in your struggles that you deserve everything. If anything is missing or any matter has a flaw, I feel particularly uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone here should learn to subtract, meaning that around the time you’re approaching 30, when I watched the Olympics in 1996 at age 28, I came up with a sentence: &lt;strong&gt;Imperfection is an important part of perfection; there&amp;rsquo;s no such thing as perfection in this world.&lt;/strong&gt; In Zeng Guofan’s long novel, he actually wrote a very important sentence: What is the best state of life? Zeng Guofan wanted to name his study “Hall of Seeking Absence,” meaning that a flower is at its best when it hasn’t fully bloomed, and the moon is at its best when it isn&amp;rsquo;t yet full. But for ordinary people, they will think this is a defect, not perfect enough, not reaching the extreme. The best way to ruin someone is to have them pursue perfection and reach the ultimate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The flower is not fully open&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This world isn&amp;rsquo;t like that. A flower is at its best when it’s not fully bloomed; once it’s in full bloom, it’s close to falling. Once the moon begins to be completely round, it’s close to slowly waning. So I feel this is a very important boost and revelation for my 30th birthday; looking good isn&amp;rsquo;t about being 40. But I feel more relaxed, freer. Why am I no longer in a suit and tie, no longer black and white, but starting to ask about happiness?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;40 years old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a Chinese saying, &amp;ldquo;forty is the age of questioning,&amp;rdquo; but thirty is subtraction and forty is confusion. It’s not really about questioning; I think in this era, most people are confused at 40. My midlife crisis came early, starting around thirty-six or seven, when I began to question whether everything I&amp;rsquo;ve done has value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it have meaning? Do I even know what happiness is anymore? This book was born out of this confusion. When you turn 30, you’ll realize that many of your goals for happiness are tied to material possessions. The idea behind &amp;ldquo;establishing oneself by 30&amp;rdquo; refers to having education and a solid foundation. You need a car and a house; otherwise, the mother-in-law won&amp;rsquo;t agree to marry her daughter to you – it’s very materialistic. But “40 not confused” is difficult. I think ancient people probably had a shorter average life expectancy than now, so they condensed it into 40 years before reaching wisdom. I feel like I’m still confused at 40; &lt;strong&gt;material things haven&amp;rsquo;t brought me the happiness I thought they would.&lt;/strong&gt; That’s also why so many people ask me when I turn 40, are you happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is that book titled &amp;ldquo;Waves of Happiness&amp;rdquo;? It&amp;rsquo;s a question mark, representing the confusion in my heart. The birth of a midlife crisis – at 40, you need to answer so many questions for yourself. Around 40, you should chat with yourself more often and read a lot of things to find answers for yourself. I’m very grateful that I entered the world of Tao Te Ching in my late thirties. As I mentioned in &amp;ldquo;White Talk,&amp;rdquo; when you reach 40 and still need to think, if the surrounding environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t change, especially the soft environment – you leave home with a pleasant mood, only to find chaos everywhere, traffic lights being disregarded, fake products, and vaccines…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said that these past few days China has been battling two typhoons, one invisible and one visible. The invisible typhoon is the vaccine, which impacts the dam of our inner security. The other typhoon – China rarely sees typhoons land in Shanghai, but that’s beside the point – what you need to think about next is this: you&amp;rsquo;ve improved yourself, you have many answers, but if the surrounding environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;I have eight characters that I feel are particularly weighty: we currently have a moral deficit and a loss of humanity. This is the biggest deficit and the greatest loss.&lt;/strong&gt; Just a few days ago, not far from here, I witnessed two cars collide; actually, the collision wasn&amp;rsquo;t that serious. The responsible party should have taken responsibility because he hit another car and told them to pull over to the side of the road. The other person also slowly agreed to move over when the car in front suddenly sped off, and no one stopped him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will he be a responsible father? Will he be a responsible son? Let alone how can he be a responsible citizen, and he might be your colleague—that&amp;rsquo;s the moral deficit and the loss of humanity. This will inevitably affect you. No matter how great you are, unless you stay at home, but the problem is that even staying at home doesn’t prevent your children from needing vaccinations; if you deliver food, the food delivery itself could have problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how can a Chinese person learn to transform from an ordinary citizen into a citizen – this is likely an important question for me personally, at the age of 40, and also for society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 30 is about subtraction, and 40 is confusion, I think the word I&amp;rsquo;d give myself for 50 should be curiosity. 50 is awkward, neither rooted in the village nor having a shop to go back to; you can advance and make gains, or retreat and just drift along. You can lie on what you’ve achieved for 10 years, and it seems possible to drift into retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recently read a book, and it had a very interesting passage stating that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley are often in their fifties and sixties – quite different from our concept. Just like China shouldn&amp;rsquo;t treat all volunteers as solely youth volunteers, so too should it not view entrepreneurship entirely as a young person’s pursuit. Last week I did a program about recruiting retired elementary and middle school teachers who will receive an annual subsidy of two or three hundred thousand yuan to teach in rural areas – and they must be excellent teachers. I said this is precisely pioneering the concept of re-employment after retirement, and it&amp;rsquo;s not just charity. However, reaching 50 still feels quite a distance away. How do we move forward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;50 years old&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for people around 50, there are two challenges. The first challenge is yourself: Are you still curious about many things? What&amp;rsquo;s your worldview like? I think my greatest gain at 50, or how I’m living right now, is &lt;strong&gt;treating each day with kindness. When you were 20, it was easy to live for tomorrow; when you’re not careful at 50, it’s easy to dwell on yesterday. But I work hard to restrain myself, neither living in the future nor the past, but treating each today with kindness. People at 50 shouldn&amp;rsquo;t always say &amp;ldquo;tomorrow&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;yesterday was so good!&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best thing to do today is watch a concert disc of Tsai Chin. She said something really good: &amp;ldquo;Every time I look at photos, I think that two years ago, I looked so beautiful,&amp;rdquo; but in those two years, I never thought I was beautiful myself. That sentence has quite a flavor. When I was 30, I didn&amp;rsquo;t think so; I thought I was handsome then and had many flaws. But looking back now after 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once young too, I used to have so much hair. So cherish every day you have now, and it would be wonderful to see you again in two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like what Shitein said, when my legs could no longer walk and I was sitting in a wheelchair, I missed the days when I could run and play basketball every day. It was very painful to reminisce about those times every day.
A few more years passed, and I developed pressure sores while in my wheelchair, making me feel terrible all over. At that time, I constantly missed the days from a few years ago when I felt no pain and could quietly sit in my wheelchair.
Years later, I developed kidney failure and now have to undergo dialysis. At this point, I miss the days when all I had were bedsores on my wheelchair. If I don’t live to be 100 with the ability to treat every day kindly, the past 50 years were for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think we should wait until 50 to understand this truth; people should realize it in their 30s or 40s – everything is easily missed. A meal during a trip, if you don’t eat it, even if you eat it 30 years later, it won’t be the same. So my first feeling at 50 is that I should cherish every today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing is curiosity. I find that I can stop being curious about many things at any time, because I’ve seen and experienced so much. But I urge myself to be curious. So now, when I do a lot of things, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – can the phone be held vertically for filming? It can. You go do on-site reporting, participate in what appears to be a grand summit. Can the live broadcast be more relaxed and fun, leaving a deeper impression on everyone? Can it then be disseminated through new media? All possible. I think curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress. Why can’t it be the most important driving force for an individual&amp;rsquo;s progress? Once a nation loses its curiosity, that nation is finished. On a larger scale, 50 is an important test. What kind of vested interest do you become in China at ages forty and fifty? I am very worried that many people around us, hoping to achieve their dreams when they were young, once they realize those dreams and become vested interests, they turn into people who obstruct others from realizing their own dreams. Am I right? And then, they treat young people and things in the way they used to dislike most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So a few years ago, I started recruiting 11 graduate students every year as a volunteer, mentoring them for two years, and now we’ve had five graduating classes, totaling 55 pure graduate students who have already graduated. I feel very happy to be in this position of privilege. You gain certain insights, and you also have the ability to guide them. After each day of teaching, I take them out to dinner, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much. But this is what a good person with privilege should do. Privilege can manifest in two ways: one is to become a stepping stone again. I once said something like, &amp;ldquo;I don’t want to say thank you too much to those who have helped me,&amp;rdquo; because my way of saying thank you is to treat the new young people with double the effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If saying “thank you” every day becomes an obstacle, the next step is to pave the way for others. I hope that those with vested interests in China – whether material, economic, ideological, cultural, or in any field – when you become one of them, consider what you should do. The people who pushed the train yesterday became the ones blocking it today; looking back at Chinese history, this pattern repeats everywhere, and it won’t change today either. It might even be more so. Therefore, I urge all those with vested interests to return to how they wanted to act when they were young – hoping to encounter certain kinds of people. Perhaps I haven&amp;rsquo;t done enough in that regard, but at least I am thinking, doing, and saying it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
