<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Diary Ramblings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/diary-ramblings/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Diary Ramblings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:08:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/diary-ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Delayed Muscle Soreness (DMS)</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/delayed-muscle-soreness-dms/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 11:53:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/delayed-muscle-soreness-dms/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been focusing on reducing fat and shaping my body, primarily through running at the gym to burn calories. I’m also supplementing this with some basic strength training to boost my basal metabolism. I’ve noticed a pattern: muscle soreness always lags behind, and not working out every day doesn’t cause as much pain; it&amp;rsquo;s really noticeable 48-72 hours after exercise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My training goals are mainly to return to my ideal weight, so the intensity of strength training isn’t planned to be particularly high. Based on my experience hiking Mount Lu in September, this type of soreness usually takes about three days to fully resolve (when I was younger, I had some experiences with dieting and my physical condition was much better, recovery was much faster). Now that my leg muscles have adapted and recovered, but I feel like the main muscle groups throughout my body still need to be reactivated and adjusted one by one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;doms-delayed-onset-muscle-soreness&#34;&gt;DOMS (Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You mentioned this phenomenon is referred to as &lt;strong&gt;Delayed Onset Muscle Soreness&lt;/strong&gt; (DOMS), often abbreviated as &lt;strong&gt;DOMS&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its main characteristic is that the onset of pain has a delay, and it’s not typically at the most intense immediately after exercise or the next day, but rather peaks between &lt;strong&gt;24 to 72 hours post-exercise&lt;/strong&gt;, which aligns with your experience (noticeable reaction two days later).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of the primary reasons why this occurs:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microscopic Muscle Fiber Damage:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DOMS is believed to be primarily caused by lactic acid buildup rather than lactic acid accumulation (lactic acid is cleared from muscles within an hour of exercise), but instead, it’s due to performing unfamiliar or high-intensity movements, particularly those involving a lot of &lt;strong&gt;eccentric contraction&lt;/strong&gt; (muscle lengthening during exertion – for example, the lowering phase of a squat or running downhill) that cause &lt;strong&gt;microscopic tears or damage in muscle fibers and connective tissue&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Inflammation Response:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These microscopic injuries trigger the body’s &lt;strong&gt;inflammatory response&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the process of the body repairing damaged tissue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;onset, development, and accumulation of this inflammatory response take time&lt;/strong&gt;. During this process, tissues release chemicals (such as histamine, prostaglandins, etc.) to stimulate nerve endings, causing pain and soreness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, the soreness doesn&amp;rsquo;t become most noticeable until the &lt;strong&gt;second or third day&lt;/strong&gt; after injury because it needs time for inflammation to fully develop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your muscle soreness is delayed because it’s a process of your body undergoing &lt;strong&gt;muscle microscopic damage&lt;/strong&gt; and an &lt;strong&gt;inflammatory response&lt;/strong&gt;, rather than immediate lactic acid buildup. If you are currently doing basic training that includes a lot of strength training and eccentric contraction movements, it&amp;rsquo;s more likely to cause this delayed soreness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-cope-with-and-address&#34;&gt;How to Cope with and Address
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rest and Recovery:&lt;/strong&gt; Allow the affected muscles adequate rest time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gentle Activity:&lt;/strong&gt; Engage in light aerobic exercise or stretching, which can help improve blood circulation, accelerate metabolic waste removal, and promote recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massage or Foam Rolling:&lt;/strong&gt; Can relieve muscle tension and stiffness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adequate Nutrition:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s also important to replenish protein (to repair muscles) and carbohydrates (to replenish energy) promptly after exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Progressive Increase in Intensity:&lt;/strong&gt; Avoid suddenly increasing exercise volume or intensity, allowing the body to gradually adapt to training.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Breaking Through the Cocoon: Examining Huawei and Xiaomi’s High-End Rivalry Following Xiaomi 17&#39;s Renaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:15:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era of information explosion, we all, to varying degrees, live within our own “information bubbles.” Algorithms recommend content that interests us, and over time, our horizons are subtly narrowed. This phenomenon seems equally applicable to the smartphone market – brand loyalty, media bias, and community voices are all weaving consumers into one bubble after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Xiaomi’s recent move, like a stone thrown into a still lake, has created ripples, attempting to break down this invisible barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Information bubbles, Xiaomi phone change 16 to 17 is not a temporary action, so much inventory, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s high-end path? Xiaomi’s high-end path ultimately relies on product strength to speak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomis-concealed-strategy-skipping-16-confronting-17&#34;&gt;Xiaomi’s “Concealed Strategy”: Skipping 16, Confronting 17
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi has resolutely renamed its upcoming flagship, set to be released as the “Xiaomi 17,” from the initially planned “Xiaomi 16,” revealing its intent – a direct challenge to Apple’s iPhone 17. This was not a spontaneous whim; for a company of this scale, any flagship product&amp;rsquo;s naming, preparation, and marketing is a massive undertaking that requires careful planning months, or even years in advance, involving millions of packaging materials, promotional items, and channel communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This renaming represents Xiaomi’s meticulously planned “concealed strategy,” a bold gamble on a brand-level strategic move. It sends a clear signal: Xiaomi is no longer content with the “value for money” label; instead, it intends to enter Apple and Huawei’s long-dominated high-end market territory with a “head-on confrontation” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By aligning itself digitally with the iPhone, Xiaomi aims to break consumers&amp;rsquo; ingrained thinking, placing its products in the same conversational context as top-tier flagships. This is Xiaomi’s bold and confident declaration of its product capabilities, and represents its most aggressive and decisive attempt to penetrate the high-end market after five years of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huaweis-high-end-path-rebuilding-glory-in-adversity&#34;&gt;Huawei’s High-End Path: Rebuilding Glory in Adversity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the topic of the high-end market is mentioned, Huawei is unavoidable. After experiencing the widely known external pressures, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s path to the high-end has been exceptionally difficult yet remarkably steadfast. Leveraging continued deep cultivation in imaging technology and breakthroughs in self-developed chips, Huawei’s Pura and Mate series remain benchmark products in the high-end market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s strategy is more like a “cultivation of inner strength.” It builds powerful technological barriers to entry, such as the XMAGE imaging brand, Kunlun Glass, HarmonyOS operating system, to create core differentiators for its products. Even when facing enormous challenges with supply chains, Huawei continues to enhance product quality, fostering extremely high user loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Huawei’s market share in China&amp;rsquo;s high-end market is steadily recovering – a story of victory based on resilience and product power. Its high-end path is one achieved through technological innovation and brand resilience, step by step, overcoming adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-battle-of-the-titans-is-ultimately-a-matter-of-product-power&#34;&gt;The Battle of the Titans is Ultimately a Matter of “Product Power”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s “One-Step Completion,” or Huawei’s “Steady and Solid,” their paths to the premium market differ, but ultimately, the landing point is always “product power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-end users are willing to pay a higher price not just for a brand logo, but also for comprehensive recognition of the technology, experience, design, and services behind the product. After the noise of marketing, what truly retains users is genuine experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus our attention on the products themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imaging Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; The Huawei Pura 70 Ultra continues to lead in the mobile photography field thanks to its unique retractable camera and powerful XMAGE imaging system. Meanwhile, Xiaomi 17 Series also features a camera system co-developed with Leica, along with new sensors and algorithms, aiming to challenge top industry standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; The Xiaomi 17 was the first to feature Qualcomm’s latest flagship Snapdragon chip, boasting natural advantages in performance release. Huawei, on the other hand, relies on iterative development of its self-designed chips, showcasing unique competitiveness in power consumption and system synergy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen &amp;amp; Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides are putting in their best efforts regarding screen quality, material, and design language. Kunlun Glass’s robust durability, combined with Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s continued investment in display technology, have become distinctive labels for their respective products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; HarmonyOS’s distributed capabilities enable Huawei to create a seamless ecosystem experience, while Xiaomi’s HyperOS is also working hard to build its own intelligent closed-loop ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketing strategies can break down consumers&amp;rsquo; “information silos,” allowing more people to see a brand’s ambition and transformation. But to truly let consumers “walk out of the house” willingly switching brands, it ultimately relies on solid product power to provide an irresistible choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi turned the digital “16” into “17,” which is not just a change in name but also a leap in its brand mentality and market strategy. Huawei, meanwhile, has rebuilt the foundation of its premium brand amidst storms. This battle between the two giants in China’s high-end smartphone market is only beginning its most exciting chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For consumers, this is undoubtedly good news. When all the giants lower their postures and refocus their attention on products themselves, we will ultimately see a more diverse and experience-driven era. And who can emerge victorious in this battle of the titans – time, and the fingertips of every user, will give the final answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Sometimes you need to learn how to interrupt.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:14:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own life trajectory, so the concept of “being a good teacher” often seems superfluous in adult circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;worldview&#34;&gt;Worldview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our life’s journey begins with vastly different formative experiences, these experiences converging and flowing like rivers to ultimately shape our unique life paths. Each story, each choice, weaves together and merges within our minds, solidifying into our perception of the world – our &lt;strong&gt;worldview&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed as tragedy may be merely a story in a book to another person. What you disdain as a lifestyle may be precisely the ideal someone else desperately pursues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding and respecting each other’s differences is the first step in comprehending this diverse world. Sometimes, &lt;strong&gt;remaining silent is also a form of understanding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to share my experiences and insights rather than engage in empty chatter. However, inevitably, you will encounter moments where observing the slow flow of water is a worthwhile strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-philosophy&#34;&gt;Investment Philosophy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My choice of &lt;strong&gt;fixed income plus&lt;/strong&gt; as the primary investment approach is driven by its emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;stable returns&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;low risk&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, I will allocate a significant portion of my asset allocation to this type of product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding stocks, I differentiate between short-term and long-term investments. In my view, &lt;strong&gt;short-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; carries a strong speculative nature, resembling more of a &lt;strong&gt;gambit&lt;/strong&gt;; while &lt;strong&gt;long-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; is genuine &lt;strong&gt;value investing&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s like founding your own company, from fundraising to IPO – you not only reap stock dividends but also gain a profound understanding of economic laws and foresight for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recognized since childhood that I have a &lt;strong&gt;gambling addiction&lt;/strong&gt;, however, studying allows me to rationally control my irrational desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of digital currencies is something I generally dislike from an investment perspective – I haven’t found any real value, but we need to understand its principles and risks. There have previously been articles discussing stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-eggs&#34;&gt;Easter Eggs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;WeChat can fold group chats, and &lt;strong&gt;your private conversations with friends can also be folded&lt;/strong&gt;, from a design perspective, all conversations belong to the same level and are only differentiated in display.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 18:57:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Using AI too much, we start thinking of AI for everything – often, learning new developments is more reliable with search engines plus official project documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong stocks entered on the dip, encountered a pullback, and then just randomly traded, resulting in basic losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strategy-trading&#34;&gt;Strategy Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily to actually practice and make money, but rather to improve my own abilities through learning. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in these trading indicators; I mostly trust the national fortune (luck) and investing in broad market indices via a buy-and-hold strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithmic-trading&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inspiration from last month’s “AI-less project” didn&amp;rsquo;t prove useful, so I started trying to implement it with AI – and that’s where the problems began. The correct approach should have been to first gather information and see what existing projects were doing. Previously, I hadn’t done any algorithmic trading; I wasn’t familiar with indicators, market data handling, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial plan was unreliable, entirely based on my own speculation (“YY”) through communication with AI. I learned about the backtesting framework this way, and looked at GitHub – the project was quite active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over-reliance on AI led to wanting to use it for everything, even requesting an AI-generated learning resource, a vibrant project, and official documentation that’s well-maintained. Prioritizing official documentation or searching for high-quality blogs is better; the learning plans provided by AI were too weak and didn&amp;rsquo;t keep up with current code versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Structure Adjustments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Download:&lt;/strong&gt; I chose Yahoo Finance – this provides daily candlestick data for price changes (price fluctuations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backtesting Official Guide:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning the basics of using the official backtesting guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TA-Lib Installation and Usage:&lt;/strong&gt; Installing and using TA-Lib, calculating common indicators, and displaying the data through backtesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing Alipay’s Fixed Investment Logic:&lt;/strong&gt; This strategy is better suited for long-term ETF investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-trading&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering Hong Kong stock trading was roughly two months ago, a simple recap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timing and motivation for buying Meituan were straightforward – I saw the net inflow of domestic funds and didn’t delve deeply into Meituan&amp;rsquo;s recent situation; coincidentally, I caught the food delivery war and became a shareholder in Meituan. Buying Xiaomi was also at a high price point, and it was appropriate to reduce my position and exit some shares when an opportunity arose. The four factories were implemented, presenting an opportunity, but one that required persistence – about three years have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timing of entry was when Hong Kong’s new consumer and technology stocks were already expensive, coupled with the concept of virtual currencies; when technology stocks retraced, it was a recurring issue – the frequency of adding to positions is not suitable for long-term investment. Today, I thought about betting on a rebound, buying a hand full, but the next day it fell and I couldn’t bear to sell it. When encountering sustained declines, one easily gets trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-term investor, my trading frequency was too high – roughly twice a week would be sufficient.
The Shanghai Composite Index is 3600; domestic large-cap stocks haven&amp;rsquo;t been much invested in through fixed deposits; this missed an opportunity as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:07:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AI has been integrated into daily development workflows, and recent investments have shifted focus from external funds to internal stocks and ETFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-log&#34;&gt;Project Log
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was bored and tried to obtain GitHub badges, starting to use the Issue module. Previously, when writing code, I always wanted to find a place to record the content of each AI modification, but creating a separate document to record it felt disorganized. Now that we have the Issue module, tagging them to distinguish between bugs, features, enhancements, etc., has made the records clear and efficient. Even if I might not need them in the future, recording them is still a form of accumulation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/issues?q=is%3Aissue&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;View Issue List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Release record, find the most recent related commits. Since all commits are AI-generated, copy all recent commit records from the web interface and give them to AI to organize – this is a good release record.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;engagement&#34;&gt;Engagement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That time it was featured on GitHub’s personal page, it passively increased the motivation to write code – after all, the data visualization made things quite fascinating. Even simple positive feedback could provide the impetus to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trae&#34;&gt;Trae
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paid for a monthly trial, honestly, it’s better in VSCode using Claude4. The practical effect is also better. Sometimes, even with the same problem, Trae gives better answers. Should I buy an annual subscription later? Given my current chaotic usage frequency, Trae might not be enough; don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much, we’ll see when we run out. Byte should still have other paid plans and purchase more call volumes.
&lt;del&gt;Simple small issues can be solved using Microsoft, GitHub Copilot, and various models can also be called.&lt;/del&gt;
The plan is to fail – GitHub Copilot is now starting to limit the number of calls &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/about-github-copilot/plans-for-github-copilot#models&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;618 opened restrictions&lt;/a&gt;
How to check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/managing-copilot/understanding-and-managing-copilot-usage/monitoring-your-copilot-usage-and-entitlements#downloading-a-monthly-usage-report&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;current usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I couldn’t resist. Since the Hong Kong Connect channel was opened, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t traded in the Hong Kong market, and I bought some Xiaomi stock thinking about their upcoming new car launch. It rose a bit, so I sold it, and when it fell, I bought it back again, repeating this process several times before the new car was released, making a small profit on the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, I didn’t know what to do but look at the cross-border capital flows of Hong Kong Connect, watching Meituan&amp;rsquo;s net inflow of funds, and followed suit by buying it in, successfully becoming a shareholder, forgetting to look at the overall capital flow, only a part of the domestic purchases, and there were still many foreign investors in the Hong Kong market. This time it was just an opportunity to practice with blue-chip stocks, slowly holding on to the final gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling positions and losses are &lt;strong&gt;contrary to human nature&lt;/strong&gt;, slow down, slow down, don’t rush. If Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s new car doesn’t perform well, should I sell? That’s a question. My investment cognition is still insufficient, and I need to read more books and learn more. The Fed isn’t planning on cutting interest rates, and the Hong Kong market plunged once, if I missed the entry time? That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be right, what if the news came out that interest rates were being cut and the Hong Kong market soared? This is investment, testing human nature.
&lt;code&gt;A phrase I often repeat: buying is for national fortune, but I don’t really believe in national fortune.&lt;/code&gt;
Aside from the belief in national fortune, &lt;strong&gt;another one is attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Since you&amp;rsquo;re going to do long-term investing, frequent monitoring of the market is pointless. Ten minutes in the morning and ten minutes at the close are enough. What is the final expected return rate? There’s still no clear stop-loss position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the market falls sharply, Tencent is a hot commodity, with capital flocking to it.
| 00700 | Tencent Holdings | 498.600 | 80.08 billion |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-1&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;03690&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;128.100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.881 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-2&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bubble Mate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;247.200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.703 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-3&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09988&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;109.800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;532.2 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-4&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01810&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.050&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41.05 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>- Four people in a university dormitory, and ten years later they went in four different directions.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/university-dormitory-four-people-ten-years-later-they-went-in-four-different-directions/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 21:37:30 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/university-dormitory-four-people-ten-years-later-they-went-in-four-different-directions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lightstone debuted today, and a former roommate from university has been working inside for many years, leading the hardware development of a particular product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding expertise, Lightstone’s core business is sports cameras, which is most closely related to his undergraduate major: &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt;. Automation is a broad field; during his sophomore year, it was divided into smaller specializations. Regarding his former roommate, there were two groups – the first group were freshman roommates, and the second group were sophomore roommates, who were re-assigned when the majors were split up. Our specialization covers embedded systems, engineering automation control, and circuit design—basically a very diverse range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After graduating from university, four people went in four different directions. Although they were all majoring in automation, each person’s choice was unique. It happened to be a fortunate coincidence that the four roommates – myself and three others – had briefly reunited in Shenzhen for two years. I was assigned to the Shenzhen branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myself&lt;/strong&gt; As I&amp;rsquo;ve written in previous articles, I started working in financial IT immediately after graduation, always focusing on Hong Kong and US stocks. The related business content updates on the site are relatively infrequent. To put it another way, while I understand the business and have some knowledge of it, it’s not deep enough. I’ve consistently done transactional-related work, and later expanded to maintaining and monitoring system bottom-layer communications, doing a lot of miscellaneous tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate A&lt;/strong&gt; It seems he started in Ningbo, working on HVAC hardware sales, then moved to Shenzhen. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the details of his previous jobs, but he jumped to ZTE once, leaving during his probation period before it even ended, and then worked at Yijing Technology for several years, leading the R&amp;amp;D of a certain sports camera’s hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate B&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t know his background experiences, currently involved in automotive hardware R&amp;amp;D in Wuhan, having done so for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate C&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working at Vanke in Shenzhen, doing construction supervision for real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-choices&#34;&gt;Life Choices
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure about the regrets of the other two, as we haven&amp;rsquo;t been in much contact – the last time I spoke to them was when they were leaving Shenzhen. We had a chaotic dinner with three “idiots” (a playful term) for our friend from Wuhan, and I made him a video call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back during university, several of us always said, &amp;ldquo;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gone into automation; I should have gone straight to the computer science department. I really loved writing code here, and we won’t go into detail about why I didn’t choose computer science – I’ve written about it in previous articles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m this age, money is an unavoidable topic. When I left Shenzhen, it was because of the high housing prices, with the intention of settling down in Hangzhou. Due to a lucky coincidence, I never settled in Hangzhou and instead worked in Shanghai for income. It was fortunate that I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy a property at a high level when Hangzhou’s houses were being absorbed. When I left Shenzhen, it coincided with the hottest period for Chinese-American stocks. I jumped from one company to another and received a salary increase, but lacked clear industry understanding: &lt;strong&gt;domestic lead flow is a gray area, with policy risks.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put, I circumvented the Hong Kong Connect and traded directly in Hong Kong and American stocks. In 2021, the government abruptly shut down domestic lead flow, causing Chinese brokerage firms to transform and their Hong Kong and American stock businesses to shrink significantly. Basically, in finance, you must comply with regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the reason for writing this article, Jieson Group surged dramatically – &lt;strong&gt;270%&lt;/strong&gt; – leading to an offer from within the company to subscribe. The specific amount here is not discussed. I can only say that Roommate A’s down payment on a house in Shenzhen was likely secured. Although we didn&amp;rsquo;t delve deeply into this subscription matter, I was also tempted to subscribe through his channels, but the scale of the investment was too large and I couldn’t handle the risk. Ultimately, Roommate A chose a safer subscription scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t have much capital, so we can’t withstand large losses; even if we could endure it, what good would it do to throw in fifty and try our luck? This kind of opportunity might not come around again in a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-choices-1&#34;&gt;Life Choices
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To say I haven’t made any money in the past ten years is a lie – I do occasionally envy those who make more, and this decade has been happy because I&amp;rsquo;ve done what I wanted to do, without experiencing any workplace bullying or manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real estate inevitably brings up the topic of money; after all, a 30% down payment is sitting there, and whether you can make money depends not only on your effort but also on the industry’s cycle and whether it can trend upwards. That would have been an opportunity to invest in Jushi (影石), as they were early on, focusing on overseas products while their domestic reputation was still lacking. The circle of Hong Kong-American stocks had become accustomed to a relaxed lifestyle, and I&amp;rsquo;d essentially given back most of my specialized skills to the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a rambling mess; it’s hard for young people to understand an entire industry, let alone formulate ten-year career plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-global-with-products&#34;&gt;Going Global with Products
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make money in foreign trade, the same products can sell for 1,000 RMB domestically, 3,000 RMB abroad, and even more. Considering the current intense price competition within China, it’s even more advantageous. Jingjie (JingShi) and DJI have already started focusing on the panoramic camera sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Jingjie and DJI, aside from leveraging the advantages of the Shenzhen industrial chain, product going global is also a crucial factor. The domestic market is fiercely competitive with severe price wars, while foreign markets offer higher prices and larger profit margins, making it easier to survive in the early stages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>2025 Major Events</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/2025-major-events/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jun 2025 23:36:01 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/2025-major-events/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Record some scattered thoughts and fragments, so as not to need to write them up separately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inspired by friends, I also wanted to create a similar sharing page, and &lt;strong&gt;Notes&lt;/strong&gt; has already been developed. However, the homepage display and historical data processing all have minor issues, which led me to think about creating an annual article to achieve a similar effect, and subsequently &lt;strong&gt;AI&lt;/strong&gt; was developed to implement the article pinning function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;february-2025&#34;&gt;February 2025
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;deepseek-goes-viral&#34;&gt;DeepSeek Goes Viral
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-02-07&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the eve of Chinese New Year, DeepSeek had become a hot topic, attracting widespread attention on social media in just a few days. This sudden surge in popularity was surprising and triggered a chain reaction in the market. Meanwhile, NVIDIA’s stock plummeted, raising concerns among many investors, who conducted large-scale short selling during this period, seemingly pointing to a “carefully orchestrated” situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;analysis-of-political-elements-in-films-during-the-spring-festival&#34;&gt;Analysis of Political Elements in Films During the Spring Festival
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-02-10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I went to the Spring Festival film release for the crowds, and this time I watched two movies that felt quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the new changes in 2025&amp;rsquo;s Spring Festival films, focusing on &lt;em&gt;Shanghai Detective 1900&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Nezha: The Devil’s Child&lt;/em&gt;. The former utilizes the backdrop of San Francisco Chinatown in 1900 to depict the discrimination and oppression faced by Chinese people, reflecting the social and political environment. The latter, as an animated film, employs rich metaphorical elements to subtly criticize the current international political landscape – such as the resemblance of Yu Huang Palace to the Pentagon mirroring the American political system, the dollar symbol on the Tian Yuan Ding symbolizing U.S. dollar hegemony, the jade amulet resembling an American green card representing status levels, and the Soul-Destroying Potion like a biochemical weapon reflecting malicious actions. Both films offer a new viewing experience and prompt reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;online-vs-offline-movie-ticket-price-differences-were-astonishing&#34;&gt;Online vs. Offline Movie Ticket Price Differences Were Astonishing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-02-11&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight people wanted to see a movie and initially planned to purchase tickets on platforms like Tao Piao Piao and Maoyan. They saw prices of 60 yuan. Luckily, they had a cinema recharge card, which required them to buy tickets at the cinema&amp;rsquo;s front desk, so they asked the staff if there were any discounts available. Surprisingly, the same showtime cost only 35 yuan when purchased directly at the front desk – this price difference was truly astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;nezha-goes-viral&#34;&gt;Nezha Goes Viral
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-02-15&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The explosive popularity of Nezha during the Spring Festival box office has evoked a strange sense of national pride, reminiscent of films like &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; and patriotic themes. While there’s been significant progress, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t reached this level. As gamers, many aspects feel overly greasy, and the combat scenes heavily resemble those found in online games. There are already numerous reports of people buying movie tickets for Nezha but not watching the film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;march-2025&#34;&gt;March 2025
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;trump-administration-imposes-tariffs-triggering-trade-turmoil&#34;&gt;Trump Administration Imposes Tariffs, Triggering Trade Turmoil
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-03-04&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The United States imposed 25% tariffs on goods from Mexico and Canada, triggering significant volatility in the North American trade chain. Canada announced retaliatory measures against U.S. goods worth $15.5 billion, while Mexico accelerated its signing of a free trade agreement with China to mitigate risks. This led to further diversification of global supply chains, presenting a window for Chinese steel companies to capitalize on domestic substitution of high-end steel materials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;may-2025&#34;&gt;May 2025
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-tiangong-and-dong-xiyi-effect-a-butterfly-phenomenon&#34;&gt;The Tiangong and Dong Xiyi Effect: A Butterfly Phenomenon
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date:&lt;/strong&gt; 2025-05-07&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Peking Union Medical College “4+4” Project (4 years of non-medical undergraduate + 4 years of medical doctorate) focuses on interdisciplinary elite cultivation. In 2025, the Dong Xiyi incident exposed its use of family background (medical/scientific research lineage) to enter the project, with questions regarding the validity of its degrees and allegations of plagiarism in her thesis, exposing contradictions between its elite recruitment model and fairness, as well as unresolved issues surrounding shortened study periods and internship training.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some say it’s a corner of Tiangong (the Space Palace), others claim it&amp;rsquo;s a case of class decline. Dong Xiyi didn’t need to be a doctor; it was her family’s unwillingness to settle for a life less than their own that led her to pursue the Peking Union College 4+4 project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;special-teacher-recruitment--a-sudden-decline&#34;&gt;Special Teacher Recruitment – A Sudden Decline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-05-12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The recruitment of special teachers in Jiangxi Province has shown a significant reduction trend from 2020-2025: the number of special teacher recruits plummeted from 6,617 to just 32 (a decrease of 99.5%), while the number of national cadre teachers decreased from 11,324 to 2,146 (a decrease of 81.1%). The proportion of core subjects (Chinese, Mathematics, and English) remained stable but declined in total numbers, while the proportions of music, art, and physical education increased but in limited absolute quantities (e.g., in 2025, they only recruited 2 people each). Policy changes have implemented “retire one, replenish one” personnel adjustments to tighten teacher resources, which are being directed towards vocational training and remote areas, leading to a significant reduction in traditional primary and secondary school positions. In 2025, some subjects planned for recruitment were zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-trade-war-suddenly-paused&#34;&gt;The Trade War Suddenly Paused
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-05-12&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade war tariffs have followed a “escalation – retaliation – negotiation” cycle, with the US-China rivalry shifting from tariff confrontation to competition over rules. Although the short-term easing has alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty remains, and it’s crucial to monitor WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical changes&amp;rsquo; sustained impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Individuals aren’t making money beyond their own expectations; the stock market crash triggered by the initial trade war this year is now largely recovered, although countless small investors have been buried along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;june-2025&#34;&gt;June 2025
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;super-hot-susuper-public-sports-economic-value-emerges&#34;&gt;Super Hot SuSuper: Public Sports Economic Value Emerges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date: 2025-06-09&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Jiangsu Super League (SuSuper) third round of matches saw an average attendance of over 10,000 people, with the “Chu Han Clash” match in Xuzhou Olympic Center drawing 22,198 spectators, breaking the record for amateur events in China. Short videos on platforms like Douyin created buzz and drove cross-city consumption for over 180,000 people, boosting hotel occupancy rates by 20%-30%. Innovative sports commercialization models saw a surge in brand exposure for sponsors such as Jiangsu Bank and Jinshilu, validating the multiplier effect of “Sports + Tourism.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>AI overuse can lead to some lingering effects.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we’ve established “AI Inspiration Collision Forum,” there’s been a lot of random content being created, with people experimenting with AI to record and publish things, but thoughtful reflection is becoming increasingly scarce. Moving forward, it would be beneficial to slightly control the output of this section and consolidate it into a monthly magazine format – releasing one article per month would suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a sort of aftereffect or side effect; efficiency has increased, but the depth and breadth of thought have declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-boost-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency Boost: Undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “Seven-Second Fish Sightseeing” column used to be poorly maintained, with only a few hot events covered. Due to laziness, I hadn’t searched the internet for relevant materials or compiled records. Now that various AI tools are available, all it takes is outlining the key points, and AI can automatically search for related events, generate articles as needed, simply format them, and publish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a blessing for lazy people – efficiency has increased significantly, almost to the point of doubling efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond writing articles, efficiency gains are real when coding. Previously, writing code often required detailed reading of API interface documentation. Now, I can skip this entirely. This is incredibly valuable because familiarizing oneself with APIs is “physical labor,” not “mental labor.” AI handles this part perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spam-content&#34;&gt;Spam Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many articles have poor quality content, not to say that there’s nothing there; it just doesn&amp;rsquo;t read well, lacking a sense of reality and what people actually experience. It’s a style I didn’t enjoy before – like chewing wax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From another perspective, AI-generated content really does feel like products of a流水线 (liú shuǐ liàn - assembly line) production, lacking soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;New Era Internet Spam&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetting&#34;&gt;Forgetting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of document is entirely AI-generated, and the reader’s context is unclear. However, over time, my own impressions will become blurred, or even forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar issues occur when writing code – without reviewing commit records, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how I originally thought about it, or why I wrote it that way. This is particularly evident with code generated through repeated communication with AI, where the final code differs significantly from the initial ideas, sometimes drastically so.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the number of times I’ve opened Google and Baidu has noticeably decreased. Many questions are now being answered by AI for searching and interaction, and the results are much better than traditional search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s mourn the &lt;code&gt;bing ai&lt;/code&gt;, which may no longer be active, a pioneering AI tool from a major company that could connect to the internet and search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m using Google less, and the number of times I visit &lt;code&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; has decreased as well. Many questions are now simply asked of AI – this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My maintained blog, originally with very little traffic, is now even less expected of; it’s primarily a place for self-reflection and recording.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Town Brahmin: The “Big Man” of Small Places</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recently, the popular &amp;ldquo;Da Bing&amp;rdquo; (Big Ice) on Douyin (TikTok) has been frequently seen with short video accounts extracted from her live streams. A listener who joined a live call asked: “Da Bing, I want to sell my house in Xi’an and return home to settle down.” Da Bing responded: “At your age, you&amp;rsquo;re in your early thirties; you can&amp;rsquo;t settle down. Your parents are on the path of aging, your children haven’t started a family or established themselves, and if you return home, you’ll still need to deal with the &lt;em&gt;poren&lt;/em&gt;.”
Let’s set aside whether the viewpoint is right or wrong, what does the term “poren” mean?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;township-brahmins-the-big-shots-of-small-places&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Township Brahmins: The “Big Shots” of Small Places&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many small county towns, people often talk about so-called &amp;ldquo;township brahmins&amp;rdquo;—the existence of these individuals seems to be a symbol of local society. They are not necessarily genuine religious figures and do not possess “high-level” titles; rather, they are seemingly ordinary but nonetheless influential people. They represent “power, status, and influence” within that county town, symbolizing a particular class or stratum in that area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-xiancheng-babao&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an “Xiancheng Babao?”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we need to understand that “Babao” originally referred to the highest caste in Indian society, representing wisdom, authority, and spiritual supremacy. In China’s county towns, the term “Xiancheng Babao” doesn&amp;rsquo;t have such a complex religious background; it’s more of a metaphor for a social phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an “Xiancheng Babao” can be understood as some “cultural authorities” within the county town – such as teachers, doctors, well-known merchants, and officials. Although their positions may seem ordinary, in this relatively closed environment, they possessed a comparatively higher social status, or their opinions and actions had influence that could not be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-the-county-town-brahmin&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is the “County Town Brahmin”?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In county towns, you’ll find figures like this – the “Brahmin” – in almost every industry. They might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators:&lt;/strong&gt; Particularly teachers who have spent decades working in the area, not necessarily graduates of prestigious universities, but who understand how to build credibility through knowledge and are widely respected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Government Officials:&lt;/strong&gt; Deputy county magistrates, section chiefs, etc., who control certain resources and power – even if their positions aren’t high-ranking, their limited scope of authority can make them local “Brahmins.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local “Entrepreneurs”:&lt;/strong&gt; Some business owners in county towns, though not large in scale, hold a certain amount of wealth and have a voice in the area. They might run one or two well-known small local businesses, wielding considerable influence within the county town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people, while not as prominent as figures in larger cities or high-ranking officials, hold a status almost equivalent to “cultural elders” or “centers of power” within this small community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-status-of-county-town-brahmins--how-does-it-impact-society&#34;&gt;The Status of “County Town Brahmins” – How Does it Impact Society?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the significance of “county town brahmins,” we must consider the unique environment of the county town. Here, information flow is slower than in large cities, and social class mobility is relatively fixed. These “brahmins” often gained prestige, knowledge, and networks through long-term dedication to the local area. They influence various aspects of local politics, economics, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural Influence:&lt;/strong&gt; In small places, especially where education systems are not as developed and people have limited choices, local &amp;ldquo;brahmins&amp;rdquo; subtly shape the cultural atmosphere through knowledge transmission in classrooms, explanations in media, and even moral guidance in social settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentration of Social Resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to the limited population and resources of county towns, these “brahmins” are often one of the primary controllers of local resources. Whether it’s social welfare, policy implementation, or approval of certain projects, they invariably have an influence. Their power of speech and decision-making allows them to hold a prominent position in local society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Networked Structure of Relationships:&lt;/strong&gt; In a relatively closed small society, interpersonal relationships are crucial. These “county town brahmins” build strong social networks to control information flow and resource allocation, enabling them to play a decisive role at critical moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-metaphor-of-the-county-sharma&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Metaphor of the “County Sharma”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite often being revered and admired, this position of “high above” is not without its issues. In modern society, it’s easy to see that many “Sharmas” – those in county-level positions – lack genuine ability and innovative spirit; instead, they maintain their status through hereditary relationships and resource monopolies. With the development of informatization, these “Sharmas’” power is gradually being broken, and new social mobility is beginning to influence the appearance of small counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, “County Sharma” is a fascinating social phenomenon that reflects the power and cultural structures within local societies. Although their “power” may not directly threaten national governance, they are undoubtedly key figures within the region. In this era of rapid information flow and accelerating social change, these “Sharmas” in county towns may be facing unprecedented challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this would have happened if we hadn’t started with curiosity about what a ‘purohito’ was, and then tossed it to &lt;code&gt;kimi&lt;/code&gt;. The result was surprisingly funny – I could see the web interface already pulling up search results, but suddenly they were unable to be displayed as related content. Then I wondered, did this word have some special significance? So I threw it at &lt;code&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/code&gt;, and that&amp;rsquo;s how this article came about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Getting out for a walk is always good.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If things had gone as the family planned, I would have stuck to studying power grids honestly and diligently, without venturing into coding. Had I erased the dust from my memory, it all stemmed from a chat with my roommate near the Spring Festival, which led to a review of my experiences over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the &lt;em&gt;gaokao&lt;/em&gt; (national college entrance examination) couldn’t be described as good or bad; I got into a 211 university, and according to Dad&amp;rsquo;s original plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work for the local electricity supply bureau. Earlier accounts had also mentioned how to gradually transition onto the IT path – something that hadn’t been fully articulated before: financial perspective and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my education in a rural school, and after primary school two, my family arranged for me to transfer to a school in the city district. Like Grandma Liu entering the Grand View Garden, I initially struggled to adapt to the bustling prosperity of the city. I hadn’t been to the cinema very often, and specifically, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone with my parents, but relatives would take me. Heaven always bestows luck upon you; back then, I met a few like-minded friends, though we lost contact later on. Looking back, that period of youth was truly wonderful. After weekend tutoring, we’d clean out the classroom plastic bottles, quickly stepping on them to flatten and pack them into our backpacks to take home for Mom to save up – accumulating them until they were enough to find a waste collector to handle disposal. We&amp;rsquo;d play chess, badminton, and Mahjong together, with push-ups as punishment for losing, which we still felt a little fortunate about; Dad had been taking me through various exercises since childhood. From this point on, my financial perspective was slightly skewed, I felt somewhat inferior, but these small misfortunes quickly passed. Our family wasn’t struggling financially, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much pocket money, sometimes couldn’t join our classmates in their activities, especially on weekends. Seeing our parents’ efforts as they moved us from the village to the city. At this time, the seed had been planted, waiting for it to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My simple-minded self was generally very happy during my studies, much like many graduates can only appreciate after graduation – studying wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a difficult task; the investment and output converted relatively easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one-1&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I layered in the memories of the Age of Empires, and during university, I encountered a laptop – it was like Pandora’s Box opening, introducing me to games and connecting me with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, sourcing goods upstream and selling them through my own community channels, earning a little money. Later, I gradually understood the operational logic of the entire chain. The products we sold were simply mass-produced by upstream programs, and their costs approached zero. At this point, the road had already started to veer off course; there were further subdivisions within the field – on the left was power grids, and on the right was automation (very complex, chip programming, factory electrical automation) – I realized that software could make money, but it wasn’t much. Although the upstream channels did earn a lot, combined with my previous background in programming, I started tinkering here and there, making a little money. When choosing between specialized fields, I naturally chose automation. After finishing my third year of coursework, I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend many classes, constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in last year’s article, inspired by the beautiful vision of hackers, I came into programming through self-study – I learned assembly language, penetration testing, game cheats, DLL hijacking, and data theft, familiarizing myself with various blackware and greyware. My parents taught me how to be a good person, and the law ultimately dissuaded me from going too far down that path; the road didn’t completely deviate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous Post Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/&#34; &gt;That Time When I Was Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also talked about a brief romance during university. Looking back, it was mostly longing for the love depicted in television dramas. As an immature mind at the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand how to love someone, let alone achieve: settling down and starting a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amidst the torrent of times, I was fortunate – university’s tribulations led me to not pursue graduate studies; I immediately entered employment and enjoyed a smooth career path riding the wave of IT. It&amp;rsquo;s now my eighth year in this profession, but the hype money vanished as the industry matured, leading to its decline. Sometimes, I question whether my initial choice was correct – perhaps entering the power grid as suggested by my father would have been a better option. Such thoughts might linger during the first five years of employment, but they gradually fade away with time. My recruitment into HSBC lasted five years without a change of company, which resulted in certain deficiencies regarding technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following arrangements from the Hangzhou headquarters, I relocated to the Shenzhen branch, experiencing a workplace struggle (which, upon reflection, proved detrimental to both sides – ultimately benefiting the board) fueled by my passion for technology. I returned to Hangzhou with a youthful exuberance, only to later withdraw and head to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I planned to settle in Hangzhou, register, and purchase property during the highest interest rates and peak housing prices, risking being trapped; my finances were limited, making it impossible to bear the burden of mortgage payments, compounded by an industry downturn, leading to emotional instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having been around for so many years, having seen so much, I’ve made my own mistakes and wasted time. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. Through experiences and through people, one inevitably grows and matures. If I were to remain at home all the time, I don’t know what form my flaws would manifest in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Revenue Generation Business Model: Raffle/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Live streamers sending iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three seemingly unrelated items are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic – a bit like a financial game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-lottery-for-gifts&#34;&gt;Platform Lottery for Gifts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset their acquisition of platform currency and purchase gifts to send to the host, &amp;ldquo;Xin Yi&amp;rdquo; (Hearty), with each platform having another gameplay mechanic. After users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but instead spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery activities, obtaining limited high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the online lottery is simply understood as the platform opening a casino. With enough participants, it’s guaranteed not to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;屌丝&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (literally &amp;ldquo;loser,&amp;rdquo; often used colloquially to describe lower-income individuals) users, fueled by a desire to try their luck and win big, hoping to hit a jackpot and then send gifts – gaining face and acting as a “big brother”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-stream-gifts-physical-items&#34;&gt;Live Stream Gifts (Physical Items)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lottery mentioned previously targets users’ own writing. Each month, the hosts have water flow tasks and popularity tasks. The gameplay of opening gift giveaways allows fans to send specific gifts or gifts of a specified amount, giving them the opportunity to participate in the lottery. The prizes could be high-end phones or cash red envelopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular hosts, this activity is very profitable, essentially equivalent to temporary zero-cost purchases. If enough people participate, the host also makes money. This tests the host’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another gameplay where the rewards are very high (cash value), and many outdoor anchors operate in this way, effectively turning it into an online gambling. Users only care about whether they can win, not the content of the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from show-type hosts, through PK mode, they induce fans to consume and recharge, and ordinary game anchors cannot drive players’ consumption sentiment. Playing games and watching live streams are both ways to pass the time and don&amp;rsquo;t want to incur additional expenses, especially &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. The lottery method can cultivate users’ recharging habits, consumption habits, and occasionally even impulsive spending (sending a lot, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini Program Ranking Rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini program with some useless workflows or provide partial game-related auxiliary services. The above are all cover stories, designed to pass Tencent’s audit – the mini program’s gameplay incorporates a ranking mechanism. Users earn points by browsing promotional ads and completing tasks, and the backend sets rankings based on these points, with higher-ranked users receiving designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Logic: Advertising Revenue &amp;gt; Operating Costs + Reward Expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mini program can also operate normally by providing reasonable services and earning revenue through appropriate advertising – this may not generate much income, but it’s a steady trickle and is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Back then, as a young boy, he might have had talent, but it wasn’t common.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s my seventh year in the job, and I’m not getting as much positive feedback on the code I write. Let me reflect on how I ended up on this &lt;code&gt;coding&lt;/code&gt; path. People’s choices, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re younger, tend to follow positive reinforcement more closely – actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city and coming into contact with computer books? Hacker’s materials? Meeting Windows systems – these are all anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time should be positioned around childhood and sneaking around with my cousin to play games on our parents&amp;rsquo; computer.&lt;/strong&gt; My cousin and I ran a shop with our uncle at the computer store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started having exposure to computers relatively early, and basic understanding was established. Later, in school, taking the microcomputer course also sparked an interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In middle school, I heard about computer competitions, which seemed really cool, but after transferring schools, this fell by the wayside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my junior high years, I was familiar with basic computer operations, and I could easily stand out during microcomputer classes. If you’re still familiar, yes, you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, it wasn’t proficiency – being familiar with office software would be even more impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-moving--relocation&#34;&gt;II. Moving / Relocation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the moving situation. When we moved to the city center, due to the neighbors, we came into contact with the library. Although we read quite a few novels, we also read a lot of magazines, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;大众软件&lt;/em&gt; (Greatest Software)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to an increasingly growing interest in computers as a product. The childhood fascination with hackers was actively pursued through relevant knowledge at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned the basics of operating systems: control panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt; is suitable for beginners; each time it explains system operations in the form of case studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greatest Software&lt;/em&gt; recommends various software, industry news, &lt;strong&gt;and of course, game news – this was the initial motivation, and it also planted the seed for gaming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, Bo Ge transferred to our class, and &lt;strong&gt;several seniors had been guaranteed admission through computer competitions in the previous two years&lt;/strong&gt;. The school leaders also paid a lot of attention to this competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a prerequisite hardware foundation – an alumnus from America donated a building to the school, which resulted in a new library and a new computer lab; it all seemed so coincidental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus Bo Ge’s popular science lectures, he was considered the computer guru in our class at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scholar + computer expert, knew how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable classroom surveillance software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school-1&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The competitions were bumpy and ultimately ended in the finals, where I didn’t quite understand the material and the questions were mostly basic algorithms. However, it was still a worthwhile experience – like taking a short trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-university&#34;&gt;Four. University
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Waiting for university major selection, I chose automation based on my parents&amp;rsquo; recommendation, but I actually wanted to pursue electrical engineering, intending to join the power supply bureau upon graduation. I didn’t learn much in the courses of my major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My self-driven learning ability was almost non-existent within the major courses; however, I found computer courses within the large curriculum very easy to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended classes for the major course while skipping lectures and diligently studied computer courses. I spent my daily time browsing forums: “JingYi Forum” (“I Love Crack”),
Combining what I learned from that bit of assembly and C++ knowledge with the skills gained from taking on orders from the forums, I earned more positive feedback and went further and further down this path, unable to be pulled back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the choice of a minor led me to choose writing code for chips, and my parents didn’t interfere much, letting me make my own decision.
At that time, &lt;strong&gt;the third key figure: my cousin&lt;/strong&gt; had a high education and worked at Baidu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My elder sister understood me and knew that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been focused on research back then, so she encouraged me to talk to my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confirmed the future development path, didn’t go home during the summer vacation, followed my advisor to work on projects, and gained experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my still-passable grades, I was admitted to Hengsheng Electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five. Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a key point I know – I learned how to bypass firewalls, took elective courses in Computer Information Retrieval, and quickly found and located information and problems. A valuable colleague, &lt;strong&gt;Mr. [硕哥&amp;rsquo;s nickname]&lt;/strong&gt;, appeared at work, gave me time to learn independently, troubleshoot issues down to their roots, and introduced me to the leaders of the R&amp;amp;D center.
These experiences laid the groundwork; in Shenzhen, everyone outside viewed me as exceptionally skilled, successfully leading the transaction channel group.
That’s where the problem lies: I lacked systematic learning in computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design. All my knowledge was based on my own past experience.
This led to frequent self-doubt regarding my code designs, a lack of guidelines for module design, and ultimately, fatigue after seven years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Onomatopoeia of the Night</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is utterly unique; there isn’t even a single homophone. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person’s life has only one opportunity, cannot be replicated, and cannot be relived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with an overwhelming number of monthly votes, far surpassing the second-place book – a gap that was truly daunting. For many years, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jiaqian and Ergen. This time, I decided to try a new author’s work and experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed a staggering two million monthly votes, while the second book only garnered eight hundred thousand – the disparity was astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge my own lack of knowledge and ability to critically evaluate the author&amp;rsquo;s writing style. However, after reading through more than fifteen chapters, I found that the plot was tightly woven and intricately connected, captivating and engaging. Given such high monthly vote numbers, it’s undeniably well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like “命,” the character “死” (death) also has no homophones within the Chinese character system. Does this similarly imply a unique and irreplaceable depth regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, and also a bipedal animal, with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everydayness&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is significantly above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you start thinking about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you start thinking about earning a billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but you don’t see the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are starting to wake up. If they could really make money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling – you’d start to find them interesting. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone in the IT industry myself, I began to feel that the “big brothers” behind these algorithms were having a bit of a problem – you recommend like this, are you thinking I’m stupid or are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; stupid? Crucially, they keep finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they&amp;rsquo;re constantly trying to figure out the most effective way to exploit my time. I started wondering how long this business model could last, and how much time they could drain from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet their minds and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It&amp;rsquo;s not really articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must be able to think of some things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lost/Confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, at some stage of life, people find themselves in a state of confusion, not knowing what they truly want, and gradually losing their pursuit of the meaning of work amidst the mundane daily routines. Looking back to when I first graduated, my heart was full of fervent aspirations – then I would without hesitation say, “I yearn to write code, to create brilliant, eye-catching code.” However, working until today, I’ve had more exposure to business-level affairs, which is largely due to the benefits brought by industry development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my lifestyle, I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet included marriage and having children, or establishing a family, in my thinking; my mind is almost blank, only focused on enjoying the present moment. Whenever weekends arrive, I enjoy quietly playing games, often spending an entire day staying at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In life, we always need something we truly love and dedicate ourselves to wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-house&#34;&gt;Buying a House
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was full of enthusiasm and planned to save diligently to buy my own property. I meticulously budgeted every day towards this goal. However, as house prices continued to rise, I transitioned from initial anxiety and disappointment to eventually becoming numb, gradually feeling that even if I bought a house, it would simply be a heavy burden I’d been carrying around – ultimately leading me to abandon the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saving-money&#34;&gt;Saving Money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving some small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, purchasing a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. However, now I approach saving with a more relaxed and “chill” attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses – I indulge in things I want to eat and boldly try new and exciting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;returning-home&#34;&gt;Returning Home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I most longed for deep down was simply to go home. There wasn’t anything particularly to do, just returning to that familiar place, feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
