<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Diary Ramblings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/diary-ramblings/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Diary Ramblings on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/diary-ramblings/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>AI overuse can lead to some lingering effects.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we’ve launched “AI Inspiration Collision Forum,” there’s been a lot of random content being recorded and published, with people rushing to use AI to document and release everything. Quiet reflection and independent thought have become increasingly scarce. Moving forward, it would be beneficial to slightly control the output of this section and consolidate it into a monthly magazine format – releasing one article per month would suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a kind of aftereffect or side effect; efficiency has increased, but the depth and breadth of thinking have declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-boost-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency Boost: Undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “Seven-Second Fish Sightseeing” column used to be poorly maintained, with only a few hot events covered. Due to laziness, I hadn’t searched the internet for relevant materials or compiled records. Now that various AI tools are available, all it takes is outlining the key points, and AI can automatically search for related events, generate articles as needed, simply format them, and publish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a blessing for lazy people – efficiency has increased significantly, almost to the point of doubling effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond writing articles, efficiency gains are real when coding. Previously, writing code often required detailed reading of API interface documentation. Now, I can skip this entirely. This is incredibly valuable because familiarizing oneself with APIs is “physical labor,” not “mental labor.” AI handles this part perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spam-content&#34;&gt;Spam Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many articles have poor quality content, not to say that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing there, but it’s difficult to read, lacking a sense of reality and what people actually experience. This is a style I didn’t enjoy in the past – like chewing wax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, AI-generated content truly feels like products of a流水线 (liú shuǐ liàn - assembly line) production, lacking soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spam of the New Internet Era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetting&#34;&gt;Forgetting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of document is entirely AI-generated, and the reader’s context is unclear. However, over time, my own impressions will become blurred, or even forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar problems occur when writing code – without reviewing commit records, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how I originally thought about it or why I wrote it that way. This is particularly noticeable with code generated through repeated communication with AI, where the final code differs significantly from the initial ideas, sometimes to the point of being completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the number of times I’ve opened Google and Baidu has noticeably decreased. Many questions are now being answered by AI for searching and interaction, and the results are much better than traditional search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s mourn the &lt;code&gt;bing ai&lt;/code&gt;, which may no longer be active, a pioneering AI tool from a major company that could connect to the internet and search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m using Google less, and I’ve reduced my visits to &lt;code&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; as well. Many questions are now simply asked of AI – this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My maintained blog, originally with very little traffic, is now even less expected of; it’s primarily a place for self-reflection and recording.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Town Brahmin: The “Big Man” of Small Places</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the popular &amp;ldquo;Da Bing&amp;rdquo; (Big Ice) on Douyin (TikTok) has been frequently seen with short video accounts extracted from her live streams. A listener who joined a live call asked: “Da Bing, I want to sell my house in Xi’an and return home to settle down.” Da Bing responded: “At your age, you&amp;rsquo;re in your early thirties; you can’t settle down. Your parents are on the path of aging, your children haven’t started a family or established themselves, and if you return home, you’ll still have to deal with the &lt;em&gt;parames&lt;/em&gt; (婆罗门) in the small county.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s put aside whether the viewpoint is right or wrong, what does the term “&lt;em&gt;parames&lt;/em&gt;” (婆罗门) mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;township-brahmins-the-big-shots-of-small-places&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Township Brahmins: The “Big Shots” of Small Places&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many small county towns, people often talk about so-called “township brahmins”—the existence of these individuals seems to be a symbol of local society. They are not necessarily genuine religious figures and do not possess “high-level” titles; rather, they are seemingly ordinary but nonetheless influential people. They represent “power, status, and influence” within that county town, symbolizing a particular class or stratum in that area.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-an-xiancheng-babao&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is an “Xiancheng Babao?”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we need to understand that “Babao” originally referred to the highest caste in Indian society, representing wisdom, authority, and spiritual supremacy. In China’s county towns, the term “Xiancheng Babao” doesn&amp;rsquo;t have such a complex religious background; it’s more of a metaphor for a social phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, an “Xiancheng Babao” can be understood as some “cultural authorities” within the county town – such as teachers, doctors, well-known merchants, and officials, etc. Although their positions may seem ordinary, in this relatively closed environment, they possessed a comparatively higher social status, or their opinions and actions had influence that could not be ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-the-township-brahmin&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Who is the &amp;ldquo;Township Brahmin&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In towns and counties, you’ll often find figures like this – the “Brahmin.” They might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Educators:&lt;/strong&gt; Particularly teachers who have spent decades working in the area, not necessarily graduates of prestigious universities, but who understand how to build credibility through knowledge and are widely respected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Government Officials:&lt;/strong&gt; Deputy county magistrates, section chiefs, etc., who control certain resources and power – even if their positions aren’t high-ranking, their limited scope of authority can make them local “Brahmins.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local &amp;ldquo;Entrepreneurs&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong&gt; Some business owners in rural towns, though not large in scale, hold a certain amount of wealth and have a voice in the community. They might operate one or two well-known local small businesses and wield considerable influence within the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-status-of-county-town-brahmins--how-does-it-impact-society&#34;&gt;The Status of “County Town Brahmins” – How Does it Impact Society?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the significance of “county town brahmins,” we must consider the unique environment of the county town. Here, information flow is slower than in large cities, and social class mobility is more fixed. These “brahmins” often accumulated prestige, knowledge, and connections through long-term dedication to the local area. They influence various aspects of local politics, economics, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cultural Influence:&lt;/strong&gt; In small places, especially where education systems may not be as developed and people have fewer choices, local &amp;ldquo;brahmins&amp;rdquo; subtly shape the cultural atmosphere through knowledge transmission in classrooms, explanations in media, and even moral guidance in social settings. &lt;strong&gt;Concentration of Social Resources:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to the limited population and resources in county-level cities, these “Brahman” figures were often one of the primary controllers of local resources. Whether it was social welfare, policy implementation, or the approval of certain projects, they invariably exerted influence. Their power of speech and decision-making allowed them to hold a position within the local society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Web of Interpersonal Relationships:&lt;/strong&gt; In a relatively closed small community, interpersonal relationships are often crucial. These “county Brahman” figures established powerful social networks to control information flow and resource allocation, thereby playing a decisive role at critical moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-metaphor-of-the-county-sharma&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Metaphor of the “County Sharma”&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the “county sharma” (or “town Brahmin”) is often regarded with respect and admiration, this position of privilege isn’t without its issues. In modern society, it&amp;rsquo;s not difficult to see that many county-level “sharmas” lack genuine ability and innovative spirit; instead, they maintain their positions through hereditary relationships and resource monopolies. With the development of informatization, these “sharmas’” power is gradually being eroded, and new social mobility is beginning to influence the appearance of small counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the “county sharma” is a fascinating social phenomenon that reflects the power and cultural structures within local societies. Although their “power” may not directly threaten national governance, they are undoubtedly key figures within the region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;None of this would have happened if we hadn’t started with curiosity about what a ‘purohito’ was, and then tossed it to ‘kimi.’ The result was surprisingly funny – I could see the web interface already pulling up search results, but instantly they were blocked from displaying related content. So I wondered, did this word hold some special significance? Then I passed it on to ‘ChatGPT,’ and that’s how this article came about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Getting out for a walk is always good.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If things had gone as the family planned, I would have stuck to studying power grids honestly and diligently, without venturing into coding. Had I erased the dust from my memory, it all stemmed from a chat with my roommate near the Spring Festival, which led to a review of my experiences over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the college entrance exam couldn’t be described as good or bad; I ended up graduating from a 211 university, and according to my father&amp;rsquo;s initial plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work for the local power supply bureau in our hometown. There had also been mentions earlier about how to step by step take this path into the IT industry – something that hadn’t been mentioned before: financial views and self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to school in a rural town in elementary school, and my family arranged for me to transfer to a school in the city in middle school, much like Grandma Liu entering the Grand View Garden; I was somewhat unaccustomed to the hustle and bustle of urban life. I hadn’t been to a movie theater very often, to be precise, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone to the movies with my parents, but rather my relatives would take me. Heaven always gives you luck; back then I met several friends who were just like me, although we lost contact later on, that period of my youth is now seen as beautiful. After catching up on tutoring over the weekend, we’d gather to collect the plastic bottles from the classroom, expertly kicking them flat and stuffing them into our backpacks to take back home for Mom to store. As they accumulated, we&amp;rsquo;d find a collector to handle their disposal. We’d also play chess, badminton, and Mahjong – if I lost, I’d do a few push-ups, which I always felt a little relieved about, as Dad had been taking me through all sorts of exercises since I was a kid. From this point on, my understanding of money was slightly skewed, and I felt a bit insecure, but these small misfortunes quickly passed. Our family wasn’t struggling; we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much pocket money, and sometimes I couldn’t join my classmates in their activities, especially on weekends. Seeing our parents’ efforts was visible to the naked eye – we had moved from the village to the city. At this point, the seeds were planted, waiting for them to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a simple-minded individual, I found my time studying to be generally very happy, much like many people can only truly appreciate after graduating – reading isn’t actually that difficult of a task, and the conversion of investment into output is relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one-1&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I absorbed the memories of the Age of Empires era. During university, encountering a laptop was like opening Pandora’s Box – I discovered games and connected with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, sourcing goods upstream and selling them through my own community channels to earn a little money. Later, I gradually understood the operational logic of the entire chain. The products we sold were merely mass-produced by upstream programs, and their costs approached zero. At this time, the road had already started to slant a bit. Within the field, there were increasingly specialized sub-disciplines: on the left was power grids, and on the right was automation (very complex – chip programming, factory electrical automation). I understood that programs could make money, but it wasn’t a huge sum; the upstream channels definitely made a lot of money. Adding to this, having a foundation in programming, I started experimenting with various things, making a little money here and there. When the time came for specialization, I naturally chose automation. After completing most of my senior-level courses, many of which I didn’t attend, I was constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s article mentioned a fascination with hackers that led me to programming – non-academic IT professionals, driven by benevolence, developed assembly language, penetration testing, game cheats, DLL hijacking, and phishing software; they became familiar with and understood various blackware and grayware. My parents taught me how to be a good person, and the law ultimately dissuaded me. The road hadn’t completely gone astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous Post Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/&#34; &gt;That Time When I Was Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a brief relationship during university. Looking back, it was more about yearning for the romance depicted in television dramas. As an immature young man at the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand how to love someone, let alone achieve: settling down and starting a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amidst the torrent of times, I was fortunate – university’s tribulations led me to a direct entry into employment rather than graduate school. Upon graduation, I joined the workforce and benefited from the IT boom, enjoying a smooth career progression. It&amp;rsquo;s now my eighth year in this profession, but the hype surrounding the industry has faded, leading to its decline. Sometimes, I question whether my initial choice was correct; perhaps following my father’s advice and joining the power grid would have been a better path. If these doubts were prevalent during the first five years of my career, they gradually dissipated with time. As a graduate trainee at HSBC, I remained for five years without changing companies – this has resulted in certain gaps in my understanding of technology, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following the arrangement of the headquarters in Hangzhou, I went to the Shenzhen branch, experiencing a workplace struggle (after clarifying the situation, both sides lost out, and the board of directors ultimately won), returning to Hangzhou with a passion for technology, carrying a touch of youthful naiveté, having run off to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle down in Hangzhou, purchase property, and register, at the highest interest rates and peak housing prices, it was intended to be a trap – my finances were too weak to cope, and if I were burdened with mortgage payments while facing an industry downturn, my emotions would easily become unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having been around for so many years, having seen so much, I’ve made my own mistakes and indulged in foolishness. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. Through experiences and encounters with people, one inevitably grows and matures. If I were to remain at home all the time, I don’t know what form my flaws would manifest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Revenue Generation Business Model: Raffle/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Live streamers sending iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three seemingly unrelated items are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic – a bit like a financial game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-lottery-for-gifts&#34;&gt;Platform Lottery for Gifts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset their acquisition of platform currency and purchase gifts to send to the host, &amp;ldquo;Xin Yi&amp;rdquo; (Hearty), with each platform having another gameplay mechanic. After users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but instead spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery activities, obtaining limited high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the online lottery is simply understood as the platform opening a casino. With enough participants, it’s guaranteed not to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;屌丝&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (literally &amp;ldquo;loser,&amp;rdquo; often used humorously to describe ordinary or unsuccessful individuals) users, fueled by a desire to gamble and win big, hoping to hit a jackpot and then send gifts – gaining face and acting as a “big brother!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-stream-gifts-physical-items&#34;&gt;Live Stream Gifts (Physical Items)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lottery mentioned in the preceding text targets users’ own writing. Each month, the hosts have water flow tasks and popularity tasks. The gameplay of opening gift giveaways allows fans to send designated gifts or gifts of a specified amount, giving them the opportunity to participate in the lottery. The prizes may include high-end phones or cash red envelopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular live streamers, this activity is very profitable, essentially equivalent to temporary zero-cost purchases. If enough people participate, the streamer also makes money. This tests the streamer’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also a gameplay where the rewards are very high (cash value), and many outdoor streamers engage in this type of scheme, which is essentially online gambling. The content of the livestream doesn’t matter; users only care about whether they can win. Excluding live streaming hosts of stage performance types, through PK (peer-versus-peer) modes, inducing fans to consume and recharge, ordinary game streamers are difficult to drive player spending sentiment. Playing games and watching live streams are primarily for entertainment and don’t necessarily lead to additional financial expenditure, especially &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. Lottery-style mechanisms can cultivate users&amp;rsquo; recharging habits, consumption habits, and occasionally even impulsive purchases (giving away a lot, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini Program Ranking Rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini program that incorporates some useless workflows or provides partial game-related auxiliary services. The previous items are all cover stories, designed to pass Tencent’s review by adding a ranking mechanism to the mini program&amp;rsquo;s gameplay – users earn points by browsing incentives and completing tasks, and the backend sets rankings based on these points, with higher-ranked users receiving designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Logic: Advertising Revenue &amp;gt; Operating Costs + Reward Expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mini program can also operate normally by providing reasonable services and earning revenue through appropriate advertising; even if the income is not substantial, it’s a steady trickle and acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Back then, as a young boy, he might have had talent, but it wasn’t common.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s my seventh year in the job, and I’m not getting as much positive feedback on the code I write. Let me reflect on how I ended up on this &lt;code&gt;coding&lt;/code&gt; path. People’s choices, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re younger, tend to follow positive reinforcement more closely – actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city and coming into contact with computer books? Hacker’s resources? Meeting Windows systems – these are all anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time should be positioned around childhood and sneaking around with my cousin to play games on our parents&amp;rsquo; computer.&lt;/strong&gt; My cousin and I ran a shop with our uncle at the computer store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started having exposure to computers relatively early, and basic understanding was established. Later, in school, taking the microcomputer course also sparked an interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In middle school, I heard about computer competitions, which seemed really cool, but after transferring schools, this fell by the wayside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my junior high years, I was familiar with basic computer operations, and I could easily stand out during microcomputer classes. If you’re still familiar, yes, you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, it wasn’t proficiency – familiarity with office software was even more impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-moving--relocation&#34;&gt;II. Moving / Relocation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the moving situation. When we moved to the city center, due to the neighbors, we came into contact with the library. Although we read quite a few novels, we also read a lot of magazines, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;大众软件&lt;/em&gt; (Greatest Software)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to an increasing interest in computers as a product. The childhood fascination with hackers was actively pursued at school, and basic operating system knowledge was learned: control panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt; is suitable for beginners; each time it presents information in the form of case studies, explaining how to operate the system.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greatest Software&lt;/em&gt; recommends various software, industry news, &lt;strong&gt;and of course, game news – this was the initial motivation and also planted the seed for gaming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, &lt;strong&gt;Bo Ge transferred to our class, and his predecessors had been secured through computer competitions for two years prior&lt;/strong&gt;, the school leaders also paid a lot of attention to this competition.
There was also a pre-existing hardware foundation – an alumnus from America donated a building to the school, which resulted in a new library and a new computer lab; it all seemed so coincidental.
Plus Bo Ge’s popular science lectures, that period was considered the computer guru of the class.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scholar + computer master, knew how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable classroom surveillance software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school-1&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The competitions were a bit bumpy and ultimately reached the finals, where I didn’t understand much and the questions were mostly basic algorithms. However, it was still worthwhile, like taking a short trip – ultimately, it was just half a bucket of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-university-arrived--university-major-selection&#34;&gt;Four. University Arrived – University Major Selection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After arriving at university, I chose automation based on my parents’ recommendation. In reality, I was interested in power electronics, intending to join the local power supply bureau upon graduation. I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn much of the professional curriculum, and my self-driven learning ability was practically non-existent within the specialized courses. However, I found computer courses within the broader curriculum very easy to grasp. I’d skip classes in the specialized subjects, diligently studying computer courses while spending my days on forums: “JingYi Forum” and “I Love Crack.” Combining what I learned from those courses with a bit of assembly and C++ knowledge, &lt;strong&gt;I started taking orders from the forums and making money, receiving increasingly positive feedback, and gradually became more and more deeply involved.&lt;/strong&gt; It was impossible to pull me back. Ultimately, I chose a minor specialization – writing code for chips – and my family didn’t pay much attention to it either, letting me choose on my own. At this point, &lt;strong&gt;the third key figure: my cousin&lt;/strong&gt;, had a high education and worked at Baidu. My “old lady” (mother-in-law) understood me, knowing that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been focused on research since childhood, so she encouraged me to talk to my cousin about it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five. Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a key point I know – I learned how to bypass firewalls, took elective courses in Computer Information Retrieval, and quickly found and located information and problems. A valuable colleague, &lt;strong&gt;Mr. [硕哥&amp;rsquo;s nickname]&lt;/strong&gt;, appeared at work, gave me time to learn independently, troubleshoot issues down to their roots, and introduced me to the leaders of the R&amp;amp;D center.
These experiences laid the groundwork; in Shenzhen, everyone outside viewed me as exceptionally skilled and successful in leading the transaction channel group.
However, there’s a problem: I lacked systematic learning in computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design. My knowledge was based solely on my past experience. This led to frequent self-doubt regarding my code designs, a lack of guidelines for module design, and ultimately, exhaustion after seven years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Onomatopoeia of the Night</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is utterly unique – not a single homophone exists. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person’s life is only once, irreplaceable, and cannot be repeated or relived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with an overwhelming number of monthly votes, far surpassing the second-place book by a vast margin – truly beyond reach. For many years, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Ergen. This time, I decided to try a new author’s work and experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed two million monthly votes, while the second book only garnered eight hundred thousand – the significant disparity was astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize my knowledge is limited and that I lack the ability to critically evaluate the book&amp;rsquo;s writing style. However, after reading through over a dozen chapters, the book’s plot is tightly paced and intricately linked, captivating readers and earning such high monthly votes – it&amp;rsquo;s truly well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like the character “ming” (life/fate), the character “si” (death) also doesn’t have any homophones in Chinese characters; does this perhaps also contain a similarly unique and irreplaceable depth of meaning regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, but also a bipedal animal, complete with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everyday sensibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is far above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you think about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you think about earning one billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but what you don’t see is the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are becoming more aware. If they could really earn money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling. It felt surprisingly engaging, to the point where you’d start to find it interesting yourself. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone who also works in the IT industry, this made me feel like the algorithm overlords were having a bit of a problem – you know, recommending things in this way. They’d constantly find new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they were trying to figure out whether I was stupid or they were. The question is, how long can this business model last? How much time can you drain from people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, just quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet down and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must always come up with something, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lost/Confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, at some stage in life, people find themselves lost in a haze of uncertainty, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose their pursuit of meaning and purpose. Looking back to when I first graduated, my heart was full of fervent aspirations – I wouldn’t hesitate to say that I longed to write code, to create brilliant, eye-catching software. However, as I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for so long, I’ve had more exposure to business-level affairs, which has largely benefited from the advantages brought about by industry development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my life philosophy, I haven’t yet incorporated things like marriage and having children, or establishing a family, into my thinking. My mind is almost empty, simply focused on enjoying the present moment. Whenever weekends arrive, I enjoy quietly playing games, often spending an entire day at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-house&#34;&gt;Buying a House
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was full of enthusiasm and planned to save diligently to buy my own property. I meticulously budgeted every day towards this goal. However, as house prices continued to rise, I transitioned from initial anxiety and disappointment to eventually becoming numb, gradually feeling that even if I bought a house, it would simply be a heavy burden on my shoulders, so I ultimately abandoned the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saving-money&#34;&gt;Saving Money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving some small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, purchasing a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. However, now I approach saving with a more relaxed and “chill” attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses – I indulge in things I want to eat and boldly try new and exciting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;returning-home&#34;&gt;Returning Home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I most longed for deep down was simply to go home. There wasn’t anything particularly to do, just returning to that familiar place, feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
