<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Spring Festival Season on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/spring-festival-season/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Spring Festival Season on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/spring-festival-season/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Nezha breaks out during Spring Festival season</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, we always gather as a family during the Spring Festival and watching movies has become an essential form of entertainment. This year&amp;rsquo;s Spring Festival season, &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; was incredibly popular, sparking discussions everywhere. The buzz is quite similar to that of &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; both films exuding a patriotic theme, which unexpectedly stirs up a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpected success of &amp;ldquo;Nezha&amp;rdquo; during the Spring Festival season, a surge of inexplicable national pride, reminiscent of previous films like &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; with patriotic themes. While acknowledging significant progress, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as it’s being made out to be. As a gamer, many aspects feel greasy. The fight scenes are heavily influenced by online games. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen numerous posts about people buying tickets for Nezha but not actually going to see the movie due to its box office performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fight-scenes-lack-texture&#34;&gt;The fight scenes lack texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a gamer, and I usually spend my days immersed in various online game worlds, so I didn’t have high expectations for movies. But I couldn’t resist the hype around 《Moana》, everyone was talking about it, so I thought, why not take a look? When I walked into the theater and the visuals came on, I felt a “thud” in my heart. Although the production quality has improved considerably compared to before, some of the scenes looked quite greasy. And the fight scenes? They were too heavily influenced by online games. Having played games for so many years, this visual style is too similar to some game scenes, lacking the texture that a movie should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-movie-fans&#34;&gt;Crazy movie fans
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie, I came out and saw that quite a few people online said they bought tickets for &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually watch it, all to boost its box office. I’m truly impressed by this move; it seems everyone is incredibly enthusiastic about this film and willing to do anything for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think back to when &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; came out, when Wu Jing shouted, “Whoever dares offend China will be punished no matter how far away they are,” so many people were filled with excitement, feeling that our Chinese military was so powerful and our country so strong. Although &amp;ldquo;The Devil’s Bond&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t have such direct patriotic slogans, it vividly showcases the essence of traditional Chinese culture. Nezha and Ao Bing, these mythological figures, we grew up listening to their stories, and the film portrays their grievances, love-hate relationships, and growth process with depth and emotion – isn’t that the charm of Chinese culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Nezha. Misunderstood and looked down upon since he was a child, yet he refused to give up, shouting &amp;ldquo;My fate is my own, not the heavens’.&amp;rdquo; This spirit is so much like the resilience ingrained in our Chinese people. No matter how great the difficulties we face, we won&amp;rsquo;t bow down, but rely on our own efforts to change our destiny. Ao Bing also exemplifies this – burdened with a family mission, seemingly cold but actually kind-hearted, willing to sacrifice himself for his friends. We often see such friendship and responsibility in real life, don’t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-progress-of-animated-films&#34;&gt;The progress of animated films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect in some aspects, it combines traditional Chinese culture with modern film technology quite well, allowing us to see the progress of Chinese animated films. Just like how &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; showed everyone China’s breakthrough in the action genre. This kind of progress makes us feel that Chinese cinema can shine on the international stage and allow foreigners to appreciate the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, no matter where we go, we carry our country and culture in our hearts. Movies like &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; are like keys, opening the door to a sense of national pride deep within us. They allow us to feel the strength of our nation and the charm of our culture amidst laughter and joy, also inspiring us to work hard in our respective positions and contribute our share to the prosperity and development of our country. This is probably why these films have become so popular and resonate with a sense of national pride. In the future, I hope there will be more movies like this, keeping this feeling of national pride full and overflowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Mystery of Spring Festival Movie Ticket Prices: Differences Between Online and Offline Sales</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight people wanted to go see a movie. We initially planned to buy tickets on Taopihao and Maoyan, but saw the price was 60 yuan. Luckily, we had a cinema recharge card that required purchasing tickets at the front desk in person. Thinking to ask if there were any discounts, we were surprised to find that the same showing only cost 35 yuan when bought at the front desk – quite a difference in price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hidden-markups-on-platform-service-fees&#34;&gt;Hidden markups on platform service fees
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While online ticketing platforms offer convenience, their service fees are not insignificant. They create a user-friendly ticket purchasing experience, such as precise seat selection and the ability to view purchase history at any time, all of which require financial investment for maintenance. These costs are added to the ticket price in the form of platform service fees, resulting in higher online ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinema-differentiation-operating-strategy&#34;&gt;Cinema Differentiation Operating Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demand for moviegoing during the Spring Festival season is surging, and theaters are using tiered pricing to maximize profits. Online platforms have high traffic, and many people are accustomed to buying tickets in advance online, so theaters set higher prices for those tickets; however, they offer lower prices to attract walk-in customers who purchase tickets directly at the front desk.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pricing-logic-behind-profit-sharing-cooperation&#34;&gt;The pricing logic behind profit sharing cooperation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The split of revenue between online platforms and cinemas affects ticket prices. Online platforms need to take a share from the box office, so they raise ticket prices to ensure profitability. Cinema counters sell tickets directly without any intermediary links, reducing costs, and naturally offering more affordable prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-consumers-buying-tickets&#34;&gt;Tips for Consumers Buying Tickets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just focus on online platforms when buying tickets in the future. Try calling the cinema front desk to ask about prices, or go directly to the front desk for inquiries – you might be surprised. If you’re a frequent moviegoer, getting a cinema membership card and enjoying member benefits can save you quite a bit of money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Analysis of Political Elements in 2025 Spring Festival Films</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:49:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I went to enjoy the atmosphere during the Spring Festival season, and this time I watched two movies, feeling it was somewhat different&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the new developments in the 2025 Spring Festival movie season, focusing on &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;The Guardian of the Galaxy: The Magic Child.&amp;rdquo; The former uses the backdrop of San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown in 1900 to depict the discrimination and oppression faced by Chinese people, reflecting the social and political environment. The latter, as an animated film, employs rich metaphorical elements to satirize the current international political landscape, such as the Yuxu Palace resembling the Pentagon, alluding to the American political system; dollar signs on the Tianyuan Ding symbolizing US dollar hegemony; the Immortal Jade Tablet akin to a green card suggesting hierarchical status; and the Soul-Destroying Pill similar to biological weapons hinting at malicious actions. Both films bring a new viewing experience and prompt reflection on the relationship between film art and political expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovation-in-the-style-of-spring-festival-season-films&#34;&gt;Innovation in the style of Spring Festival season films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, films released during the Spring Festival season have been lighthearted and family-friendly, aiming to help audiences relax and unwind during the holiday. However, the 2025 Spring Festival season broke with convention as &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha: Ayakoya&amp;rdquo; incorporated rich political elements, sparking widespread discussion among viewers and ushering in a new era for Spring Festival films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vivid-reflection-of-the-eras-politics&#34;&gt;A Vivid Reflection of the Era&amp;rsquo;s Politics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;《Mystery of Tangram》is set in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown in 1900, a time when Chinese people overseas faced severe racial discrimination and oppression. As the protagonists investigate the case, they must not only solve the mystery but also confront discrimination and unfair treatment from all sides of society. The film’s portrayal of racial discrimination and power struggles realistically reflects the social and political environment of the time, allowing us to see the arduous struggle that Chinese immigrants made for survival and dignity during that turbulent era. The underlying political issues are worthy of in-depth reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such historical background inevitably brings to mind the current difficulties faced by overseas Chinese in the business sector, such as the TikTok and Zhou Shuzhong incident&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 6, 2024, local time, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit rejected TikTok’s request and upheld the constitutionality of a law mandating its sale on national security grounds. In a memo to employees, TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew wrote that the next step will be “to seek an injunction and await review by the U.S. Supreme Court.” The event originated from the passage of the &amp;ldquo;Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversary Controlled Applications Act&amp;rdquo; in the United States, which stipulates that ByteDance must divest its U.S. TikTok business within 270 days of the bill&amp;rsquo;s passage, with a final deadline for the forced sale of January 19, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Shou Zi Chew also faced numerous challenges at various hearings. On January 31, 2024, local time, the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee held a hearing on &amp;ldquo;Big Tech and the Online Child Sexual Exploitation Crisis.&amp;rdquo; Prominent anti-China lawmaker Tom Cotton questioned Shou Zi Chew with a series of 8 questions about nationality, including asking his country of origin, whether he had applied for Chinese or American citizenship, and even questioning the nationalities of his wife and children. Although the hearing&amp;rsquo;s theme was &amp;ldquo;online child sexual exploitation,&amp;rdquo; the senator shifted the topic to TikTok being owned by the Chinese company ByteDance, forcing Shou Zi Chew to answer questions unrelated to the subject matter. Just like the discrimination faced by Chinese people overseas in &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900,&amp;rdquo; Shou Zi Chew is experiencing unfair treatment and questioning due to TikTok&amp;rsquo;s background in the business realm. This series of events reflects that overseas Chinese have always faced numerous obstacles from external forces when pursuing their own development and protecting their rights, whether it was racial discrimination a century ago or today’s political manipulation in commerce—all of which deserve our deep reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-analysis-of-the-political-metaphor-behind-ne-zha-the-demon-child&#34;&gt;An Analysis of the Political Metaphor Behind &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha: The Demon Child&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ne Zha&amp;rsquo;s Revenge, while appearing to be an ordinary animated film, is filled with political metaphors in its various settings and plot points&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mapping of the Power System&lt;/strong&gt;: The Biying Palace is portrayed as the supreme power center of the realm of immortals, with an architectural style similar to the Pentagon in the United States. Its interior is predominantly white, symbolizing Western hegemonic powers pushing their agenda under the guise of &amp;ldquo;universal values.&amp;rdquo; The “Demon Extermination Squad” led by Wuliang Immortal, and its subordinates, Lunu and He Nü, are believed to correspond to the US alliance system, specifically Japan and South Korea. The “online meeting” scene in Biying Palace, where the Twelve Golden Immortals sit and discuss the &amp;ldquo;War of the Conferred Gods,&amp;rdquo; is likened to NATO meetings led by the United States, which suppress other countries under the banner of &amp;ldquo;maintaining order.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The suggestion of economic hegemony: The Tianyuan Cauldron, used for alchemy in Yuxu Palace, has a dollar sign at the entrance, metaphorically representing how the United States &amp;ldquo;alchemizes&amp;rdquo; resources from other countries through economic hegemony. In the film, Wuliang Xianweng throws the dragon clan into the cauldron to be refined under the guise of “acting on behalf of heaven,” similar to how certain countries seek benefits by exploiting &amp;ldquo;international rules.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The metaphor of identity and hierarchy: The jade pendant representing the divine status that Nezha receives is highly similar to a US green card in color and design, symbolizing the exclusion and hierarchical division of immortals towards &amp;ldquo;outsiders,&amp;rdquo; hinting at the differences in identity and unequal treatment between different countries and groups in reality&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The allusion to malicious acts: The Oblivion Pill forced on Nezha by the Immortal Wonderman, resembling a bioweapon, subtly mocks certain countries that, under the guise of &amp;ldquo;saving the world,&amp;rdquo; engage in destruction and ruin of other nations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbol of Resources and Development&lt;/strong&gt;: As a key element in reshaping the bodies of Nezha and Ao Bing, Qise Baolian (Seven-Colored Lotus) symbolizes the energy and technological lifelines monopolized by powerful nations. The acquisition of its “essence and elixir” requires passing the “immortality examination” of Yuxu Palace, reflecting the dependence of developing countries on core resources and the &amp;ldquo;rule-based predation&amp;rdquo; they face under a hegemonic system. The lotus’s temporary failure and recovery conditions allude to the survival challenges faced by small nations amidst energy crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-deep-reflection-on-film-art-and-political-expression&#34;&gt;A deep reflection on film art and political expression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two films incorporated political elements into the nationwide movie-going frenzy during the Spring Festival season, bringing audiences a new viewing experience. They are no longer just purely entertaining works but more like mirrors reflecting political issues in history and reality. This has sparked deep reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression. Will directors increasingly convey their views on society and politics through film in future creations? Can cinema, as a powerful cultural medium, take on greater attention to and contemplation of social realities while maintaining artistic expression? These questions are worth exploring when appreciating films, and we also look forward to the film industry bringing more exciting integration of art and reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Doutao large language model isn&amp;rsquo;t very reliable today; it froze several times, and the article got stuck halfway through without allowing me to continue. I had to start a new session.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
