<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Spring-Festival-Season on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/spring-festival-season/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Spring-Festival-Season on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/spring-festival-season/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Nezha breaks out during Spring Festival season</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For Chinese people, watching movies has become an essential entertainment during the Spring Festival season when families reunite. This year&amp;rsquo;s Spring Festival film releases were dominated by &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha,&amp;rdquo; which was incredibly popular and sparked widespread discussion. The buzz surrounding it is reminiscent of “Wolf Warrior,” both films carrying a strong patriotic theme that evokes a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpected success of &amp;ldquo;Nezha&amp;rdquo; during the Spring Festival season, sparking a sense of national pride reminiscent of films like &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; demonstrates a patriotic theme. While acknowledging significant progress, the film isn&amp;rsquo;t quite as impressive as some claim. As a gamer, I find many aspects feel overly slick and the fight scenes lean heavily towards an MMO style. Numerous reports indicate people buying tickets to see it but ultimately not going due to its performance pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fight-scenes-lack-texture&#34;&gt;The fight scenes lack texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a gamer, I usually spend my days immersed in online games and didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for movies. But the buzz around &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; was undeniable; everyone was talking about it, so I figured I’d check it out. Once I entered the theater and saw the visuals, I felt a jolt. While the production quality has improved considerably, some scenes looked a bit greasy. And the fight sequences? They were too heavily influenced by online game aesthetics. Having played games for so long, this visual style is too similar to certain in-game environments, lacking the texture one expects from a film.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-movie-fans&#34;&gt;Crazy movie fans
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After seeing the movie, I checked online and saw that quite a few people bought tickets for &amp;ldquo;The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Child&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually watch it, all to boost its box office. That’s impressive dedication – clearly, there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of enthusiasm for this film, and everyone wants to do something to support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s recall &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; when Wu Jing shouted, “Whoever dares offend China will be punished no matter how far away they are,” many people were thrilled and felt that our Chinese military was so powerful, and our country so strong. While &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; doesn’t have such direct patriotic slogans, it vividly showcases traditional Chinese culture. We grew up listening to the stories of mythological figures like Nezha and Ao Bing; the film portrays their conflicts, love, and growth with depth and emotion – isn&amp;rsquo;t that the charm of Chinese culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Nezha. Misunderstood and looked down upon since childhood, yet he refused to give in, declaring &amp;ldquo;My fate is my own, not the heavens&amp;rsquo;.&amp;rdquo; That spirit is so much like the resilience ingrained in us Chinese people. No matter how great the difficulty, we don’t back down, but strive to change our destiny through effort. Ao Bing also exemplifies this – burdened by a family mission, seemingly cold but truly kind-hearted, willing to sacrifice himself for his friends. We often see such friendship and responsibility in real life, don&amp;rsquo;t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advancement-of-animated-films&#34;&gt;Advancement of animated films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;The Devils Who Laugh&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect, it effectively combines traditional Chinese culture with modern film technology, showcasing the progress of Chinese animation. Just as &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; demonstrated a breakthrough for Chinese cinema in action films, this kind of advancement gives us hope that Chinese movies can shine on the international stage and allow foreigners to appreciate the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, wherever we go, we carry our nation and culture in our hearts. Films like &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; are like keys, unlocking a sense of national pride deep within us. They allow us to experience the strength of our country and the charm of our culture amidst laughter and joy, inspiring us to work hard in our respective fields and contribute to the prosperity and development of our nation. This is likely why these films have become so popular and resonate with such strong feelings of national pride. We hope for more films like this in the future, to keep this sense of pride brimming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Mystery of Spring Festival Movie Ticket Prices: Differences Between Online and Offline Sales</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spring-festival-movie-tickets-price-mystery-online-vs-offline/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight wanted to see a movie. We planned to buy tickets on Taopihao and Maoyan, but saw the price was 60 yuan. Luckily, we had a cinema recharge card that required purchasing tickets at the front desk in person. Thinking to ask about any discounts, we were surprised to find the same showing only cost 35 yuan there – quite a difference!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hidden-platform-fees&#34;&gt;Hidden platform fees
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While online ticketing platforms offer convenience, their service fees are significant. They invest in user-friendly features like seat selection and purchase history tracking, which require funding. These costs are passed on to the customer through service fees, resulting in higher ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinema-differentiation-strategies&#34;&gt;Cinema Differentiation Strategies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Demand for movie tickets during the Spring Festival is surging, and theaters are using tiered pricing to maximize profits. Online platforms have high traffic, so many people buy tickets in advance online, resulting in higher prices for those tickets. Meanwhile, walk-in customers buying at the front desk receive lower prices to attract them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-pricing-logic-behind-profit-sharing&#34;&gt;The pricing logic behind profit sharing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Online platforms and cinemas cooperate through revenue-sharing models that affect ticket prices. To ensure profitability, platforms take a percentage of the box office, leading to higher ticket costs. Cinema counters, without intermediary fees, offer more affordable tickets due to lower costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips-for-buying-tickets&#34;&gt;Tips for Buying Tickets
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t just look at online platforms when buying tickets. Try calling the cinema directly or visiting the front desk – you might find a surprise. If you’re a frequent moviegoer, consider getting a membership card to enjoy member discounts and save money.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>An Analysis of Political Elements in 2025 Spring Festival Films</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:49:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I went out during Spring Festival season, but this time I saw two movies and had a different feeling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the new trends in the 2025 Spring Festival film season, focusing on &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;New Deity: The Magchild Incites the Sea.&amp;rdquo; The former uses the backdrop of San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown in 1900 to depict the discrimination and oppression faced by Chinese people, reflecting the social and political environment. The latter, as an animated film, employs rich metaphorical elements to satirize the current international political landscape—for example, Jade Pure Palace resembling the Pentagon alluding to the American political system, dollar signs on the Tianyuan Cauldron symbolizing US dollar hegemony, the Immortal Jade Tablet mirroring the green card suggesting hierarchical status, and the Soul-Destroying Pill akin to biological weapons hinting at malicious actions. Both films offer a new viewing experience and prompt reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovation-in-spring-festival-film-styles&#34;&gt;Innovation in Spring Festival film styles
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditionally, Spring Festival films have been lighthearted and family-friendly, aiming to help audiences relax during the holiday season and rarely addressing sensitive political topics. However, this year&amp;rsquo;s 2025 Spring Festival lineup breaks with convention; &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;New God of War: Nezha Revolution&amp;rdquo; incorporate rich political elements, sparking widespread discussion among viewers and ushering in a new era for Spring Festival films.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-vivid-reflection-of-the-eras-politics&#34;&gt;A Vivid Reflection of the Era&amp;rsquo;s Politics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Lost Tiger&amp;rdquo; is set in 1900 San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown, a time when Chinese immigrants faced severe racial discrimination and oppression. As the protagonists investigate a case, they must navigate not only the mystery but also societal prejudice and unfair treatment. The film’s portrayal of racism and power struggles realistically reflects the social and political climate of the era, revealing the arduous struggle for survival and dignity undertaken by Chinese immigrants during that turbulent time—a situation with underlying political issues worthy of deeper consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This historical context inevitably brings to mind the current challenges faced by overseas Chinese in the business world, such as the TikTok and Zhou Shuzhong incident&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 6, 2024, local time, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit rejected TikTok&amp;rsquo;s request, upholding the constitutionality of a law requiring its sale on national security grounds. TikTok CEO Shou Zi Chew wrote in a memo to employees that the next step will be &amp;ldquo;seeking an injunction and awaiting review by the U.S. Supreme Court.&amp;rdquo; The event stems from the “Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversary Controlled Applications” law, which mandates that ByteDance divest its U.S. TikTok operations within 270 days of the bill&amp;rsquo;s passage, with a final sale deadline of January 19, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously, Shou Zi Chew faced numerous challenges at various hearings. On January 31, 2024, during a Senate Judiciary Committee hearing on &amp;ldquo;Big Tech and the Online Child Sexual Exploitation Crisis,&amp;rdquo; prominent anti-China lawmaker Tom Cotton repeatedly questioned him with 8 nationality-related inquiries, including his own citizenship, whether he had applied for Chinese or American citizenship, and even the nationalities of his wife and children. Despite the hearing&amp;rsquo;s focus being on online child sexual exploitation, the senator shifted the topic to TikTok’s ownership by the Chinese company ByteDance, forcing Chew to answer questions unrelated to the theme. Similar to the unwarranted discrimination faced by Chinese in &amp;ldquo;Detective Chinatown 1900,&amp;rdquo; Shou Zi Chew is experiencing unfair treatment and scrutiny in the business world due to TikTok&amp;rsquo;s background. These events reflect that overseas Chinese have consistently encountered significant external obstacles when pursuing their own development and protecting their rights across different eras. Whether it was racial discrimination a century ago or today’s political maneuvering in commerce, these situations warrant deep reflection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-analysis-of-the-political-metaphors-behind-ne-zha-the-demon-child&#34;&gt;An Analysis of the Political Metaphors Behind &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha: The Demon Child&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While appearing as an ordinary animated film, &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha: The Demon Child&amp;rdquo; is rich with political allegories in its settings and plot&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Jade Void Palace is portrayed as the supreme power center of the realm, with an architectural style similar to the Pentagon, predominantly white in color, symbolizing Western powers using &amp;ldquo;universal values&amp;rdquo; as a pretext for hegemony. The “Demon Eradication Team,” led by the Limitless Immortal Elder, and its subordinates, Lù Nán and Hè Nǚ, are seen as corresponding to the US alliance system involving Japan and South Korea. The Jade Void Palace’s “online meeting” scene, with the Twelve Golden Immortals discussing the &amp;ldquo;War of the Conferred Gods,&amp;rdquo; mirrors a NATO summit led by the United States, ostensibly maintaining order while suppressing other nations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Tianyuan Cauldron, used for alchemy in Yuxu Palace, features dollar signs at its entrance, symbolizing how the United States &amp;ldquo;alchemizes&amp;rdquo; resources from other nations through economic hegemony. In the film, Wuliang Xianweng throws the dragon clan into the cauldron under the guise of “acting on behalf of heaven,” mirroring certain countries exploiting others by leveraging &amp;ldquo;international rules.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nezha&amp;rsquo;s immortal identity jade pendant, with its color and design resembling the U.S. green card, symbolizes the celestial realm’s exclusion and stratification of “outsiders,” hinting at the identity differences and unequal treatment between different countries and groups in reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The forced consumption of the Soul-Destroying Pill by Nezha, compelled by the Immortal Wonderman, resembles a bioweapon and satirizes certain nations that, under the guise of &amp;ldquo;saving the world,&amp;rdquo; engage in destruction and devastation abroad&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Seven-Colored Treasure Lotus, crucial for reshaping the bodies of Nezha and Ao Bing, symbolizes energy and technology lifelines monopolized by powerful nations. Obtaining its “essence” requires passing the Yu Xu Palace’s “immortality exam,” reflecting developing countries&amp;rsquo; dependence on core resources and exploitation within a hegemonic system. The lotus’s temporary failure and recovery conditions allude to small nations’ survival challenges amidst energy crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-deep-reflection-on-film-art-and-political-expression&#34;&gt;A Deep Reflection on Film Art and Political Expression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These films, integrated with political elements during the nationwide Chinese New Year moviegoing boom, offer audiences a new viewing experience—no longer just entertainment, but more like a mirror reflecting political issues within history and reality. This prompts deeper reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression. Will directors increasingly convey their views on society and politics through film? Can cinema, as a powerful cultural medium, balance artistic expression with greater attention to and contemplation of social realities? These questions warrant thorough exploration while enjoying films, and we look forward to more exciting developments from the film industry in fusing art and reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Doutou large language model wasn&amp;rsquo;t very reliable today – it froze several times, got stuck halfway through an article, and I had to start a new session&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
