<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Logitech on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/logitech/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Logitech on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/logitech/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Installing Win11 Logitech G431 Headset Drivers</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/win11-logitech-g431-headphone-driver-installation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 07:20:17 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/win11-logitech-g431-headphone-driver-installation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Picking up where we left off, I came back to find an update for Ghub. It was a little exciting that the customer service issue of not being able to load properly seemed to be resolved. However, after a lot of troubleshooting – reinstalling and uninstalling – it still doesn&amp;rsquo;t work correctly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I contacted customer service for a solution, but was told an engineer could provide remote assistance. Unfortunately, their working hours are the same as mine, so I had to give up. Now I&amp;rsquo;m reviewing previous troubleshooting records and preparing to manually install the driver.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;get-the-driver-installation-package&#34;&gt;Get the driver installation package
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;How can I obtain the driver files since Logitech doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide standalone driver installation packages?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the system image installation package left over from the previous system reinstall, we can reinstall the system in a local virtual machine. In a clean environment, deploy Ghub separately, integrate the headset device into the virtual machine, locate the driver path, and copy it out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Related paths:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C:\ProgramData\LGHUB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C:\Windows\System32\DriverStore\FileRepository\logi_audio.inf_amd64_010b035044e24be4&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;device-manager&#34;&gt;Device Manager
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key is how to find the second path. Let&amp;rsquo;s briefly review how to manually manage driver files in Windows 11. This area covers two system-provided drivers and one from Logitech.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second driver in the image is from Logitech. We analyze the current device drivers, searching all driver paths within the virtual machine. First, you need to find files starting with &amp;ldquo;logi,&amp;rdquo; then compare them. You&amp;rsquo;ll be able to locate the driver file; copy the entire folder and you’ll have the installation package.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-driver&#34;&gt;Install driver
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While still in Device Manager, click &amp;ldquo;Update Driver,&amp;rdquo; then &amp;ldquo;Browse my computer for drivers.&amp;rdquo; This will take you to the following screen:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you open it, you&amp;rsquo;ll only see one drive – a standard USB drive. Choose &amp;ldquo;Install from disk&amp;rdquo; and select the folder we copied earlier. After installation, a Logitech-specific driver will appear in the dropdown list; switch the device driver to this newly installed one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anatomy-equipment-drivers&#34;&gt;Anatomy equipment drivers
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The drivers for this device are provided by the system. You only need to check if there&amp;rsquo;s an exclamation mark next to the driver; if so, enter the driver selection interface and switch to a different type of driver before switching back to restore normal functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;completed&#34;&gt;Completed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The headphone microphone volume is back to normal, and the familiar ear monitoring function has returned&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Logitech headset driver installation failed</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/logitech-headset-driver-installation-failed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 21:46:12 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/logitech-headset-driver-installation-failed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If you didn&amp;rsquo;t understand these things, you wouldn&amp;rsquo;t waste hours troubleshooting; you would contact customer service immediately&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/logitech-headset-driver-installation-failed/20240531220709.png&#34;
	width=&#34;693&#34;
	height=&#34;489&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;GHUB&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;141&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;340px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the C drive on my home desktop computer ran out of space. I allocated a 256GB SSD for it, but have been having issues with it frequently. Since moving to Shanghai, I&amp;rsquo;ve been busy with various matters, and finally found time last week to reinstall the operating system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The system reinstall went smoothly, and installing everyday software and setting up the development environment presented no issues. A few days later, intending to relax with some games, I realized the drivers for my mouse and headset weren&amp;rsquo;t installed yet. Both devices are Logitech, so I downloaded GHUB, which automatically recognized the hardware and installed the drivers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, an unexpected issue occurred. The mouse driver installed smoothly, but the headset driver continuously displayed &amp;ldquo;Loading.&amp;rdquo; I suspect incompatibility between the latest version of Windows 11 and Logitech&amp;rsquo;s drivers caused the installation failure. I then began searching for information and attempting to manually install the driver, but the problem persisted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the translation: Simply put, what is the function of each device’s driver?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The mouse driver mainly adjusts functions like movement speed. I rarely use macros; restoring previously saved parameters is sufficient.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The driver primarily functions for headphone monitoring, which is very useful during team voice communication as it allows me to hear my own voice. While the system&amp;rsquo;s microphone settings offer a similar feature, the driver implementation works better.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite repeated attempts, the headphones&amp;rsquo; drivers consistently failed to load. Today, I finally thought to contact customer service for assistance and see if there was a solution. Customer service informed me that their servers have recently been experiencing issues, causing abnormal driver downloads. They are working on resolving this issue and advised me to wait until the next update when the problem should be fixed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the headphone driver issue hasn&amp;rsquo;t been resolved yet, we at least know the cause, and hope it can be fixed soon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mouse-driver-settings&#34;&gt;Mouse driver settings
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/logitech-headset-driver-installation-failed/20240531220930.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;G502&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/logitech-headset-driver-installation-failed/20240531220903.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;768&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;G502&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;133&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;320px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
