<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Manufacturing on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/manufacturing/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Manufacturing on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/manufacturing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>US-China trade war</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a tangent, the differences between socialism with Chinese characteristics and capitalism. From the older generation, I’ve heard that to get rich, you must first build roads. Infrastructure construction in China is funded by the state; in a capitalist society, these would be contracted out. In remote areas, there are no profits to be made, so companies wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be willing to take on the work. Talking too much will stray from the current article’s theme. Ordinary people may feel that the trade war has little impact on their lives, but in reality, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. In the IT industry I work in, memory, hard drives, CPUs, and graphics cards – the core components of assembling a computer – all come from foreign factories. The cost of these parts accounts for 50% of the total price of the machine. High-end manufacturing is imperative. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sino-American trade war that began in 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sino-American trade war, also known as the China–United States trade war, or more briefly as the Sino-US trade dispute, Sino-US trade friction, Sino-US trade quarrel, or US-China trade war, is a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China steals American intellectual property and business secrets,&amp;rdquo; and directed the United States Trade Representative to impose tariffs on goods imported from China under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, involving an estimated total value of $60 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed a 25% additional tariff on Chinese exports worth $340 billion. The Ministry of Commerce of China responded with retaliatory measures on the same day, imposing a 25% additional tariff on U.S. exports to China worth $340 billion, including soybeans, one of the most exported products from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US and China had previously reached a consensus in May 2018 to suspend the trade war and issued a joint statement seeking resolution. However, the Office of the United States Trade Representative subsequently announced on June 16th a first batch of tariffs targeting $500 billion worth of Chinese goods entering the US, raising the original 10% tariff rate to 25%. In response, the State Council Tariff Commission of China retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce also resumed anti-dumping investigations on multiple US products. On July 6th, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% tariff on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods in the first batch of tariffs, marking the formal implementation of Trump&amp;rsquo;s China tariff policy (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently subject to a 25% tariff on August 23rd). The Ministry of Commerce later stated in a statement that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; Customs authorities said that China’s countermeasures had been implemented immediately after the US tariffs took effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 summit in Buenos Aires, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump reached a consensus to conduct 90-day negotiations and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the United States announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on Chinese goods entering the United States valued at approximately $200 billion, bringing the total subject to tariffs to $250 billion. The measure took effect on June 1 for Chinese products arriving at U.S. ports. On May 13, the State Council Tariff Commission of China announced that it would raise tariffs by 5% to 25% on certain imports from the United States valued at $60 billion, effective June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced a postponement of the U.S. tariff increase to June 15, while the State Council Tariff Commission of China stated that China’s retaliatory tariffs would take effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, the leaders of the two countries, Xi Jinping and Donald Trump, held talks at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart trade consultations and for the United States not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the progress of China’s purchases of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that starting September 1, 2019, a 10% tariff would be imposed on all remaining Chinese goods exported to the United States valued at $300 billion. On August 5, the exchange rate of the renminbi against the U.S. dollar fell below the 7 threshold. On the same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that it was designating China as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and on August 24 announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; in response, the United States increased the tariff rate previously imposed on $300 billion worth of Chinese goods to 15%, and raised the current 25% tariff on $250 billion worth of Chinese goods to 30%, but this was later put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2020, China and the United States signed the Phase One trade agreement&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
