<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Futures on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/futures/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Futures on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/futures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hong Kong stock futures basics</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets evolve, investors are seeking more effective investment tools to enhance returns. To meet this demand, Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a series of stock futures contracts representing stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, Hong Kong Joint Stock Exchange Limited (Joint Stock). These contracts offer high liquidity and active trading, allowing investors to participate in the performance of individual companies while benefiting from features like short selling and leverage available in derivative markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors can choose to invest in stock futures representing specific industries if they believe that industry&amp;rsquo;s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a financial instrument equivalent to a specified quantity of stock at a predetermined price on a future date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expires&#34;&gt;Contract expires
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The profit or loss amount, calculated as the difference between the initial agreement price and the final settlement price, multiplied by the contract multiplier, will be deducted from the account of the contract holder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price is the official closing price reported on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on the last trading day for the relevant stock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If stock futures investors wish to close their positions before expiration, short sellers only need to buy back a futures contract, while long position holders sell a futures contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-deposit&#34;&gt;Security deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When trading futures, both buyers and sellers must first pay an initial margin as a guarantee of fulfilling the contract. The clearing house calculates daily profits and losses on all open contracts at the closing market price, which serves as the basis for debiting or crediting investor accounts. If adverse market conditions result in losses that reduce the margin below the required level, the exchange will require investors to replenish their funds within a specified timeframe to maintain the initial margin level (i.e., topping up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low transaction fees: Each stock futures contract represents the value of thousands of shares, and commissions for buying or selling contracts depend on the number of contracts traded, resulting in very low costs relative to the contract&amp;rsquo;s value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short selling stocks is now easier: Investors can profit in a downturn by short selling stock futures, as this process is readily available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market makers are required by Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing to simultaneously provide bid and ask prices within a specified range to ensure market liquidity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage allows investors to buy or sell stock futures contracts by paying only a small portion of the contract&amp;rsquo;s face value, making hedging and trading more cost-effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing foreign exchange risk for overseas investors: Stock futures contracts provide a way for foreign investors to invest in high-quality local stocks, as trading them requires margin rather than the full contract value, significantly reducing their exposure to foreign exchange risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading is conducted through an electronic trading system: stock futures contracts are bought and sold using the exchange&amp;rsquo;s electronic system. Orders are executed based on price and time priority, with real-time display of bid prices, ask prices, and transaction prices, achieving the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The clearing house provides performance guarantees: stock futures contracts will be registered, cleared, and guaranteed by Hong Kong Futures Clearing Company Limited (the Clearing House), a wholly-owned subsidiary of the exchange. As the Clearing House acts as counterparty to all open positions, participants are relieved from counterparty risk. However, this guarantee does not cover clearing members&amp;rsquo; financial obligations to their clients; investors should carefully select their brokers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealer-system&#34;&gt;Dealer system
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants may register as market makers for individual stock futures, providing both bid and ask prices within a specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should note that individual stock futures may not have market maker registrations offering bid-ask spreads, and trading will be based on market order units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stocks-and-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of trading stocks and futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trading stock futures involves high risk. Losses can exceed the initial margin deposit, potentially requiring you to pay additional funds in a short period. Failure to do so may result in forced liquidation of your positions, with all losses borne by you. Therefore, it is essential that you understand the risks of trading stock futures and assess whether they are suitable for you. Before trading, consult a broker or financial advisor based on your financial situation and investment goals to determine if trading futures and options contracts is appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjust-comments&#34;&gt;Adjust comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changes to a company&amp;rsquo;s equity structure through share offerings or bonus shares can affect the stock price at net asset value or effective date, potentially impacting open positions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all other factors remain the same, the value of a shareholder&amp;rsquo;s holdings will not change on the net asset value date. However, this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures unless appropriate adjustments are made to the futures contract. Without adjusting the settlement price and if the multiplier of the stock futures contract remains unchanged, an adjustment in the underlying stock price would create unreasonable and unfair effects on the value of the stock futures position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clearing house adjusts rates to maintain fair value for futures contracts, making changes only when significant alterations occur. The Hong Kong Exchange will announce the details of these adjustments, and exchange participants must inform their clients about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Stock futures contracts overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-provider-code&#34;&gt;Information Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
