<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Futures on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/futures/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Futures on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/futures/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hong Kong Futures Basic Concepts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets continue to evolve, investors have begun seeking more effective investment tools to enhance their investment returns. To meet investor demand, The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a range of stock futures contracts, all of which represent stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange (HKEX), which boasts high trading volumes and active liquidity. Through investing in stock futures, investors can participate in the performance of individual companies while also benefiting from the short selling and leverage effects offered by the derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the underlying stocks represented by stock futures are typically leading companies within their respective industries, investors can select to invest in those industry-specific futures if they believe a particular sector’s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a specified quantity of financial value (contract size) equivalent to a specified number of shares (the underlying stock) at a predetermined price (the agreed-upon price) on a future, specified date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All stock futures contracts are settled in cash; there is no physical delivery of the underlying stock at expiration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expiry&#34;&gt;Contract Expiry
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon contract expiry, the profit or loss amount is calculated as the difference between the agreed-upon price and the final settlement price multiplied by the contract multiplier, which will be deducted from the clearing member’s margin account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price refers to the official closing price of the stock reported by the Shanghai Stock Exchange on the last trading day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a futures investor wishes to close out their position before expiry, a short seller only needs to buy back one futures contract, while a long position holder must sell one futures contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;margin-deposit&#34;&gt;Margin Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In futures trading, both buyers and sellers are required to initially deposit a basic margin as collateral to fulfill the contract. After each daily settlement, the clearing organization calculates profits or losses for all open contracts based on the closing market price and uses this to deduct from the investor’s margin account. If unfavorable market conditions result in an investor incurring losses that cause their margin to fall below the specified level, the exchange will require the investor to top up their margin within a designated timeframe to maintain it at the original basic margin level (i.e., to cover).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low Transaction Fees: Each stock futures contract is equivalent to thousands of shares, but brokerage commissions are determined by the number of contracts, making transaction costs relatively low in terms of value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier Short Selling: Because investors can easily short stocks through futures contracts, they can profit during market declines by shorting stock futures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market Maker System: To ensure market liquidity, The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited (HKEX) requires market makers to simultaneously provide buy and sell prices within a specified range, maintaining circulation in the stock futures market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage Effect: Investors only need to pay a margin representing a small portion of the contract value when buying or selling stock futures contracts, making hedging and trading more cost-effective. - Reduce foreign investor’s currency risk: Stock futures contracts provide a way for overseas investors to invest in high-quality local stocks because buying and selling stock futures only requires paying a margin, rather than the full value of the contract, thereby significantly reducing the currency risk borne by overseas investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading through electronic trading systems: Stock futures contracts are traded using the Taiwan Futures Exchange’s electronic trading system. All orders are executed in the order of price and time, and immediate display of buy prices, sell prices, and transaction prices ensures the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-1&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearing companies provide performance guarantees: Stock futures contracts will be registered, settled, and guaranteed by HKFE Clearing Ltd (the clearing company), a wholly owned subsidiary of the Hong Kong Futures Exchange.  Due to the clearing company being the counterparty for all open positions, there is no need for participants in the exchange to bear counterparty risk between themselves. However, the scope of this guarantee does not include the financial responsibility of the exchange participants towards their clients; investors should exercise caution and diligence when selecting a broker for buying and selling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-making&#34;&gt;Market Making
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants or individual stock futures contracts may register as market makers on the exchange and simultaneously provide both buy and sell prices within the specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should note that individual stock futures contracts may not have a market maker registered to provide buy-sell spreads, and their trades will be based on market trading units. &lt;strong&gt;Investors should be aware that buying and selling stock futures without a registered market maker may involve liquidity risk, and caution should be exercised before entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stock-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of Trading Stock Futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock futures involve high risks. Losses arising from trading stock futures may exceed the initial margin paid at opening, potentially requiring you to pay additional margins within a short period. If unable to meet these payments, your position may be liquidated, and you will bear all resulting losses. Therefore, it is crucial to fully understand the risks involved in trading stock futures and assess whether it aligns with your financial situation and investment objectives. Before engaging in transactions, consult with a broker or financial advisor to determine if futures and options contracts are suitable for your circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjusting-comments&#34;&gt;Adjusting Comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a listed company changes its capital structure through methods such as offering shares or issuing bonus shares, this will lead to changes in the stock price at the time of net asset valuation or the effective date, and may also affect uncovered contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If other circumstances remain unchanged, the value held by shareholders’ portfolios will not change on the settlement day, but this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures. Unless the futures contract is appropriately adjusted. If the initial pricing remains unchanged and the contract multiplier remains constant, the adjustment of the stock price will unfairly and unjustly affect the value of the stock futures holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the clearing organization determines the adjustment ratio, it does so based on maintaining the fair value of the futures contracts and only makes adjustments when there are significant changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Futures Contracts Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/futures-contracts-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Futures Contracts Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-provider-code&#34;&gt;News Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/news_provider_code.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;News Provider Code&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/products/listed-derivatives/single-stock/stock-futures?sc_lang=zh-cn#list_of_stock_futures&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Exchange - Derivatives / Stocks / Stock Futures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
