<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Forex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/forex/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Forex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/forex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding buy rate and sell rate in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate.&amp;rdquo; Many people may not be clear on these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, we will use a simple example to help everyone understand the meaning and function of these rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;What are &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to buy foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you sell foreign currency (like US dollars) to a bank, the bank will pay you in RMB according to the buying rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to sell foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell it to you at the selling rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exchange rate at which the bank buys foreign currency from you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The price the bank offers you for foreign currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that banks&amp;rsquo; buying and selling exchange rates are typically different, with the selling rate generally higher than the buying rate. This difference is how banks make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-study-analysis&#34;&gt;Case Study Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let&amp;rsquo;s take a specific example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you go to a bank to exchange for US dollars, and the bank&amp;rsquo;s exchange rate is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.0 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.2 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You sell US dollars to a bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have $1,000 and want to sell it to a bank, the bank will calculate using its buy rate&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1,000 USD x 7.0 CNY/USD = 7,000 CNY
\]
&lt;p&gt;That means the bank will give you 7,000 RMB. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;买入汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are selling dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-2-you-buy-us-dollars-with-rmb&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: You buy US dollars with RMB
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars, the bank will calculate using the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$972.22 USD
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, 7000 RMB can be exchanged for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;卖出汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are purchasing dollars from a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-buy-rate-different-from-the-sell-rate&#34;&gt;Why is the buy rate different from the sell rate?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the bank&amp;rsquo;s selling exchange rate (7.2 RMB/USD) is higher than its buying exchange rate (7.0 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from foreign exchange transactions by exploiting this difference. In other words, banks make a profit by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
Selling exchange rate (7.2) - Buying exchange rate (7.0) = 0.2 RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference is the bank&amp;rsquo;s source of profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank buys foreign currency from you at this exchange rate (the rate when you sell foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank sells foreign currency to you at this exchange rate (the rate when you buy foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between the buying and selling exchange rates is the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these exchange rate concepts allows us to better know how much foreign currency we will receive or how much Chinese Yuan is needed to purchase it when exchanging currencies. Hopefully, this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has seen significant volatility, breaking through 7.26</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the broader market decline are likely linked to global central bank policies, the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise interest rate cut, US economic data performance, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors collectively impacted the foreign exchange and stock markets, leading to Renminbi volatility and A-share declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the link provided, the Renminbi exchange rate experienced a significant fluctuation on March 22, 2024. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yuan weakened at opening, with the dollar exceeding 7.24 against the offshore RMB to 7.24926 and surpassing 7.22 against the onshore RMB to 7.22360, both breaking highs seen since November 17, 2023. At the time of this report, the dollar has broken past 7.26, reaching a low of 7.2639, and the trend continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 22, the central bank set the midpoint of the yuan against the dollar at 7.1004, a decrease of 62 basis points, with an expanded adjustment range&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affected by multiple factors, China&amp;rsquo;s three major A-share indices opened and closed lower, with declines exceeding 1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior currency trader at a Hong Kong investment firm stated that foreign exchange market volatility is primarily due to the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s unexpected rate cut boosting the dollar, combined with a strong US economy and persistent inflation potentially delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the dollar index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is a &amp;ldquo;super central bank week&amp;rdquo; for global markets, with interest rate decisions to be announced by central banks in the US, Japan, UK, Australia, and more. The Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise rate cut marks the first such action among G10 central banks since the pandemic began, disrupting market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangda Bank financial market researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent RMB fluctuations, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies like the US dollar, and short-term volatility will not alter the year&amp;rsquo;s upward trend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
