<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Forex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/forex/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Forex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/forex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you have $1,000 USD and want to sell these dollars to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
1000 \, \text{USD} \times 7.0 \, \text{CNY/USD} = 7000 \, \text{CNY}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7,000 CNY. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling USD to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline in the A-share market may be related to the dynamics of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank, the performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors jointly acted on the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to fluctuations in the Renminbi and the decline in the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant volatility. Here’s a detailed breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through:&lt;/strong&gt; At opening, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar-offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and the on-shore RMB rising to a high of 7.22360, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of release by Lianhe Chat, the dollar-offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 mark, with the lowest reported at 7.2639 and the trend remained unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Exchange Rate Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the Renminbi’s midpoint exchange rate against the dollar at 7.1004, a devaluation of 62 basis points, with the adjustment magnitude expanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened low and continued to fall, with declines exceeding 1% overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Foreign Exchange Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment institution stated that the volatility in the foreign exchange market was mainly due to the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank boosting the dollar, coupled with strong U.S. economic data and the potential persistence of inflation delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is the “Super Central Bank Week” for global markets, with the central banks of the United States, Japan, Britain, Australia, and other countries all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss Central Bank unexpectedly announced a cut in interest rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, which broke the market balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecast for Renminbi Trend:&lt;/strong&gt; Zhou Miaohua, researcher at Light Industry Bank’s Financial Market Department, stated that despite some fluctuations in the Renminbi recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the dollar, and short-term volatility will not change the RMB&amp;rsquo;s trend of steady appreciation throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
