<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Foreign Exchange on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/foreign-exchange/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Foreign Exchange on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 03:15:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/foreign-exchange/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding buy rate and sell rate in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, especially at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate.&amp;rdquo; Many people may not be clear about these two concepts, or even confused. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s use a simple example to help everyone understand the meaning and function of these two rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-buy-exchange-rate-and-sell-exchange-rate&#34;&gt;What are &amp;ldquo;buy exchange rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell exchange rate&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buy rate is the exchange rate at which a bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currency; that is, when you sell foreign currency (such as US dollars) to a bank, the bank will pay you in RMB according to the buy rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selling exchange rate is the rate at which a bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currency; that is, when you buy foreign currency with Chinese Yuan, the bank will sell it to you at the selling exchange rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The buy exchange rate is the price at which a bank buys foreign currency from you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: The price the bank offers you for foreign currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that banks&amp;rsquo; buying and selling exchange rates are usually different, with the selling rate generally higher than the buying rate. This difference is the bank’s source of profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-study-analysis&#34;&gt;Case Study Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these two exchange rates, let&amp;rsquo;s take a specific example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you go to the bank to exchange for US dollars, and the exchange rate offered by the bank is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy exchange rate: 1 US dollar = 7.0 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: 1 US dollar = 7.2 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-the-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You sell US dollars to the bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have $1,000 and want to sell it to a bank; the bank will calculate based on its buying exchange rate&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1000 x 7.0 yuan/dollar = 7000 yuan
\]
&lt;p&gt;That means the bank will give you 7,000 RMB. The exchange rate here is a &lt;strong&gt;buy rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are selling dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-2-you-buy-us-dollars-with-rmb&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: You buy US dollars with RMB
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate based on the selling exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$7,000 yuan ÷ 7.2 yuan/dollar = $972.22
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7000 Chinese Yuan for approximately 972.22 US dollars. The exchange rate here is a &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are buying US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-buying-exchange-rate-different-from-the-selling-exchange-rate&#34;&gt;Why is the buying exchange rate different from the selling exchange rate?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the bank&amp;rsquo;s buying exchange rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling exchange rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from foreign exchange transactions by using this difference in rates. In other words, banks make a profit by charging a higher selling exchange rate and paying a lower buying exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
Selling exchange rate (7.2) - Buying exchange rate (7.0) = 0.2 RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference is the bank&amp;rsquo;s source of profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy exchange rate: The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the rate at which you sell foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: This is the exchange rate at which the bank sells foreign currency to you (the exchange rate when you buy foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between the buying and selling exchange rates is the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you understand these exchange rate concepts, you can more clearly know how much foreign currency you will receive when exchanging currencies, or how much Chinese Yuan (RMB) you need to spend to buy foreign currency. I hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant volatility, breaking through 7.26</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline of the broader market may be related to the actions of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss National Bank, the performance of US economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors collectively impacted the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to volatility in the Renminbi exchange rate and a decline in A-share markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the content of the link you provided, on March 22, 2024, the exchange rate of the Renminbi experienced a significant fluctuation. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US dollar exchange rate against the offshore renminbi broke through: The yuan weakened at the opening of the day, with the dollar versus the offshore renminbi rising above 7.24 to 7.24926 and rising above 7.22 to 7.22360 against the onshore renminbi during intraday trading, both breaking through highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time this reporter from Caiyun Society reported, the dollar versus the offshore renminbi broke through the 7.26 level, falling to a low of 7.2639, and the trend has not stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PBOC Midpoint Adjustment: On March 22, the central bank announced that the RMB exchange rate against the US dollar was set at 7.1004, down 62 basis points, with a larger adjustment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A-share market reacted with a decline, influenced by various factors; all three major indices opened and closed lower, with falls exceeding 1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons for Forex Market Volatility: A senior currency trader from an investment firm in Hong Kong stated that forex market volatility is primarily due to the US dollar being boosted by the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s unexpected interest rate cut, combined with a strong US economy and persistent inflation which may delay interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the US Dollar Index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Updates:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is a &amp;ldquo;super central bank week&amp;rdquo; for global markets, as central banks in the United States, Japan, the UK, Australia, and many other countries will announce interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss National Bank unexpectedly announced an interest rate cut, becoming the first G10 central bank to do so since the outbreak of the pandemic, which disrupted market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangda Bank&amp;rsquo;s Financial Markets Research Department researcher Zhou Maohua stated that, although the renminbi has experienced some fluctuations recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the US dollar. Short-term volatility will not change the year’s trend of a steady and upward trajectory for the renminbi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
