<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Protobuf on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/protobuf/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Protobuf on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/protobuf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Protobuf Zero Value Pitfalls: When Default Values Become an Invisible Killer of Business Logic</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/protobuf-zero-value-trap/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 15:26:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/protobuf-zero-value-trap/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The US stock market has three trading sessions: pre-market, live market, and post-market. The logic for pushing data – whether it’s full data or numerical increments – is optimized to conserve bandwidth (sending as little data as possible). Initially, only the full dataset is sent in the first transmission; subsequent transmissions are incremental updates of all fields.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why not use the optimal solution? This involves multiple project teams, some of which have been live for many years. As we’re a new integration, we can only strive for compatibility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-series-of-issues&#34;&gt;A Series of Issues
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Just from the summary, it might seem like there aren&amp;rsquo;t any problems, but once the system architecture is brought in, a series of issues arise. Immediately after resolving the previous issue, a new one emerged – this problem was caused by the prior one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;unable-to-identify-trading-intervals&#34;&gt;Unable to Identify Trading Intervals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The market phase is defined in &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; as 0, but due to incremental push data delivery, the business side cannot effectively identify whether this &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo; represents the default value or a genuine business value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In simpler terms: Each time a &amp;lsquo;0&amp;rsquo; is received, it’s impossible to determine if it’s the new market phase setting or the &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; default value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;introducing-optional&#34;&gt;Introducing Optional
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since protobuf release 3.15, proto3 supports using the optional keyword (just as in proto2) to provide presence information for a scalar field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The group’s communication protocol is based on &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt;, but due to historical reasons, the version selected was older and did not support the &lt;code&gt;optional&lt;/code&gt; keyword. As you know, because we introduced &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; from the ground up, publishing the project as a static library, this resulted in needing to upgrade the entire build chain, which was a very high cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gcc-version-issues&#34;&gt;GCC Version Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After painstakingly devising a solution, we planned to release two different underlying versions to control the propagation of dependencies for the new &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; version as much as possible. However, during compilation, we discovered that the &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; version was too low and did not support the new features of &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commonly used server types in our team are CentOS7 and CentOS8. The default &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; version on CentOS7 is 4.8, while the default &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; version on CentOS8 is 8.3. Since the new features of &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; require a &lt;code&gt;gcc&lt;/code&gt; version of 7.4 or higher, CentOS7 could not support it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://gcc.gnu.org/bugzilla/show_bug.cgi?id=82461&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Bug 82461 - [7 Regression] Temporary required for brace-initializing (non-literal-type) member variable&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, after a lot of troubleshooting, we moved the deployments of related services and the compilation server to CentOS8, resolving this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reasonable-enumeration&#34;&gt;Reasonable Enumeration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the entire problem, there’s a simpler and more efficient solution: adjust the enumeration definition to start numbering from 1 instead of 0. This effectively distinguishes between default values and business values, avoiding all the aforementioned issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-starting-from-1-is-more-reasonable&#34;&gt;Why Starting from 1 is More Reasonable?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt;, enum types have a default value fixed to 0. If we define meaningful business values as 0 (e.g., &amp;ldquo;Market Open&amp;rdquo;), in incremental pushes, the business side cannot determine whether the received 0 is a business value or an unset default value. However, if the enum starts from 1, 0 can be reserved for a meaningless default value or “Unknown” state, solving the problem directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended Practice:
When designing &lt;code&gt;protobuf&lt;/code&gt; enums, always define 0 as a meaningless default value (e.g., &lt;code&gt;UNKNOWN&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;RESERVED&lt;/code&gt;).
Assign actual business values starting from 1 to ensure they are distinguished from the default value of 0.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this small adjustment, we not only resolved the issue of identifying market hours but also provided a valuable lesson for future protocol design.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
