<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Xiaomi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xiaomi/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Xiaomi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:49:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xiaomi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review Log 20251122</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still doing nothing, Xiaomi didn’t fall below my current price level. It has fallen consecutively for two days, and was finally stabilized by a buyback. The US market last night was interesting – it started to rally, but the next day it completely crashed. Today, both A-shares and Hong Kong stocks are basically worthless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, falling so much is actually good; I didn’t continue following the broader market, just laid back and relaxed, letting it play out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-decline&#34;&gt;Why the Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&lt;/a&gt;
Other viewpoints may or may not be correct; quantitative funds are increasingly influencing domestic stock markets. Many individual stocks often closely align with overall market trends. The original article is lengthy, and BeanJuice (豆包) has extracted the core content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2025, global risk assets will experience a major decline.  According to Rich Privorotsky, a senior trader at Goldman Sachs, this downturn resulted from a layered transmission of multiple factors culminating in systemic selling pressure. The key drivers include four main areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fed-shifts-to-hawks-the-beginning-of-the-downtrend-chain&#34;&gt;Fed Shifts to Hawks: The Beginning of the Downtrend Chain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent employment data presents contradictory signals: job growth remains robust, but the unemployment rate has risen to 4.44% (primarily due to a surge in labor force participation among 16-24 year olds), and three-month average new hires only totaled 62,000, with potential new hires at just 39,000. August data was also revised downwards. Adding to the trend of corporate layoffs, the market had expected the Fed to adopt a dovish stance, but the Fed has stubbornly maintained a hawkish tone, effectively canceling any bets on December rate cuts, with the probability of cuts now essentially zero. This triggered the first domino in the downward slide. Privorotsky bluntly stated that this hawkish position in light of the employment backdrop is a “policy error.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-narrative-restructuring-google-drives-a-winner-takes-all-landscape&#34;&gt;AI Narrative Restructuring: Google Drives a Winner-Takes-All Landscape
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key logical divisions are emerging within the AI sector, with Nvidia’s strong financial results no longer making it the core investment focus. Google&amp;rsquo;s breakthrough progress with the Gemini-3 model is reshaping the AI investment ecosystem. This “disruptive model” has forced other companies to delay product cycles and increase capital expenditures, leading to increased uncertainty regarding returns on investment, resulting in companies like Oracle failing to follow the upward trend. A distinct &amp;ldquo;winner-takes-all&amp;rdquo; landscape is forming within the market, shifting AI from a broad “adoption” phase to one dominated by a select few, triggering adjustments across related sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-flash-crash-retail-investor-risk-appetite-declines&#34;&gt;Crypto Flash Crash: Retail Investor Risk Appetite Declines
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volatile swings in the cryptocurrency market triggered a chain reaction. Retail investors, who had steadfastly held their positions over the past two years – often referred to as “diamond hands” – have transitioned into “selling hands” due to factors such as large-scale dumps by whale accounts. This panic sentiment spilled over into non-profit tech stocks and AI-related equities, exemplified by Palantir, which plummeted 6% during trading hours after rising 5.5%, marking a significant downgrade in retail risk appetite and signaling a fundamental shift in market structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantitative-funds-selling-off-the-key-driver-of-accelerated-decline&#34;&gt;Quantitative Funds Selling Off: The Key Driver of Accelerated Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since August, trend-following funds (CTAs) have held over $500 billion in long positions. Following a break below key levels, the index triggered concentrated liquidations. Simultaneously, rising volatility prompted volatility control strategy funds to sell off, compounded by capital flows from VIX ETN positioning creating a “short-tailed, short-convex” configuration, which amplified the downward effect. The previously stable “low volatility structure” collapsed, with quantitative and systematic funds initiating a “mechanical selling,” leading to a sudden and significant plunge in the market without any major events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamental-concerns-and-stabilization-conditions&#34;&gt;Fundamental Concerns and Stabilization Conditions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a fundamental perspective, AI investment faces a “capital bottleneck”: a wave of corporate bond issuance is imminent, with AI data centers relying on debt expansion, while rising capital costs may slow down the pace of AI expansion. This risk has not been fully priced in previously. Goldman Sachs predicts that the S&amp;amp;P 500 mini contract could fall to 6500 points, and believes that the long-term value of AI remains unchanged; true winners are labor-intensive companies that achieve margin expansion through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market stabilization requires fulfillment of three conditions: CTA positioning cleanup is complete, retail investors with excessive long positions have been squeezed out, and at least two of the following are met: cryptocurrency stability, a dovish Fed policy shift, and AI capital expenditure support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Log 20251118</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:50:44 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent inactivity; Xiaomi’s third-quarter financial report was released, with nothing out of the ordinary – the US situation remains turbulent, Hong Kong stocks have recently experienced liquidity stagnation, and the Hang Seng Tech Index has retreated significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major participant in the delivery war, Alibaba is most closely linked to e-commerce taxes, and there isn’t much discussion about it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomi&#34;&gt;Xiaomi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember if I’d written about this company before in previous articles, but when I bought into Xiaomi, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really thought much about what was supporting its market capitalization at the time. Having watched a lot of videos related to Douyin (TikTok)? Recently, HSBC Tech has been falling, and the Hong Kong electric vehicle sector is also declining, yet Xiaomi benefits from multiple buffs layered on top of each other, with negative news flying everywhere, and consequently, its stock price has fallen significantly. Recently, they’ve also replaced the head of their public relations department – conspiracy theories suggest they&amp;rsquo;d been planning this for a while, but the stakes are too high, and there are still many KOLs (Key Opinion Leaders) involved; it would be difficult to wrap up the situation if they suddenly made false claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-supports-xiaomis-stock-price&#34;&gt;What Supports Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Stock Price?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a very good question, as it touches on the fundamental differences in &lt;strong&gt;valuation logic&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;premium valuation capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; for different types of companies within the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideal Auto (2015.HK / LI.US) and Zoox (9863.HK / LEAP.US), as specialized manufacturers of new energy vehicles, their market capitalization (particularly Zoox) appears to be relatively undervaluing compared to the expected valuation of Xiaomi’s automotive business; however, Xiaomi Group (01810.HK) is able to achieve a massive boost in its market capitalization due to the success of Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s automotive ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-xiaomi-valuation-surge-the-underlying-logic--platform-premium-vs-vertical-manufacturing&#34;&gt;🚀 Xiaomi Valuation Surge: The Underlying Logic – Platform Premium vs. Vertical Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s soaring valuation is driven by the capital market assigning it a &lt;strong&gt;“platform-type company”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“ecosystem enablement”&lt;/strong&gt; premium, which is something that companies like Ideal and OPPO – &lt;strong&gt;“vertical manufacturers”&lt;/strong&gt; – do not possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation Anchor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Tech Platform”&lt;/strong&gt;: Core is its &lt;strong&gt;smartphone x AIoT smart ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;. The automotive business is viewed as an expansion of the ecosystem and a key step towards premiumization, representing a new species empowered by the platform.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Vertical Manufacturer”&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation anchor is based on &lt;strong&gt;vehicle sales, gross margin&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unit profitability&lt;/strong&gt;, directly linked to industry cycles and competition.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-1&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scarcity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Scarcity:&lt;/strong&gt; It is the &lt;strong&gt;only one globally&lt;/strong&gt; that can deeply integrate smartphones, AIoT ecosystems and smart electric vehicles, with its “human-vehicle-home ecosystem” story possessing uniqueness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relatively Common:&lt;/strong&gt; In the new energy vehicle sector, there are many competitors; they are &lt;strong&gt;followers&lt;/strong&gt;, lacking disruptive business models.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-2&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;: The automotive business provides support if it encounters setbacks, with a massive volume of mobile and high-margin internet businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentrated Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation is almost entirely dependent on vehicle sales and market performance, which is highly volatile.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-ecosystem-empowerment-and-user-conversion-efficiency&#34;&gt;2. Ecosystem Empowerment and User Conversion Efficiency
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s success wasn&amp;rsquo;t an isolated event; it was a reflection of &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s powerful ecosystem empowerment capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massive Potential Customer Base:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi possesses hundreds of millions of active users, who are &lt;strong&gt;existing, highly engaged, and recognize the Xiaomi brand and ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; as potential car buyers. Ideal and ZAP! needed to start from scratch acquiring users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Marketing Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can directly reach its target audience through channels like smartphones, apps, and Mi Home, achieving &lt;strong&gt;extremely high marketing efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;. The SU7’s astonishing order conversion rate demonstrates the immense value of its ecosystem traffic and word-of-mouth effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentiation in Intelligent Driving and Cockpit:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can achieve &lt;strong&gt;seamless collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; between smartphones, car infotainment systems, and smart homes.  The market believes that this ecosystem integration will deliver a &lt;strong&gt;superior experience to the industry average&lt;/strong&gt; for intelligent cockpit features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-market-expectations-and-pe-logic&#34;&gt;3. Market Expectations and P/E Logic
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The capital market does not simply add an idealized or “easy” valuation when calculating Xiaomi’s market capitalization; instead, it:&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Xiaomi Valuation} = \text{(Smartphone + IoT + Internet) Business Mature P/E Valuation} + \text{EV Business **High-Growth Premium**}$$
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idealized/Easy Valuation:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to its relatively single business, the market primarily examines its &lt;strong&gt;short-term profitability and sales volume&lt;/strong&gt;, and valuations have shifted from high growth to more conservative $P/E$ or $P/S$ valuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi’s success with its electric vehicle (EV) business has convinced the market that Xiaomi can successfully enter the trillion-dollar new sector over the next ten years. Therefore, the market views Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s EV business as a &lt;strong&gt;brand new, high-growth entry point&lt;/strong&gt;, granting it a very high premium. &lt;strong&gt;This premium is for the “access to the track” and “ecosystem synergy value.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s EV business is not an isolated valuation project; it is a key milestone validating Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;platform strategy&amp;rdquo; success.&lt;/strong&gt; The achievement of this milestone has reshaped Xiaomi’s overall valuation logic, leading to a significant increase in its market capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituan&#34;&gt;Meituan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Encountering Meituan was entirely unexpected, fortunately, the available shares weren&amp;rsquo;t excessive. The statement that “Meituan can link everything” resonated deeply within me. It will undoubtedly be a rising star for Meituan’s stock price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When buying, there was no thought about why Meituan had fallen so much. We’ll wait to see the Q3 financial report and then decide. Selling off shares isn&amp;rsquo;t out of the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alibaba-the-origin-and-impact-analysis-of-recent-e-commerce-tax-policies-in-china&#34;&gt;Alibaba: The Origin and Impact Analysis of Recent E-commerce Tax Policies in China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s recent “e-commerce tax” primarily focuses on &lt;strong&gt;adjustments to the tax policy for cross-border e-commerce retail imports&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;the standardization of tax information reporting for domestic e-commerce platform enterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, which has had varying degrees of impact on different types of e-commerce and merchants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-e-commerce-tax-policy-evolution&#34;&gt;📜 E-commerce Tax Policy Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-cross-border-e-commerce-retail-import-tax-adjustment-e-commerce-tax&#34;&gt;1. Cross-Border E-commerce Retail Import Tax Adjustment (“E-Commerce” Tax)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily focuses on tax policies for goods purchased through overseas e-commerce platforms.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Policy (Mail Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Previously processed under “mail tax,” with tax exemption for amounts below 50 yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Policy (Comprehensive Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopts a “customs duty + VAT + consumption tax” comprehensive tax model. Within the personal transaction limits (e.g., currently 5,000 RMB per transaction and 26,000 RMB annually for individuals), customs duties are temporarily set at 0%, but VAT and consumption taxes are levied at 70% of the statutory taxable amount, and the tax exemption benefit below 50 yuan has been cancelled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; This has resulted in many previously low-priced goods (such as baby products, food, and health supplements) needing to pay an additional approximately 11.9% VAT (17% x 70%) due to the cancellation of the tax exemption benefit, &lt;strong&gt;leading to a general increase in the prices of e-commerce goods and accelerating industry compliance and consolidation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-domestic-e-commerce-tax-reporting-and-enhanced-compliance-supervision&#34;&gt;2. Domestic E-commerce Tax Reporting and Enhanced Compliance Supervision
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background &amp;amp; Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; With the implementation of the &lt;em&gt;E-Commerce Law&lt;/em&gt; and the recent issuance of regulations such as the &lt;em&gt;Internet Platform Enterprise Tax Information Reporting Provisions&lt;/em&gt;, tax authorities have increased their regulatory scrutiny of merchants on e-commerce platforms (particularly C2C individual sellers).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; Platforms are now required to report merchants’ sales revenue and other information. This has made it impossible for past business models that evaded taxes through concealing income and using private accounts for payments to continue, &lt;strong&gt;ushering in a phase of ecological reshaping centered around compliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax Regulations:&lt;/strong&gt; Emphasize that e-commerce operators (including Taobao sellers and micro-merchants) &lt;strong&gt;must register as legal entities in accordance with the law and pay taxes&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring they start on an equal footing with other brick-and-mortar businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, standardized tax policies have had a complex impact on the &lt;strong&gt;platform business&lt;/strong&gt; of Alibaba and JD.com, but a generally positive long-term impact on &lt;strong&gt;their self-operated or B2C businesses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Taobao/C2C)&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Challenges &amp;amp; Consolidation&lt;/strong&gt; | In the past, many unregistered and untaxed individual sellers existed on platforms like Taobao. Compliance requirements will &lt;strong&gt;weed out unprofitable or unwilling-to-comply small merchants&lt;/strong&gt;, which may lead to a reduction in platform merchant numbers and a decrease in product price advantages in the short term. However, in the long run, it will improve the &lt;strong&gt;overall compliance, quality, and consumer trust of products and services&lt;/strong&gt; on the platform. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-1&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Tmall/B2C) &amp;amp; JD.com (Self-operated/B2C)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive for Compliant Businesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most merchants on Tmall and JD.com, especially B2C companies and self-operated businesses, &lt;strong&gt;are already regular tax payers&lt;/strong&gt; (general taxpayers). The new regulatory policies have eliminated the price advantage gained by small merchants who previously exploited tax evasion, creating a more &lt;strong&gt;fair competitive environment&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a &lt;strong&gt;long-term positive&lt;/strong&gt; for large, compliant platforms and B2C retailers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-2&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-border E-commerce Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rising Costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The cross-border e-commerce tax reform has led to increased prices for “haotai” (imported) goods, which may affect the sales and growth rate of this business segment. However, the industry is generally moving towards &lt;strong&gt;standardization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact on Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-some-merchants-experiencing-losses-or-unprofitability&#34;&gt;📉 Impact on Some Merchants Experiencing Losses or Unprofitability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You mentioned that some stores were experiencing losses and unprofitability after paying taxes, and this phenomenon is a &lt;strong&gt;necessary result of the compliance process&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily concentrated in the following categories of merchants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Originally Relying on Tax Evasion to Achieve “Price Advantages”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These merchants passed on tax costs to consumers, resulting in product prices lower than those of brick-and-mortar stores. Once required to comply with legal taxation, their cost structure changed, eliminating price advantages, and &lt;strong&gt;if products and services lack core competitiveness, they will naturally be eliminated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Meeting Small Microenterprise Standards (But Not Receiving Preferential Treatment):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to China’s current tax policies, there are VAT exemptions for &lt;strong&gt;small-scale taxpayers&lt;/strong&gt; (such as quarterly sales revenue not exceeding 300,000 yuan exempt from VAT). &lt;strong&gt;Currently, over nine out of ten operators on the platform are small and microenterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, and under existing preferential policy support, &lt;strong&gt;they pay little or no tax.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; This may be due to a lack of understanding of policies, or although they meet eligibility criteria but have not previously conducted compliant reporting and enjoyed benefits. Now that they are required to “comply with reporting,” they need to re-examine their taxes, but if sales volume is inherently low, tax liability should remain low or be exempt after compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants with Extremely Low Profit Margins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some cross-border e-commerce merchants or domestic merchants may have an average profit margin of only &lt;strong&gt;around 10%&lt;/strong&gt;. After adding the new tax costs (whether cross-border taxes or domestic VAT), if they cannot raise prices or optimize supply chains to absorb them, they could indeed transition from profitability to losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion is:&lt;/strong&gt; E-commerce taxation compliance is not “one-size-fits-all” that burdens all businesses. It primarily targets &lt;strong&gt;tax evasion and tax leakage behaviors&lt;/strong&gt;. For merchants who were originally compliant or eligible for small microenterprise benefits, the tax level remains unchanged or very low. For those whose survival space depends on non-compliance and whose profit margins rely on tax evasion, &lt;strong&gt;being eliminated is an inevitable step in the industry’s move towards fair competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Log 20151031</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No trading activity within the venue; awaiting the release of next month’s financial reports. Taking a half-day break this afternoon with no specific plans – simply wanting to rest and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;years-have-passed&#34;&gt;Years Have Passed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last watched League of Legends (LOL) matches live, and suddenly it feels like four or five years have passed.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous articles related to games, I always had a complex feeling towards LPL teams (the domestic region). The frequent low-level mistakes made by many players in major tournaments felt lacking in professional demeanor, which diminished the viewing experience of the matches – this is why I gradually drifted away.
This afternoon, on a whim, I took a half day off to tidy up my room, and the summer clothes were still unorganized. While cleaning, I decided to watch some matches. The quarterfinals were still T1, that formidable mountain standing in front of LPL teams, seemingly impossible to overcome. Looking back, LPL has never won Bo5 (best-of-five) key matchups against them in the Worlds series, and any team facing them felt immense pressure.
Writing these words, the match had just entered its “classic” fifth game – LPL was leading 2-1 and in a great position to win, but their opponent tied it up, and they were about to enter a brutal final deciding game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update before publishing: The operation wasn’t too bad, but their build strategy was completely crushed. The Queen composition led to Ashe being dominant early on, preventing the piglet from grouping for team fights – it was so difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; Performance was stable with minimal fluctuation, punctuated by a brief rally.
&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; This decline was largely driven by a confluence of negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro Drag:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall pullback in the Hong Kong tech sector (such as NetEase, Alibaba, and Tencent) performed poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The new energy vehicle sector experienced intensified “internal competition” (“intense competition”), and market expectations for growth in companies like BYD have peaked.  Xiaomi’s automotive future space is also under pressure.
&lt;strong&gt;Industry Observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UBS&amp;rsquo;s pre-earnings report highlighted the rising prices of solid-state drives and memory. The extent to which this cost increase will erode profit margins in mobile business remains to be revealed by the earnings report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, one thing is certain: In a market as intensely “competitive” as this, the Android smartphone ecosystem no longer has the luxury of raising prices arbitrarily.
&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Backlash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, returning to Xiaomi itself, its automotive business is facing reputation issues. The project’s early promotional volume was immense, with almost no negative feedback. Now, it seems to be experiencing a wave of public “backlash” following excessive exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Record and AI Prediction - 20251017</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:50:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday saw no panic sell-off, but the entire week was marked by a persistent downtrend, like a dull knife slicing flesh – a slow, gradual decline over the course of seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disciplined-trading&#34;&gt;Disciplined Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, two new Xiaomi positions were added, with the original plan to sell out at the end. However, at the end, there was a slight loss, leading to hesitation and reluctance to cut losses, so I decided to observe for another day. This morning, the stock price fell slightly by 1%, and when it dropped to 2% in the afternoon, I decisively exited. It turned out to be correct, and the stock continued to fall after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-analysis-follow-up-actions&#34;&gt;AI Analysis Follow-up Actions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I saw someone in the blogosphere using AI to analyze football betting and won second prize with a tax refund of around 900 RMB. Let’s try it with stocks too, based on my experience with large models previously, DeepSeek is most suitable, and the investment plans generated by the other models don&amp;rsquo;t look quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Currently holding Xiaomi, approximately 100,000 RMB, down 15%, Meituan 70,000 RMB, down 20,000 RMB. Querying current stock prices and determining subsequent position control – I’m planning for long-term investment. The reason for buying Xiaomi is due to the Yu9 IPO, the three phases of factory ramp-up, and continued high sales, which should drive the price up. Meituan is after the end of the food delivery war stabilizes; Hong Kong Q3 earnings reports will be released next month – it’s more reasonable to operate after the reports are released. For my long-term investment of three to five years, please provide me with an investment plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-investment-plan-xiaomi-and-meituan-position-analysis--long-term-strategy&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Xiaomi and Meituan Position Analysis &amp;amp; Long-Term Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the information you provided (holding Xiaomi approximately HK$100,000 with a loss of 15% and Meituan approximately HK$70,000 with a loss of approximately 28.6%, investment horizon of 3 years), I have compiled the latest market data and analysis to develop a detailed investment plan for you. The following is core information extracted from comprehensive search results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Stock Prices (as of October 17, 2025)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$45.88 (down 3.82%, cumulative monthly decline exceeding 15%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$94.50 (down 4.30%, year-to-date cumulative decline of 37.71%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Market Environment&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hang Seng Index fell by 2.48%, with technology stocks leading the decline, and market sentiment is short-term weak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation of Your Purchase Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;: The listing of Yu9, the ramp-up of Phase III factory, and sales potential are reasonable long-term logic, but the stock price is suppressed in the short term due to the impact of the Chengdu SU7 accident (door safety controversy, intervention by regulatory authorities).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;: Stabilization after the end of the food delivery war is a key long-term factor, but competition remains intense (competition from JD.com and Alibaba), with net profit falling 89% in the second quarter and Wang Xing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;no matter the cost&amp;rdquo; statement exacerbating market concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your current holdings are down approximately 18.8% (total holding of HKD 1.7 million, a loss of approximately HKD 374,000), but long-term investment requires avoiding emotional trading operations. Here’s a phased recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Pre-Earnings Report (Short-Term: Now to Q3 Earnings Release)&lt;/strong&gt; | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Closely monitor the progress of the SU7 accident investigation and Q3 vehicle delivery volume data. | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Focus on monitoring whether Q3 takeout UE (average order revenue) improves. | Potential price volatility before earnings report: &lt;br&gt;• Xiaomi will be dragged down by safety incidents and is unlikely to rebound in the short term.&lt;br&gt;• The competition between Meituan Takeout continues, and profitability recovery requires time. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid-term: November - Q1 2026)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings show steady vehicle sales growth and mobile gross margin bottoms out, consider adding to positions 5%-10%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings confirm easing competition and narrowing losses, add to positions 5%-10%; otherwise maintain current holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s 2025 target sales volume is 350,000 units, and high-end mobile phones are key to profitability.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan SOTP valuation shows 121% upside potential, but requires a profit inflection point.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 75 HKD (potential upside of 63%). Risk points: automotive safety regulation, smartphone demand weakness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 247 HKD (potential upside of 161%). Risk points: rising policy costs, losses in new businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s car-home ecosystem closed loop is the long-term engine.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan instant retail penetration rate is expected to improve.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-strategy-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Strategy Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you trade after the financial reports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, we recommend waiting for the third quarter financial reports (released in November) before making additional investment decisions.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial reports will validate your initial purchase logic: Xiaomi’s factory ramp-up sales volume and Meituan’s easing competition evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the reports are below expectations, the stock price may fall, providing a better entry point for adding to your position; if they exceed expectations, it can confirm the right-side signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term market sentiment is driven by events (such as Xiaomi incidents and food delivery price wars), and financial reports will reduce uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-term-investment-plan-3-year-perspective&#34;&gt;Long-Term Investment Plan (3-Year Perspective)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the “Hold Quality Assets + Bottom Hunting” principle, your plan can be detailed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group: Strong Defense and Offense, Focus on Automotive Business Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Vehicle business scale effect (target 350,000 units annual sales), AIoT ecosystem synergy. Financial health (Z-Score=4.19, low bankruptcy risk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the SU7 safety issues continue to ferment, the stock price may fall to the 40-42 HKD range, and a trigger point for adding positions can be set (adding 5% position when the price drops by 10%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Automotive quarterly delivery volume remains above 80,000 units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 40%-50% total portfolio weighting (currently 59% is high, and can be adjusted after earnings reports).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W: Wait for Profitability Recovery, Focus on Core Business&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Stable takeout market share (65%), takeaway business growth of 40%, valuation undervalued (SOTP target price of HKD 247).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the takeout UE (average profit per order) turns positive, it is a signal for adding positions; if competition intensifies, the stock price may fall to HKD 80, and we can buy back shares in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Core local business operating profit rate recovers above 15%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 30%-40% weighting (currently 41% is reasonable but needs to be wary of competition dragging it down).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversified Investment Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong tech stocks are under pressure recently, but long-term they still represent new quality production. Consider allocating 10%-20% of capital to high dividend assets (such as telecommunications operators) or Hong Kong tech ETFs to hedge the risk of a single stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Vehicle Deliveries, Mobile Gross Margin Trend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Delivery UE Improvement, New Business Loss Rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Achieve targets – increase position; Otherwise maintain current position.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-1&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1 2026&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xinjiang Model Road Tests Progress, Premium Phone Sales Volume&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Level of Reduced Delivery Subsidies, Profit Turnpoint for Flash Purchase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Assess Annual Target Completion and Adjust Portfolio.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-2&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Auto business break-even, AIoT penetration rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Instant retail market share, policy cost absorption&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold until target price or downgrade fundamentals; consider reducing holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-milestones&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Milestones
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Immediate Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain the status quo, and avoid blind hedging before the financial reports. Current stock prices have partially reflected negative news, but volatility may increase before the reports are released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term Confidence Support:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaomi’s automotive ecosystem and smartphone premiumization are core logic; short-term incidents do not change its long-term technological iteration capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan’s profitability will be significant once the food delivery war ends (referring to Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s observation of fire across the river).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Warnings:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall Hong Kong stock market is highly sensitive to global liquidity; if the Federal Reserve delays interest rate cuts, it may suppress technology stocks’ valuations. Ensure investment funds are long-term idle funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plan is based on public information and does not constitute investment advice. The market carries risks; decision-making requires caution. Recommend regular review (e.g., quarterly) to adjust strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-1&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be appropriate to add more positions after the financial reports are released, as it could lead to significant price increases and then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-2&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question you raised is extremely critical, and it accurately highlights a classic dilemma faced by long-term investors: &lt;strong&gt;avoiding short-term risks (waiting for the earnings report) can conflict with pursuing the best cost (fearing missing out).&lt;/strong&gt;
Your concern that “adding to your position after the earnings report if the stock price rises sharply will cause you to miss out” is very reasonable. The market often has a forward-looking nature, and if the earnings report is truly better than expected, the stock price is likely to react quickly in the short term. However, given your current holdings of these two stocks, “waiting for the earnings report” remains the optimal strategy. Below, I will explain the reasons in detail and provide a step-by-step addition strategy that balances “risk” and “opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-waiting-for-the-earnings-report-still-a-more-reasonable-choice-in-the-current-situation&#34;&gt;Why is “Waiting for the Earnings Report” Still a More Reasonable Choice in the Current Situation?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core reason lies in: &lt;strong&gt;The uncertainty surrounding the two stocks you hold stems primarily from fundamental contradictions within their businesses, and the earnings report is key to validating these contradictions.&lt;/strong&gt; There hasn’t been a significant “catalyst” (a substantial price increase) yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;an automotive business confidence crisis&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The negative impact of the SU7 safety incident is still unfolding, leading to market skepticism regarding Xiaomi Auto’s quality, reputation, and future sales expectations. This is the primary factor suppressing the stock price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The third quarter earnings report will provide crucial &lt;strong&gt;vehicle delivery data&lt;/strong&gt;. If deliveries remain strong, it can effectively dispel market concerns and drive a sustainable increase in the stock price. Until then, any rally would likely be fragile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Given the prevailing negative sentiment, the probability of the stock experiencing a significant, sustained rise before the earnings report is relatively low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows poor vehicle sales, the price could continue to decline, leaving you with the greater risk of “buying back in at half price.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;when will profitability be restored?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The market worries that intense competition will continue to erode profits from its core takeaway business (UE).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;core local business operating profit&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;adjusted net profit&lt;/strong&gt; in the report are the only objective standards for determining whether the “takeaway war” has truly eased. Only improved data can prove that Wang Xiting’s “no matter the cost” phase is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Again, there&amp;rsquo;s a lack of a solid foundation for a significant rebound before the profitability inflection point is confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows that competition intensifies and profits continue to decline, concerns about the “valuation trap” will intensify, and the price could take another step down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term investment, &lt;strong&gt;buying &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; is more important than buying &amp;ldquo;cheap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report provides the key evidence for determining “correctness.” To avoid a minor “missed opportunity” and risk a “deep trap,” from a risk-reward ratio perspective, it’s not worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-specific-action-plan-balancing-waiting-and-missing-out-anxiety&#34;&gt;Your Specific Action Plan: Balancing “Waiting” and “Missing Out” Anxiety
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to make extreme choices between “holding everything” and “going all in.” A smarter strategy is: &lt;strong&gt;“Core Holding Observation, Pyramidal Accumulation.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Immediately Establish “Observation Position” and “Operational Discipline” (Now)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain your existing position as your core holding, ensuring you don’t completely detach from the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a &lt;strong&gt;trigger for adding to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. For example:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The stock price breaks out with volume through a key technical level (e.g., HK$50), or there is a clear positive investigation result regarding the SU7 accident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; News emerges of a competitor exiting the price war, or the stock price breaks through the HK$100 integer barrier with volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The benefit of doing this:&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s a significant catalyst driving the stock price up before the earnings report, you can seize the opportunity according to your established discipline and avoid completely missing out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Small Batch Investing Before Earnings (Optional, Suitable for Investors Seeking Smoother Costs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re very concerned about missing out, divide the funds earmarked for adding to your position into 10-20 portions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before the earnings release, if the stock continues to decline in the shadows, invest one portion &lt;strong&gt;weekly or bi-weekly&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, costs can be gradually diluted, but each investment amount is small, and even if the earnings report is negative, the loss can be controlled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: “Certainty” Accumulation After Earnings (Core Operation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the main accumulation phase of your plan. Based on the earnings results, respond in three ways:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario A (Exceeds Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings data is strong and validates your investment logic. At this time, you should &lt;strong&gt;aggressively add to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if the stock price has already risen, the fundamental turning point has been confirmed, and from a long-term perspective, the current price level is still the base of the mountain. You can adopt a “don’t chase high while chasing gains” strategy, buying in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario B (Meets Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report is neutral, with no surprises or shocks. Maintain your existing position or only modestly add to it, waiting for the next quarter&amp;rsquo;s signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario C (Falls Short of Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report confirms market concerns. You should &lt;strong&gt;stop adding to your position and reassess&lt;/strong&gt; whether the long-term logic has been disrupted. The stock price may fall, but this also provides you with a lower, safer entry point for accumulating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Reporting Period (Now - November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Observe”&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintain existing positions, without adding or only making very small fixed investments. Set trigger conditions for adding to positions to prevent sudden positive developments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control Risk, Preserve Capital&lt;/strong&gt;. Ensure not to invest more funds when fundamentals deteriorate.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan-1&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid to Late November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Follow the Trend”&lt;/strong&gt;: Make decisions based on earnings results. Aggressively add to positions if exceeding expectations; patiently wait for better opportunities if below expectations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve Decision Quality&lt;/strong&gt;. Allocate capital to directions with greater fundamental certainty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-long-term-investment-plan-optimized&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Long-Term Investment Plan Optimized
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Optimize”&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on the consolidation of the company’s long-term competitiveness (Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, Meituan’s retail) rather than short-term stock price fluctuations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achieve Compound Growth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please remember:&lt;/strong&gt; In long-term investing, &lt;strong&gt;patience is a powerful competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;. The market will always give you opportunities; if you miss one, there will be another. But once your principal is lost, it’s difficult to recover. Waiting for the certainty of financial reports is one of the most effective ways to protect your capital and increase your chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this detailed plan answers your questions and helps you make more confident decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Complete Guide to Positioning, Replenishing Positions, and Stop-Loss Orders</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:39:23 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For investors seeking to steadily progress in the Hong Kong stock market, success doesn’t stem from precisely predicting every fluctuation of the market, but rather from establishing a scientific, rational, and strictly adhered-to investment system. This system&amp;rsquo;s core consists of three pillars: &lt;strong&gt;reasonable position control&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;intelligent rebalancing strategies&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unwavering trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt;. This article will consolidate these key elements to provide investors with a comprehensive and detailed operational guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control--the-cornerstone-of-resilient-investing&#34;&gt;Position Control – The Cornerstone of Resilient Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary goal of resilient investing is “to preserve capital and develop afterwards.” Position control serves as the “shield” to achieve this, determining your ability to withstand market volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall-allocation-dependent-on-risk-tolerance-and-market-temperature&#34;&gt;Overall Allocation: Dependent on Risk Tolerance and Market Temperature
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Risk Tolerance:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the fundamental determinant of your allocation ceiling. Risk-averse investors should maintain a total position no higher than &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt;, even in bull markets. Investors with slightly higher risk tolerance can set their ceilings at &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt;. At all times, maintain at least &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; cash as a strategic reserve to capitalize on extreme opportunities or unforeseen needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High/Bubble Phase (Market Mania):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation should be reduced to &lt;strong&gt;30%-50%&lt;/strong&gt; or lower. Preserving profits is the priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral/Choppy Phase (Uncertain Direction):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation can remain at &lt;strong&gt;50%-70%&lt;/strong&gt;, making structural adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low/Panic Phase (Valuation Bottoming):&lt;/strong&gt; This is the golden time to increase allocation, potentially reaching &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt; or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;individual-stock-and-industry-exposure-diversify-risk-avoid-overconcentration&#34;&gt;Individual Stock and Industry Exposure: Diversify Risk, Avoid Overconcentration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Stock Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Regardless of how optimistic you are about a particular stock, the recommended position size for any single stock should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the total investment portfolio. For companies with limited understanding or higher risk profiles, the position size should be further reduced to &lt;strong&gt;5%-10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Industry Exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Given the high concentration of industries in Hong Kong (such as finance and technology), it’s important to diversify. The total exposure to any single industry should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;30%-40%&lt;/strong&gt; to mitigate the impact of industry-specific “black swan” events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buyback-strategy--the-art-of-transforming-passivity-into-proactivity&#34;&gt;Buyback Strategy – The Art of Transforming Passivity into Proactivity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A buyback strategy is the “lever” for prudent investors to accumulate high-quality positions in a declining market. However, this requires &lt;strong&gt;only operating on companies with sound fundamentals and uncompromised core competitiveness.&lt;/strong&gt; For companies with deteriorating fundamentals or “penny stocks,” the only correct action is to cut losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-much-to-buy-on-dips-for-adding-to-position&#34;&gt;How much to buy on dips for adding to position?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of accumulating during a decline is “buying lower,” but this must be executed with a plan and discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pyramidal Accumulation Strategy (Wide Base, Narrow Top):&lt;/strong&gt; This is a relatively conservative approach where the amount purchased increases as the price falls further.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Position Building:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish a &lt;strong&gt;base position&lt;/strong&gt; within a reasonable valuation range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops 15%-20% from the initial position building price. This is a common re-entry point, filtering out normal market fluctuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the first refill price (cumulative decline of approximately 30%-40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the second refill price (cumulative decline potentially reaching around 50%). At this point, it’s typically extreme panic. If the company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals remain solid, it’s a great buying opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-it-reasonable-to-add-to-the-position-a-few-times&#34;&gt;Is it reasonable to add to the position a few times?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To avoid overinvesting capital in a wrong decision, the number of times to add to the position should not be excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended number of additions: 2-3 times is appropriate.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk control:&lt;/strong&gt; If the stock price still doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve after 2-3 major add-on purchases, you must re-examine your initial investment logic. Unlimited adding may lead to a single holding ratio being too high, dragging down the entire investment portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain cash reserves:&lt;/strong&gt; Excessive additions will quickly deplete available funds, causing you to miss other better opportunities that appear in the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trading-discipline--the-core-for-newbies-progression&#34;&gt;Trading Discipline – The Core for Newbies’ Progression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If position sizing and stop-lossing are “techniques,” then trading discipline is the “way.” For novice traders, adhering to discipline is a decisive factor in whether they can survive in the market long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planning-and-execution-discipline-never-go-into-battle-without-a-plan&#34;&gt;Planning and Execution Discipline: Never Go into Battle Without a Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan Before Trade:&lt;/strong&gt; Every trade must be preceded by a clear understanding of the &lt;strong&gt;buy rationale, target price (take profit), and stop-loss level&lt;/strong&gt;. During the trade, strictly adhere to the plan and avoid emotional interference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Riding the Wave and Panic Selling:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcome the fear of missing out (FOMO) and panic selling emotions. Only execute trades at points that align with your plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-and-capital-management-discipline-survival-is-the-priority&#34;&gt;Risk and Capital Management Discipline: Survival is the Priority
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strict Stop-Loss, No Hesitation:&lt;/strong&gt; A stop-loss is the lifeline for protecting your capital. The most dangerous habit for beginners is to hold onto losing trades. Set your stop-loss levels at &lt;strong&gt;-5% to -10%&lt;/strong&gt;, and execute without hesitation upon reaching them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Add to Losing Trades to Average Down to Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a fatal error. If a trade proves to be wrong (falling below the stop-loss), the correct approach is to exit, not to invest more money to “dilute the cost.” This can turn a small mistake into a major disaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mindset-and-emotional-control-discipline-be-the-master-of-your-emotions&#34;&gt;Mindset and Emotional Control Discipline: Be the Master of Your Emotions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept Losses as Part of Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; No one can win every battle. View small losses as a necessary cost of trading, focusing on the long-term overall profit/loss ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Get Greedy from Profits, Don’t Be Bitter from Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; Break free from a “gambling mentality,” don&amp;rsquo;t take risks due to profits, and don’t retaliate with impulsive trades due to losses. Maintain a calm mindset and remain consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-and-review-discipline-continuous-evolution&#34;&gt;Learning and Review Discipline: Continuous Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain a Trading Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;  Detailed record of your thought process and results for each trade, with regular reviews to analyze successes and failures. This is the most effective way to self-improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stick to Your Circle of Competence:&lt;/strong&gt; Only invest in areas you understand and can truly comprehend. Avoid unfamiliar fields and complex financial products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patience-and-discipline-are-superior-to-everything-else&#34;&gt;Patience and Discipline are Superior to Everything Else
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a prudent Hong Kong stock investor, your goal isn’t to be a speculator dancing on the crest of market waves, but rather to be like a discerning general, orchestrating strategy from behind the scenes. Please treat &lt;strong&gt;position control&lt;/strong&gt; as your steadfast shield, &lt;strong&gt;opportunistic buying strategies&lt;/strong&gt; as your sharp spear, and &lt;strong&gt;trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt; as an immutable military code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the initial stages of trading, &lt;strong&gt;prioritize “minimizing losses” over “making big profits.”&lt;/strong&gt; Through continuous learning, practice, and review, you will ultimately achieve long-term, steady wealth appreciation in this market brimming with opportunities and challenges. Remember, patience and discipline are always more important qualities than predicting the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Productivity and Marketing</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/productivity-and-marketing/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 19:15:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/productivity-and-marketing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;“As I recall, Xiaomi was able to break through initially thanks to its solid product quality and distinctive cost-performance advantage – in those early years, other brands would often price similar models at four or five thousand yuan, while Xiaomi could keep the price under two thousand yuan. Many people were switching phones at that time, and they chose Xiaomi because of the ‘low-cost entry into high configuration.’”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-situation&#34;&gt;Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, in the past two or three generations of flagship phones, the upgrade momentum has noticeably weakened. Every time I look at new product parameters and features, it’s hard to have a “wow” moment – most are minor adjustments: such as camera algorithm optimization, slight battery life improvements, or simply changing the color scheme. There&amp;rsquo;s a lack of core changes that leave a lasting impression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After reading the full text of Xiaomi 17’s launch event, this feeling is even more pronounced — this generation’s upgrades are still limited, whether it’s performance or features, they haven’t stepped out of the “minor repairs” category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Actually, this isn&amp;rsquo;t just about Xiaomi; the entire digital technology industry now faces a similar situation: significant breakthroughs in hardware are becoming increasingly difficult to achieve, and the industry as a whole seems to be entering a slowdown. Unlike several years ago, when there were dazzling new developments every year – screen refresh rates increased, charging speeds doubled – it’s now much more difficult to achieve disruptive breakthroughs in hardware.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With many rational users dominating discussions on Zhihu (a Chinese Q&amp;amp;A platform), the related topics for Xiaomi 17&amp;rsquo;s launch are overwhelmingly critical, highlighting the small upgrade intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;marketing-prowess&#34;&gt;Marketing Prowess
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The runaway success of the Xiaomi SU7 unexpectedly reached a large number of previously overlooked female users, allowing Xiaomi to discover new user growth segments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost simultaneously, the “Xiaomi 16 directly renamed to Xiaomi 17” event perfectly capitalized on this attention – not only did this break external stereotypes about Xiaomi phones, but it also leveraged “porting” to generate buzz.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goodwill accumulated by the SU7’s users resonated with the public sentiment surrounding the rebranding: those interested in the SU7 would be curious about Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s phone products, and those who noticed the renaming would also be more inclined to learn about Xiaomi’s reputation thanks to the SU7’s positive word-of-mouth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, this synergy allowed the Xiaomi 17 launch event to successfully break through to a significant number of non-traditional users who were previously unfamiliar with Xiaomi.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Breaking Through the Cocoon: Examining Huawei and Xiaomi’s High-End Rivalry Following Xiaomi 17&#39;s Renaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:15:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era of information explosion, we all, to varying degrees, live within our own “information bubbles.” Algorithms recommend content that interests us, and over time, our horizons are subtly narrowed. This phenomenon seems equally applicable to the smartphone market – brand loyalty, media bias, and community voices are all weaving consumers into one bubble after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Xiaomi’s recent move, like a stone thrown into a still lake, has created ripples, attempting to break down this invisible barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Information bubbles, Xiaomi phone change 16 to 17 is not a temporary action, so much inventory, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s high-end path? Xiaomi’s high-end path ultimately relies on product strength to speak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomis-concealed-strategy-skipping-16-confronting-17&#34;&gt;Xiaomi’s “Concealed Strategy”: Skipping 16, Confronting 17
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi has resolutely renamed its upcoming flagship, set to be released as the “Xiaomi 17,” from the initially planned “Xiaomi 16,” revealing its intent – a direct challenge to Apple’s iPhone 17. This was not a spontaneous whim; for a company of this scale, any flagship product&amp;rsquo;s naming, preparation, and marketing is a massive undertaking that requires careful planning months, or even years in advance, involving millions of packaging materials, promotional items, and channel communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This renaming represents Xiaomi’s meticulously planned “concealed strategy,” a bold gamble on a brand-level strategic move. It sends a clear signal: Xiaomi is no longer content with the “value for money” label; instead, it intends to enter Apple and Huawei’s long-dominated high-end market territory with a “head-on confrontation” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By aligning itself digitally with the iPhone, Xiaomi aims to break consumers&amp;rsquo; ingrained thinking, placing its products in the same conversational context as top-tier flagships. This is Xiaomi’s bold and confident declaration of its product capabilities, and represents its most aggressive and decisive attempt to penetrate the high-end market after five years of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huaweis-high-end-path-rebuilding-glory-in-adversity&#34;&gt;Huawei’s High-End Path: Rebuilding Glory in Adversity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the topic of the high-end market is mentioned, Huawei is unavoidable. After experiencing the widely known external pressures, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s path to the high-end has been exceptionally difficult yet remarkably steadfast. Leveraging continued deep cultivation in imaging technology and breakthroughs in self-developed chips, Huawei’s Pura and Mate series remain benchmark products in the high-end market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s strategy is more like a “cultivation of inner strength.” It builds powerful technological barriers to entry, such as the XMAGE imaging brand, Kunlun Glass, HarmonyOS operating system, to create core differentiators for its products. Even when facing enormous challenges with supply chains, Huawei continues to enhance product quality, fostering extremely high user loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Huawei’s market share in China&amp;rsquo;s high-end market is steadily recovering – a story of victory based on resilience and product power. Its high-end path is one achieved through technological innovation and brand resilience, step by step, overcoming adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-battle-of-the-titans-is-ultimately-a-matter-of-product-power&#34;&gt;The Battle of the Titans is Ultimately a Matter of “Product Power”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s “One-Step Completion,” or Huawei’s “Steady and Solid,” their paths to the premium market differ, but ultimately, the landing point is always “product power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-end users are willing to pay a higher price not just for a brand logo, but also for comprehensive recognition of the technology, experience, design, and services behind the product. After the noise of marketing, what truly retains users is genuine experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus our attention on the products themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imaging Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; The Huawei Pura 70 Ultra continues to lead in the mobile photography field thanks to its unique retractable camera and powerful XMAGE imaging system. Meanwhile, Xiaomi 17 Series also features a camera system co-developed with Leica, along with new sensors and algorithms, aiming to challenge top industry standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; The Xiaomi 17 was the first to feature Qualcomm’s latest flagship Snapdragon chip, boasting natural advantages in performance release. Huawei, on the other hand, relies on iterative development of its self-designed chips, showcasing unique competitiveness in power consumption and system synergy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen &amp;amp; Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides are putting in their best efforts regarding screen quality, material, and design language. Kunlun Glass’s robust durability, combined with Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s continued investment in display technology, have become distinctive labels for their respective products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; HarmonyOS’s distributed capabilities enable Huawei to create a seamless ecosystem experience, while Xiaomi’s HyperOS is also working hard to build its own intelligent closed-loop ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketing strategies can break down consumers&amp;rsquo; “information silos,” allowing more people to see a brand’s ambition and transformation. But to truly let consumers “walk out of the house” willingly switching brands, it ultimately relies on solid product power to provide an irresistible choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi turned the digital “16” into “17,” which is not just a change in name but also a leap in its brand mentality and market strategy. Huawei, meanwhile, has rebuilt the foundation of its premium brand amidst storms. This battle between the two giants in China’s high-end smartphone market is only beginning its most exciting chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For consumers, this is undoubtedly good news. When all the giants lower their postures and refocus their attention on products themselves, we will ultimately see a more diverse and experience-driven era. And who can emerge victorious in this battle of the titans – time, and the fingertips of every user, will give the final answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Meituan’s Losses to Bond Mismatch</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the turbulent and unpredictable stock market, we often use faith and expectations as our compass, attempting to navigate through the fog and reach the shores of wealth. However, when our voyage deviates from the guidance of the compass, it’s easy to lose direction, even to run aground. This essay is about one such journey, beginning with an unwavering obsession with &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose and fell repeatedly amidst the waves of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clash-of-faith-and-reality-xiaomis-gains-and-losses&#34;&gt;The Clash of Faith and Reality: Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Gains and Losses
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, I bought into Xiaomi with unwavering &lt;strong&gt;faith&lt;/strong&gt; in Lei Jun and a hopeful vision for the company’s electric vehicles. At the time, faith was a powerful force, temporarily blinding me to Lei Jun’s shrewdness as a capitalist and overlooking the risks posed by the High-Level Flash Lightning Distribution Platform. Fortunately, several &lt;strong&gt;wave trading&lt;/strong&gt; operations ended with modest profits, giving me a sweet taste of entering the Hong Kong stock market for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this self-confidence soon followed. After making a small profit on &lt;strong&gt;Jiu Fang&lt;/strong&gt; stocks, I became somewhat &lt;strong&gt;dazed&lt;/strong&gt;, relying solely on the flow of net buying funds from the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect&lt;/strong&gt; indicator instead of rational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituans-waterloo-and-blind-re-positioning&#34;&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waterloo&amp;rdquo; and Blind Re-positioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by the flow of funds, I turned my attention to &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;. However, this time, I didn’t delve into the company’s &lt;strong&gt;financial data&lt;/strong&gt;, its &lt;strong&gt;historical trends&lt;/strong&gt;, or even realize the raging &lt;strong&gt;food delivery war&lt;/strong&gt; that was unfolding. When the stock price began to fall, I failed to cut my losses in time and instead blindly &lt;strong&gt;added to my position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares trading at HK$20,000-30,000, limitations on capital prevented me from managing my positions freely, which undoubtedly exacerbated my losses in Meituan. This lesson deeply made me realize that in the Hong Kong stock market, blind re-positioning is like trying to fill a constantly leaking bathtub with more water – it only accelerates the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-people-are-lucky---an-unexpected-gain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stupid People Are Lucky&amp;rdquo; - An Unexpected Gain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was worrying about Meituan&amp;rsquo;s losses, an unexpected turn of events occurred – I bought &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;. Although I didn’t hold onto it, I quickly sold it and used the profit to offset some of Meituan’s losses. This might be what’s meant by “stupid people are lucky,” allowing me to temporarily escape Meituan&amp;rsquo;s predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finance-more-important-fundamentals-than-investing&#34;&gt;Finance: More Important Fundamentals Than Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience also made me re-examine my &lt;strong&gt;financial management&lt;/strong&gt; approach, aside from the ups and downs of the stock market. At the time, I invested a sum intended for short-term emergency funds into &lt;strong&gt;Chinese bonds&lt;/strong&gt;. This money was meant to be used for payment within two months, but the short-term holding yield on the bonds wasn&amp;rsquo;t high, and it also posed liquidity issues. If I had instead chosen to deposit this money into a &lt;strong&gt;money fund&lt;/strong&gt;, I could have earned more stable returns and readily redeemed it, better meeting my funding needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
