<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Xiaomi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xiaomi/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Xiaomi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:25:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xiaomi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Breaking Through the Cocoon: Examining Huawei and Xiaomi’s High-End Rivalry Following Xiaomi 17&#39;s Renaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 10:15:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/breaking-through-the-cocoon-examining-huawei-and-xiaomis-high-end-rivalry-following-xiaomi-17s-renaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In an era of information explosion, we all, to varying degrees, live within our own “information bubbles.” Algorithms recommend content that interests us, and over time, our horizons are subtly narrowed. This phenomenon seems equally applicable to the smartphone market – brand loyalty, media bias, and community voices are all weaving consumers into one bubble after another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Xiaomi’s recent move, like a stone thrown into a still lake, has created ripples, attempting to break down this invisible barrier.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Information bubbles, Xiaomi phone change 16 to 17 is not a temporary action, so much inventory, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s high-end path? Xiaomi’s high-end path ultimately relies on product strength to speak&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomis-concealed-strategy-skipping-16-confronting-17&#34;&gt;Xiaomi’s “Concealed Strategy”: Skipping 16, Confronting 17
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi has resolutely renamed its upcoming flagship, set to be released as the “Xiaomi 17,” from the initially planned “Xiaomi 16,” revealing its intent – a direct challenge to Apple’s iPhone 17. This was not a spontaneous whim; for a company of this scale, any flagship product&amp;rsquo;s naming, preparation, and marketing is a massive undertaking that requires careful planning months, or even years in advance, involving millions of packaging materials, promotional items, and channel communications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This renaming represents Xiaomi’s meticulously planned “concealed strategy,” a bold gamble on a brand-level strategic move. It sends a clear signal: Xiaomi is no longer content with the “value for money” label; instead, it intends to enter Apple and Huawei’s long-dominated high-end market territory with a “head-on confrontation” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By aligning itself digitally with the iPhone, Xiaomi aims to break consumers&amp;rsquo; ingrained thinking, placing its products in the same conversational context as top-tier flagships. This is Xiaomi’s bold and confident declaration of its product capabilities, and represents its most aggressive and decisive attempt to penetrate the high-end market after five years of effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huaweis-high-end-path-rebuilding-glory-in-adversity&#34;&gt;Huawei’s High-End Path: Rebuilding Glory in Adversity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the topic of the high-end market is mentioned, Huawei is unavoidable. After experiencing the widely known external pressures, Huawei&amp;rsquo;s path to the high-end has been exceptionally difficult yet remarkably steadfast. Leveraging continued deep cultivation in imaging technology and breakthroughs in self-developed chips, Huawei’s Pura and Mate series remain benchmark products in the high-end market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Huawei’s strategy is more like a “cultivation of inner strength.” It builds powerful technological barriers to entry, such as the XMAGE imaging brand, Kunlun Glass, HarmonyOS operating system, to create core differentiators for its products. Even when facing enormous challenges with supply chains, Huawei continues to enhance product quality, fostering extremely high user loyalty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today, Huawei’s market share in China&amp;rsquo;s high-end market is steadily recovering – a story of victory based on resilience and product power. Its high-end path is one achieved through technological innovation and brand resilience, step by step, overcoming adversity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-battle-of-the-titans-is-ultimately-a-matter-of-product-power&#34;&gt;The Battle of the Titans is Ultimately a Matter of “Product Power”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s “One-Step Completion,” or Huawei’s “Steady and Solid,” their paths to the premium market differ, but ultimately, the landing point is always “product power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High-end users are willing to pay a higher price not just for a brand logo, but also for comprehensive recognition of the technology, experience, design, and services behind the product. After the noise of marketing, what truly retains users is genuine experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s focus our attention on the products themselves:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Imaging Capability:&lt;/strong&gt; The Huawei Pura 70 Ultra continues to lead in the mobile photography field thanks to its unique retractable camera and powerful XMAGE imaging system. Meanwhile, Xiaomi 17 Series also features a camera system co-developed with Leica, along with new sensors and algorithms, aiming to challenge top industry standards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Performance:&lt;/strong&gt; The Xiaomi 17 was the first to feature Qualcomm’s latest flagship Snapdragon chip, boasting natural advantages in performance release. Huawei, on the other hand, relies on iterative development of its self-designed chips, showcasing unique competitiveness in power consumption and system synergy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Screen &amp;amp; Design:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides are putting in their best efforts regarding screen quality, material, and design language. Kunlun Glass’s robust durability, combined with Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s continued investment in display technology, have become distinctive labels for their respective products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; HarmonyOS’s distributed capabilities enable Huawei to create a seamless ecosystem experience, while Xiaomi’s HyperOS is also working hard to build its own intelligent closed-loop ecosystem.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marketing strategies can break down consumers&amp;rsquo; “information silos,” allowing more people to see a brand’s ambition and transformation. But to truly let consumers “walk out of the house” willingly switching brands, it ultimately relies on solid product power to provide an irresistible choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi turned the digital “16” into “17,” which is not just a change in name but also a leap in its brand mentality and market strategy. Huawei, meanwhile, has rebuilt the foundation of its premium brand amidst storms. This battle between the two giants in China’s high-end smartphone market is only beginning its most exciting chapter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For consumers, this is undoubtedly good news. When all the giants lower their postures and refocus their attention on products themselves, we will ultimately see a more diverse and experience-driven era. And who can emerge victorious in this battle of the titans – time, and the fingertips of every user, will give the final answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Meituan’s Losses to Bond Mismatch</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the turbulent and unpredictable stock market, we often use faith and expectations as our compass, attempting to navigate through the fog and reach the shores of wealth. However, when our voyage deviates from the guidance of the compass, it’s easy to lose direction, even to run aground. This essay is about one such journey, beginning with an unwavering obsession with &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose and fell repeatedly amidst the waves of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clash-of-faith-and-reality-xiaomis-gains-and-losses&#34;&gt;The Clash of Faith and Reality: Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Gains and Losses
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, I bought into Xiaomi with unwavering &lt;strong&gt;faith&lt;/strong&gt; in Lei Jun and a hopeful vision for the company’s electric vehicles. At the time, faith was a powerful force, temporarily blinding me to Lei Jun’s shrewdness as a capitalist and overlooking the risks posed by the High-Level Flash Lightning Distribution Platform. Fortunately, several &lt;strong&gt;wave trading&lt;/strong&gt; operations ended with modest profits, giving me a sweet taste of entering the Hong Kong stock market for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this self-confidence soon followed. After making a small profit on &lt;strong&gt;Jiu Fang&lt;/strong&gt; stocks, I became somewhat &lt;strong&gt;dazed&lt;/strong&gt;, relying solely on the flow of net buying funds from the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect&lt;/strong&gt; indicator instead of rational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituans-waterloo-and-blind-re-positioning&#34;&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waterloo&amp;rdquo; and Blind Re-positioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by the flow of funds, I turned my attention to &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;. However, this time, I didn’t delve into the company’s &lt;strong&gt;financial data&lt;/strong&gt;, its &lt;strong&gt;historical trends&lt;/strong&gt;, or even realize the raging &lt;strong&gt;food delivery war&lt;/strong&gt; that was unfolding. When the stock price began to fall, I failed to cut my losses in time and instead blindly &lt;strong&gt;added to my position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares trading at HK$20,000-30,000, limitations on capital prevented me from managing my positions freely, which undoubtedly exacerbated my losses in Meituan. This lesson deeply made me realize that in the Hong Kong stock market, blind re-positioning is like trying to fill a constantly leaking bathtub with more water – it only accelerates the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-people-are-lucky---an-unexpected-gain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stupid People Are Lucky&amp;rdquo; - An Unexpected Gain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was worrying about Meituan&amp;rsquo;s losses, an unexpected turn of events occurred – I bought &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;. Although I didn’t hold onto it, I quickly sold it and used the profit to offset some of Meituan’s losses. This might be what’s meant by “stupid people are lucky,” allowing me to temporarily escape Meituan&amp;rsquo;s predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finance-more-important-fundamentals-than-investing&#34;&gt;Finance: More Important Fundamentals Than Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience also made me re-examine my &lt;strong&gt;financial management&lt;/strong&gt; approach, aside from the ups and downs of the stock market. At the time, I invested a sum intended for short-term emergency funds into &lt;strong&gt;Chinese bonds&lt;/strong&gt;. This money was meant to be used for payment within two months, but the short-term holding yield on the bonds wasn&amp;rsquo;t high, and it also posed liquidity issues. If I had instead chosen to deposit this money into a &lt;strong&gt;money fund&lt;/strong&gt;, I could have earned more stable returns and readily redeemed it, better meeting my funding needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
