<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>The Seven Seconds of a Fish&#39;s Experience on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/the-seven-seconds-of-a-fishs-experience/</link>
        <description>Recent content in The Seven Seconds of a Fish&#39;s Experience on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/the-seven-seconds-of-a-fishs-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war suddenly put on hold</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of tariffs in the 2025 trade war presented a cycle of &amp;ldquo;escalation — retaliation — consultation,&amp;rdquo; as the US-China competition shifted from tariff confrontation to rules-based competition. While short-term easing alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty remains, and it is necessary to monitor the continued impact on the global economy from WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People can&amp;rsquo;t earn money beyond their own understanding. The stock market crash triggered by the trade war this year, even now that losses have been largely recovered, has buried countless small investors along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analysis of the timeline for tariffs in trade wars in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a breakdown of the 2025 trade war tariff timeline, incorporating key events from China, the US, and other countries to illustrate the evolving dynamics of tariff policies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-tariff-escalation-and-retaliation&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Tariff Escalation and Retaliation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;US tariffs on China&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 2, the Trump administration signed Executive Order 14257, announcing a 34% tariff on goods imported from China, covering products from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 8th, the United States further increased tariffs on Chinese goods from 34% to 84% and signed Executive Orders 14259 and 14266, imposing additional tariffs on more products&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 10th: The White House revised an executive order, raising the total tariffs on China to 145%, and increasing tariffs on small packages (such as raising the tax rate on goods under $800 from 90% to 120%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s countermeasures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 4th, China announced tariffs of 34% on all goods originating from the United States, covering areas such as agricultural products, automobiles, and energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 10th, China will raise retaliatory tariffs from 34% to 84%, matching the escalation by the US side&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On April 12th: China canceled 91% of the tariffs imposed on US goods (corresponding to the portion cancelled by the US side) and suspended the implementation of the remaining 24% tariffs for 90 days, retaining 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tariff disputes among other countries&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US-Canada trade war: The United States has imposed a 25% tariff on steel and aluminum products from Canada. Canada retaliated by imposing tariffs on US$298 billion worth of American goods and filed a complaint with the WTO.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The EU is imposing tariffs of up to 25% on US goods, while Japan has expressed concerns about tariffs on US automobiles, calling the trade war &amp;ldquo;harmful to both sides.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-easing&#34;&gt;II. May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff Easing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China-U.S. High-Level Economic and Trade Talks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From May 10th to 11th, China and the United States held 16 hours of talks in Geneva, Switzerland, reaching the &amp;ldquo;China-US Geneva Trade Talks Joint Statement.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;May 12th: Both sides announced suspension of some tariffs
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The United States has suspended 24% of tariffs on China (for 90 days), retained 10%, and canceled additional taxes scheduled for April 8th and 9th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China will suspend 24% of retaliatory tariffs, retain 10%, and remove non-tariff measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sides agreed to establish a consultation mechanism and regularly hold trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reduction and rule-making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic Impact and Policy Adjustments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US domestic pressure: High tariffs are causing small and medium-sized enterprises to go out of business (such as Amazon sellers being forced to close due to soaring tariffs), and inflation expectations are heating up (core PCE is expected to rise to 3.3%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China&amp;rsquo;s rare earth countermeasures: China has tightened controls on rare earth exports, cracked down on smuggling, and impacted the US military industry and new energy supply chain, forcing them to seek waivers for tariffs on rare earths and other key minerals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The WTO and multilateral response&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China have separately filed appeals with the WTO over US steel and aluminum tariffs and &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; alleging violations of the non-discrimination principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala warned that US tariffs could cause a 1% contraction in global trade volume in 2025 and exacerbate the difficulties faced by developing countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exemption List and Industry Impact&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US exemption goods: A 37-page list covering strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT tubes exposes supply chain vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US tariffs on imported cars of 25% have led to a global forecast of a 2% decline in auto production, with a 9% reduction in North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Political and strategic game&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; but was criticized as unilateral bullying, triggering a backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is responding to protectionism by expanding market access (such as the China International Import Expo, and zero-tariff commitments) and attracting cooperation from developing countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-of-timeline&#34;&gt;Summary of Timeline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Time&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Event&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On April 2, 2025, the United States will impose a 34% tariff on China, covering goods from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On April 8th, the United States will raise tariffs on China to 84% and introduce new tax administrative orders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On April 10, China retaliated with a tariff of 34%, later raised to 84%; the US revised its tariffs to 145%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On April 12, the United States exempted certain goods (such as technology products), and China canceled 91% of its retaliatory tariffs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US, China and Japan talks in Geneva reached a joint statement agreeing to suspend 24% tariffs (for 90 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;On May 12, both sides announced a suspension of tariffs and a negotiation mechanism, easing trade tensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;five-trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Five: Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term easing and long-term competition: The suspension of tariffs between China and the US sends a positive signal, but structural contradictions (such as high technology and energy) remain, and midterm elections may affect policy continuity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global supply chain restructuring: Companies are accelerating adjustments to their supply chains, with Mexico and Southeast Asia benefiting from “nearshoring,” but rising costs may dampen the recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The predicament of multilateral mechanisms: The WTO dispute settlement mechanism is constrained, regional trade agreements (such as the UK-US agreement) have become alternative options, but this exacerbates fragmentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Jiangxi Province&#39;s Special Post and National Civil Servant Teacher Recruitment Data (2020-2025): Trends and Insights into Change</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/jiangxi-specialized-post-and-national-cadre-teacher-recruitment-data-trends-and-transformation-insights-2020-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 18:59:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/jiangxi-specialized-post-and-national-cadre-teacher-recruitment-data-trends-and-transformation-insights-2020-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2020-2025 teacher recruitment in Jiangxi Province shows a significant reduction trend: the number of special post teachers recruited decreased sharply from 6,617 to 32 (a decrease of 99.5%), and national cadre teachers decreased from 11,324 to 2,146 (a decrease of 81.1%). The proportion of core subjects (language, mathematics, English) remains stable but the total number is shrinking; although the proportion of subjects such as music, arts, and physical education has increased, the absolute numbers are limited (e.g., only 2 people were recruited in 2025 for each). Policy changes have implemented &amp;ldquo;one position reduction, one position replacement&amp;rdquo; staffing restrictions, with teacher resources shifting towards vocational education and remote areas, leading to a significant reduction in traditional primary and secondary school positions. In 2025, the planned number for some subjects was zero.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The number of specialized teaching positions recruited annually in Jiangxi Province, statistics for the past five years, categorized by subject and compiled into a table&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;——————&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to recruitment announcements and public data released by the Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education, the Department of Human Resources and Social Security, and other official bodies, here is a summary of the hiring situation for special-post teachers and national civil servant teachers from 2020-2025. It should be noted that &lt;strong&gt;the 2025 data represents planned recruitment numbers&lt;/strong&gt;, and subject details were not fully disclosed in some years; disciplines marked as &amp;ldquo;not subdivided&amp;rdquo; in the table represent total statistics or missing data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-2020-2025-jiangxi-province-special-post-teacher-recruitment-data&#34;&gt;I. 2020-2025 Jiangxi Province Special Post Teacher Recruitment Data
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Recruitment Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Ethics and Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fine Arts&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unspecified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,617&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;900&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;317&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6,020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;450&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;280&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,835&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;180&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;650&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,008&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;380&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;32&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-jiangxi-province-national-civil-servant-teacher-recruitment-data-for-2020-2025&#34;&gt;II. Jiangxi Province National Civil Servant Teacher Recruitment Data for 2020-2025
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Year&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Total Recruitment Number&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese Language&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Mathematics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physics&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chemistry&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Biology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Politics/Ethics &amp;amp; Rule of Law&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;History&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Geography&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Music&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Physical Education&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fine Arts&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Information Technology&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Unspecified&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2020&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;11,324&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;524&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2021&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;13,324&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;700&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;624&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2022&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2023&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;7,821&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1,200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;500&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;421&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2024&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3,957&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;750&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;600&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;350&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;257&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2025&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;2,146&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;400&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;380&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;300&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;250&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;150&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;120&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;80&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;86&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-data-description&#34;&gt;III. Data Description
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data sources: Annual recruitment announcements and official statistics from the Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education and the Human Resources and Social Security Department (actual figures for 2020-2024, planned figures for 2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject Classification
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specialized teachers focusing on compulsory education subjects in rural areas will be limited to a small number of core subject positions in 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The national curriculum covers all grade levels, with a more comprehensive range of subjects, including early childhood education and special education (not listed separately due to data not being subdivided)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trend analysis
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall recruitment sharply decreased: The number of specialized positions for teachers in 2025 is down 99.5% compared to 2020, and the number of national civil service teachers is down 81.1%, reflecting changes in population structure and adjustments to educational resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hot and Cold Topics in Academic Fields
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proportion of core subjects (Chinese, Mathematics, and English) remains stable, but recruitment volume is shrinking year by year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The proportion of subjects such as arts, physical education, and music has increased, but the absolute numbers are limited (e.g., only 2 students will be admitted for each of arts, physical education, and music in 2025)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some subjects (such as English) have stopped admitting new students due to a decrease in student numbers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Policy Background:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tightening of staffing quotas: Implementing a “replace one with one” policy, strictly controlling new quota allocations, and achieving a 68.6% proportion of off-quota positions in 2024&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Structural adjustments: Teacher resources will be directed towards vocational education and remote areas, with a significant reduction in hiring for traditional primary and secondary schools&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iv-recommendations-for-obtaining-complete-data&#34;&gt;IV. Recommendations for Obtaining Complete Data
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official channels
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Provincial Department of Education website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://jyt.jiangxi.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://jyt.jiangxi.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Provincial Department of Human Resources and Social Security website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://rst.jiangxi.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://rst.jiangxi.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tool Recommendations:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Provincial Public Personnel Examination Website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.jxpta.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.jxpta.com&lt;/a&gt;): Download of Past Job Postings&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Jiangxi Smart Education Platform (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.jxedu.gov.cn&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.jxedu.gov.cn&lt;/a&gt;): Special Post Teacher Data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Precautions:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some disciplines (such as Information Technology) are planned to have 0 enrollment in 2025, but recruitment may be supplemented through transfer admissions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Subject classifications may vary annually (such as the merging of “Morality and Rule of Law” with “Ideological and Political Education”), so please refer to the announcement for that year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For more detailed subject position distribution or regional breakdown data, we recommend contacting the local education bureau directly or querying through the official recruitment system&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Celestial Realm of Medical Education and the Butterfly Effect of the Dong Xi Ying Incident</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 01:08:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Peking Union “4+4” program (4 years of non-medical undergraduate studies + 4 years of medical doctoral studies) emphasizes interdisciplinary elite training. The Dong Xiying incident in 2025 exposed its reliance on family background (a lineage of medical professionals/researchers) for entry into the program, raising questions about the clarity of her academic credentials and allegations of plagiarism in her thesis. This incident revealed a contradiction between the elitism of the recruitment model and fairness, while issues regarding shortened training periods and supervised practice remain unresolved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompt&#34;&gt;Prompt
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog post: The origins and development of Concordia 4+4, core points: a corner of the celestial palace glimpsed by mortals, Dong Mingmei&amp;rsquo;s family background, it’s impossible for a normal medical PhD to graduate in eight years, Dong Mingmei&amp;rsquo;s family background and educational background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-palace-of-medicine-at-peking-union-medical-college-disassembled-a-44-system&#34;&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Palace of Medicine&amp;rdquo; at Peking Union Medical College, Disassembled: A 4+4 System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;4+4&amp;rdquo; program at Peking Union Medical College, launched in 2018, has been regarded as a “heavenly palace” for medical education in China. Designed to emulate the American medical education system, and guided by the principles of &amp;ldquo;embracing individuals with multidisciplinary backgrounds,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;embracing those who love medicine,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;embracing talent from all over the world,&amp;rdquo; this program seeks to create a break within the traditional medical education system. Its core logic lies in &lt;strong&gt;replacing the traditional 5+3+3 model (5 years for undergraduate + 3 years for master&amp;rsquo;s + 3 years for doctorate) with 4 years of non-medical undergraduate education + 4 years of doctoral training&lt;/strong&gt;, aiming to cultivate leading medical professionals with cross-disciplinary expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Celestial Palace&amp;rdquo; attribute is reflected in three dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elite Requirements for Admission:&lt;/strong&gt; Initially, applicants were required to have graduated from universities ranked within the top 50 by QS/Times/US News or among the top 10 US News liberal arts colleges (such as Barnard College). Later, while the requirement was relaxed to include institutions ranked within the top 100, a GPA of 3.6 or higher, or being in the top 30% of their class, remained necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The internationalization of training pathways: adopting an American-style organ-system integrated curriculum and PBL teaching method, students must complete core courses such as anatomy and pathology within 4 years, and participate in clinical internships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The controversy surrounding the quality of graduates: Although the pass rate for the national medical licensing examination (95.2%) is slightly lower than the traditional eight-year program (98.5%), most graduates enter hospitals affiliated with Peking Union Medical Center, and their career development shows no significant difference from the traditional path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dong-xi-ying-incident-cracks-in-heavenly-palace-seen-by-ordinary-people&#34;&gt;The Dong Xi-ying Incident: Cracks in &amp;ldquo;Heavenly Palace&amp;rdquo; Seen by Ordinary People
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 2025, a report of extramarital affairs involving Dr. Xiao Fei, a thoracic surgeon at the Sino-Japanese Friendship Hospital, unexpectedly revealed the &amp;ldquo;mysterious veil&amp;rdquo; surrounding the Peking Union Medical Center&amp;rsquo;s 4+4 project. The resume of the involved party, Dong Xiying, has raised three questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ambiguity of educational background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The controversy surrounding Dong Xiying&amp;rsquo;s academic credentials: she claims to have graduated from Columbia University, but in fact attended its affiliated college, Barnard College (ranked 14th in the 2025 US News liberal arts colleges). Although the school meets Concordia’s “Top 20 Liberal Arts Colleges” requirement, its diploma simultaneously lists &amp;ldquo;Barnard College&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Columbia University,&amp;rdquo; which can easily be mistaken for a degree from Columbia&amp;rsquo;s main campus in the domestic recruitment market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Professional Cross-Disciplinary Controversy&lt;/strong&gt;: The path of an undergraduate degree in economics combined with a doctorate in clinical medicine, while meeting the &amp;ldquo;multidisciplinary background&amp;rdquo; positioning of the 4+4 program, has been questioned for lacking a foundation in pre-medical coursework. Her doctoral dissertation, &amp;ldquo;Research on Multi-Modal Image Fusion Technology in Medical Image Analysis,&amp;rdquo; has been accused of high similarity to a Beijing University of Science and Technology invention patent, suspected of academic misconduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The particularity of family background&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic resource monopoly: His father is a secretary at the China Metallurgical Corporation Research Institute, his mother is an associate dean at the Beijing University of Technology Engineering Technology Research Institute, his grandfather is an academician in the field of imaging at Peking Union Medical College, his maternal grandparents are foreign academicians in the field of materials science, and his aunts and uncles are professors at Peking University. This &amp;ldquo;medicine + research + university&amp;rdquo; composite family background provides him with hidden resources such as letters of recommendation (requiring two biomedical associate professors) and scientific research cooperation (such as patents from Beijing University of Technology).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Career trajectory jumps: transitioning from thoracic surgery to urology during the residency period, with research spanning multiple fields including orthopedics, gastroenterology, and imaging – leading to accusations of &amp;ldquo;paving the way with resources.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amplification of the debate over the academic system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The rationale for time compression: traditional medical doctorates require 11 years (5+3+3), while the 4+4 program compresses this to 8 years. Although Peking Union Medical College emphasizes &amp;ldquo;curriculum integration&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;early clinical exposure,&amp;rdquo; some doctors point out that its clinical internship time (12 months) is still less than the traditional eight-year system (18 months), which may affect skill accumulation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The controversy over internship exemptions: Some internship bases allow 4+4 graduates to be exempted from one year of internship, raising concerns about undermining fairness in the industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-predicament-of-medical-education-behind-the-controversy&#34;&gt;The predicament of medical education behind the controversy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dong Xi-ying incident reflects the deep-rooted contradictions in China&amp;rsquo;s medical education system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Conflict Between Elitism and Fairness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;application-review system&amp;rdquo; of the 4+4 project is essentially a transplant of the American medical school model, but China lacks standardized exams like the MCAT, and subjective evaluations such as letters of recommendation and research experience are easily influenced by family background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data shows that among the 2023 graduates with a 4+4 program, 30% came from Tsinghua, Peking University, and Fudan University combined, 25% came from overseas prestigious universities, and family background had a significant impact on applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The realities of reform in the education system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The cost of time compression: The research output of 4+4 students (such as the number of papers) is significantly lower than that of the traditional eight-year system, and has been criticized for prioritizing clinical practice over research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different levels of recognition within the industry: Top-tier hospitals value the Peking Union Medical Center brand, while community hospitals are cautious about the clinical abilities of 4+4 program graduates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Dilemma of Integrating Medical Education with International Standards&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US 4+4 model requires passing the MCAT exam and completing a 3-7 year residency, while China&amp;rsquo;s 4+4 program simplifies the admission and residency stages, resulting in a superficial resemblance but not the substance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to data from the Ministry of Education, in the 2024 national enrollment for medical doctoral programs, the proportion of 4+4 projects is less than 5%, and their large-scale promotion still faces obstacles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-reconstructing-the-celestial-palace-order-of-medical-education&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Reconstructing the &amp;ldquo;Celestial Palace&amp;rdquo; Order of Medical Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controversy surrounding the Union 4+4 project is fundamentally a clash between elite education and public expectations. When a corner of &amp;ldquo;Tiangong&amp;rdquo; (meaning space station, metaphorically referring to top-tier medical training) is glimpsed by ordinary people, what&amp;rsquo;s exposed isn&amp;rsquo;t just flaws in individual cases, but deeper contradictions within the entire medical education system. Future reforms need to focus on three levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparent selection mechanisms: Introduce standardized tests (such as a Chinese version of the MCAT) to reduce the influence of subjective factors like letters of recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extend the residency training period: Restore the residency training time for 4+4 graduates to 3 years to ensure clinical competency standards are met&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen process supervision: Establish an academic integrity review mechanism and conduct rigorous originality verification for interdisciplinary research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;heavenly palace&amp;rdquo; of medical education should not be the privilege of a few, but rather a cradle for cultivating true medical elites. Only when fairness in selection mechanisms, rigor in the training process, and standardization in career development are comprehensively guaranteed can this “heavenly palace experiment” in medical education truly take root and flourish.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tariff storm, stock market crash</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 03:49:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, global stock markets have experienced sharp volatility, primarily due to the new round of comprehensive tariffs announced by US President Donald Trump, which has sparked market concerns about a global trade war and economic recession&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tariff policies trigger market panic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump announced last week that he would impose high tariffs on all imported goods, with tariffs of up to 50% on imports from China, aiming to correct what he called an unfair global trade system. This move has led to a panic sell-off in global markets as investors worry that escalating trade tensions will stifle global economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Global stock markets plunged sharply&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, major stock indexes suffered heavy losses. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell by more than 1,200 points, while the Nasdaq Composite Index dropped 4% and the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index fell 3.8%, entering bear market territory. Asian and European markets were also not spared, with the Nikkei 225 in Japan falling nearly 8% and European stock markets dropping 6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors seek safe-haven assets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with market volatility, investors are turning to safe-haven assets such as bonds and the yen. However, the market volatility index (VIX) has surged above 60, indicating heightened market panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economists warn of stagflation risk&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economists warn that tariff policies could lead to “stagflation” in the US economy – a situation where economic growth stagnates, inflation rises, and high unemployment coexist. JPMorgan Chase has raised the probability of a recession in the U.S. economy in 2025 to 60%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reactions from various governments and businesses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments around the world have stated that they will take retaliatory measures. For example, the EU trade commissioner said that it would begin imposing retaliatory tariffs on US goods on April 15th. The business community has also expressed concerns; Wall Street firms like Goldman Sachs have raised the probability of a US economic recession to 45%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Conclusion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, global markets are facing unprecedented challenges; investors need to closely monitor trade policy developments and market changes, and manage risks and asset allocation&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Nezha breaks out during Spring Festival season</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-nizha-breakthrough/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, we always gather as a family during the Spring Festival and watching movies has become an essential form of entertainment. This year&amp;rsquo;s Spring Festival season, &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; was incredibly popular, sparking discussions everywhere. The buzz is quite similar to that of &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; both films exuding a patriotic theme, which unexpectedly stirs up a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The unexpected success of &amp;ldquo;Nezha&amp;rdquo; during the Spring Festival season, a surge of inexplicable national pride, reminiscent of previous films like &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior,&amp;rdquo; with patriotic themes. While acknowledging significant progress, it&amp;rsquo;s not as good as it’s being made out to be. As a gamer, many aspects feel greasy. The fight scenes are heavily influenced by online games. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen numerous posts about people buying tickets for Nezha but not actually going to see the movie due to its box office performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-fight-scenes-lack-texture&#34;&gt;The fight scenes lack texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a gamer, and I usually spend my days immersed in various online game worlds, so I didn’t have high expectations for movies. But I couldn’t resist the hype around 《Moana》, everyone was talking about it, so I thought, why not take a look? When I walked into the theater and the visuals came on, I felt a “thud” in my heart. Although the production quality has improved considerably compared to before, some of the scenes looked quite greasy. And the fight scenes? They were too heavily influenced by online games. Having played games for so many years, this visual style is too similar to some game scenes, lacking the texture that a movie should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-movie-fans&#34;&gt;Crazy movie fans
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie, I came out and saw that quite a few people online said they bought tickets for &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; but didn&amp;rsquo;t actually watch it, all to boost its box office. I’m truly impressed by this move; it seems everyone is incredibly enthusiastic about this film and willing to do anything for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot&#34;&gt;Plot
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s think back to when &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; came out, when Wu Jing shouted, “Whoever dares offend China will be punished no matter how far away they are,” so many people were filled with excitement, feeling that our Chinese military was so powerful and our country so strong. Although &amp;ldquo;The Devil’s Bond&amp;rdquo; doesn&amp;rsquo;t have such direct patriotic slogans, it vividly showcases the essence of traditional Chinese culture. Nezha and Ao Bing, these mythological figures, we grew up listening to their stories, and the film portrays their grievances, love-hate relationships, and growth process with depth and emotion – isn’t that the charm of Chinese culture?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s talk about Nezha. Misunderstood and looked down upon since he was a child, yet he refused to give up, shouting &amp;ldquo;My fate is my own, not the heavens’.&amp;rdquo; This spirit is so much like the resilience ingrained in our Chinese people. No matter how great the difficulties we face, we won&amp;rsquo;t bow down, but rely on our own efforts to change our destiny. Ao Bing also exemplifies this – burdened with a family mission, seemingly cold but actually kind-hearted, willing to sacrifice himself for his friends. We often see such friendship and responsibility in real life, don’t we?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-progress-of-animated-films&#34;&gt;The progress of animated films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t perfect in some aspects, it combines traditional Chinese culture with modern film technology quite well, allowing us to see the progress of Chinese animated films. Just like how &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; showed everyone China’s breakthrough in the action genre. This kind of progress makes us feel that Chinese cinema can shine on the international stage and allow foreigners to appreciate the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, no matter where we go, we carry our country and culture in our hearts. Movies like &amp;ldquo;Ne Zha&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Wolf Warrior&amp;rdquo; are like keys, opening the door to a sense of national pride deep within us. They allow us to feel the strength of our nation and the charm of our culture amidst laughter and joy, also inspiring us to work hard in our respective positions and contribute our share to the prosperity and development of our country. This is probably why these films have become so popular and resonate with a sense of national pride. In the future, I hope there will be more movies like this, keeping this feeling of national pride full and overflowing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Four Measures Issued to Boost Real Estate and Central Bank</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promote-real-estate-central-bank-four-measures/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 20:42:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promote-real-estate-central-bank-four-measures/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove interest rate limits on housing loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Starting tomorrow, the housing fund interest rate will be lowered by 0.25%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The down payment ratio for first-time homebuyers has been lowered to 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;30 billion yuan affordable housing refinancing loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;abolish-the-interest-rate-policy-limits-for-first-time-and-second-time-commercial-personal-housing-loans-at-the-national-level&#34;&gt;Abolish the interest rate policy limits for first-time and second-time commercial personal housing loans at the national level
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Shanghai Head Office, branches in each province, autonomous region, directly-administered municipality and separately planned cities; all state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and all joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, adapt to the new changes in the supply-demand relationship of China’s real estate market and people&amp;rsquo;s new expectations for high-quality housing, and promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, we hereby notify you of the following matters regarding the adjustment of interest rate policies on commercial personal housing loans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I. Abolish the interest rate policy limits for first-time and second-time home commercial loans at the national level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China’s provincial branches, in accordance with the principle of city-specific policies, will guide each province’s local market interest rate pricing self-discipline mechanism. Based on the real estate market conditions within their jurisdictions and the requirements of local governments, they will independently determine whether to set lower limits for commercial individual housing loan interest rates and the level of those limits (if any).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banking and financial institutions should, based on the interest rate lower limits determined by each provincial market interest rate pricing self-discipline mechanism (if any), and combined with their own operating conditions, customer risk profiles, and other factors, reasonably determine the specific interest rate level for each loan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-interest-rate-for-personal-housing-provident-fund-loans-has-been-lowered-by-025-percentage-points&#34;&gt;The interest rate for personal housing provident fund loans has been lowered by 0.25 percentage points
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Shanghai Head Office, branches in each province, autonomous region, directly-administered municipality and separately planned cities; policy banks, state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and various joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China has decided that starting May 18, 2024, the interest rates for individual housing provident fund loans will be reduced by 0.25 percentage points. The interest rates for first-time home loans with terms of less than or equal to 5 years and over 5 years will be adjusted to 2.35% and 2.85%, respectively. The interest rates for second-time home loans with terms of less than or equal to 5 years and over 5 years will be adjusted to no lower than 2.775% and 3.325%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-down-payment-ratio-will-be-adjusted-to-no-less-than-15&#34;&gt;The down payment ratio will be adjusted to no less than 15%
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Shanghai Head Office, branches in each province, autonomous region, municipality directly under the central government, and separately planned cities; all regulatory bureaus of the National Financial Regulatory Administration; state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee and the State Council, adapt to the new changes in the supply and demand relationship of China&amp;rsquo;s real estate market, and meet people’s new expectations for high-quality housing, and to promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, we hereby notify you of the following regarding policies on individual home loans:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For resident families purchasing commercial residential properties through loans, the minimum down payment ratio for first-home commercial personal housing loans is adjusted to no less than 15%, and the minimum down payment ratio for second-home commercial personal housing loans is adjusted to no less than 25%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on this, each provincial branch of the People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China and each sub-division of the National Financial Regulatory Administration will, in accordance with the requirements of local government regulation and following the principle of city-specific policies, independently determine the lower limit for the first and second home down payment ratio for commercial personal housing loans within their respective jurisdictions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-central-bank-will-establish-a-rmb-300-billion-affordable-housing-refinancing-program&#34;&gt;The central bank will establish a RMB 300 billion affordable housing refinancing program
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 4 p.m., representatives from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the Ministry of Natural Resources, the People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, and the National Financial Regulatory Administration gathered at a routine policy briefing held by the State Council to introduce related policies regarding ensuring housing delivery&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the meeting, Vice Governor of the People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Yao Ling announced that the central bank will establish a 300 billion yuan affordable housing refinancing facility to support local state-owned enterprises in acquiring completed but unsold commercial properties at reasonable prices for use as rental or sales-based affordable housing. This is expected to stimulate 500 billion yuan in bank loans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the central bank, the term for affordable housing lending is one year, with a possible extension of four times, and an interest rate of 1.75%. It targets 21 nationwide banks, encouraging them to provide loans to local state-owned enterprises selected by municipal governments to acquire completed but unsold commercial properties for use as affordable housing. The acquired commercial properties are strictly limited to those already built and unsold by real estate developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China will soon release a notice on establishing affordable housing refinancing loans regarding this policy&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Starch-tube snacks and roadside stalls: The news influence of capital</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sausages-and-street-vendors-capital-news-influence/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:31:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sausages-and-street-vendors-capital-news-influence/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;315 did not actually report on the chicken bone gelatin issue; this problem itself is confusing the CCTV 3·15 Gala’s official exposure with other food safety hotspots that occurred at the same time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;journalism&#34;&gt;Journalism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 315 Gala listed nine manufacturers, but none of them produced sausage. Now, the nominated brands have lost all their buzz, while this focus on &amp;ldquo;tang mian chang&amp;rdquo; (starch sausage) – a popular snack found everywhere and likely the most common one – feels like it&amp;rsquo;s being unfairly targeted. I traced the news source to a CCTV report published on 3.15 investigating ham sausages, but it only listed ingredients from several manufacturers without finding any issues. Then, this reporter claimed, through an employee of a factory, that chicken bone meal was sometimes used as a substitute for chicken – essentially hearsay. She then asked pet food stores selling chicken bone meal on Taobao if it&amp;rsquo;s safe for human consumption. Isn’t that ridiculous? Would a pet food vendor actually recommend people eat it? Subsequently, rumors spread claiming starch sausage contained chicken bone meal, which is unsafe for humans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The current situation is likely causing many factories to close down, and hundreds of thousands of small vendors across the country are facing a predicament where they can&amp;rsquo;t sell their goods and have no business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-of-the-human-world&#34;&gt;Reality of the human world
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to a report by the Xiaoxiang Morning News on March 17th, on March 16th in Sanmenxia, Henan, the day after the “starch-paste sausage collapse incident,” a woman set up her stall to sell starch-paste sausages. However, two hours passed without any customers, and she eventually quietly ate the sausages herself. The person who filmed the scene said that he used to be able to eat four or five starch-paste sausages at a time, but after learning about the chicken bone powder inside, he resolutely stopped eating them. That day, curious to see if anyone would still buy starch-paste sausages after the exposure, he witnessed the vendor selling not a single one in two hours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auntie has no idea about this tapioca sausage incident; she just knows that suddenly, nobody is buying her grilled sausages today&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old woman isn&amp;rsquo;t wrong; she’s just trying to feed her family. The old woman doesn&amp;rsquo;t even know if the product has problems or is qualified, nor does she know what bone glue is. They don&amp;rsquo;t understand the internet; they are simply people at the bottom trying to find a way to survive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The starch sausage collapsed, but those paying the bill are individual grassroots vendors. It&amp;rsquo;s a painful process.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;regulatory-failure&#34;&gt;Regulatory failure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, one afternoon, a colleague of mine who had come from out of town and I went to lunch, passing by a stall selling grilled sausages and stir-fried beef&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I blurted out, &amp;ldquo;Do people still eat black technology sausages and sirloin like this?&amp;rdquo; Because in my mind, the last time I ate a starch sausage was probably about fifteen years ago&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My colleague hesitated for a moment, then said tactfully, &amp;ldquo;Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s because you live in a big city. In our hometown, a small place like that, pickled vegetables, instant noodles, and sausage are part of everyday life.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I was in school, my dad would only let me have a grilled sausage if I got a perfect score on my test. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t because they were unhygienic; it’s just that a grilled sausage cost 1.5 yuan—enough to buy two jin of vegetables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first heard the idea of calling instant noodles, carbonated drinks, and spicy-flavored fish snacks &amp;ldquo;junk food&amp;rdquo; after I started studying in Beijing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized the arrogance in my careless words just now and remained silent. But this incident left a deep impression on me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this is the daily life of most ordinary people in China&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Their lives lacked the sophisticated &amp;ldquo;Mediterranean diet,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;green organic vegetables,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;non-GMO soybeans.&amp;rdquo; They only cared about whether they could buy some cheap yet delicious vegetables, meat, and snacks, allowing the whole family to enjoy their few moments of happiness&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the items on the shelves, what are they made of, whether they will poison their health, and if there are any peculiar chemical ingredients&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was never something they should care about or understand&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They simply believed that if there were any problems, someone would take care of it and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t appear on the shelves&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But after watching the 315 gala, everyone realized that wasn&amp;rsquo;t the case&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The electronic scales in markets and gas pumps at gas stations can be fitted with high-tech modified motherboards, requiring content creators to risk being assaulted while filming videos so that regulators can finally realize the issue and take action&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cured pork with pickled plums in live-streaming rooms and the powdered sausage sold at street stalls were actually made from rotten meat and bone powder. It took CCTV reporters to go undercover and film footage before anyone would verify it or investigate the source and origin of the goods.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;health tonic wine&amp;rdquo; heavily promoted on TV channels and airport advertisements needed someone to release a video exposing its secrets before it was suddenly removed overnight and disappeared from public view&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is once a year&amp;rsquo;s 315 enough to drop five or six products that have been selling for a long time, just like this?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Who else would they turn to after already having eaten and bought from them?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Dongfang Zhenxuan&#39;s Short Essay Controversy: A Clash of Culture and Commerce</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/dongfang-zhenxuan-essay-controversy-culture-vs-commerce/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 18:57:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/dongfang-zhenxuan-essay-controversy-culture-vs-commerce/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Oriental Select incident involving short essays is a network controversy triggered by the denial from the official Oriental Select account that Dong Yuhui was the author of all the short essays. The truth is now impossible to verify, and corporate power struggles have pushed this matter into the spotlight.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The myth of the seven-second memory span of fish – I&amp;rsquo;ve been letting AI write about it, trying both &lt;code&gt;Bing AI&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;ChatGPT plus&lt;/code&gt;. The former provides more complete information, still leveraging a larger pool of data from search engines. However, its blog post output is incomplete and the formatting feels rigid. The latter generates content based on keywords, which isn’t always comprehensive, but can produce full blog posts. Providing reference URLs allows it to optimize the generated draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dong Yuhui incident involving Oriental Selection is a dispute over copyright and authorship, beginning on December 5, 2023, and involving a series of interactions between the livestreamer Dong Yuhui and Oriental Selection. This controversy not only reveals the complexity of business operations but also prompts deep reflection on contemporary commercial culture and online society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-5-2023-event-start&#34;&gt;December 5, 2023: Event Start
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oriental Selection released a teaser video, and host Dong Yuhui&amp;rsquo;s recitation of a &amp;ldquo;short essay&amp;rdquo; quickly went viral&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dongfang Zhenxuan stated in video comments that these short essays were mostly created by the copywriting team and not entirely written by Dong Yuhui&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-13-2023-dong-yu-huis-response&#34;&gt;December 13, 2023: Dong Yu Hui&amp;rsquo;s Response
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dong Yu Hui published a long article, opposing the stigmatization of anyone under the guise of &amp;ldquo;fan circles,&amp;rdquo; and stating his position on the matter&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-14-2023-managements-response&#34;&gt;December 14, 2023: Management&amp;rsquo;s Response
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oriental Selection CEO Sun Dongxue released an apology video, admitting flaws in the company&amp;rsquo;s management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dong Yuhui also received an apology from Dongfang Zhenxuan Chairman Yu Minhong, who responded to the incident&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-16-2023-major-decision&#34;&gt;December 16, 2023: Major Decision
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Oriental Selection officially announced that Sun Dongxu is removed from his CEO position, and Yu Minhong will concurrently serve as CEO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On the same day, Yu Minhong issued an apology letter stating that he would remove the blacklisting of netizens in the livestreaming room&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;december-18-2023-dong-yu-huis-new-role&#34;&gt;December 18, 2023: Dong Yu Hui&amp;rsquo;s New Role
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental Education &amp;amp; Technology Group has appointed Dong Yuhui as Cultural Assistant to the Chairman of New Oriental Education &amp;amp; Technology Group, and concurrently Vice President of New Oriental Tourism Group&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yu Minhong revealed that he will establish a studio with Dong Yuhui and open new live streaming accounts and rooms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-and-reflection&#34;&gt;Conclusion and Reflection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This incident is not only a dispute over copyright and authorship, but also reflects the collision of culture and commerce at a deeper level. In the context of this digital age characterized by fragmentation, the ownership of content creation has become a topic worthy of deep consideration. The Oriental Select short essay event is not just a media storm; it&amp;rsquo;s a profound reflection on contemporary commercial culture and online society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As observers, how should we view this collision of culture and commerce? While pursuing commercial interests, how can we protect and respect the creators&amp;rsquo; labor fruits? These questions are worthy of deep reflection by each of us&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The curtain-raising of anti-corruption in finance</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China: Efforts to combat corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector must be intensified, and addressing the “four vices” should be pursued thoroughly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-political-bureau-of-the-communist-party-of-china&#34;&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China (CPC) held a meeting on September 27 to review the comprehensive report on the findings of the first round of inspections by the CPC Central Commission for Discipline Inspection during the 20th CPC National Congress. General Secretary of the CPC Xi Jinping presided over the meeting. The meeting emphasized that, taking the rectification of issues identified through inspections as an opportunity, it is necessary to further strengthen the Party’s overall leadership, urge inspected Party organizations to enhance their political awareness and earnestly fulfill the responsibilities and missions entrusted by the CPC Central Committee, continuously strengthen the core functions and core competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the essential material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, increase the efforts of financial institutions in serving the real economy and national strategies, and promote high-quality development. It is necessary to balance development and security, firmly establish a bottom-line and extreme thinking mindset, take effective measures to prevent and resolve major risks, and resolutely safeguard the safety threshold. Efforts should be made to deepen the comprehensive and strict governance of the Party, tighten and implement the responsibility of Party committee secretaries as first responsible persons, the “one-post, two-responsibilities” system for members of leading bodies, and the supervisory responsibilities of disciplinary inspection and supervision organs, with a particular focus on strengthening supervision over &amp;ldquo;top leaders&amp;rdquo; at all levels. Efforts should also be increased to combat corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, address issues related to “formalism and bureaucracy,” and deepen investigations and rectification efforts, promoting a system where officials dare not, cannot, and do not want to engage in corruption. It is necessary to earnestly implement the Party’s organizational principles for the new era, strengthen leading body construction, cadre and talent team building, and grassroots Party organization construction. The results of inspections should be comprehensively utilized to deepen reform, improve systems, promote source governance, and facilitate a combination of curative and preventative measures. (Xinhua)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Causing major financial risks! Liu Liange, former secretary of the Communist Party Committee and chairman of China Banking Regulatory Commission, has been expelled from the Party&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission, with the approval of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission has initiated an investigation into Liu Liange, former secretary of the party committee and chairman of Bank of China, for serious violations of discipline and law
After investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original aspirations and mission, failed to resolutely implement the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee, neglected his responsibilities in financial risk prevention and control, extensively interfered with credit projects in violation of regulations, illegally disbursed loans, resulting in major financial risks. He performed poorly in fulfilling the principal responsibility for comprehensively strengthening discipline and governance, seriously damaged the political ecology of his unit, secretly brought prohibited books and publications into the country, and deliberately resisted organizational inspections. He disregarded the spirit of the Central Eight-point Regulation, violated regulations by accepting gifts and cash, entering private clubs, and receiving skiing and travel arrangements, and long-term borrowed vehicles belonging to those he managed. He failed to report personal matters as required, did not truthfully explain issues during organizational inquiries, and improperly appointed, adjusted, or promoted cadres based on personal considerations. He engaged in commercial activities and operated enterprises illegally; interfered with funds lending in violation of regulations and privately retained classified materials. His morals were corrupt, his family conduct was improper, and he failed to properly guide and educate his relatives. He had no bottom line for discipline and law, abused his power for personal gain, “relied on finance to make money from finance,” used his position to seek benefits for others in areas such as loan financing and project cooperation, and illegally accepted large sums of property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu Liange seriously violated Party political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline, and daily life discipline, constituting serious official misconduct and suspected bribery and illegal loan disbursement crimes. He failed to restrain himself before and after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, with severe consequences and a negative impact. In accordance with regulations such as the &amp;ldquo;Regulations on Party Discipline,&amp;rdquo; the &amp;ldquo;Law on Supervision of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China,&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Law on Administrative Punishment of Civil Servants,&amp;rdquo; following deliberation by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and approval by the Communist Party of China Central Committee, it was decided to impose the disciplinary action of expulsion from the Party on Liu Liange; revoke the benefits he was entitled to according to regulations; terminate his qualifications as a delegate to the 20th National Congress of the CPC; confiscate the proceeds of his violations and illegal activities; and transfer the issues involving suspected crimes to the procuratorial organ for examination and prosecution, along with all related assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Li Xiaopeng, former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Guangda Group, has been removed from his party membership and public office due to serious violations of discipline and law. (CCTV News)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission reported, according to news from the Disciplinary Committee and Supervisory Commission of Guizhou Province: Li Zhiming, former Party Secretary and Chairman of Guizhou Bank, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and investigation by the Disciplinary Committee and Supervisory Commission of Guizhou Province&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huijin-increases-its-holdings-in-the-four-largest-banks-after-eight-years&#34;&gt;Huijin increases its holdings in the four largest banks after eight years
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, the four largest state-owned commercial banks – Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank – each announced that they had received increased holdings from Huijin Capital, amounting to 27.61 million shares, 37.27 million shares, 24.89 million shares, and 18.38 million shares respectively; Huijin Capital plans to continue increasing its holdings in the four banks on the secondary market within the next six months&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>China&#39;s COVID-19 lifting of restrictions</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-coronavirus-unlocking/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 19:22:04 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-coronavirus-unlocking/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The policy was announced very suddenly and implemented quickly; health codes are no longer required, nor are they checked at public venues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Browsing the New York Times Chinese website, the entire layout is discussing China reopening&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do not evaluate policies, just record what is happening around you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beijing never had a &amp;ldquo;clearance&amp;rdquo; in the first place. With the opening of restrictions, it spread rapidly, with widespread infections. Among my friends, no one has experienced severe illness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shenzhen, bordering Guangzhou, has also begun to develop rapidly; I&amp;rsquo;m based in Shanghai, but due to my company being near the suburbs, there hasn’t been widespread infection yet when I’m writing this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The protective measures in my hometown were inadequate, leading to widespread diffusion afterward&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It feels roughly the same as before, suddenly loosening up, with a new policy every week until it was fully opened&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can&amp;rsquo;t be denied that the three-year zero-COVID policy had an effect, fostering a sense of acceptance and going with the flow&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Pelosi visits Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 22:57:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not understanding politics, not making comments, just recording this &amp;ldquo;carnival&amp;rdquo; on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random-thoughts&#34;&gt;Random thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tangshan beating incident and the elementary school textbook cultural invasion incident from a while ago, I wonder how many people still remember. These hot topics in the news have become numbing; there&amp;rsquo;s no much feeling, just watching dramas as usual after work, treating it like entertainment. The economic situation is already like this, and an outbreak of war won’t make things better. I don’t understand politics, and I won’t comment on it, just recording this &amp;ldquo;carnival&amp;rdquo; online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview-of-the-2022-sichuanyaan-earthquake&#34;&gt;Overview of the 2022 Sichuan–Ya’an earthquake
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2022 visit to Taiwan by Nancy Pelosi, often referred to as Pelosi&amp;rsquo;s visit to Taiwan, refers to the trip to Taiwan during a tour of Asian countries by Nancy Pelosi, the 52nd Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives, in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the US House of Representatives Speaker being considered the third most powerful figure in the United States and planning a visit to Taiwan, with the date approaching China&amp;rsquo;s People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army Foundation Day on August 1st in the short term and the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the 2022 US elections, and the 2022 local elections in Taiwan in the long term, the Chinese government has expressed strong protests. The People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army dispatched destroyer formations to the northeast waters of the Taiwan Strait and mobilized two carrier strike groups, Shandong and Liaoning. The Eastern Theater Command and Southern Theater Command conducted large-scale live-fire exercises in the East China Sea and South China Sea respectively. On the US side, the Ronald Reagan Carrier Strike Group has arrived near the Taiwan Strait to protect a possible visit by Pelosi, and multiple batches of reconnaissance aircraft and aerial refueling tankers have been deployed to the US military base at Kadena Air Force Base in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden had a video conference before the visit, which involved the Taiwan issue. Taiwanese and international media reported that Speaker Nancy Pelosi and a congressional delegation are expected to arrive at Taipei Songshan Airport on August 2, spend the night there, and meet with Republic of China President Tsai Ing-wen and other high-ranking government officials on August 3. Some observers believe that Pelosi’s visit to Taiwan could trigger a new crisis in the Taiwan Strait, the first since the 1996 Taiwan Strait Missile Crisis over two decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-11&#34;&gt;08-11
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s basically settled today, and the headlines for this period have mostly been about various naval exercises. Zhihu has also been working hard, changing up the way they update the trending topics every day, all talking about this same thing. The editor worked hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Shanghai Hot Pot Lockdown</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/shanghai-yuanyang-pot-closure/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 23:03:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/shanghai-yuanyang-pot-closure/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The leadership team insisted just a couple of days ago that Shanghai wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be locked down, saying it was very important. But now, either pressured by the situation or to protect their own reputations, they’ve taken a cross-river approach. First, they sealed off the area across from Huangpu River for a period, and then they will seal off this side of the river.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;city-closure&#34;&gt;City closure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I had very little memory of SARS as a child, having experienced it back then. Later, when I saw related information, I realized that it ended before widespread diffusion occurred because the incubation period was relatively short. I remember being in elementary school at the time, and we were dismissed early every day. The classroom always smelled of disinfectant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been almost three years since the COVID-19 pandemic started in late 2019. People working outside their hometowns have gotten used to it, wearing masks when necessary. This wave of the epidemic in Shanghai initially originated from Hong Kong and spread to Shenzhen through cross-border entry points. The situation here in Shanghai was also caused by a series of imported cases from Hong Kong. The authorities finally announced that the outbreak was due to inadequate protective measures at quarantine hotels, leading to the spread of the virus after mutation. While the toxicity of the mutated virus has weakened, its transmission speed has increased through the hotel&amp;rsquo;s ventilation system. Initially, it wasn’t serious and could have been contained.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are always confident. The leaders in Shanghai are the same. They will choose us for our gridded risk control, precise prevention and control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results are now visible to everyone; the new cases have accumulated beyond 20,000. Driven to desperation, they chose a lockdown, but avoided using the term &amp;ldquo;lockdown&amp;rdquo; externally, as they had previously stated in press conferences that Shanghai did not need a lockdown, preserving what little face they had left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-groceries&#34;&gt;Buy groceries
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The food delivery industry is a new sector created by the internet. The core of it is that you need someone to deliver for you, right? But due to widespread lockdowns caused by the pandemic, businesses could operate, but there was no one to make deliveries – the entire chain lacked its final link. People outside might not understand why everyone in Shanghai, an international metropolis, suddenly rushed to buy groceries. But if you think about it, it makes sense. Most people are from out of town, working and living in rented apartments. They usually eat at company cafeterias or restaurants, rarely cooking at home. When the usual routes were blocked, those who could afford it started buying groceries. Because this lockdown announcement wasn&amp;rsquo;t given in advance, most people didn’t have a significant stockpile of food or vegetables. This led to the rush seen in the videos, and that kind of gathering directly caused another wave of infections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;industry&#34;&gt;Industry
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone I know works in the IT industry. The pandemic affected me, and I experienced working from home. Back in 2019, I was stuck at home for almost a month, rescheduling train tickets countless times, unable to determine when I could return to Shenzhen. It&amp;rsquo;s unimaginable how people in the catering, tourism, or many service industries have been getting by these past few years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Decline of Capital Monopoly and the Online Education Industry</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The stock market has fallen sharply over the past two trading days, and new investors have experienced the risks of the market. Our country is about to enter an aging stage, and the birth rate data is bleak – the decline far exceeded estimates from relevant experts. Industries hindering the birth rate will be cracked down on by our party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-workload&#34;&gt;Reducing student workload
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We, born in the 90s, didn&amp;rsquo;t have so many extracurricular classes or tutoring sessions. After school, we would just run wild and play – partly because our families couldn’t afford it, and partly because tutoring services hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet established a brand reputation to convince parents. Twenty years have passed. Starting in 2019, the capitalization of K12 education began, with companies like Yuanfudao emerging as leading online tutoring platforms. With capital backing, they concentrated resources to create various prestigious tutoring programs, and even exorbitant fees couldn&amp;rsquo;t deter parental enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process of urbanization, many parents have broken free from poverty and achieved upward mobility through education. Their work as office workers leaves them with little time to care for their children; they are under immense pressure themselves and don&amp;rsquo;t want their children to fall behind their peers. It’s difficult for someone from a humble background to rise above it without an appropriate education. In China, ordinary families find it hard to maintain or further advance their social class without one. If a child enters vocational high school, the perceived decline in social status is something most parents cannot accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look back at why extracurricular tutoring exists, and why parents need it. The knowledge and example questions in textbooks are easy to understand, but many subjects cover a broad range of topics, though they are mostly superficial concepts without much depth. Talent selection mechanisms require a certain degree of differentiation, which leads to a contradiction: test questions based solely on textbook knowledge cannot achieve the screening effect and need to be expanded horizontally and vertically. These areas are impossible for teachers to cover in class, and this space has fostered the growth of extracurricular tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document contains a large amount of content, with thirty detailed provisions regulating various aspects. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the guiding document outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce overall homework volume and duration comprehensively, alleviating students&amp;rsquo; excessive workload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the quality of schools’ after-school services to meet students&amp;rsquo; diverse needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly regulate and govern off-campus tutoring activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly improve the quality of education and teaching, ensuring that students learn well and master their studies while at school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen supporting measures and enhance capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully organized and implemented, striving for practical results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elite-education&#34;&gt;Elite education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the education industry, there&amp;rsquo;s another phenomenon: an increasing number of private schools are emerging, and public schools are struggling to provide sufficient high-quality resources (leading to the rise of academic district housing). Various large-scale education groups attract quality teachers with high salaries, establish excellent teaching environments, and gradually build their own brands. The most famous example is the &lt;strong&gt;Yancheng Model&lt;/strong&gt;. In my hometown, the average company salary is around 3,000 yuan, while a good private elementary school can cost between 9,000 to 10,000 yuan for an entire year of tuition. Education groups create a virtuous cycle: I charge high tuition fees, but the teachers are excellent, and the students achieve good grades. This allows me to raise tuition fees, and parents will still send their children here. Public school resources (teachers) will gradually be attracted to private schools, eventually becoming synonymous with inferior education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithm-squeezing&#34;&gt;Algorithm squeezing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data indicates that Meituan has nearly four million signed-up riders, with 400,000 to 500,000 active riders. Many rely on this work to support their families. Endless algorithmic pressure squeezes delivery time, reducing people to quantifiable units and feeding them into calculations. It constantly explores the breaking point of delivery personnel. They think they&amp;rsquo;re clever, &lt;strong&gt;disregarding human nature to serve capital&lt;/strong&gt;. The market is here; let’s play it well, sustainably, rather than &lt;strong&gt;monopolizing and granting special privileges – a capitalist game where reckless growth will inevitably end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility&#34;&gt;Stock market volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 2021, education stocks represented by New Oriental performed a fancy dive, and the good future followed in American trading before the market opened, &lt;strong&gt;halving its stock price&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our country has gradually entered an aging population phase, and various social phenomena affecting family planning must be addressed; internet companies with monopolistic practices and excessive overtime have been fined, and the education industry where capital is concentrated has also been regulated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no allowing for the capitalization of the education industry; one vote directly rejects companies in that sector from going public and seeking financing, resulting in widespread lamentations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental&amp;rsquo;s Severed Waist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waist-cutting New Oriental&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s Plunge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s Plunge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regulators Intensify Scrutiny, Online Education Industry Suddenly &amp;ldquo;Brakes&amp;rdquo;
The General Office of the State Council issued the &amp;ldquo;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Tutoring Burden for Students in Compulsory Education Stage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China trade war</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a tangent, the differences between socialism with Chinese characteristics and capitalism. From the older generation, I’ve heard that to get rich, you must first build roads. Infrastructure construction in China is funded by the state; in a capitalist society, these would be contracted out. In remote areas, there are no profits to be made, so companies wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be willing to take on the work. Talking too much will stray from the current article’s theme. Ordinary people may feel that the trade war has little impact on their lives, but in reality, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. In the IT industry I work in, memory, hard drives, CPUs, and graphics cards – the core components of assembling a computer – all come from foreign factories. The cost of these parts accounts for 50% of the total price of the machine. High-end manufacturing is imperative. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Sino-American trade war that began in 2018&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sino-American trade war, also known as the China–United States trade war, or more briefly as the Sino-US trade dispute, Sino-US trade friction, Sino-US trade quarrel, or US-China trade war, is a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States of America&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China steals American intellectual property and business secrets,&amp;rdquo; and directed the United States Trade Representative to impose tariffs on goods imported from China under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, involving an estimated total value of $60 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed a 25% additional tariff on Chinese exports worth $340 billion. The Ministry of Commerce of China responded with retaliatory measures on the same day, imposing a 25% additional tariff on U.S. exports to China worth $340 billion, including soybeans, one of the most exported products from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US and China had previously reached a consensus in May 2018 to suspend the trade war and issued a joint statement seeking resolution. However, the Office of the United States Trade Representative subsequently announced on June 16th a first batch of tariffs targeting $500 billion worth of Chinese goods entering the US, raising the original 10% tariff rate to 25%. In response, the State Council Tariff Commission of China retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce also resumed anti-dumping investigations on multiple US products. On July 6th, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% tariff on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods in the first batch of tariffs, marking the formal implementation of Trump&amp;rsquo;s China tariff policy (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently subject to a 25% tariff on August 23rd). The Ministry of Commerce later stated in a statement that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; Customs authorities said that China’s countermeasures had been implemented immediately after the US tariffs took effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 summit in Buenos Aires, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump reached a consensus to conduct 90-day negotiations and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the United States announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on Chinese goods entering the United States valued at approximately $200 billion, bringing the total subject to tariffs to $250 billion. The measure took effect on June 1 for Chinese products arriving at U.S. ports. On May 13, the State Council Tariff Commission of China announced that it would raise tariffs by 5% to 25% on certain imports from the United States valued at $60 billion, effective June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced a postponement of the U.S. tariff increase to June 15, while the State Council Tariff Commission of China stated that China’s retaliatory tariffs would take effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, the leaders of the two countries, Xi Jinping and Donald Trump, held talks at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart trade consultations and for the United States not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the progress of China’s purchases of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that starting September 1, 2019, a 10% tariff would be imposed on all remaining Chinese goods exported to the United States valued at $300 billion. On August 5, the exchange rate of the renminbi against the U.S. dollar fell below the 7 threshold. On the same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that it was designating China as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and on August 24 announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; in response, the United States increased the tariff rate previously imposed on $300 billion worth of Chinese goods to 15%, and raised the current 25% tariff on $250 billion worth of Chinese goods to 30%, but this was later put on hold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2020, China and the United States signed the Phase One trade agreement&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
