<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Real-Estate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/real-estate/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Real-Estate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/real-estate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Promoting Real Estate and Central Bank’s Four-pronged Measures</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promoting-real-estate-and-central-bank-four-measures/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 20:42:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/promoting-real-estate-and-central-bank-four-measures/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancellation of Property Mortgage Interest Rate Floor&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Public Housing Fund (Prudential Loan) Interest Rate Will Be Reduced by 0.25% Starting Tomorrow&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;First-Time Homebuyers Down Payment Ratio Reduced to 15%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;300 Billion Yuan in Guaranteed Affordable Housing Repurchase Loans&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cancellation-of-national-level-first-and-second-time-home-purchase-mortgage-interest-rate-policy-lower-bounds&#34;&gt;Cancellation of National-Level First and Second-Time Home Purchase Mortgage Interest Rate Policy Lower Bounds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, Shanghai Headquarters, branches of the provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned cities; state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and all joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to implement the decision-making deployment of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council, adapt to the new supply and demand relationship in China’s real estate market and the new expectations of the people for high-quality housing, and promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, the following matters regarding adjustments to commercial personal mortgage interest rate policies are hereby notified:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cancellation of the lower bound on interest rates for commercial personal mortgages for first-time and second-time home purchases at the national level. Here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“II. The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China (PBOC) branches at provincial levels, in accordance with the policy of ‘fine-tuning,’ guide provincial interest rate pricing self-regulatory mechanisms, based on the market conditions and regulatory requirements of each city within their jurisdiction. Financial institutions autonomously determine whether to set lower limits for commercial personal housing loan rates and levels within those limits (if applicable).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;III. Banks and financial institutions should, in accordance with the interest rate limits established by provincial market pricing self-regulatory mechanisms (if any), rationally determine the specific interest rate level for each loan, taking into account the institution’s operating conditions and customer risk profiles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-personal-housing-mortgage-loan-interest-rates-by-025-percentage-points&#34;&gt;Reducing Personal Housing Mortgage Loan Interest Rates by 0.25 Percentage Points
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, Shanghai Headquarters, branches of the People’s Bank of China in provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned cities; branches of policy banks, state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The People’s Bank of China has decided to reduce personal housing mortgage loan interest rates by 0.25 percentage points, effective May 18, 2024. The interest rates for first-time and second-home personal housing mortgage loans with a term of less than 5 years (including 5 years) will be adjusted to 2.35% and 2.85%, respectively.  The interest rates for first-time and second-home personal housing mortgage loans with a term of less than 5 years (including 5 years) will also be no lower than 2.775% and 3.325%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;down-payment-ratio-adjusted-to-no-less-than-15&#34;&gt;Down Payment Ratio Adjusted to No Less Than 15%
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China, Shanghai Headquarters, branches of the People’s Bank of China in provinces, autonomous regions, municipalities directly under the central government, and planned unitary cities; the Regulatory Bureau of the National Financial Supervision and Administration; all state-owned commercial banks, Postal Savings Bank of China, and all joint-stock commercial banks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To implement the decisions and plans of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council, to adapt to the new supply and demand relationship in China’s real estate market and the new expectations of people for high-quality housing, and to promote the stable and healthy development of the real estate market, the following notification is issued regarding personal mortgage loan policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For residential households purchasing commercial personal mortgages for primary residences, the minimum down payment ratio for primary residence mortgages has been adjusted to no less than 15%, and the minimum down payment ratio for secondary residence commercial personal mortgages has been adjusted to no less than 25%. Based on this, the branches of the People’s Bank of China and various affiliated institutions of the National Financial Supervision and Administration Commission independently determine the minimum lower limits for commercial personal housing mortgage down payments in each jurisdiction’s cities according to the city government’s control requirements and the principle of “managed autonomy,” following the policy of “city-specific measures.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-central-bank-will-establish-a-30-billion-yuan-guarantee-housing-refinancing-loan&#34;&gt;The Central Bank Will Establish a 30 Billion Yuan Guarantee Housing Refinancing Loan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At 4:00 PM, representatives from the Ministry of Housing and Urban-Rural Development, the Ministry of Natural Resources, the People’s Bank of China, and the National Financial Supervision and Administration Commission gathered at a routine policy briefing by the State Council to introduce measures to effectively ensure contract fulfillment (保交房).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the meeting, People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China Vice Governor Tao Ling announced that the central bank will establish a 30 billion yuan guarantee housing refinancing loan to support local state-owned enterprises in purchasing completed but unsold commercial properties at reasonable prices for use as self-built or rental-based affordable housing. This is expected to drive bank loans by 50 billion yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the People’s Bank of China, the guarantee housing refinancing loan term can be extended up to four times annually with a rate of 1.75%, aimed at 21 nationwide banks. It incentivizes banks to lend to local state-owned enterprises selected by city governments to purchase completed but unsold commercial properties for use as affordable housing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
