<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>nights-naming-art</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character for &amp;ldquo;fate&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;life,&amp;rdquo; 命, stands alone – it has no homonyms. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life is unique and unrepeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flipping through the rankings on Qidian Chinese, &amp;ldquo;Night&amp;rsquo;s Naming Technique&amp;rdquo; is dominating with its monthly votes, far ahead of second place by a huge margin – practically unattainable. I’ve mostly read works from established authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Er Gen in the past, but this time I decided to try a new author and experience a different kind of reading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, &amp;ldquo;Night&amp;rsquo;s Naming&amp;rdquo; had reached two million monthly tickets, significantly surpassing the second-place novel with only eighty thousand, a remarkable difference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I lack the expertise to evaluate the writing of this book. However, having read through more than ten chapters, the plot is tightly paced and intricately connected, captivating the reader. The high number of votes it received is well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, like the character for &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo; (命), the character for &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; (死) also has no homophones in Chinese. Does this perhaps suggest that the end of life is equally unique and irreplaceable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
