<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:38:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>nights-naming-art</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is unique; there isn’t even a single homophone. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life has only one opportunity, cannot be replicated, and cannot be relived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with over two million monthly votes, a significant gap from the second-place ranking. Previously, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Ergen; this time, I decided to try a new author’s work to experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed two million monthly votes, while the second-place ranking stood at only eight hundred thousand – a staggering disparity that left me speechless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize my knowledge is limited and I lack the ability to critically evaluate the author’s writing style. However, after reading through over a dozen chapters, the book’s plot is tightly paced and intricately linked, captivating readers and earning such high monthly votes – it&amp;rsquo;s truly well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like the character “ming” (life/fate), the character “si” (death) also doesn’t have any homophones in Chinese characters; does this perhaps also contain a similarly unique and irreplaceable depth of meaning regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
