<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Start-Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/start-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Onomatopoeia of the Night</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is utterly unique; there isn’t even a single homophone. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person’s life has only one opportunity, cannot be replicated, and cannot be relived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with an overwhelming number of monthly votes, far surpassing the second-place book – a gap that was truly daunting. For many years, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jiaqian and Ergen. This time, I decided to try a new author’s work and experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed a staggering two million monthly votes, while the second book only garnered eight hundred thousand – the disparity was astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge my own lack of knowledge and ability to critically evaluate the author&amp;rsquo;s writing style. However, after reading through more than fifteen chapters, I found that the plot was tightly woven and intricately connected, captivating and engaging. Given such high monthly vote numbers, it’s undeniably well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like “命,” the character “死” (death) also has no homophones within the Chinese character system. Does this similarly imply a unique and irreplaceable depth regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
