<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Wechat-Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Wechat-Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>WeChat Mini Program Background and Development Environment</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:59:11 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction to and Preparation for WeChat Mini Programs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-wechat-mini-programs-exist&#34;&gt;Why do WeChat mini programs exist?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improved experience: Slow loading of embedded webpages, blank screens; Native app experiences offer faster loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standards and Management: For WeChat, accessing and managing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the release of mini-programs, WeChat launched a &lt;em&gt;bold_italicized&lt;/em&gt; feature exposing its native capabilities—WeChat Pay and Wechat Cards. However, developers used web development languages, allowing them to bypass some of WeChat&amp;rsquo;s regulations. Mini-programs have their own descriptive language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-mini-program&#34;&gt;What is a mini program?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mini-programs are applications that can be used without needing to be downloaded or installed, realizing the dream of app &lt;strong&gt;触手可及&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can open the application by scanning a QR code or searching, which also embodies the &lt;strong&gt;用完即走&lt;/strong&gt; concept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;unobtrusive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-between-mini-programs-and-mobile-apps&#34;&gt;The difference between mini-programs and mobile apps
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No installation, no memory usage, easy sharing: Scan code, mini-program card, search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-mini-programs-do&#34;&gt;What can mini programs do?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Tools: Zhihu Trending, Weibo Hot Topics, Mobike, Jinri Toutiao, Tencent Map, Tencent Translate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retail: Pinduoduo, JD Shopping, Mogujie, Meili Fresh, Xiaomi Mall, Watson&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games: Jump, Happy Landlord, Happy Mahjong, Douyu Live Streaming, YY Live Streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course content is from 2018, and some of the applications mentioned have since closed down&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-preparation&#34;&gt;Development preparation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register for a mini-program account: Fill in the information as required, then click the activation link in your email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Registration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to the Mini Program Management Console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete mini-program information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binding Developer: Individual developers – the WeChat account used for login is the administrator account, no additional binding is required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email addresses have limitations, so a new one is needed. However, &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; email allows for aliases, and WeChat&amp;rsquo;s backend doesn’t verify them. I tried it out; the mini-program name was tricky, but anything involving trademarks easily fails review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service categories can be selected or customized, with up to five categories per mini-program&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view information about the mini-program and enable message push within settings. Enabling message push allows you to use message templates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developer-tools-a-personal-account&#34;&gt;Developer Tools (A Personal Account)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normal download and installation, no special notes. Briefly understand, enter directly in visitor mode. To enable phone debugging (viewing the development version of the mini-program), log in to the mini-program developer account and then click settings, switching to the specified mini-program within project details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-structure&#34;&gt;Code structure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JS: Interaction logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JSON: Data Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UI elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interface styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
