<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Wechat-Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Wechat-Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>WeChat Mini Program Background and Development Environment</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:59:11 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;WeChat Mini Program Introduction and Development Preparation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-mini-programs-exist&#34;&gt;Why Mini Programs Exist
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Better Experience:&lt;/strong&gt; Slow web loading and blank screens; native app experience with faster loading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Standards &amp;amp; Management:&lt;/strong&gt; For WeChat, onboarding and management
Before mini programs were released, WeChat published an SDK called &lt;code&gt;Jssdk&lt;/code&gt;, which opened up parts of the original WeChat capabilities: WeChat Pay, coupons. However, developers used web development languages to develop logic, bypassing some WeChat regulations. Mini Programs have their own description language.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-mini-programs&#34;&gt;What are Mini Programs?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mini programs are applications that can be used without needing to download and install them. They realize the dream of having applications &lt;strong&gt;within easy reach&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can open an application simply by scanning a QR code or searching for it. This also reflects the concept of &lt;strong&gt;use-it-and-leave-it&lt;/strong&gt; – users don’t have to worry about installing too many apps. Applications will be ubiquitous and available at any time, but they &lt;strong&gt;don&amp;rsquo;t require installation or uninstallation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;differences-between-mini-programs-and-mobile-applications&#34;&gt;Differences Between Mini Programs and Mobile Applications
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No installation required, doesn&amp;rsquo;t occupy memory, easy to spread: QR code scanning, mini program cards, Search One Search (Sohu Search)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-mini-programs-can-do&#34;&gt;What Mini Programs Can Do
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Tools: Zhihu Hot Rankings, Weibo Hot Topics, Mobike Bikes, Today Headline, Tencent Maps, Tencent Translate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retail: Pinduoduo, JD.com Shopping, Mugujie, Daily Fresh, Xiaomi Mall, Watsons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games: Jump Rope, Happy Mahjong, Happy Mahjong, Douyu Live Streaming, YY Live Streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Course content is from 2018; some application vendors have already gone bankrupt now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-preparation&#34;&gt;Development Preparation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register a Mini Program Account: Simply fill in the information normally, and click the activation link on the email.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Registration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log into the Mini Program Management Backstage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complete Mini Program Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bind Developer: For individual developers, use the WeChat account you’re logged in with as the administrator account; no additional binding is required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email has certain restrictions – it needs a new email, but you can apply aliases for QQ emails, and the WeChat background will not verify them. After trying this, the name of the mini program is quite troublesome. As soon as it involves trademarks, it’s prone to audit failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can select service categories and also add custom ones; a Mini Program can add five categories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Settings, you can view the Mini Program&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; information and enable message push; with message push enabled, you can use the Message Template function.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developer-tools-as-described-by-the-author&#34;&gt;Developer Tools (as described by the author)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Normal download and installation, with no special considerations – just a basic understanding. Simply enter in Guest Mode, and if you want to enable mobile debugging (i.e., view the mini-program development version on your phone), you need to log into the mini-program developer account, then click Settings, and switch to the specified mini-program’s &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; within Project Details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-structure&#34;&gt;Code Structure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;js: Interaction logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;json: Data configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wxml: UI elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wxss: UI styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
