<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>WeChat Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/</link>
        <description>Recent content in WeChat Mini-Program on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/wechat-mini-program/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>WeChat Mini Program Background and Development Environment</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Mar 2023 21:59:11 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-mini-program-background-and-development-environment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Introduction to and Preparation for WeChat Mini Programs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-wechat-mini-programs-exist&#34;&gt;Why do WeChat mini programs exist?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A better experience: Slow loading of embedded webpages, white screens; Native app experiences offer faster loading&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Standards and Management: For WeChat, accessing and managing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the release of mini-programs, WeChat released an SDK called JSSDK, which exposed WeChat&amp;rsquo;s native capabilities such as Wechat Pay and cards. However, developers developed based on web development language logic, allowing them to bypass some of WeChat’s regulations. Mini-programs have their own description language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-mini-program&#34;&gt;What is a mini program?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mini programs are applications that can be used without downloading or installing, realizing the dream of apps being readily accessible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users can open the application by scanning a QR code or searching for it, which also embodies the &amp;ldquo;use and leave&amp;rdquo; concept&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Users don&amp;rsquo;t need to worry about whether they have installed too many applications. Applications will be everywhere, readily available, but without the need for installation or uninstallation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-difference-between-mini-programs-and-mobile-apps&#34;&gt;The difference between mini-programs and mobile apps
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;No installation required, doesn&amp;rsquo;t take up memory space, easy to share: scan a code, mini-program card, search&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-can-mini-programs-do&#34;&gt;What can mini programs do?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Tools: Zhihu Hot List, Weibo Trending Topics, Mobike, Jinri Toutiao, Tencent Map, Tencent Translate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Retail: Pinduoduo, JD Shopping, Mogujie, Meili Fresh, Xiaomi Mall, Watson&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games: Jump Jump, Happy Landlord, Happy Mahjong, Douyu Live Streaming, YY Live Streaming&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course content is from 2018, and now some of the application vendors have already gone out of business&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;development-preparation&#34;&gt;Development preparation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registering a mini-program account: You can register by filling in the information normally, and activate your account by clicking on the activation link in the email&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information Registration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to the Mini Program Management Console&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perfect/Complete Mini Program Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binding Developer: For individual developers, the WeChat account used for login is the administrator account and does not require any additional binding operations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email addresses have certain limitations, so a new email address is needed. QQ email allows for aliases, and the WeChat backend doesn&amp;rsquo;t verify them. I tried it out, but changing the name of the mini-program is tricky; anything involving trademarks tends to fail during review.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Service categories can be selected, or you can add your own; a mini-program can include five categories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can view the applet’s &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; information and enable message push notifications within settings. Enabling message push notifications allows you to use message template functions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;developer-tools-a-personal-account&#34;&gt;Developer Tools (A Personal Account)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The download and installation are normal, with no special notes. A quick understanding is sufficient; you can directly enter in visitor mode. If you want to enable phone debugging, which allows viewing the development version of the mini-program on your phone, you need to log in to the mini-program developer account and then click on settings, switch to the specified mini-program &lt;code&gt;ID&lt;/code&gt; within project details.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-structure&#34;&gt;Code structure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JS: Interaction logic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JSON: Data Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WXML: The elements of the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;wxss: Styles for the interface&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
