<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war put on hold</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 trade war tariff evolution showed a cycle of &amp;ldquo;escalation — retaliation — consultation,&amp;rdquo; shifting the US-China competition from tariff confrontation to rules-based competition. While short-term easing alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty remains; monitor the WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical changes&amp;rsquo; continued impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People cannot earn money beyond their understanding. The stock market crash triggered by the trade war this year, even with a partial recovery now, has claimed countless retail investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timeline of Trade War Tariffs in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of the 2025 trade war tariff timeline, incorporating key events from China, the US, and other countries to illustrate the evolution of tariff policies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-tariff-escalation-and-retaliation&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Tariff Escalation and Retaliation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration signed order 14257, announcing a 34% tariff on Chinese goods imported into the US, covering products from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. is further raising tariffs on China from 34% to 84%, and has signed Executive Orders 14259 and 14266, imposing additional tariffs on more goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The White House revised an executive order, raising the total tariffs on China to 145%, and increasing duties on small parcels (e.g., raising the tariff rate on goods under $800 from 90% to 120%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China announced a 34% tariff on all goods originating from the United States, covering sectors like agriculture, automobiles, and energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China will retaliate by raising tariffs from 34% to 84%, matching the US escalation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is removing 91% of tariffs on US goods (corresponding to the portion agreed upon by the US) and suspending the implementation of 90% of the remaining 24% tariffs, while retaining 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US imposed a 25% tariff on Canadian steel and aluminum products, prompting Canada to retaliate with tariffs on $2.98 billion worth of US goods and file a complaint with the WTO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The EU is imposing tariffs of up to 25% on US goods, while Japan expressed concerns over tariffs on US cars, calling the trade war &amp;ldquo;lose-lose.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-easing&#34;&gt;May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff Easing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China and the United States held 16 hours of talks in Geneva, Switzerland, resulting in the China-U.S. Geneva Trade Talks Joint Statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sides announce suspension of some tariffs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US has suspended 24% of tariffs on China (for 90 days), retained 10%, and canceled additional duties scheduled for April 8th and 9th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China will suspend 24% of retaliatory tariffs, retain 10%, and remove non-tariff measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sides agreed to hold regular economic and trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reductions and rule-making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High tariffs are causing small and medium-sized enterprises to fail (e.g., Amazon sellers forced to close due to surging tariffs), and inflation expectations are rising (core PCE is projected to rise to 3.3%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China has tightened controls on rare earth exports, cracked down on smuggling, and impacted US military and new energy industries, forcing them to seek waivers for tariffs on key minerals like rare earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China have both filed disputes with the WTO against the US steel and aluminum tariffs and &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; alleging violations of the non-discrimination principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala warned that U.S. tariffs could cause a 1% decline in global trade volume by 2025, exacerbating the difficulties faced by developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 37-page list covers strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT tubes, exposing supply chain vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US imposed a 25% tariff on imported cars, leading to a projected 2% drop in global auto production and a 9% reduction in North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; but was criticized as unilateral bullying, prompting a backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is responding to protectionism by expanding market access (such as through import fairs and zero-tariff commitments) to attract cooperation from developing countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline-summary&#34;&gt;Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US is imposing 34% retaliatory tariffs on China, covering goods from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US will raise tariffs on China to 84% and introduce new tax orders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China retaliates with tariffs, initially 34%, later raised to 84%; US modifies tariffs to 145%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US waived tariffs on some goods (like tech products), and China canceled 91% of its retaliatory tariffs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China, US, and Japan Geneva talks result in a joint statement agreeing to suspend 24% tariffs (for 90 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both sides announced suspension of tariffs and a consultation mechanism, easing trade tensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tariff suspension between China and the US sends a positive signal, but structural issues (such as high technology and energy) remain, and midterm elections may affect policy continuity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies are accelerating supply chain adjustments; Mexico and Southeast Asia benefit from &amp;ldquo;nearshoring,&amp;rdquo; but rising costs may curb recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WTO dispute settlement mechanism is limited, and regional trade agreements (such as the US-UK agreement) have become alternative options, but this exacerbates fragmentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tariff storm, stock market crash</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 03:49:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, global stock markets have experienced sharp volatility, largely due to new comprehensive tariff measures announced by U.S. President Donald Trump, sparking market concerns about a global trade war and economic recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;President Trump announced tariffs on all imported goods last week, with up to a 50% tariff on imports from China, aiming to correct what he called an unfair global trade system. This move triggered panic selling in global markets as investors worried that escalating trade tensions would stifle global economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the United States, major stock indexes suffered significant losses. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell by more than 1,200 points, while the Nasdaq Composite and S&amp;amp;P 500 indices dropped 4% and 3.8%, respectively, entering bear market territory. Asian and European markets were also affected, with the Nikkei 225 in Japan falling nearly 8% and European stock markets declining by 6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Faced with market volatility, investors are shifting to safe-haven assets like bonds and the yen. However, a surge in the VIX to above 60 indicates escalating market panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economists warn that tariff policies could lead to &amp;ldquo;stagflation&amp;rdquo; in the U.S. economy – a situation of stagnant growth, rising inflation, and high unemployment occurring simultaneously. JPMorgan Chase has raised the probability of a U.S. recession in 2025 to 60%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments worldwide have announced retaliatory measures. For example, the EU trade commissioner stated that they will begin imposing retaliatory tariffs on US goods on April 15th. Businesses have also expressed concerns; Goldman Sachs, for instance, has raised the probability of a US economic recession to 45%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, global markets are facing unprecedented challenges; investors need to closely monitor trade policy developments and market changes, while managing risk and allocating assets&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Broad-based index investing: Broker ETFs, Hang Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to buy a solid blue-chip stock and just leave it, but I never managed to do it. When it fell, I didn&amp;rsquo;t add to my position, and when it rose, I sold it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding suitable blue-chip stocks is troublesome; it&amp;rsquo;s better to choose a broad index and buy an ETF. The current plan is: securities ETF, Hang Seng Tech Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trading strategy has a professional term: left-side dip buying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broker-etfs&#34;&gt;Broker ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Securities ETF refers to exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that primarily invest in listed securities broker stocks within the Chinese stock market. Securities ETFs typically track a specific securities brokerage index, such as the China Securities Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought it before, but chased after the price and ended up losing money, so I cleared out my position. In China&amp;rsquo;s market, every bull market sees brokerages rise; how much they rise depends on investor sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-technology-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Technology Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is a stock index launched by the Hong Kong Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology sector in the Hong Kong market. It includes major tech companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering areas such as internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituents and their weightings in the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) are as follows (data compiled from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;舜宇集团 (舜宇光学科技集团有限公司) (01810.HK): Approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Resources Pharmaceutical Holdings (00700.HK): Approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country Garden (09988.HK): Approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;京东集团-SW&lt;/strong&gt; (09618.HK): Approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;舜宇光学科技集团有限公司 (Sunvision Technology Co., Ltd.) (03690.HK): Approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(01024.HK): Approximately 6.10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold (02015.HK): Approximately 6.09%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;中芯国际&lt;/strong&gt; (00981.HK): Approximately 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(09999.HK): Approximately 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approximately 4.48%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 66.6% (some sources indicate a combined share of the top ten between 68%-69%, with differences due to varying statistical time points)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-notes&#34;&gt;Key Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index caps the weighting of any single stock at 8%. For example, SMIC&amp;rsquo;s weighting previously exceeded 8% before adjustments in March 2025 but was subsequently reduced to comply with this limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On May 16, 2025, Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD (01211.HK) will be added to the index and China Literature (00772.HK) removed. The adjustment will take effect on June 6. Therefore, as of today (May 20), the constituent stocks are based on the pre-adjustment list; BYD is not yet included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The top ten components are dominated by internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, and Meituan), with significant weighting in new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Li Auto) and semiconductors (SMIC), reflecting the index&amp;rsquo;s coverage of technology and the new economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differences in data from various sources are primarily due to differing statistical time points. For example, data from March 2025 shows the top ten combined share at approximately 69.4%, while data from May 14th indicates 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-to-position-on-a-pullback-on-the-left-side&#34;&gt;Add to position on a pullback (on the left side)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;left-side topping up&amp;rdquo; strategy is an investment approach where investors buy in batches during a sustained stock price decline, anticipating the price is nearing a bottom to reduce holding costs and profit from future price increases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method falls under the category of &amp;ldquo;left-side trading,&amp;rdquo; meaning taking a counter-trend position before the market has clearly bottomed out. In practice, investors typically employ a &amp;ldquo;pyramid&amp;rdquo; accumulation strategy, gradually increasing buy quantities as the price declines to lower their average holding cost. For example, initially buying a certain number of shares; if the price continues to fall, they increase their buying volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying in batches during a downturn can lower average cost basis and set the stage for future profits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing positions before the market reverses can yield greater returns when the trend improves if your judgment is correct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the stock price continues to fall, it may lead to greater losses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adequate financial support is required for continuous restocking, and there&amp;rsquo;s a risk of funds being locked up long-term&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, &amp;ldquo;right-side trading&amp;rdquo; involves buying after a clear market trend and price recovery signal, offering lower risk but potentially missing early gains. Therefore, investors should choose a strategy that aligns with their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance, aiming to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies and provide a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and formulate corresponding investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is based on the expected future cash flows of an asset, which are then discounted to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes intrinsic value and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method assesses a company&amp;rsquo;s relative value by comparing its valuation metrics (e.g., P/E, P/B, P/S) to those of comparable companies in the same industry. Relative valuation is easy to implement and widely used for quick assessments and peer comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method determines a company&amp;rsquo;s value by assessing its net asset value, which is the difference between total assets and liabilities. The asset-based approach is suitable for asset-dominant companies such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and formulate buy-or-sell strategies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influencing its success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company needs to fairly value its assets and liabilities to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial statements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that valuation results are influenced by various factors, including market conditions, company operations, and macroeconomic indicators. Therefore, a comprehensive consideration of all factors, combined with qualitative and quantitative analysis, is necessary to achieve more accurate assessments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Making money takes time; rushing it wont help</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading, while I haven&amp;rsquo;t made a fortune, I also haven&amp;rsquo;t lost too much. The biggest issue is an unreasonable cash flow plan and unstable mindset. Currently, my primary income comes from work – a fixed salary. My tolerance for financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; buying too little means you won’t profit when prices rise, while buying too much leads to losses when they fall. A stable mindset is therefore crucial; it helps steady our ship of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing through stock trading: The importance of mindset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides dabbling in small-cap and newly listed stocks when I first started, the investments I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on since have been primarily blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hengan Electronics, ZTE, and various large-cap index funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it stemmed from greed wanting more—rushing to increase holdings at the start, then facing a cash flow crisis. Expenses like insurance, buying property, and getting married were major drains on funds; the overall plan lacked sufficient financial buffer, leading to later shortages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy blue-chip stocks, it&amp;rsquo;s like relying on [someone] dependable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Evergrande ran into problems, bank stocks plummeted, allowing for a successful opportunity to sell off. However, this demonstrates a flawed understanding of the broader economy – real estate&amp;rsquo;s share in the national economy is too significant, with far-reaching implications that cannot be ignored. The subsequent market decline and the sustained rise of dividend stocks over roughly two years reflect this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The early stages of the trade war saw significant damage, with stock prices falling sharply, but they gradually recovered afterward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This stock belongs to the former employer. After Ant Financial&amp;rsquo;s divestiture, the price dropped significantly, but it has market makers who can push it up several times a year. With proper position sizing, losses will be minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-that-devours-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The &amp;ldquo;monster&amp;rdquo; that devours reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When stock prices rise steadily and investors&amp;rsquo; paper profits increase, greed quietly takes root. Many, seeing prices already at high levels, still fantasize about continued upward trends and seek greater returns, unwilling to take profits. Blinded by greed, they forget market rules and the existence of risk. For example, during speculative surges in certain hot-topic stocks, some investors, witnessing short-term doubling or even multiple times increases, become deeply involved, continuously adding positions with the hope of being the last winners. However, markets don&amp;rsquo;t stay exuberant forever; when bubbles burst and prices plummet, these greed-driven investors often suffer heavy losses. Greed robs them of their ability to analyze and decide rationally, turning them into &amp;ldquo;gamblers&amp;rdquo; rather than wise investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-shackles-binding-your-hands-and-feet&#34;&gt;Fear: Shackles binding your hands and feet
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the opposite of greed. Fear is equally destructive in the stock market. When market conditions turn sharply downward and prices plummet, investors easily panic. This fear erodes their confidence; even with fundamentally sound stocks, they rush to sell to avoid further losses. For example, during the global financial crisis, many high-quality blue-chip stocks also fell dramatically. Some investors, overwhelmed by fear, failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies and sold their shares at rock-bottom prices, missing out on substantial returns from subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses but can also create a lasting psychological shadow, deterring them from re-entering the market and causing them to miss investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blindly-following-trends-a-fog-that-obscures-direction&#34;&gt;Blindly following trends: A &amp;ldquo;fog&amp;rdquo; that obscures direction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blindly following the crowd is another common psychological trap for investors in stock trading and wealth management. In an era of information overload, investment advice, market rumors, and trending news abound. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment skills, blindly imitating others&amp;rsquo; actions. Seeing others profit from buying a particular stock, they rush to buy without careful consideration; hearing so-called &amp;ldquo;insider tips,&amp;rdquo; they invest everything they have. This blind following neglects the necessary research and analysis of individual stocks, leaving investors lost like ships in fog, losing their direction. For example, some concept stocks may generate short-term gains for followers initially, but as hype fades, prices plummet, turning those unaware and blindly following into &amp;ldquo;bag holders.&amp;rdquo; They fail to realize that each investor has different risk tolerance, investment goals, and time horizons; what works for others might not work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-a-hidden-shoal&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: A Hidden &amp;ldquo;Shoal&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is a significant issue in the mindset of stock and financial investments. After experiencing initial investment successes, some investors become inflated with pride, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict price movements. They disregard the complexity and uncertainty of the market, leading to excessive trading, blindly expanding their investment scale, and even using high leverage for speculation. However, the market is unpredictable, and overconfident investors often suffer significant losses from unexpected market fluctuations. For example, inexperienced but initially successful investors may believe they possess professional investment skills and begin frequent buying and selling while continuously increasing their investments. When systemic risks or negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to stop their losses in time due to their overconfidence, resulting in substantial capital erosion. Overconfidence is like a submerged reef, appearing calm and harmless on the surface but capable of wrecking an investor&amp;rsquo;s financial ship unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-sound-financial-management&#34;&gt;How to adjust your mindset for sound financial management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a correct investment philosophy: Investors should understand that stock trading and wealth management are for the long-term, stable growth of assets, not for getting rich quick. Through learning investment knowledge, understanding market patterns, and adopting value investing and long-term investment principles, avoid being swayed by short-term gains and market sentiment. For example, thoroughly research a company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals – its profitability, industry position, management team, etc. – to select stocks with long-term investment value, rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a sound investment plan: Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable plan. Clearly define key elements such as investment amount, timeframe, expected return, and stop-loss point, and adhere to the plan strictly. This helps avoid impulsive decisions driven by emotional fluctuations. For example, limit each stock&amp;rsquo;s allocation to a certain percentage of your total assets; take profits when prices reach your target gains, and cut losses decisively when they hit your stop-loss level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control your emotions and stay calm: When facing market volatility, learn to manage your emotions and remain calm and rational. Relieve investment pressure through methods like distraction, exercise, and communication. Avoid letting emotions negatively impact your investment decisions. When the market experiences significant fluctuations, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine your investment strategy with the fundamentals of the stocks, and make a rational judgment instead of blindly following trends or panicking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous learning and reflection are essential in the ever-evolving stock market. Investors must consistently acquire new knowledge and skills, stay informed about macroeconomic trends, industry developments, and company information to improve their investment capabilities. Regularly reflecting on investment behavior, summarizing lessons learned, identifying issues with mindset and decision-making, and making timely adjustments are also crucial. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze successes and failures, and consider how to avoid similar errors in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in the stock market is a long and challenging journey where mindset plays a crucial role. Maintaining rationality, composure, humility, and independent thinking are essential for navigating market volatility and achieving wealth preservation and growth. Investors should consider cultivating a positive mindset as a fundamental part of their investment process, enabling them to steer their financial future successfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fund and fixed income wealth management</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of us born in the 90s, we didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis because we were young and not yet focused on investing. The bull market of 2015 was dramatic, with a significant correction before government intervention stabilized it. This brought the concept of investment funds into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alipay, as a natural traffic entry point under Ant Group, was initially positioned as a payment tool. Most people chose Alipay for buying funds compared to WeChat. Alipay successfully transformed fund sales into ordinary shopping. The bull market starting in 2019 and the mutual support among fund managers were ultimately driven by pandemic-induced monetary easing. Those who entered (the market) profited, while those who watched became envious and rushed to enter. The speed at which new funds surpass 10 billion yuan is accelerating. With even older generations now buying funds, trillion-dollar funds are within reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the rise of Ant Group&amp;rsquo;s internet-based fund sales platform, ordinary people typically encountered fund sales only when depositing money at banks, where branch managers would enthusiastically promote various financial products. The packaging and promotional information on the internet, along with the exorbitant advertising fees paid by fund sales institutions, have made Alipay’s fund advertisements completely detached from reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The provided growth data only shows the returns for the past three years on the table, and only the annualized average return for legacy funds. Why don&amp;rsquo;t they publish the annual average return separately? Is it difficult to calculate? No, it’s because the data is unfavorable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t easily encourage customers to buy the fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investments&#34;&gt;Fixed income investments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has not yet entered the era of negative interest rates. Bank deposits and government bonds are the most reliable fixed-income products; pure bond funds are also a good option. You can easily find China&amp;rsquo;s average salary by checking data released by local statistical bureaus. Here’s a simple scenario: with 2 million yuan in assets, an annualized return of 4% would generate annual income exceeding the average salary in most cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s a lot I could write. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading books on economics; don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow trends. For ordinary families, the core of financial management is preservation of value, not chasing get-rich-quick schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing the right thing at the right time yields the greatest value. Studying diligently and obtaining a good education is better than earning pocket money distributing flyers. Working hard after graduation brings substantial returns in salary increases. When starting a family, learn to care for your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those interested can check out this speech: Regarding time, you need to read many books to find the answer; the full text is available on this site&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
