<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:19:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Comprehensive Analysis: Capital Gains Tax, CRS, and Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp; US Stocks Investment Tax Guide</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:12:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks, understanding relevant tax regulations is crucial. This article will comprehensively analyze what capital gains tax is, why it applies to investments in Hong Kong and US stocks, and explain the workings of CRS (Common Reporting Standard). Furthermore, this article will also provide detailed answers regarding the tax responsibilities and specific tax rates for mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks through various channels (Hong Kong brokers, Hong Kong-Shanghai Link, and Shenzhen-Hong Kong Link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-concept-breakdown&#34;&gt;Core Concept Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-capital-gains-tax-cgt&#34;&gt;What is Capital Gains Tax (CGT)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital Gains Tax (CGT), often abbreviated as CGT, is a tax levied on the &lt;strong&gt;profits realized from selling assets&lt;/strong&gt;. These assets can include stocks, bonds, real estate, precious metals, and more. When you sell an asset for a price higher than your purchase price, the resulting gains (known as capital gains) may be subject to Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that not all countries or regions levy Capital Gains Tax. For example, Hong Kong currently does not impose Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-subject-to-capital-gains-tax&#34;&gt;Why are Hong Kong and US Stocks Subject to Capital Gains Tax?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States is a country that levies capital gains tax. For non-U.S. taxpayers (such as most mainland investors), while selling US stocks typically qualifies for exemption from capital gains tax, certain conditions must be met (e.g., residency in the U.S. for no more than 183 days within a year). However, dividends received from US stocks are subject to withholding income tax at a rate of usually 30%, but according to the China-U.S. Tax Agreement, mainland Chinese residents can apply to reduce this rate to 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; As stated above, Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax. Therefore, regardless of the channel through which you trade Hong Kong stocks, no tax is payable on the difference between purchase and sale prices. This doesn’t mean that mainland residents don&amp;rsquo;t need to declare this income to the Chinese mainland tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-crs-reporting-common-reporting-standard&#34;&gt;What is CRS Reporting (Common Reporting Standard)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CRS, or the “Common Reporting Standard,” is a global standard for the automatic exchange of financial account information. Its primary purpose is to combat tax evasion involving offshore accounts and cross-border tax avoidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it Works:&lt;/strong&gt; In simple terms, financial institutions (such as banks and brokers) that have signed up to CRS need to identify the non-resident taxpayers’ accounts and report their account information (including names, addresses, taxpayer status, account balances, and annual total income) to their local tax authorities. These tax authorities then exchange this information with the relevant tax authorities of the countries/territories where the account holders are residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Mainland Investors:&lt;/strong&gt; For mainland residents who open accounts with Hong Kong brokers, due to their tax residency being China, Hong Kong financial institutions will exchange their account information through the Hong Kong Customs and Excise Department to the Chinese State Taxation Administration. This means that the inland tax authorities can gain access to information about its residents’ overseas financial assets and income, providing a basis for collecting global income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inland-resident-hong-kong--us-stock-trading-tax-breakdown&#34;&gt;Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp;amp; US Stock Trading Tax Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, Chinese tax residents are required to pay personal income tax on their &lt;strong&gt;income sourced globally&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that even if investment gains occur abroad and may be exempt in the local jurisdiction, there is still an obligation to declare and pay taxes to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Chinese tax department has intensified its enforcement of taxation regarding individual overseas income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-via-hong-kong-brokers&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong and US Stocks via Hong Kong Brokers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a mainland resident, trading Hong Kong and US stocks through Hong Kong brokers (such as Futu Securities, Tiger Brokerage, etc.), your tax responsibilities are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; The profits you receive from the difference between buying and selling US stocks belong to “transfer pricing income.” According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, it should be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities. Although the United States typically exempts non-residents from capital gains taxes, Chinese tax residents still need to pay taxes on this global income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from US stocks will usually have 10% withheld by the broker as estimated income tax (enjoying preferential tax agreements between China and the US). This tax paid abroad can be offset when declaring it in China, but the offset amount cannot exceed the taxable amount calculated according to Chinese tax laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; Although Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax, profits from Hong Kong stock trading (price differences) are also considered “transfer pricing income” and must be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from H shares (companies registered in mainland China and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 20% personal income tax withheld by the company. Dividends received from non-H shares (companies registered in Hong Kong or overseas and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 10% dividend tax withheld in Hong Kong. This tax paid abroad can also be offset when declaring it in China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-stocks-via-the-hksar-mainland-china-bond-connect-hk--sh&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong Stocks via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To promote capital market connectivity between Mainland China and Hong Kong, the government has introduced targeted tax incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; According to announcements from the Ministry of Finance, the State Taxation Administration, and the Securities and Futures Commission, personal income tax is currently &lt;strong&gt;exempted&lt;/strong&gt; on any &lt;strong&gt;capital gains&lt;/strong&gt; realized by mainland individual investors through the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH) when buying and selling listed stocks on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. This incentive policy has been explicitly &lt;strong&gt;extended to December 31, 2027&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend Income:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), the H Share company will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Non-H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), China Merchants Service Bureau will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;. Any pre-paid personal income tax paid in Hong Kong can be claimed for tax refund by submitting a valid withholding certificate to the relevant tax authority of China Merchants Service Bureau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Brokerage Firms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, 20% Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US Withholding 10%, Can be Deducible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-1&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, Rate 20%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Withheld 20%; Non-H Shares: Hong Kong Advance 10%, Deductible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-2&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect (沪港通)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exempted (until end of 2027)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Deduction of 20%; Non-H Shares: Listing Deduction of 20%, Hong Kong Tax Already Paid Can Be Refunded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-3&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The information above is based on current policies. Tax regulations may change, and investors are advised to consult with a professional tax advisor or monitor the latest information released by the tax authorities before making investment decisions and filing tax returns to ensure compliance. The typical time frame for reporting foreign income is from March 1st to June 30th of the following year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Premium Whole Life Insurance Policy Interpretation</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:13:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult for ordinary people to understand a policy document, and traditional financial planning is based on understanding annualized returns. However, the calculation method of an increasing term life insurance policy is Internal Rate of Return (IRR), and there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between these two – what’s the difference and why does it exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When funds are invested in one go, &lt;strong&gt;Internal Rate of Return (IRR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return (Annualized Return)&lt;/strong&gt; produce the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;laymans-explanation&#34;&gt;Layman&amp;rsquo;s Explanation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you planted a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lump Sum Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; You invested the money to buy the sapling and the fertilizer for the first year all at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt; This is like measuring how much your tree grows each year, then calculating the average percentage it grows by per year. It measures how much your money grew on average over one year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRR (Internal Rate of Return):&lt;/strong&gt; The IRR concept is broader and can handle situations with multiple cash inflows and outflows. However, in a simple scenario where you have a single investment and a single return, IRR also seeks to find an “average annual growth rate” that makes the money grow at this percentage over time, exactly equaling the amount you finally receive back.
Because in a single investment, single return scenario, there are no intermediate cash flows (like regular dividends or additional investments), the calculation of IRR is simplified into finding a compound annual growth rate, which is exactly what the annualized return expresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;An Example
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2024, you invested &lt;strong&gt;10,000 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Term:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Return:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2027, you received back &lt;strong&gt;13,310 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-annualized-return&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The formula for calculating annualized return is:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{\text{Ending Value}}{\text{Beginning Value}} \right)^{\frac{1}{\text{Investment Period}}} - 1$$
&lt;p&gt;
Substituting the data:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{13310}{10000} \right)^{\frac{1}{3}} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = (1.331)^{0.3333} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
&lt;p&gt;
Therefore, the annualized return on this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;. This means your money grew an average of 10% per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-internal-rate-of-return-irr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Internal Rate of Return (IRR):&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;IRR is the discount rate that makes the net present value (NPV) of all cash flows zero. In this example, the cash flows include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2024: -10,000 (Cash outflow – investment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2027: +13,310 (Investment recovery)
We need to find a discount rate &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; such that:
$$-10000 + \frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 0$$
$$\frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 10000$$
$$(1+r)^3 = \frac{13310}{10000} = 1.331$$
$$1+r = (1.331)^{\frac{1}{3}}$$
$$1+r = 1.1$$
$$r = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
Therefore, the internal rate of return (IRR) for this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this simple example of a one-time investment and one-time recovery, you will find that the results of calculating the annualized yield and internal rate of return are identical. This is because in this specific case, the IRR calculation logic is equivalent to the compound interest calculation logic used to determine the annualized yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRR truly comes into play when an investment involves &lt;strong&gt;multiple cash flows&lt;/strong&gt;, such as investing in a fund where you contribute money each month, or investing in a project that pays dividends at different points in time and ultimately recovers a final sum of money. In this complex cash flow pattern, the annualized yield may not accurately measure the true return on investment, while IRR can better reflect the time value of money and the overall rate of return for the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:07:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AI has been integrated into daily development workflows, and recent investments have shifted focus from external funds to internal stocks and ETFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-log&#34;&gt;Project Log
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was bored and tried to obtain GitHub badges, starting to use the Issue module. Previously, when writing code, I always wanted to find a place to record the content of each AI modification, but creating a separate document to record it felt disorganized. Now that we have the Issue module, tagging them to distinguish between bugs, features, enhancements, etc., has made the records clear and efficient. Even if I might not need them in the future, recording them is still a form of accumulation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/issues?q=is%3Aissue&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;View Issue List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Release record, find the most recent related commits. Since all commits are AI-generated, copy all recent commit records from the web interface and give them to AI to organize – this is a good release record.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;engagement&#34;&gt;Engagement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That time it was featured on GitHub’s personal page, it passively increased the motivation to write code – after all, the data visualization made things quite fascinating. Even simple positive feedback could provide the impetus to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trae&#34;&gt;Trae
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paid for a monthly trial, honestly, it’s better in VSCode using Claude4. The practical effect is also better. Sometimes, even with the same problem, Trae gives better answers. Should I buy an annual subscription later? Given my current chaotic usage frequency, Trae might not be enough; don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much, we’ll see when we run out. Byte should still have other paid plans and purchase more call volumes.
&lt;del&gt;Simple small issues can be solved using Microsoft, GitHub Copilot, and various models can also be called.&lt;/del&gt;
The plan is to fail – GitHub Copilot is now starting to limit the number of calls &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/about-github-copilot/plans-for-github-copilot#models&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;618 opened restrictions&lt;/a&gt;
How to check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/managing-copilot/understanding-and-managing-copilot-usage/monitoring-your-copilot-usage-and-entitlements#downloading-a-monthly-usage-report&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;current usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I couldn’t resist. Since the Hong Kong Connect channel was opened, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t traded in the Hong Kong market, and I bought some Xiaomi stock thinking about their upcoming new car launch. It rose a bit, so I sold it, and when it fell, I bought it back again, repeating this process several times before the new car was released, making a small profit on the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, I didn’t know what to do but look at the cross-border capital flows of Hong Kong Connect, watching Meituan&amp;rsquo;s net inflow of funds, and followed suit by buying it in, successfully becoming a shareholder, forgetting to look at the overall capital flow, only a part of the domestic purchases, and there were still many foreign investors in the Hong Kong market. This time it was just an opportunity to practice with blue-chip stocks, slowly holding on to the final gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling positions and losses are &lt;strong&gt;contrary to human nature&lt;/strong&gt;, slow down, slow down, don’t rush. If Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s new car doesn’t perform well, should I sell? That’s a question. My investment cognition is still insufficient, and I need to read more books and learn more. The Fed isn’t planning on cutting interest rates, and the Hong Kong market plunged once, if I missed the entry time? That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be right, what if the news came out that interest rates were being cut and the Hong Kong market soared? This is investment, testing human nature.
&lt;code&gt;A phrase I often repeat: buying is for national fortune, but I don’t really believe in national fortune.&lt;/code&gt;
Aside from the belief in national fortune, &lt;strong&gt;another one is attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Since you&amp;rsquo;re going to do long-term investing, frequent monitoring of the market is pointless. Ten minutes in the morning and ten minutes at the close are enough. What is the final expected return rate? There’s still no clear stop-loss position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the market falls sharply, Tencent is a hot commodity, with capital flocking to it.
| 00700 | Tencent Holdings | 498.600 | 80.08 billion |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-1&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;03690&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;128.100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.881 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-2&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bubble Mate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;247.200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.703 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-3&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09988&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;109.800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;532.2 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-4&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01810&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.050&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41.05 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and getting anxious won’t help either.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs, and my ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; and if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from when I first entered the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my focus shifted to blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hisense Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in blue chips is like aligning with “old money”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Evergrande’s problems arose, bank stocks plummeted alongside it, successfully identifying the exit point. This reflected a lack of understanding regarding the broader economic market; real estate accounted for too much of China&amp;rsquo;s economy, and the implications were too extensive to simply “land” – the subsequent continued decline in the stock market saw blue-chip stocks like Industrial Bank continue to rise for about two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, ZTESC suffered a severe blow, with its share price also falling dramatically. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hisense Electronics is an old veteran; after Ant Financial withdrew, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock had a controlling shareholder manipulating it, and it could surge several times each year. With reasonable position sizing, you wouldn’t lose much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bond-investment&#34;&gt;Bond Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say it was a lucky outcome, essentially benefiting from falling interest rates. There were changes at my job in Hangzhou, leading me to abandon the idea of buying a house and liquidate my existing bank term deposits. I then focused on reinvesting previously held bonds, significantly increasing my bond investment ratio. Fortunately, interest rates have been declining for several years, allowing me to capitalize on the “bull market” in bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my six months back in Hangzhou, I had plenty of time to reflect and gain clarity. Real estate isn’t a necessity, nor is staying in a particular location – my ability to handle stress was thus improved. If I were to lose my job, the mortgage would be like a mountain to climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-return-expectations&#34;&gt;Investment Return Expectations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The expected annualized oral commitment is comparable to a three-year fixed bank deposit,” but in reality, it’s greedy and wants more. From the initial frantic increase (adding positions), to later exhausting cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represent significant outflows of capital, and overall, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough capital flow left over, leading to insufficient funds later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subsequent plan is to long-term hold &lt;strong&gt;brokerage ETFs&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index&lt;/strong&gt;, with an asset allocation that still includes insurance as a base, medium-to-long term bonds, and stock funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fixed Income Funds / Bond Funds</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 90s, we didn’t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis – after all, we were young and hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet started to focus on finance. The roaring bull market of 2015 came with a lot of fanfare, and when it ended, it made quite a stir, ultimately requiring government intervention to stabilize the markets. Simultaneously, this brought the concept of “funds” into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a natural traffic entry for Ant Financial, Alipay was born with the positioning of a payment tool. When purchasing funds, Alipay and WeChat both saw widespread adoption – most people chose Alipay. Alipay has successfully transformed fund sales into an ordinary shopping experience. Starting in 2019, during the small bull market, fund managers’ “warming up” recruitment, ultimately driven by the monetary easing guided by the COVID-19 pandemic. Those who entered made a profit, those who didn&amp;rsquo;t enter envied them and rushed to join. The scale of new funds broke through the hundred billion mark at an increasingly rapid pace, and with grandmothers starting to buy funds, another trillion fund is not far off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Alipay’s explosive rise as a code-driven internet fund sales platform, ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s contact with fund sales was primarily when depositing money in banks, where the branch manager would enthusiastically introduce various investment products. The internet packaging and promotional page information guidance, the exorbitant advertising fees given by fund sales institutions, completely detached Alipay’s fund advertisements from rationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal bank fixed-term investment returns are 4%, P2P investments that played wildly in recent years were 8%, credit card repayment interest rates are 12%. Our protagonist, Alipay&amp;rsquo;s promoted funds – 150% and 250% – were popular in the market, making everyone happy, both inside and outside the market? Alipay was playing with fire.&lt;/strong&gt; The advertised returns only showed the three-year cumulative yield chart, while traditional fund companies only presented annualized average yields. Why didn’t they dare to present the annual average yield alone? Because it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t look good, and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t guide customers to purchase funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investment&#34;&gt;Fixed Income Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entered a negative interest rate era, making bank deposits and government bonds the most secure fixed-income products. Pure credit funds are also a good option. You can refer to the data published by local statistical bureaus to find China’s average wage levels. I’ll present a simple scenario: with an asset size of 2 million (CNY), an annualized yield of 4%, the annual income will exceed most cities&amp;rsquo; average wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s much more I could write. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading a variety of economic books yourself – don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow. For ordinary families, the core of financial planning is preservation, not chasing risky dreams of getting rich quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right thing at the right time has the greatest value; study diligently when you’re studying, and getting a good degree is better than earning pocket money by distributing flyers; work seriously when you first graduate, and the growth in your salary will bring you substantial returns; and when you start a family, learn to take care of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue-1&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those interested can take a look at this speech transcript: On Time, you need to read many books to find the answer. The text transcript is available on our site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
