<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:15:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Big Tech Dominance in the U.S. Stock Market Intensifies: The Top 10 Companies Account for 40% of Market Capitalization, Is AI a Bubble or a Revolution?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/big-tech-dominance-in-the-us-stock-market-intensifies-the-top-10-companies-account-for-40-of-market-capitalization-is-ai-a-bubble-or-a-revolution/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 23:01:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/big-tech-dominance-in-the-us-stock-market-intensifies-the-top-10-companies-account-for-40-of-market-capitalization-is-ai-a-bubble-or-a-revolution/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Analysis of NVIDIA’s “Play” Worth a Billion Investment
The global capital market is witnessing an unprecedented wave of centralization in 2025, centered around artificial intelligence (AI). This narrative not only reshapes the tech industry&amp;rsquo;s landscape but also exacerbates wealth inequality on Wall Street. The former &amp;ldquo;Magnificent Seven&amp;rdquo; no longer adequately describes today’s dynamics; the market is now dominated by a handful of super winners.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article will delve into three key questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What proportion of the entire stock market do the top ten U.S. companies represent in terms of market capitalization?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does AI constitute a bubble? Is NVIDIA’s (NVIDIA) multi-billion dollar “reciprocal investment” with OpenAI justified?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s recent investment moves, and what is the underlying strategic logic behind them?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Write article: What proportion of the entire stock market do the top ten U.S. companies represent? Does AI constitute a bubble? Are NVIDIA’s investments and reciprocal investment with OpenAI justified? Compile NVIDIA’s recent investment actions and analyze their rationale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;market-concentration-top-10-giants-dominate-40-of-us-stock-market-capitalization&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Concentration: Top 10 Giants Dominate 40% of US Stock Market Capitalization&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the latest data from October to November 2025, the concentration in the US stock market (represented by the S&amp;amp;P 500 Index) has reached a remarkable level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The top 10 US companies in the S&amp;amp;P 500 currently account for approximately 40% of the index’s total market capitalization.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This figure represents an even greater increase than the roughly 30% held by the “Big Seven” a year or two ago. As of early November 2025, the top 10 US companies were approximately:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NVIDIA:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approaching $5 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $4 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Microsoft:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $3.85 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alphabet (Google):&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $3.4 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Amazon:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $2.6 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broadcom:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $1.75 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meta Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $1.63 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tesla:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $1.52 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Berkshire Hathaway:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $1.03 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JPMorgan Chase:&lt;/strong&gt; Market Cap Approximately $0.85 Trillion&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This high concentration means that the stock price performance of a few key companies can determine the entire market’s direction. And the core fuel driving this “super-concentration” is, without question – &lt;strong&gt;Artificial Intelligence&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-bubble-and-the-100-billion-closed-loop-nvidias-mutual-investment-with-openai&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI Bubble and the $100 Billion “Closed Loop”: NVIDIA’s “Mutual Investment” with OpenAI&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “mutual investment” between NVIDIA and OpenAI, which you mentioned, became a global shock event by September 2025. This wasn&amp;rsquo;t traditional VC investment, but a strategic partnership valued at &lt;strong&gt;$100 billion&lt;/strong&gt;, representing a significant shift in the AI landscape.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The “Closed Loop” Structure of the Partnership:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NVIDIA Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; NVIDIA announced it would invest up to &lt;strong&gt;$100 billion&lt;/strong&gt; in OpenAI.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI Procurement:&lt;/strong&gt; OpenAI will utilize this funding (and other financing) to purchase NVIDIA’s chip systems, committing to deploy at least &lt;strong&gt;10 ExaWatts (EW)&lt;/strong&gt; of computing power – involving millions of GPUs – and adopting NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s next-generation “Vera Rubin” platform starting in 2026.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Is This Model Reasonable?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a highly controversial topic, with market opinions divided between “revolution” and “bubble.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perspective 1: Reasonable - It’s the Inevitable Choice of the ‘AI Revolution’ (The Revolution Case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For OpenAI (the Buyer):&lt;/strong&gt; The path to Artificial General Intelligence (AGI) requires near-unlimited computing power.  In today&amp;rsquo;s market, NVIDIA’s GPUs are the most powerful and have the most mature ecosystems – they are the “shovels.” Locking down supply of top-tier chips for several years is the only way to ensure its continued leadership in the AI arms race.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For NVIDIA (the Seller):&lt;/strong&gt; OpenAI is its largest and most important customer. By investing $100 billion and deeply binding itself with OpenAI, NVIDIA effectively secures a massive order for its next-generation platform (Vera Rubin), guaranteeing future revenue and absolute market dominance over several years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perspective 2: Unreasonable - It’s a Classic ‘AI Bubble’ Feature (The Bubble Case)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Closed Loop Financing”:&lt;/strong&gt; Critics argue this is a “left hand, right hand” capital game. NVIDIA gives money to OpenAI, which then uses that money to order from NVIDIA. This creates massive revenue and growth on paper, but significantly amplifies valuations and bubbles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Financial Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Reports indicate NVIDIA was even discussing providing OpenAI with &lt;strong&gt;loan guarantees&lt;/strong&gt; to build data centers.  This means if OpenAI’s business model fails in the future (e.g., AGI doesn&amp;rsquo;t materialize or operating costs are too high leading to bankruptcy), NVIDIA faces risks of tens of billions – or even hundreds of billions – in debt.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Raises Antitrust Concerns:&lt;/strong&gt; This transaction is viewed by regulators and competitors as “anti-competitive.” Analysts worry that, as a market “arms dealer,” NVIDIA will use its investment to deeply bind itself with the largest “mercenary” OpenAI, incentivizing it to refuse selling chips to OpenAI’s competitors (like Anthropic, Google, etc.), or offer worse terms, thereby stifling innovation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; This model is NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s high-risk, high-reward strategic &amp;ldquo;play&amp;rdquo; to ensure its AI dominance. It’s both a catalyst for massive AI development and potentially the footnote on the largest bubble in history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nvidias-investment-empire-a-calculated-demand-creation&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s Investment &amp;ldquo;Empire&amp;rdquo;: A Calculated Demand Creation&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nvidia has long been more than just a “chip vendor.” Through its venture capital arm (NVIDIA GPU Ventures), it is actively transforming into the “banker” and “ecosystem builder” for the entire AI gold rush.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-nvidias-recent-key-investment-actions&#34;&gt;📈 NVIDIA’s Recent Key Investment Actions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;NVIDIA&amp;rsquo;s investment pace has accelerated dramatically in 2024-2025. As of October 2025, NVIDIA has invested in &lt;strong&gt;59 AI startups&lt;/strong&gt; this year, surpassing the 55 invested in throughout 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Its investment portfolio covers almost every vertical within AI, with a focus on:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OpenAI (Foundation Models)&lt;/strong&gt;: In September 2025, it reached a strategic investment and procurement agreement valued at &lt;strong&gt;$100 billion&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Poolside (AI Programming)&lt;/strong&gt;: Revealed to lead an investment of up to &lt;strong&gt;$100 million&lt;/strong&gt;, supporting the development of AI software engineers in October 2025.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nokia (6G/Telecoms)&lt;/strong&gt;: Announced a strategic partnership and invested &lt;strong&gt;$100 million&lt;/strong&gt; jointly developing AI-RAN (Radio Access Network) to capture the 6G market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Figure AI (Humanoid Robots)&lt;/strong&gt;: Investing in this star robotics company, positioning itself for the future of “Embodied Intelligence.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Perplexity AI (AI Search)&lt;/strong&gt;: Investing in this OpenAI competitor, securing a foothold in the next-generation information gateway.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wayve (Autonomous Driving)&lt;/strong&gt;: Investing in the UK’s autonomous driving company to ensure its dominance in automotive chips.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-investment-logic-analysis-why-is-it-reasonable&#34;&gt;🤔 Investment Logic Analysis: Why is it Reasonable?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nvidia CEO Huang Renjun’s strategy is very clear. The core logic of its investments isn&amp;rsquo;t purely financial returns, but rather to serve its core chip business, which can be summarized into three key objectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Core Objective: “Invest, Then Buy My Chips”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is Nvidia’s most direct investment logic. Nvidia injects capital into startups (like Poolside), who in turn use this money to purchase Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s expensive GB300 or next-generation GPUs. This not only locks in customers but also artificially creates demand, forming a “mutually beneficial” business ecosystem between Nvidia and its invested companies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Strategic Objective: Building a &amp;ldquo;CUDA Ecosystem Moat&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia’s true moat is its CUDA software platform. By scattering money across all levels of the AI ecosystem (robotics, biopharmaceuticals, autonomous driving, AI programming), Nvidia ensures that these most promising future companies develop from day one based on the CUDA platform. This prevents competitors (like AMD, Intel) from shaking Nvidia&amp;rsquo;s position even if their hardware keeps up in terms of performance – they simply can’t disrupt Nvidia’s dominance in the software ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Expansion Objective: Securing New Tracks for Chips&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia needs to constantly find the next “AI wave” to support its $500 billion valuation. Its investment in Nokia (6G) is to push its AI chips into the massive telecommunications infrastructure market; its investment in Figure AI (robotics) is a bet on &amp;ldquo;embodied intelligence&amp;rdquo; becoming the next major consumer of computing power after cloud computing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-trickery-under-monopoly&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary: “Trickery” Under Monopoly&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The unprecedented concentration in the US stock market reflects the productivity leap brought about by the AI revolution, but it also carries enormous risks of bubbles. The billion-dollar “closed loop” partnership between Nvidia and OpenAI is a microcosm of this high-stakes gamble.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nvidia’s investment strategy is a meticulously planned “trickery”: It leverages its strong capital strength to &lt;strong&gt;not only become a “weapons supplier” in the AI era, but also to transform into a “banker” and “rule maker,”&lt;/strong&gt; ensuring that all paths to the future are paved with Nvidia chips. This strategy is highly rational and efficient from a business perspective, but it also exposes it to significant antitrust pressure and potential financial risks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For investors, understanding this game driven by AI, led by giants, and strengthened by capital closed loops is key to comprehending the current market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Record and AI Prediction - 20251017</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:50:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday saw no panic sell-off, but the entire week was marked by a persistent downtrend, like a dull knife slicing flesh – a slow, gradual decline over the course of seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disciplined-trading&#34;&gt;Disciplined Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, two new Xiaomi positions were added, with the original plan to sell out at the end. However, at the end, there was a slight loss, leading to hesitation and reluctance to cut losses, so I decided to observe for another day. This morning, the stock price fell slightly by 1%, and when it dropped to 2% in the afternoon, I decisively exited. It turned out to be correct, and the stock continued to fall after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-analysis-follow-up-actions&#34;&gt;AI Analysis Follow-up Actions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I saw someone in the blogosphere using AI to analyze football betting and won second prize with a tax refund of around 900 RMB. Let’s try it with stocks too, based on my experience with large models previously, DeepSeek is most suitable, and the investment plans generated by the other models don&amp;rsquo;t look quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Currently holding Xiaomi, approximately 100,000 RMB, down 15%, Meituan 70,000 RMB, down 20,000 RMB. Querying current stock prices and determining subsequent position control – I’m planning for long-term investment. The reason for buying Xiaomi is due to the Yu9 IPO, the three phases of factory ramp-up, and continued high sales, which should drive the price up. Meituan is after the end of the food delivery war stabilizes; Hong Kong Q3 earnings reports will be released next month – it’s more reasonable to operate after the reports are released. For my long-term investment of three to five years, please provide me with an investment plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-investment-plan-xiaomi-and-meituan-position-analysis--long-term-strategy&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Xiaomi and Meituan Position Analysis &amp;amp; Long-Term Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the information you provided (holding Xiaomi approximately HK$100,000 with a loss of 15% and Meituan approximately HK$70,000 with a loss of approximately 28.6%, investment horizon of 3 years), I have compiled the latest market data and analysis to develop a detailed investment plan for you. The following is core information extracted from comprehensive search results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Stock Prices (as of October 17, 2025)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$45.88 (down 3.82%, cumulative monthly decline exceeding 15%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$94.50 (down 4.30%, year-to-date cumulative decline of 37.71%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Market Environment&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hang Seng Index fell by 2.48%, with technology stocks leading the decline, and market sentiment is short-term weak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation of Your Purchase Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;: The listing of Yu9, the ramp-up of Phase III factory, and sales potential are reasonable long-term logic, but the stock price is suppressed in the short term due to the impact of the Chengdu SU7 accident (door safety controversy, intervention by regulatory authorities).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;: Stabilization after the end of the food delivery war is a key long-term factor, but competition remains intense (competition from JD.com and Alibaba), with net profit falling 89% in the second quarter and Wang Xing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;no matter the cost&amp;rdquo; statement exacerbating market concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your current holdings are down approximately 18.8% (total holding of HKD 1.7 million, a loss of approximately HKD 374,000), but long-term investment requires avoiding emotional trading operations. Here’s a phased recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Pre-Earnings Report (Short-Term: Now to Q3 Earnings Release)&lt;/strong&gt; | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Closely monitor the progress of the SU7 accident investigation and Q3 vehicle delivery volume data. | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Focus on monitoring whether Q3 takeout UE (average order revenue) improves. | Potential price volatility before earnings report: &lt;br&gt;• Xiaomi will be dragged down by safety incidents and is unlikely to rebound in the short term.&lt;br&gt;• The competition between Meituan Takeout continues, and profitability recovery requires time. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid-term: November - Q1 2026)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings show steady vehicle sales growth and mobile gross margin bottoms out, consider adding to positions 5%-10%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings confirm easing competition and narrowing losses, add to positions 5%-10%; otherwise maintain current holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s 2025 target sales volume is 350,000 units, and high-end mobile phones are key to profitability.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan SOTP valuation shows 121% upside potential, but requires a profit inflection point.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 75 HKD (potential upside of 63%). Risk points: automotive safety regulation, smartphone demand weakness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 247 HKD (potential upside of 161%). Risk points: rising policy costs, losses in new businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s car-home ecosystem closed loop is the long-term engine.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan instant retail penetration rate is expected to improve.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-strategy-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Strategy Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you trade after the financial reports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, we recommend waiting for the third quarter financial reports (released in November) before making additional investment decisions.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial reports will validate your initial purchase logic: Xiaomi’s factory ramp-up sales volume and Meituan’s easing competition evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the reports are below expectations, the stock price may fall, providing a better entry point for adding to your position; if they exceed expectations, it can confirm the right-side signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term market sentiment is driven by events (such as Xiaomi incidents and food delivery price wars), and financial reports will reduce uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-term-investment-plan-3-year-perspective&#34;&gt;Long-Term Investment Plan (3-Year Perspective)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the “Hold Quality Assets + Bottom Hunting” principle, your plan can be detailed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group: Strong Defense and Offense, Focus on Automotive Business Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Vehicle business scale effect (target 350,000 units annual sales), AIoT ecosystem synergy. Financial health (Z-Score=4.19, low bankruptcy risk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the SU7 safety issues continue to ferment, the stock price may fall to the 40-42 HKD range, and a trigger point for adding positions can be set (adding 5% position when the price drops by 10%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Automotive quarterly delivery volume remains above 80,000 units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 40%-50% total portfolio weighting (currently 59% is high, and can be adjusted after earnings reports).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W: Wait for Profitability Recovery, Focus on Core Business&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Stable takeout market share (65%), takeaway business growth of 40%, valuation undervalued (SOTP target price of HKD 247).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the takeout UE (average profit per order) turns positive, it is a signal for adding positions; if competition intensifies, the stock price may fall to HKD 80, and we can buy back shares in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Core local business operating profit rate recovers above 15%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 30%-40% weighting (currently 41% is reasonable but needs to be wary of competition dragging it down).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversified Investment Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong tech stocks are under pressure recently, but long-term they still represent new quality production. Consider allocating 10%-20% of capital to high dividend assets (such as telecommunications operators) or Hong Kong tech ETFs to hedge the risk of a single stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Vehicle Deliveries, Mobile Gross Margin Trend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Delivery UE Improvement, New Business Loss Rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Achieve targets – increase position; Otherwise maintain current position.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-1&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1 2026&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xinjiang Model Road Tests Progress, Premium Phone Sales Volume&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Level of Reduced Delivery Subsidies, Profit Turnpoint for Flash Purchase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Assess Annual Target Completion and Adjust Portfolio.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-2&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Auto business break-even, AIoT penetration rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Instant retail market share, policy cost absorption&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold until target price or downgrade fundamentals; consider reducing holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-milestones&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Milestones
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Immediate Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain the status quo, and avoid blind hedging before the financial reports. Current stock prices have partially reflected negative news, but volatility may increase before the reports are released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term Confidence Support:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaomi’s automotive ecosystem and smartphone premiumization are core logic; short-term incidents do not change its long-term technological iteration capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan’s profitability will be significant once the food delivery war ends (referring to Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s observation of fire across the river).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Warnings:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall Hong Kong stock market is highly sensitive to global liquidity; if the Federal Reserve delays interest rate cuts, it may suppress technology stocks’ valuations. Ensure investment funds are long-term idle funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plan is based on public information and does not constitute investment advice. The market carries risks; decision-making requires caution. Recommend regular review (e.g., quarterly) to adjust strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-1&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be appropriate to add more positions after the financial reports are released, as it could lead to significant price increases and then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-2&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question you raised is extremely critical, and it accurately highlights a classic dilemma faced by long-term investors: &lt;strong&gt;avoiding short-term risks (waiting for the earnings report) can conflict with pursuing the best cost (fearing missing out).&lt;/strong&gt;
Your concern that “adding to your position after the earnings report if the stock price rises sharply will cause you to miss out” is very reasonable. The market often has a forward-looking nature, and if the earnings report is truly better than expected, the stock price is likely to react quickly in the short term. However, given your current holdings of these two stocks, “waiting for the earnings report” remains the optimal strategy. Below, I will explain the reasons in detail and provide a step-by-step addition strategy that balances “risk” and “opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-waiting-for-the-earnings-report-still-a-more-reasonable-choice-in-the-current-situation&#34;&gt;Why is “Waiting for the Earnings Report” Still a More Reasonable Choice in the Current Situation?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core reason lies in: &lt;strong&gt;The uncertainty surrounding the two stocks you hold stems primarily from fundamental contradictions within their businesses, and the earnings report is key to validating these contradictions.&lt;/strong&gt; There hasn’t been a significant “catalyst” (a substantial price increase) yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;an automotive business confidence crisis&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The negative impact of the SU7 safety incident is still unfolding, leading to market skepticism regarding Xiaomi Auto’s quality, reputation, and future sales expectations. This is the primary factor suppressing the stock price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The third quarter earnings report will provide crucial &lt;strong&gt;vehicle delivery data&lt;/strong&gt;. If deliveries remain strong, it can effectively dispel market concerns and drive a sustainable increase in the stock price. Until then, any rally would likely be fragile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Given the prevailing negative sentiment, the probability of the stock experiencing a significant, sustained rise before the earnings report is relatively low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows poor vehicle sales, the price could continue to decline, leaving you with the greater risk of “buying back in at half price.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;when will profitability be restored?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The market worries that intense competition will continue to erode profits from its core takeaway business (UE).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;core local business operating profit&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;adjusted net profit&lt;/strong&gt; in the report are the only objective standards for determining whether the “takeaway war” has truly eased. Only improved data can prove that Wang Xiting’s “no matter the cost” phase is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Again, there&amp;rsquo;s a lack of a solid foundation for a significant rebound before the profitability inflection point is confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows that competition intensifies and profits continue to decline, concerns about the “valuation trap” will intensify, and the price could take another step down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term investment, &lt;strong&gt;buying &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; is more important than buying &amp;ldquo;cheap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report provides the key evidence for determining “correctness.” To avoid a minor “missed opportunity” and risk a “deep trap,” from a risk-reward ratio perspective, it’s not worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-specific-action-plan-balancing-waiting-and-missing-out-anxiety&#34;&gt;Your Specific Action Plan: Balancing “Waiting” and “Missing Out” Anxiety
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to make extreme choices between “holding everything” and “going all in.” A smarter strategy is: &lt;strong&gt;“Core Holding Observation, Pyramidal Accumulation.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Immediately Establish “Observation Position” and “Operational Discipline” (Now)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain your existing position as your core holding, ensuring you don’t completely detach from the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a &lt;strong&gt;trigger for adding to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. For example:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The stock price breaks out with volume through a key technical level (e.g., HK$50), or there is a clear positive investigation result regarding the SU7 accident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; News emerges of a competitor exiting the price war, or the stock price breaks through the HK$100 integer barrier with volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The benefit of doing this:&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s a significant catalyst driving the stock price up before the earnings report, you can seize the opportunity according to your established discipline and avoid completely missing out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Small Batch Investing Before Earnings (Optional, Suitable for Investors Seeking Smoother Costs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re very concerned about missing out, divide the funds earmarked for adding to your position into 10-20 portions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before the earnings release, if the stock continues to decline in the shadows, invest one portion &lt;strong&gt;weekly or bi-weekly&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, costs can be gradually diluted, but each investment amount is small, and even if the earnings report is negative, the loss can be controlled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: “Certainty” Accumulation After Earnings (Core Operation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the main accumulation phase of your plan. Based on the earnings results, respond in three ways:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario A (Exceeds Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings data is strong and validates your investment logic. At this time, you should &lt;strong&gt;aggressively add to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if the stock price has already risen, the fundamental turning point has been confirmed, and from a long-term perspective, the current price level is still the base of the mountain. You can adopt a “don’t chase high while chasing gains” strategy, buying in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario B (Meets Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report is neutral, with no surprises or shocks. Maintain your existing position or only modestly add to it, waiting for the next quarter&amp;rsquo;s signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario C (Falls Short of Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report confirms market concerns. You should &lt;strong&gt;stop adding to your position and reassess&lt;/strong&gt; whether the long-term logic has been disrupted. The stock price may fall, but this also provides you with a lower, safer entry point for accumulating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Reporting Period (Now - November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Observe”&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintain existing positions, without adding or only making very small fixed investments. Set trigger conditions for adding to positions to prevent sudden positive developments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control Risk, Preserve Capital&lt;/strong&gt;. Ensure not to invest more funds when fundamentals deteriorate.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan-1&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid to Late November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Follow the Trend”&lt;/strong&gt;: Make decisions based on earnings results. Aggressively add to positions if exceeding expectations; patiently wait for better opportunities if below expectations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve Decision Quality&lt;/strong&gt;. Allocate capital to directions with greater fundamental certainty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-long-term-investment-plan-optimized&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Long-Term Investment Plan Optimized
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Optimize”&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on the consolidation of the company’s long-term competitiveness (Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, Meituan’s retail) rather than short-term stock price fluctuations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achieve Compound Growth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please remember:&lt;/strong&gt; In long-term investing, &lt;strong&gt;patience is a powerful competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;. The market will always give you opportunities; if you miss one, there will be another. But once your principal is lost, it’s difficult to recover. Waiting for the certainty of financial reports is one of the most effective ways to protect your capital and increase your chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this detailed plan answers your questions and helps you make more confident decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Meituan’s Losses to Bond Mismatch</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the turbulent and unpredictable stock market, we often use faith and expectations as our compass, attempting to navigate through the fog and reach the shores of wealth. However, when our voyage deviates from the guidance of the compass, it’s easy to lose direction, even to run aground. This essay is about one such journey, beginning with an unwavering obsession with &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose and fell repeatedly amidst the waves of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clash-of-faith-and-reality-xiaomis-gains-and-losses&#34;&gt;The Clash of Faith and Reality: Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Gains and Losses
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, I bought into Xiaomi with unwavering &lt;strong&gt;faith&lt;/strong&gt; in Lei Jun and a hopeful vision for the company’s electric vehicles. At the time, faith was a powerful force, temporarily blinding me to Lei Jun’s shrewdness as a capitalist and overlooking the risks posed by the High-Level Flash Lightning Distribution Platform. Fortunately, several &lt;strong&gt;wave trading&lt;/strong&gt; operations ended with modest profits, giving me a sweet taste of entering the Hong Kong stock market for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this self-confidence soon followed. After making a small profit on &lt;strong&gt;Jiu Fang&lt;/strong&gt; stocks, I became somewhat &lt;strong&gt;dazed&lt;/strong&gt;, relying solely on the flow of net buying funds from the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect&lt;/strong&gt; indicator instead of rational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituans-waterloo-and-blind-re-positioning&#34;&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waterloo&amp;rdquo; and Blind Re-positioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by the flow of funds, I turned my attention to &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;. However, this time, I didn’t delve into the company’s &lt;strong&gt;financial data&lt;/strong&gt;, its &lt;strong&gt;historical trends&lt;/strong&gt;, or even realize the raging &lt;strong&gt;food delivery war&lt;/strong&gt; that was unfolding. When the stock price began to fall, I failed to cut my losses in time and instead blindly &lt;strong&gt;added to my position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares trading at HK$20,000-30,000, limitations on capital prevented me from managing my positions freely, which undoubtedly exacerbated my losses in Meituan. This lesson deeply made me realize that in the Hong Kong stock market, blind re-positioning is like trying to fill a constantly leaking bathtub with more water – it only accelerates the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-people-are-lucky---an-unexpected-gain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stupid People Are Lucky&amp;rdquo; - An Unexpected Gain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was worrying about Meituan&amp;rsquo;s losses, an unexpected turn of events occurred – I bought &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;. Although I didn’t hold onto it, I quickly sold it and used the profit to offset some of Meituan’s losses. This might be what’s meant by “stupid people are lucky,” allowing me to temporarily escape Meituan&amp;rsquo;s predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finance-more-important-fundamentals-than-investing&#34;&gt;Finance: More Important Fundamentals Than Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience also made me re-examine my &lt;strong&gt;financial management&lt;/strong&gt; approach, aside from the ups and downs of the stock market. At the time, I invested a sum intended for short-term emergency funds into &lt;strong&gt;Chinese bonds&lt;/strong&gt;. This money was meant to be used for payment within two months, but the short-term holding yield on the bonds wasn&amp;rsquo;t high, and it also posed liquidity issues. If I had instead chosen to deposit this money into a &lt;strong&gt;money fund&lt;/strong&gt;, I could have earned more stable returns and readily redeemed it, better meeting my funding needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Sometimes you need to learn how to interrupt.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:14:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own life trajectory, so the concept of “being a good teacher” often seems superfluous in adult circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;worldview&#34;&gt;Worldview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our life’s journey begins with vastly different formative experiences, these experiences converging and flowing like rivers to ultimately shape our unique life paths. Each story, each choice, weaves together and merges within our minds, solidifying into our perception of the world – our &lt;strong&gt;worldview&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed as tragedy may be merely a story in a book to another person. What you disdain as a lifestyle may be precisely the ideal someone else desperately pursues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding and respecting each other’s differences is the first step in comprehending this diverse world. Sometimes, &lt;strong&gt;remaining silent is also a form of understanding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to share my experiences and insights rather than engage in empty chatter. However, inevitably, you will encounter moments where observing the slow flow of water is a worthwhile strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-philosophy&#34;&gt;Investment Philosophy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My choice of &lt;strong&gt;fixed income plus&lt;/strong&gt; as the primary investment approach is driven by its emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;stable returns&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;low risk&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, I will allocate a significant portion of my asset allocation to this type of product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding stocks, I differentiate between short-term and long-term investments. In my view, &lt;strong&gt;short-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; carries a strong speculative nature, resembling more of a &lt;strong&gt;gambit&lt;/strong&gt;; while &lt;strong&gt;long-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; is genuine &lt;strong&gt;value investing&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s like founding your own company, from fundraising to IPO – you not only reap stock dividends but also gain a profound understanding of economic laws and foresight for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recognized since childhood that I have a &lt;strong&gt;gambling addiction&lt;/strong&gt;, however, studying allows me to rationally control my irrational desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of digital currencies is something I generally dislike from an investment perspective – I haven’t found any real value, but we need to understand its principles and risks. There have previously been articles discussing stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-eggs&#34;&gt;Easter Eggs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;WeChat can fold group chats, and &lt;strong&gt;your private conversations with friends can also be folded&lt;/strong&gt;, from a design perspective, all conversations belong to the same level and are only differentiated in display.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Aug 2025 18:57:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Using AI too much, we start thinking of AI for everything – often, learning new developments is more reliable with search engines plus official project documentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong stocks entered on the dip, encountered a pullback, and then just randomly traded, resulting in basic losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strategy-trading&#34;&gt;Strategy Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not necessarily to actually practice and make money, but rather to improve my own abilities through learning. I don&amp;rsquo;t believe in these trading indicators; I mostly trust the national fortune (luck) and investing in broad market indices via a buy-and-hold strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithmic-trading&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The inspiration from last month’s “AI-less project” didn&amp;rsquo;t prove useful, so I started trying to implement it with AI – and that’s where the problems began. The correct approach should have been to first gather information and see what existing projects were doing. Previously, I hadn’t done any algorithmic trading; I wasn’t familiar with indicators, market data handling, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The initial plan was unreliable, entirely based on my own speculation (“YY”) through communication with AI. I learned about the backtesting framework this way, and looked at GitHub – the project was quite active.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over-reliance on AI led to wanting to use it for everything, even requesting an AI-generated learning resource, a vibrant project, and official documentation that’s well-maintained. Prioritizing official documentation or searching for high-quality blogs is better; the learning plans provided by AI were too weak and didn&amp;rsquo;t keep up with current code versions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project Structure Adjustments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Download:&lt;/strong&gt; I chose Yahoo Finance – this provides daily candlestick data for price changes (price fluctuations).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Backtesting Official Guide:&lt;/strong&gt; Learning the basics of using the official backtesting guide.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TA-Lib Installation and Usage:&lt;/strong&gt; Installing and using TA-Lib, calculating common indicators, and displaying the data through backtesting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Implementing Alipay’s Fixed Investment Logic:&lt;/strong&gt; This strategy is better suited for long-term ETF investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-trading&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering Hong Kong stock trading was roughly two months ago, a simple recap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timing and motivation for buying Meituan were straightforward – I saw the net inflow of domestic funds and didn’t delve deeply into Meituan&amp;rsquo;s recent situation; coincidentally, I caught the food delivery war and became a shareholder in Meituan. Buying Xiaomi was also at a high price point, and it was appropriate to reduce my position and exit some shares when an opportunity arose. The four factories were implemented, presenting an opportunity, but one that required persistence – about three years have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The timing of entry was when Hong Kong’s new consumer and technology stocks were already expensive, coupled with the concept of virtual currencies; when technology stocks retraced, it was a recurring issue – the frequency of adding to positions is not suitable for long-term investment. Today, I thought about betting on a rebound, buying a hand full, but the next day it fell and I couldn’t bear to sell it. When encountering sustained declines, one easily gets trapped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a long-term investor, my trading frequency was too high – roughly twice a week would be sufficient.
The Shanghai Composite Index is 3600; domestic large-cap stocks haven&amp;rsquo;t been much invested in through fixed deposits; this missed an opportunity as well.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>RWA (Real World Assets) and Web3: A New Bottle of Old Wine?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/rwa-real-world-assets-and-web3-a-new-bottle-of-old-wine/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:48:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/rwa-real-world-assets-and-web3-a-new-bottle-of-old-wine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Driven by the tide of technological innovation, RWA (Real World Assets) and Web3 have become hot topics in the financial industry. Traditional financial institutions – once regarded as conservative and stable giants – are now actively embracing these emerging concepts, vigorously promoting the development of RWA and DeFi (Decentralized Finance). However, behind this technology-driven transformation lies a core question worth pondering: Are these dazzling new concepts truly disruptive innovation, or simply giving traditional financial businesses a “new look”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rwa-and-web3-decoding-core-concepts&#34;&gt;RWA and Web3: Decoding Core Concepts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RWA (Real World Assets), referring to real-world assets,&lt;/strong&gt; are tangible or intangible assets from the physical world that are issued and traded as digital assets on a blockchain through “tokenization” technology. These assets can encompass real estate, bonds, private credit, artwork, carbon credits, and more. Its core value lies in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Liquidity:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividing illiquid assets (such as real estate) into smaller shares, reducing investment barriers, and enabling them to be traded easily on secondary markets like stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improving Transparency and Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizing blockchain’s immutability and traceability to simplify asset issuance, trading, and settlement processes, reduce intermediaries and human error, ultimately lowering costs and improving efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding Financing Channels:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing asset owners with a globalized, more efficient financing platform, breaking down geographical and traditional financial intermediary restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3, often referred to as “the next generation internet,”&lt;/strong&gt; has core principles of building a decentralized, user-owned and controlled internet ecosystem. Unlike the Web2 era dominated by a few tech giants, Web3 is based on blockchain technology, aiming to return data ownership and control to users. Its key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralization:&lt;/strong&gt; Information and applications are no longer stored on single company servers but distributed across numerous nodes in the network, reducing the risk of single points of failure and censorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Sovereignty:&lt;/strong&gt; Users have greater control over their personal data, choosing with whom to share it and how it is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permissionless and Censorship-Resistant:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone can participate in the network, publish applications or use services without needing approval from centralized authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-are-traditional-financial-institutions-embracing-rwa-and-defi&#34;&gt;Why Are Traditional Financial Institutions Embracing RWA and DeFi?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional financial institutions are actively pushing for RWA and DeFi primarily due to the following strategic considerations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency Gains &amp;amp; Cost Reduction:&lt;/strong&gt; The traditional financial system is characterized by significant manual auditing, complex clearing and settlement processes, and burdensome compliance steps, leading to inefficiency and high costs. Through smart contracts and blockchain technology, DeFi and RWA can automate many of these processes, significantly reducing operational costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating New Revenue Streams &amp;amp; Markets:&lt;/strong&gt; The emergence of RWA has opened up new asset classes and business models for financial institutions. For example, providing tokenized services for real estate or private credit projects, underwriting, and trading can generate new fees and consulting revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responding to Competition &amp;amp; Maintaining Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt; Competition from fintech companies and crypto native enterprises is intensifying. By proactively positioning themselves in RWA and DeFi, traditional financial institutions can demonstrate their innovative capabilities, attract a new generation of clients, and secure a favorable position in the future financial landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Transparency &amp;amp; Risk Management:&lt;/strong&gt; The transparency offered by blockchain helps improve the visibility of underlying asset information, allowing investors to better assess risks.  Furthermore, standardized token protocols and automated compliance checks can also enhance risk management efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-essence-new-wine-in-an-old-bottle&#34;&gt;Business Essence: New Wine in an Old Bottle?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite RWA and DeFi bringing innovation in technology and models, from a core business logic perspective, the current RWA-related businesses undertaken by traditional financial institutions are largely extensions and digital upgrades of their &lt;strong&gt;traditional businesses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking &lt;strong&gt;RWA&lt;/strong&gt; as an example, its core is to tokenize traditional assets. This process bears a striking resemblance to traditional &lt;strong&gt;Asset Securitization (ABS)&lt;/strong&gt;. ABS involves transforming illiquid assets with predictable cash flows into tradable securities in financial markets through packaging and layering. RWA simply shifts the carrier of securitization from traditional electronic certificates to blockchain-based tokens. Its essence remains &lt;strong&gt;credit intermediation and asset management&lt;/strong&gt; – selecting high-quality assets, structuring them, and selling them to investors. For example, packaging the future rental income rights of a commercial property into tokens is no different than issuing Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) in terms of its core financial nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in the &lt;strong&gt;DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; sector, although its “decentralized” concept aims to disrupt traditional financial intermediaries, the way current institutions are participating is primarily to &lt;strong&gt;utilize their technological advantages to optimize existing businesses&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, using smart contracts to simplify loan approval and disbursement processes or conducting more efficient cross-border payments and settlements through decentralized exchanges. Its core business of &lt;strong&gt;lending, trading, and payment&lt;/strong&gt; remains the cornerstone of the financial system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It can be said that traditional financial institutions driving RWA and DeFi is more like a “self-revolution,” namely, without changing its core financial functions, using new technologies to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and expand markets.&lt;/strong&gt; They are not trying to completely overthrow themselves but rather hope to consolidate and expand their industry position through technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, RWA and Web3 have undoubtedly brought profound changes to the financial industry. They have solved many pain points in traditional finance through technology. However, for traditional financial institutions at this stage, embracing these technologies is more like a cautious and pragmatic strategic choice. Its core business logic has not fundamentally changed, still revolving around assets, credit, and transactions – these ancient financial themes.  As technology matures and regulation improves, we may see more disruptive financial innovations; however, given the current situation, “new wine in an old bottle” is perhaps the most accurate description.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>HKSG Flash Crash Sell-Off Case</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:12:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[The company recently raised capital in the Hong Kong market](Nine Fang Zhi Tu.pdf), this fundraising is similar to Xiaomi’s operation, and this article breaks down the details. &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nine-fang-intelligent-investment-and-sales-interpretation&#34;&gt;Nine Fang Intelligent Investment and Sales Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the fees associated with participating in the offering; when can these stocks be sold, what other important information is contained in this document?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This placement activity is a &lt;strong&gt;pre-existing shareholder first, then new&lt;/strong&gt; placement method, targeting new investors (placements), &lt;strong&gt;does not involve retail investor subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are not a placement agent-selected placement recipient (i.e., professional/institutional/individual investors), you do not need to pay any fees.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement-1&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, if you are a placement agent, the fees involved include:
| Placement Price | ✅ Yes | HKD 39.25 per share |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-reselling&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Reselling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Reseller&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resell price &lt;strong&gt;excludes&lt;/strong&gt; commission, transaction fees, stamp duty etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Brokerage Agent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Transaction Fee / Exchange Trading Fee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charged according to Hong Kong Stock Exchange rules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangements&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangements
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Broker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp Duty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp duty of 0.13% is payable for Hong Kong stock purchases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-costs-associated-with-distribution&#34;&gt;✅ Costs Associated with Distribution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-shares-can-be-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Shares Can Be Sold
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the announcement content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The share placement will be undertaken by the placing agents based on their best efforts to place shares with no less than six noteholders… &lt;strong&gt;It is anticipated that none of the noteholders will become a major shareholder of the Company immediately following completion of the share placement.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-can-shares-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Can Shares Sold?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shares sold through the placement can be freely traded once settlement is complete;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no lock-up period;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can be bought and sold freely on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange secondary market;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The placement deadline is &lt;strong&gt;July 17, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, with expected settlement to occur shortly after &lt;strong&gt;July 17th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-important-information-in-announcement&#34;&gt;✅ Important Information in Announcement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-of-funds-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Funds (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine Square Capital will use this money to do four things:
| On-Chain Financial Resource Investment | Undefined | Invest in RWA underlying assets, digital asset exchanges, trust banks, and stablecoin operators |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Services Layout | Undefined | Investment services for digital assets targeting consumers in Hong Kong and the Middle East regions |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Investment Advisory New Model | Unspecified | AI + Research, Combining MCN Operational Experience |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funding-allocation-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supplemental Liquidity Funding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unspecified&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;General corporate use&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;offer-price-discount-is-significant&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer Price Discount is Significant&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;6.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the closing price of 41.75 HKD on July 15th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;17.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 5-day average price of 47.30 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;15.3%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 10-day average price of 46.36 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Share Structure Changes**

- Following the public offering, **total shares outstanding increased from 448 million to 468 million**.
- Existing shareholders’ ownership percentages were **slightly diluted**, but they **continue to maintain a controlling stake**.
- An additional 20,000,000 shares will be held by the underwriters, representing approximately **4.27%** of total outstanding shares.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-disclaimer&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The offering may not be completed, and requires fulfillment of multiple prerequisites (such as market stability, regulatory approval, and the absence of significant adverse events)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is not completed within 14 days, the subscription matter will automatically become invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail investors are excluded from this placement; the placed shares have no lock-up period and can be traded immediately after settlement. Jiu Fang Investment plans to use HK$746 million to invest in digital assets and on-chain finance, potentially transitioning towards Web3 and AI robo-advisor directions in the future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-old-then-new-distribution-method-explained&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Old, Then New&amp;rdquo; Distribution Method Explained
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Existing shareholders first old shares then new&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; is a &lt;strong&gt;common Hong Kong distribution method&lt;/strong&gt;, known in English as &lt;strong&gt;Top-up Placement&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can understand as a two-step operation of “&lt;strong&gt;major shareholders sell old shares first and then subscribe to new shares&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-to-understand-it&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example to understand it
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking the case of &lt;strong&gt;Jiutian Intelligence Investment&lt;/strong&gt; as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Major shareholders sell old shares (First Old)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing shareholders (such as Coreworth Investments) sell their existing holdings of &lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 old shares&lt;/strong&gt; to market investors (the underwriter) at a price of HKD 39.25 per share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder reducing their holding&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;total issued capital remains unchanged&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Company issues new shares to major shareholders (Later New)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company then issues an equal number (&lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 shares&lt;/strong&gt;) of new shares to these major shareholders at a price of HKD 39.25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major shareholder uses the proceeds from selling old shares to buy back new shares, &lt;strong&gt;restoring their holding quantity to its original state&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, the total issued capital increases (from 448 million shares to 468 million shares), &lt;strong&gt;effectively meaning the company has successfully raised capital&lt;/strong&gt;, while the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder&amp;rsquo;s shareholding ratio is slightly diluted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avoid the lengthy process of issuing new shares, instead selling old shares first and then supplementing with new shares to quickly raise capital.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-1&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The majority shareholders will maintain their voting power, and control won&amp;rsquo;t be significantly diluted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-2&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attract New Investors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Through discounted share sales (private placements), attract institutional or high-net-worth investors to enter the market, optimizing the shareholder structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-3&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Not newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Can be immediately traded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;These are existing shares on the market, which can be directly circulated after being sold to new investors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-1&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Shares&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;⚠️ Lock-up Period (typically 180 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shares newly issued by the company, given to original shareholders, and typically require a lock-up period.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-2&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-one-sentence-summary&#34;&gt;✅ One-Sentence Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sell Old, Buy New&amp;rdquo; refers to major shareholders initially selling their existing shares to the market and then purchasing an equal amount of new shares from the company, simultaneously raising capital for the company while maintaining control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-connect-issuance-rules-interpretation&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Connect Issuance Rules Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: Your question is very central: &lt;strong&gt;Why do Hong Kong-listed companies seem to be able to “freely” issue shares? Is the Hong Kong market rulebook particularly relaxed?&lt;/strong&gt;
The answer is: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, HKEX offers significantly more flexibility than the Shanghai A-share market&lt;/strong&gt;, but it’s &lt;strong&gt;not “unlimited,”&lt;/strong&gt; rather there&amp;rsquo;s a system of &lt;strong&gt;“relaxed but limited” rules.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require shareholder meeting approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ The Board of Directors can authorize share issuance not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;20% of the total equity&lt;/strong&gt; annually at the annual general meeting, and no further meetings are required thereafter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Each issuance must be held with a &lt;strong&gt;separate shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt; and pass by a 2/3 majority vote.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require SEC approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ As long as it’s no more than 20% of share capital + offering price is no more than 20%, it can “flash allocation”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Must undergo SEC &lt;strong&gt;case-by-case review&lt;/strong&gt;, which takes longer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Issuance Ratio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Maximum of 20% per issuance, cumulative dilution within 12 months shall not exceed 25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Generally not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-2&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discount Margin Limit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Offering price shall not be lower than 80% of the market price (maximum discount of 20%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Non-public placements shall not be lower than 80% of the market price&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock-up Period&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Typically &lt;strong&gt;30 days or none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;6~36 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-3&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Proceeds Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Disclosure of use only, no substantive review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Must detail use of proceeds, SEC can veto&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-hong-kong-stocks-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ Hong Kong Stocks vs. A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-does-the-hong-kong-stock-exchange-look-casual&#34;&gt;✅ Why Does the Hong Kong Stock Exchange Look “Casual”?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“General Mandate” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
Once a year, shareholders authorize the board to issue up to 20% new shares at their annual general meeting. Afterwards, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meetings are required&lt;/strong&gt;, and the board can selectively issue shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Flash Placement” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
If the issuance does not exceed 20% of the share capital and the discount is no more than 20%, &lt;strong&gt;the issuance can be completed within 24 hours without approval&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No SEC Case-by-Case Approval:
The Hong Kong Stock Exchange only conducts &lt;strong&gt;formative review&lt;/strong&gt;, without substantive intervention in the use of funds or company quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-why-was-jiufang-zhitou-able-to-do-old-and-new-this-time&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: Why was JiuFang ZhiTou able to &amp;ldquo;do old and new&amp;rdquo; this time?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JiuFang ZhiTou obtained a &lt;strong&gt;general authorization&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;2025 June 20th shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for up to a 20% increase in new shares (i.e., up to 89,671,400 shares).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This issuance of 20,000,000 shares represents only &lt;strong&gt;4.46% of the capital&lt;/strong&gt;, far below the 20% limit, and &lt;strong&gt;fully complies with the authorization conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meeting is needed&lt;/strong&gt; nor &lt;strong&gt;is approval from the Securities Regulatory Commission required&lt;/strong&gt;; the board of directors can make the decision to implement it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-1&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong stocks allow “board of directors + annual authorization” rapid issuance under a streamlined process, provided it doesn’t exceed 20% of the share capital and the price cap, enabling “flash placement,” while A-shares require shareholder approval plus SEC review, resulting in a longer, more restrictive procedure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-2&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Jiu Fang Zhi Tu (Nine Fang Intelligent Investment) is not “arbitrary issuance,” but rather &lt;strong&gt;legally and compliantly utilized the relaxed mechanisms of the Hong Kong stock market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Comprehensive Analysis: Capital Gains Tax, CRS, and Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp; US Stocks Investment Tax Guide</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:12:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks, understanding relevant tax regulations is crucial. This article will comprehensively analyze what capital gains tax is, why it applies to investments in Hong Kong and US stocks, and explain the workings of CRS (Common Reporting Standard). Furthermore, this article will also provide detailed answers regarding the tax responsibilities and specific tax rates for mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks through various channels (Hong Kong brokers, Hong Kong-Shanghai Link, and Shenzhen-Hong Kong Link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-concept-breakdown&#34;&gt;Core Concept Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-capital-gains-tax-cgt&#34;&gt;What is Capital Gains Tax (CGT)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital Gains Tax (CGT), often abbreviated as CGT, is a tax levied on the &lt;strong&gt;profits realized from selling assets&lt;/strong&gt;. These assets can include stocks, bonds, real estate, precious metals, and more. When you sell an asset for a price higher than your purchase price, the resulting gains (known as capital gains) may be subject to Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that not all countries or regions levy Capital Gains Tax. For example, Hong Kong currently does not impose Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-subject-to-capital-gains-tax&#34;&gt;Why are Hong Kong and US Stocks Subject to Capital Gains Tax?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States is a country that levies capital gains tax. For non-U.S. taxpayers (such as most mainland investors), while selling US stocks typically qualifies for exemption from capital gains tax, certain conditions must be met (e.g., residency in the U.S. for no more than 183 days within a year). However, dividends received from US stocks are subject to withholding income tax at a rate of usually 30%, but according to the China-U.S. Tax Agreement, mainland Chinese residents can apply to reduce this rate to 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; As stated above, Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax. Therefore, regardless of the channel through which you trade Hong Kong stocks, no tax is payable on the difference between purchase and sale prices. This doesn’t mean that mainland residents don&amp;rsquo;t need to declare this income to the Chinese mainland tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-crs-reporting-common-reporting-standard&#34;&gt;What is CRS Reporting (Common Reporting Standard)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CRS, or the “Common Reporting Standard,” is a global standard for the automatic exchange of financial account information. Its primary purpose is to combat tax evasion involving offshore accounts and cross-border tax avoidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it Works:&lt;/strong&gt; In simple terms, financial institutions (such as banks and brokers) that have signed up to CRS need to identify the non-resident taxpayers’ accounts and report their account information (including names, addresses, taxpayer status, account balances, and annual total income) to their local tax authorities. These tax authorities then exchange this information with the relevant tax authorities of the countries/territories where the account holders are residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Mainland Investors:&lt;/strong&gt; For mainland residents who open accounts with Hong Kong brokers, due to their tax residency being China, Hong Kong financial institutions will exchange their account information through the Hong Kong Customs and Excise Department to the Chinese State Taxation Administration. This means that the inland tax authorities can gain access to information about its residents’ overseas financial assets and income, providing a basis for collecting global income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inland-resident-hong-kong--us-stock-trading-tax-breakdown&#34;&gt;Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp;amp; US Stock Trading Tax Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, Chinese tax residents are required to pay personal income tax on their &lt;strong&gt;income sourced globally&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that even if investment gains occur abroad and may be exempt in the local jurisdiction, there is still an obligation to declare and pay taxes to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Chinese tax department has intensified its enforcement of taxation regarding individual overseas income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-via-hong-kong-brokers&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong and US Stocks via Hong Kong Brokers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a mainland resident, trading Hong Kong and US stocks through Hong Kong brokers (such as Futu Securities, Tiger Brokerage, etc.), your tax responsibilities are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; The profits you receive from the difference between buying and selling US stocks belong to “transfer pricing income.” According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, it should be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities. Although the United States typically exempts non-residents from capital gains taxes, Chinese tax residents still need to pay taxes on this global income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from US stocks will usually have 10% withheld by the broker as estimated income tax (enjoying preferential tax agreements between China and the US). This tax paid abroad can be offset when declaring it in China, but the offset amount cannot exceed the taxable amount calculated according to Chinese tax laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; Although Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax, profits from Hong Kong stock trading (price differences) are also considered “transfer pricing income” and must be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from H shares (companies registered in mainland China and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 20% personal income tax withheld by the company. Dividends received from non-H shares (companies registered in Hong Kong or overseas and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 10% dividend tax withheld in Hong Kong. This tax paid abroad can also be offset when declaring it in China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-stocks-via-the-hksar-mainland-china-bond-connect-hk--sh&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong Stocks via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To promote capital market connectivity between Mainland China and Hong Kong, the government has introduced targeted tax incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; According to announcements from the Ministry of Finance, the State Taxation Administration, and the Securities and Futures Commission, personal income tax is currently &lt;strong&gt;exempted&lt;/strong&gt; on any &lt;strong&gt;capital gains&lt;/strong&gt; realized by mainland individual investors through the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH) when buying and selling listed stocks on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. This incentive policy has been explicitly &lt;strong&gt;extended to December 31, 2027&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend Income:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), the H Share company will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Non-H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), China Merchants Service Bureau will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;. Any pre-paid personal income tax paid in Hong Kong can be claimed for tax refund by submitting a valid withholding certificate to the relevant tax authority of China Merchants Service Bureau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Brokerage Firms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, 20% Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US Withholding 10%, Can be Deducible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-1&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, Rate 20%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Withheld 20%; Non-H Shares: Hong Kong Advance 10%, Deductible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-2&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect (沪港通)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exempted (until end of 2027)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Deduction of 20%; Non-H Shares: Listing Deduction of 20%, Hong Kong Tax Already Paid Can Be Refunded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-3&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The information above is based on current policies. Tax regulations may change, and investors are advised to consult with a professional tax advisor or monitor the latest information released by the tax authorities before making investment decisions and filing tax returns to ensure compliance. The typical time frame for reporting foreign income is from March 1st to June 30th of the following year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Premium Whole Life Insurance Policy Interpretation</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:13:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult for ordinary people to understand a policy document, and traditional financial planning is based on understanding annualized returns. However, the calculation method of an increasing term life insurance policy is Internal Rate of Return (IRR), and there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between these two – what’s the difference and why does it exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When funds are invested in one go, &lt;strong&gt;Internal Rate of Return (IRR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return (Annualized Return)&lt;/strong&gt; produce the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;laymans-explanation&#34;&gt;Layman&amp;rsquo;s Explanation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you planted a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lump Sum Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; You invested the money to buy the sapling and the fertilizer for the first year all at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt; This is like measuring how much your tree grows each year, then calculating the average percentage it grows by per year. It measures how much your money grew on average over one year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRR (Internal Rate of Return):&lt;/strong&gt; The IRR concept is broader and can handle situations with multiple cash inflows and outflows. However, in a simple scenario where you have a single investment and a single return, IRR also seeks to find an “average annual growth rate” that makes the money grow at this percentage over time, exactly equaling the amount you finally receive back.
Because in a single investment, single return scenario, there are no intermediate cash flows (like regular dividends or additional investments), the calculation of IRR is simplified into finding a compound annual growth rate, which is exactly what the annualized return expresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;An Example
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2024, you invested &lt;strong&gt;10,000 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Term:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Return:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2027, you received back &lt;strong&gt;13,310 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-annualized-return&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The formula for calculating annualized return is:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{\text{Ending Value}}{\text{Beginning Value}} \right)^{\frac{1}{\text{Investment Period}}} - 1$$
&lt;p&gt;
Substituting the data:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{13310}{10000} \right)^{\frac{1}{3}} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = (1.331)^{0.3333} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
&lt;p&gt;
Therefore, the annualized return on this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;. This means your money grew an average of 10% per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-internal-rate-of-return-irr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Internal Rate of Return (IRR):&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;IRR is the discount rate that makes the net present value (NPV) of all cash flows zero. In this example, the cash flows include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2024: -10,000 (Cash outflow – investment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2027: +13,310 (Investment recovery)
We need to find a discount rate &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; such that:
$$-10000 + \frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 0$$
$$\frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 10000$$
$$(1+r)^3 = \frac{13310}{10000} = 1.331$$
$$1+r = (1.331)^{\frac{1}{3}}$$
$$1+r = 1.1$$
$$r = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
Therefore, the internal rate of return (IRR) for this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this simple example of a one-time investment and one-time recovery, you will find that the results of calculating the annualized yield and internal rate of return are identical. This is because in this specific case, the IRR calculation logic is equivalent to the compound interest calculation logic used to determine the annualized yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRR truly comes into play when an investment involves &lt;strong&gt;multiple cash flows&lt;/strong&gt;, such as investing in a fund where you contribute money each month, or investing in a project that pays dividends at different points in time and ultimately recovers a final sum of money. In this complex cash flow pattern, the annualized yield may not accurately measure the true return on investment, while IRR can better reflect the time value of money and the overall rate of return for the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:07:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AI has been integrated into daily development workflows, and recent investments have shifted focus from external funds to internal stocks and ETFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-log&#34;&gt;Project Log
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was bored and tried to obtain GitHub badges, starting to use the Issue module. Previously, when writing code, I always wanted to find a place to record the content of each AI modification, but creating a separate document to record it felt disorganized. Now that we have the Issue module, tagging them to distinguish between bugs, features, enhancements, etc., has made the records clear and efficient. Even if I might not need them in the future, recording them is still a form of accumulation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/issues?q=is%3Aissue&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;View Issue List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Release record, find the most recent related commits. Since all commits are AI-generated, copy all recent commit records from the web interface and give them to AI to organize – this is a good release record.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;engagement&#34;&gt;Engagement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That time it was featured on GitHub’s personal page, it passively increased the motivation to write code – after all, the data visualization made things quite fascinating. Even simple positive feedback could provide the impetus to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trae&#34;&gt;Trae
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paid for a monthly trial, honestly, it’s better in VSCode using Claude4. The practical effect is also better. Sometimes, even with the same problem, Trae gives better answers. Should I buy an annual subscription later? Given my current chaotic usage frequency, Trae might not be enough; don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much, we’ll see when we run out. Byte should still have other paid plans and purchase more call volumes.
&lt;del&gt;Simple small issues can be solved using Microsoft, GitHub Copilot, and various models can also be called.&lt;/del&gt;
The plan is to fail – GitHub Copilot is now starting to limit the number of calls &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/about-github-copilot/plans-for-github-copilot#models&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;618 opened restrictions&lt;/a&gt;
How to check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/managing-copilot/understanding-and-managing-copilot-usage/monitoring-your-copilot-usage-and-entitlements#downloading-a-monthly-usage-report&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;current usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I couldn’t resist. Since the Hong Kong Connect channel was opened, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t traded in the Hong Kong market, and I bought some Xiaomi stock thinking about their upcoming new car launch. It rose a bit, so I sold it, and when it fell, I bought it back again, repeating this process several times before the new car was released, making a small profit on the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, I didn’t know what to do but look at the cross-border capital flows of Hong Kong Connect, watching Meituan&amp;rsquo;s net inflow of funds, and followed suit by buying it in, successfully becoming a shareholder, forgetting to look at the overall capital flow, only a part of the domestic purchases, and there were still many foreign investors in the Hong Kong market. This time it was just an opportunity to practice with blue-chip stocks, slowly holding on to the final gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling positions and losses are &lt;strong&gt;contrary to human nature&lt;/strong&gt;, slow down, slow down, don’t rush. If Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s new car doesn’t perform well, should I sell? That’s a question. My investment cognition is still insufficient, and I need to read more books and learn more. The Fed isn’t planning on cutting interest rates, and the Hong Kong market plunged once, if I missed the entry time? That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be right, what if the news came out that interest rates were being cut and the Hong Kong market soared? This is investment, testing human nature.
&lt;code&gt;A phrase I often repeat: buying is for national fortune, but I don’t really believe in national fortune.&lt;/code&gt;
Aside from the belief in national fortune, &lt;strong&gt;another one is attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Since you&amp;rsquo;re going to do long-term investing, frequent monitoring of the market is pointless. Ten minutes in the morning and ten minutes at the close are enough. What is the final expected return rate? There’s still no clear stop-loss position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the market falls sharply, Tencent is a hot commodity, with capital flocking to it.
| 00700 | Tencent Holdings | 498.600 | 80.08 billion |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-1&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;03690&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;128.100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.881 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-2&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bubble Mate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;247.200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.703 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-3&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09988&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;109.800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;532.2 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-4&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01810&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.050&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41.05 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and getting anxious won’t help either.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs, and my ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; and if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from when I first entered the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my focus shifted to blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hisense Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in blue chips is like aligning with “old money”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Evergrande’s problems arose, bank stocks plummeted alongside it, successfully identifying the exit point. This reflected a lack of understanding regarding the broader economic market; real estate accounted for too much of China&amp;rsquo;s economy, and the implications were too extensive to simply “land” – the subsequent continued decline in the stock market saw blue-chip stocks like Industrial Bank continue to rise for about two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, ZTESC suffered a severe blow, with its share price also falling dramatically. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hisense Electronics is an old veteran; after Ant Financial withdrew, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock had a controlling shareholder manipulating it, and it could surge several times each year. With reasonable position sizing, you wouldn’t lose much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bond-investment&#34;&gt;Bond Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say it was a lucky outcome, essentially benefiting from falling interest rates. There were changes at my job in Hangzhou, leading me to abandon the idea of buying a house and liquidate my existing bank term deposits. I then focused on reinvesting previously held bonds, significantly increasing my bond investment ratio. Fortunately, interest rates have been declining for several years, allowing me to capitalize on the “bull market” in bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my six months back in Hangzhou, I had plenty of time to reflect and gain clarity. Real estate isn’t a necessity, nor is staying in a particular location – my ability to handle stress was thus improved. If I were to lose my job, the mortgage would be like a mountain to climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-return-expectations&#34;&gt;Investment Return Expectations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The expected annualized oral commitment is comparable to a three-year fixed bank deposit,” but in reality, it’s greedy and wants more. From the initial frantic increase (adding positions), to later exhausting cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represent significant outflows of capital, and overall, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough capital flow left over, leading to insufficient funds later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subsequent plan is to long-term hold &lt;strong&gt;brokerage ETFs&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index&lt;/strong&gt;, with an asset allocation that still includes insurance as a base, medium-to-long term bonds, and stock funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fixed Income Funds / Bond Funds</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 90s, we didn’t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis – after all, we were young and hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet started to focus on finance. The roaring bull market of 2015 came with a lot of fanfare, and when it ended, it made quite a stir, ultimately requiring government intervention to stabilize the markets. Simultaneously, this brought the concept of “funds” into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a natural traffic entry for Ant Financial, Alipay was born with the positioning of a payment tool. When purchasing funds, Alipay and WeChat both saw widespread adoption – most people chose Alipay. Alipay has successfully transformed fund sales into an ordinary shopping experience. Starting in 2019, during the small bull market, fund managers’ “warming up” recruitment, ultimately driven by the monetary easing guided by the COVID-19 pandemic. Those who entered made a profit, those who didn&amp;rsquo;t enter envied them and rushed to join. The scale of new funds broke through the hundred billion mark at an increasingly rapid pace, and with grandmothers starting to buy funds, another trillion fund is not far off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Alipay’s explosive rise as a code-driven internet fund sales platform, ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s contact with fund sales was primarily when depositing money in banks, where the branch manager would enthusiastically introduce various investment products. The internet packaging and promotional page information guidance, the exorbitant advertising fees given by fund sales institutions, completely detached Alipay’s fund advertisements from rationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal bank fixed-term investment returns are 4%, P2P investments that played wildly in recent years were 8%, credit card repayment interest rates are 12%. Our protagonist, Alipay&amp;rsquo;s promoted funds – 150% and 250% – were popular in the market, making everyone happy, both inside and outside the market? Alipay was playing with fire.&lt;/strong&gt; The advertised returns only showed the three-year cumulative yield chart, while traditional fund companies only presented annualized average yields. Why didn’t they dare to present the annual average yield alone? Because it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t look good, and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t guide customers to purchase funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investment&#34;&gt;Fixed Income Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entered a negative interest rate era, making bank deposits and government bonds the most secure fixed-income products. Pure credit funds are also a good option. You can refer to the data published by local statistical bureaus to find China’s average wage levels. I’ll present a simple scenario: with an asset size of 2 million (CNY), an annualized yield of 4%, the annual income will exceed most cities&amp;rsquo; average wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s much more I could write. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading a variety of economic books yourself – don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow. For ordinary families, the core of financial planning is preservation, not chasing risky dreams of getting rich quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right thing at the right time has the greatest value; study diligently when you’re studying, and getting a good degree is better than earning pocket money by distributing flyers; work seriously when you first graduate, and the growth in your salary will bring you substantial returns; and when you start a family, learn to take care of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue-1&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those interested can take a look at this speech transcript: On Time, you need to read many books to find the answer. The text transcript is available on our site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
