<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pursuit-Of on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pursuit-of/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pursuit-Of on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pursuit-of/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What we have been seeking throughout our lives is…</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang Yi-zi said: Human relationships, spanning a lifetime of mutual support and dependence, may be held within one’s embrace, understood in the confines of one room; or they may arise from entrusted messages, dissolving into the vastness beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a lifetime, like a fleeting flower. Like grass and trees blossoming and withering, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet, in this life, desires are numerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a child, I lay under lotus plants and hemp in the stream, busy catching the east wind to fly kites, chasing yellow butterflies in haste,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also learned to grow gourds by the shade of mulberry trees, returning home with a full meal after dusk, not shedding my cloak to lie beneath the moonlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I grew older, I hoped to be inscribed on the gold list, to have a beautiful woman accompany me, to have endless wealth, to rise continuously, to have a full table of guests, to sing and play every night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When old, I wanted health and longevity, welcome childhood servants, young children waiting at the door, a chessboard, a confidant, a bottle of wine, a courtyard, enjoying family harmony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see people rushing about in a panic, only seeking a few taels of broken silver. Yet, this broken silver, can it dispel all kinds of melancholy in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half the people are still struggling with their lives, where do they have time to seek meaning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, human life is just an experience, like plants, sun and moon – experiencing the cycle of desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t understand it, you’ll feel like a fleeting moment in the vastness of the world, a tiny grain of sand on the Yangtze River. When you understand it, you’re happy with what you encounter, temporarily possessing yourself, content and self-sufficient, unaware of your approaching old age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, flowers, and tea. You can pursue the clear breeze on the river or the bright moon in the mountains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But don’t overly concern yourself with the results; they will all eventually pass away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a lifetime of hardship, when you arrive in this world, try to experience the joys and sorrows, birth, old age, sickness, and death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the quote from The Tale of the Sea Deer:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are short, and we will eventually lose them, so why not be a little bolder – love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream – there are many things with no answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed &lt;em&gt;The Analects of Zan Gong&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Cliff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the rise of past generations, one feels a sense of longing; if only they could be brought together as one, never to have lamented or mourned, unable to convey it within my heart. I know that dying in one’s lifetime is an absurdity, and the tragedy of Zang and Peng is a false fabrication. Those who look upon us now are like we look upon them then. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
