<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pursuit-Of on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pursuit-of/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pursuit-Of on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pursuit-of/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What is it that we spend our whole lives pursuing?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s interactions with their spouse can last a lifetime—sometimes arising from shared ideals and understanding within the home, sometimes stemming from entrusting one’s fate and wandering beyond societal constraints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s life is like a fleeting moment; like grass and trees, flourishing in spring and withering in autumn; like the rising and setting of the sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I have so many desires in this life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lying by the stream as a child, peeling lotus pods, while eagerly releasing kites in the east wind, chasing after yellow butterflies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leaned against mulberry trees to learn about melons, returned with a full meal after dusk, and slept under the bright moon without taking off his raincoat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I hope to achieve great success, have a beautiful partner, enjoy abundant wealth, rise through the ranks, host lavish gatherings, and celebrate every night with music and revelry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging, yet desiring health and longevity – welcome servants, await children, a game of chess, a close friend, a pot of wine, a courtyard, and the enjoyment of family life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People rush about, chasing after a few coins. Yet those very coins can ease all sorts of worldly sorrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are struggling just to make ends meet; who has time to pursue meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, life is merely an experience—like grass, trees, the sun, and moon—a cycle of desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not understanding life leads to the feeling that we are like mayflies adrift in the universe, a grain of sand in the vast ocean. We lament our fleeting existence and envy the endless flow of the Yangtze River. Understanding life brings joy in what is encountered, satisfaction with what one gains, contentment without seeking more, unaware of approaching old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, and tea; you can chase the clear breeze on the river, or the bright moon in the mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be overly concerned with the outcome; results are fleeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To exhaust a lifetime, arriving in this world to experience as much joy and sorrow, birth and death as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this line from Big Fish &amp;amp; Begonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are short, and we will inevitably lose them, so let&amp;rsquo;s be bold – love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream. There are many things in life with no answers, so let’s be bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like &amp;ldquo;The Pavilion of Prince Shaobo&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ode to the Red Cliffs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of grief over the passing of others are like a binding agreement; I have never faced literature without lamenting, unable to contain it within my heart. Indeed, knowing that life and death are illusory and that equating ages is futile. Those who come after will view us as we now view those gone before. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
