<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/network/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Upgrading from a desktop to a 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network connectivity.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktop hardware three-in-one, in the previous text we mentioned PCIe adapter for solid state drives, where did the old SSDs go? Of course they weren&amp;rsquo;t wasted – if they were damaged, they were disassembled and installed on the newly purchased ‘MechMaker Mini-3765H’ (bought a year ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new machine has powerful hardware specifications: 2.5G dual network interfaces, PCIe4.0, WiFi6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I moved house and my room doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a dedicated router for networking, so the machines are connected via wireless networks. The ASUS motherboard desktop’s wireless card performance wasn’t great, or perhaps it was the router’s wireless access, which resulted in slow upload speeds between local networks, leading to poor network speeds between the machines. I purchased a 2.5G NIC and installed it on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, all the slots on the motherboard are full: graphics card, wireless card, 2.5G NIC, PCIe adapter for solid state drives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network Instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both machines connect to the internet using their original wireless network cards, but are directly connected via Ethernet cables between the two ends, with both sides equipped with 2.5G network cards.  The specifics of how to connect the Ethernet cables between the two machines aren&amp;rsquo;t detailed here – there are many tutorials available online; just remember to disable your firewall. You can select either machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-subnet-speed-testing&#34;&gt;Two Subnet Speed Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-lan&#34;&gt;Router LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan&#34;&gt;Direct LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wutongsuimeng.github.io/post/%E7%BB%99hugo%E6%B7%BB%E5%8A%A0mermaid%E6%94%AF%E6%8C%81/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Adding Mermaid Support to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why does a newly installed gigabit fiber to the home (FTTH) connection only test at 100 Mbps?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/new-gigabit-fiber-slow-speed/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:29:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/new-gigabit-fiber-slow-speed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Want your home network to be lightning fast? The key is understanding cable selection, optical terminals (ONTs), and router configuration, as well as those seemingly insignificant details. This blog post will guide you through easily learning how to build a gigabit network using six types of cables, and how to ensure your network speed isn&amp;rsquo;t restricted by simple device checks and configurations. Let’s explore together and make your home network fly!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/gigabit-fiber-slow-speed/image.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1001&#34;
	height=&#34;590&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Manual Repair&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;169&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;407px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-an-in-depth-analysis-of-network-transmission-media&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: An In-Depth Analysis of Network Transmission Media
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When discussing achieving gigabit network access, the carrier that supports high-speed information transmission – cables – plays a crucial role. Below we will provide detailed interpretations of Cat5, Cat6, and Cat7 cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-five-category-cables-cat5&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Five-Category Cables (CAT5)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CAT5 cables, also known as CAT5, are an earlier and more widely adopted type of twisted pair cable. Each pair of wire pairs is designed with a precise helical structure to reduce crosstalk. It’s primarily used for 10/100Mbps Fast Ethernet, with a maximum transmission frequency of approximately 100MHz. While it was once widely applied, CAT5 cables cannot meet current demands for gigabit and even higher speeds due to physical limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-six-category-cables-cat6&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Six-Category Cables (CAT6)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of technology, six-category cables have emerged. Compared to five-category cables, six-cable materials adopted stricter manufacturing standards and more advanced structural designs, significantly improving anti-interference capability and transmission efficiency, supporting data transfer rates up to 1Gbps, and with a transmission distance of up to 100 meters under ideal conditions, which perfectly meets the access requirements of Gigabit networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-seven-category-cables-cat7&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Seven-Category Cables (CAT7)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Seven-category cables represent the current cutting edge of twisted pair cabling technology. It not only offers a significant leap in transmission rates, theoretically supporting speeds up to 10Gbps, but also incorporates a complete shielding system, including shielding between each pair and overall external shielding, which greatly reduces external electromagnetic interference and near-end crosstalk, ensuring data transmission stability and accuracy. However, CAT7 cables are primarily used for future 10 Gigabit Ethernet or specific high-requirement scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When setting up a gigabit home network environment, choosing six-category cables is the most economical and efficient choice to fully unleash the potential of the gigabit fiber optic.  Furthermore, ensuring that all connection cables meet quality standards and strictly adhering to standard wiring practices are also important aspects in guaranteeing network performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two-deep-dive-into-core-network-devices--the-impact-of-optical-cat-光猫-and-router-lan-port-bandwidth&#34;&gt;Chapter Two: Deep Dive into Core Network Devices – The Impact of Optical Cat (光猫) and Router LAN Port Bandwidth
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-optical-cat-ont-and-its-lan-port-bandwidth&#34;&gt;The Importance of Optical Cat (ONT) and its LAN Port Bandwidth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;An Optical Cat, or Optical Network Terminal (ONT), is the core device for home broadband access. Its function is to convert optical signals from fiber optic cables into digital signals for use by home network devices. For users with gigabit fiber connections, whether the ONT supports gigabit transmission is particularly important. If the ONT’s WAN port only supports 100 Mbps, even if the incoming fiber rate is high, it will be limited to 100 Mbps due to this bottleneck. Similarly, the ONT&amp;rsquo;s LAN port also needs to have a gigabit output capability; otherwise, routers or other devices connected to it cannot obtain the true gigabit rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-role-of-bandwidth-on-router-lan-ports&#34;&gt;The Role of Bandwidth on Router LAN Ports
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The router’s LAN ports are responsible for distributing the data received to various terminal devices. When a router&amp;rsquo;s LAN port is only 100 Mbps, even if other devices are configured well, it can only achieve 100 Mbps local network communication. Therefore, when building a Gigabit home network, it’s important to ensure that the router’s WAN port can receive 1 Gbps data and that the LAN ports also provide data output capabilities at the Gigabit level, so that all smart devices in your home can enjoy the smooth experience brought by high-speed networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, it&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that some older or low-end routers may have a LAN port automatic negotiation mechanism, which means that even if the router itself supports 1 Gbps, it may be downgraded to a 100 Mbps mode due to cable issues, device compatibility, and other reasons. Therefore, correctly configuring router parameters, enabling forced gigabit mode, and pairing it with a gigabit switch or direct device are key steps in achieving a full gigabit network. After upgrading to gigabit fiber, be sure to check and replace with gigabit optical switches and gigabit routers to ensure all device interfaces meet gigabit standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three-the-hidden-mystery--how-a-broken-subline-impacts-gigabit-network-speed&#34;&gt;Chapter Three: The Hidden Mystery – How a Broken Subline Impacts Gigabit Network Speed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;line-fault-and-network-performance-degradation&#34;&gt;Line Fault and Network Performance Degradation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the speed tests, the network consistently maintained a connection without any apparent disconnects. As it was a newly deployed broadband for residential use, the distribution box was cluttered with equipment, and the technician frequently adjusted the optical transceiver and power outlet positions. This occasionally resulted in speed test results reaching gigabit speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the previous information, we had already analyzed and troubleshooted network cable types and optical transceiver LAN port speeds. Ultimately, the culprit was discovered to be a broken brown sub-cable within the network cable itself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of the break: When the technician installed the crystal head, he applied a little too much force, causing one of the sub-cables to break in half. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t completely severed, and subsequent adjustments to the optical transceiver position caused it to eventually break completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;six-category-cable-lines-function-analysis&#34;&gt;Six Category Cable Lines Function Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six category cables adhere to the TIA/EIA-568-B standard and contain eight twisted pairs of wires, color-coded as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Orange / Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Green / Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Blue / Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Brown / Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under the Gigabit Ethernet (1000BASE-T) standard, these eight lines consist of four pairs working simultaneously, with the following division of labor:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The White Orange and Orange pair of wires (1&amp;amp;2) is used for transmitting data (Tx+/-);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The White Green and Green pair of wires (3&amp;amp;6) is used for receiving data (Rx+/-);&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The White Blue and Blue pair of wires (4&amp;amp;5) and the White Brown and Brown pair of wires (7&amp;amp;8) were not originally primary in Gigabit Ethernet, but may be enabled in certain advanced applications (such as some PoE power delivery or future technology expansions). In traditional 100 Mbps networks, only four lines – 1, 2, 3, and 6 – could be used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;impact-of-breakaway-pairs-on-network-speed&#34;&gt;Impact of Breakaway Pairs on Network Speed
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the above scenarios, if a brown sub-cable (i.e., brown or brown-white wire) breaks, theoretically it will cause speed degradation in gigabit networks, as gigabit networks require all four pairs of wires to transmit bidirectionally simultaneously to achieve full speed. However, due to home network devices often having auto-negotiation features, when a cable issue is detected, they will revert to a lower operating rate that functions normally, which is the megabit mode. This explains why even with a broken sub-cable, the network can remain connected and operate at megabit speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, while a broken brown sub-cable does not affect the basic operation of a megabit network, it can become a key limiting factor for network speed in gigabit environments. Until a thorough diagnosis and repair is conducted, the full potential of gigabit fiber cannot be truly realized. This also serves as a reminder that we should not overlook any potential network infrastructure issues when encountering similar situations – even seemingly minor connection glitches can become hidden obstacles to a high-speed networking experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Office migration, the servers are inaccessible.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/office-migration-server-unavailable/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 01:42:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/office-migration-server-unavailable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Administrative notice, office relocation from the second floor to the fifteenth floor – a standard, routine desk move.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-sense&#34;&gt;Design Sense
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/office-move-server-inaccessible/20230311014537.png&#34;
	width=&#34;511&#34;
	height=&#34;916&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Office Building&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;55&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;133px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migration&#34;&gt;Migration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Closing up shop, packing everything away, a familiar route, a new workstation – adjusting computer cabling, finding a comfortable posture to start working.
(ÒωÓױ)! – Connecting the network cable, accessing the frequently used servers for the team, but they were inaccessible. I tried switching to wireless networking, and access was normal again. Initially, I thought it was a problem with the server’s IP address settings, the wired network at the new workstation wasn&amp;rsquo;t included in the firewall configuration, so adjusting it resolved the issue; this subnet isn’t just one server – when trying to access other servers, they were all working normally. Gradually, confusion arose? Let professional people handle professional matters, and finally, a colleague from the operations department pinpointed the cause: This server was deployed with &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt;, and the default network of the &lt;code&gt;docker0&lt;/code&gt; service conflicted with the wired network configuration of the office, causing data packets sent to it to not receive responses and being routed to the &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; service. Other servers didn’t deploy &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; services, so I use this one more frequently. Occasionally, I use containers to deploy some test services, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t expect to encounter this scenario. Looking back, considering the entire group is located in a single office building, it’s not strange that IT colleagues divided network segments using addresses starting with &lt;code&gt;172&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;docker0&#34;&gt;docker0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Restart the service, switch to a new network, and the server recovers normal access.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://yeasy.gitbook.io/docker_practice/advanced_network/docker0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Docker from Beginner to Advanced - docker0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
