<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/network/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Upgraded desktop PC to a 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network connections</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The desktop hardware upgrades continue – we mentioned the PCIe adapter for solid-state drives in a previous article. Where did the old SSDs go? They weren&amp;rsquo;t wasted; they were removed and installed in the new computer I bought (a year ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new machine has impressive hardware specs: 2.5G dual network ports, PCIe 4.0, and WiFi 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently moved, and the room lacks a dedicated router for networking. Devices connect via wireless network. The ASUS motherboard desktop&amp;rsquo;s wireless card performance is lacking, possibly due to router wireless access or slow upload speeds between local networks, resulting in poor speed between machines. A new 2.5G NIC was purchased and installed in the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network Instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The machines still use the original wireless network cards for internet access, but are directly connected with a network cable. Both ends have 2.5G network cards. How to connect them via Ethernet is widely documented online; remember to disable firewalls and designate one machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD;
    A[机器1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: - &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS] --&amp;gt;|网线直连（2.5G）| B[机器2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS];
    A --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
    B --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speed-test-between-two-networks&#34;&gt;Speed test between two networks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-local-area-network&#34;&gt;Router local area network
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.3.237
Connecting to host 192.168.3.237, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.3.122 port 1656 connected to 192.168.3.237 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.00   sec  9.17 MBytes  76.7 Mbits/sec
[  4]   1.00-2.00   sec  9.91 MBytes  83.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec  8.74 MBytes  73.3 Mbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec  10.2 MBytes  85.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec  9.23 MBytes  77.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec  8.80 MBytes  73.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.01   sec  8.00 MBytes  66.8 Mbits/sec
[  4]   7.01-8.00   sec  7.69 MBytes  64.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.01   sec  9.72 MBytes  81.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   9.01-10.01  sec  7.63 MBytes  63.6 Mbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan-connection&#34;&gt;Direct LAN connection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.4.1
Connecting to host 192.168.4.1, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.4.2 port 1524 connected to 192.168.4.1 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.01   sec   178 MBytes  1.48 Gbits/sec
[  4]   1.01-2.00   sec   204 MBytes  1.72 Gbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec   214 MBytes  1.80 Gbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec   229 MBytes  1.92 Gbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec   202 MBytes  1.69 Gbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec   213 MBytes  1.79 Gbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.00   sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
[  4]   7.00-8.00   sec   192 MBytes  1.61 Gbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.00   sec   220 MBytes  1.84 Gbits/sec
[  4]   9.00-10.00  sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why is the speed only 100 Mbps despite having newly installed gigabit fiber?</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/new-gigabit-fiber-slow-speed/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:29:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/new-gigabit-fiber-slow-speed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Want lightning-fast home internet? It all comes down to choosing the right network cable, configuring your ONT and router, and paying attention to those subtle details. This blog will guide you through creating a gigabit network with Cat6 cables and how to ensure optimal speed through simple device checks and configurations. Let&amp;rsquo;s explore together and boost your home internet!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-in-depth-analysis-of-network-transmission-media&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: In-depth Analysis of Network Transmission Media
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When discussing achieving gigabit network access, the carrier—network cables—plays a crucial role in transmitting high-speed information. The following provides a detailed explanation of Cat 5, Cat 6, and Cat 7 cables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-provided-text-is-empty-please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate&#34;&gt;The provided text is empty. Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Category 5 Ethernet cable, also known as CAT5, is an early type of twisted-pair cabling that uses a precise spiral structure to reduce crosstalk. It&amp;rsquo;s primarily suitable for 10/100Mbps Fast Ethernet with a maximum transmission frequency of approximately 100MHz. While widely used in the past, it cannot meet current demands for gigabit and higher speeds due to physical limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With technological advancements, Cat6 cabling emerged. Compared to Cat5 cabling, Cat6 utilizes stricter manufacturing standards and more advanced structural designs, significantly improving interference resistance and transmission efficiency. It supports transfer rates up to 1Gbps and can achieve a distance of 100 meters under ideal conditions – perfectly meeting the access requirements for Gigabit networks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3&#34;&gt;3
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Category 7 cabling represents the pinnacle of current twisted-pair technology. It offers a significant increase in transmission rates, theoretically supporting up to 10Gbps, and incorporates a complete shielding system—shielding for each pair of wires as well as overall outer shielding—to greatly reduce external electromagnetic interference and near-end crosstalk, ensuring data transmission stability and accuracy. However, Category 7 cabling is primarily intended for future 10 Gigabit Ethernet or specific high-demand applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When building a Gigabit home network, using Cat6 cabling is the most economical and efficient choice to fully leverage the potential of Gigabit fiber. Ensuring all connection cables are of qualified quality and strictly following standard wiring practices are also crucial for network performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-delving-into-network-core-devices--the-impact-of-optical-network-terminal-ont-and-router-lan-port-bandwidth&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: Delving into Network Core Devices – The Impact of Optical Network Terminal (ONT) and Router LAN Port Bandwidth
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-the-optical-network-terminal-ont-and-its-lan-port-bandwidth&#34;&gt;The importance of the optical network terminal (ONT) and its LAN port bandwidth
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Optical Network Terminal (ONT), also known as an optical modem, is the core device for home broadband access. Its function is to convert the light signal from fiber optic cables into digital signals for use by home network devices. For gigabit fiber users, it&amp;rsquo;s crucial that the ONT supports gigabit transmission. If the ONT’s WAN port only supports 100 Mbps, even with a higher-speed fiber connection, the speed will be limited to 100 Mbps due to this bottleneck. Similarly, the ONT’s LAN port also needs to have gigabit output capabilities; otherwise, routers or other connected devices won&amp;rsquo;t achieve true gigabit speeds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-role-of-bandwidth-for-router-lan-ports&#34;&gt;The role of bandwidth for router LAN ports
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The router&amp;rsquo;s LAN port distributes received data to terminal devices. When the LAN port is limited to Gigabit, even with well-configured devices, network communication will be restricted to a 100Mbps speed. Therefore, when building a Gigabit home network, ensure the router’s WAN port can receive Gigabit data and that its LAN port also offers Gigabit output capabilities so all smart devices can enjoy a smooth experience thanks to high-speed networking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that some older or lower-end routers may have a LAN port auto-negotiation mechanism. This means they might operate in 100Mbps mode instead of Gigabit, even if the router itself supports it, due to factors like cabling or device compatibility. Therefore, correctly configuring router parameters, enabling forced Gigabit mode, and using a Gigabit switch or direct connection are crucial steps for achieving a full Gigabit network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After upgrading to fiber optic internet, be sure to check and replace your optical network terminal (ONT) and router with gigabit-compatible devices to ensure all interfaces meet the gigabit standard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-the-hidden-mystery--how-a-broken-sub-thread-impacts-gigabit-network-speed&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: The Hidden Mystery – How a Broken Sub-Thread Impacts Gigabit Network Speed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;subnet-cable-failure-and-network-performance-degradation&#34;&gt;Subnet cable failure and network performance degradation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The network remained connected throughout the speed test, with no apparent disconnections. As this is a newly installed broadband connection, the utility box is cluttered and adjustments to the optical network terminal&amp;rsquo;s cabling and power outlet placement occasionally result in speeds reaching gigabit levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on previous data, we analyzed and eliminated potential issues such as network cable model and optical modem LAN port speed, ultimately discovering that a broken brown internal wire within the network cable was the culprit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cable broke because the installer pulled on it too hard when installing the crystal head, partially severing a wire. Subsequent movement while adjusting the optical network terminal&amp;rsquo;s location eventually caused it to break completely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;functionality-of-eight-wires-in-six-categories-of-network-cables&#34;&gt;Functionality of Eight Wires in Six Categories of Network Cables
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Six-category network cables follow the TIA/EIA-568-B standard, consisting of eight twisted pairs with the following color coding:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White Orange / Orange&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;White-green / Green&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blue / Light Blue&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Brown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under Gigabit Ethernet (1000BASE-T) standards, these eight wires operate with four pairs working simultaneously, each with a specific function&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These wires (1 &amp;amp; 2), labeled white-orange and orange, are used for data transmission (Tx+/–)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These wires (3 &amp;amp; 6) – white/green and green – are used for data reception (Rx+/–)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These pairs of wires—white-blue and blue (4&amp;amp;5) and white-brown and brown (7&amp;amp;8)—are not typically used in Gigabit Ethernet, but may be enabled in certain advanced applications like partial PoE power or future technology extensions. In traditional 100Mbps networks, only the four wires 1, 2, 3, and 6 are required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-impact-of-broken-chains-on-network-speed&#34;&gt;The impact of broken chains on network speed
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the described scenario, if a brown sub-line (brown or brown-white) is broken, it can theoretically reduce speed in a Gigabit network because Gigabit networks require simultaneous bidirectional transmission on all four pairs of wires to achieve full speed. However, due to the auto-negotiation feature often found in home network devices, when a cable issue is detected, they will revert to a lower, functional rate – typically 100Mbps. This explains why the connection remains active and operates at 100Mbps even with one sub-line broken.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, while a single broken brown fiber strand doesn&amp;rsquo;t affect basic gigabit network operation, it can be a key factor limiting speed in a terabit environment. Only through thorough diagnosis and repair can the full potential of the terabit fiber be realized. This serves as a reminder that we shouldn’t overlook any potential network infrastructure issues, even seemingly minor faults that don&amp;rsquo;t impact basic connectivity, as they may become hidden obstacles to high-speed network performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Office relocation, servers are inaccessible</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/office-migration-server-unavailable/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Mar 2023 01:42:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/office-migration-server-unavailable/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Office relocation notice: Moving from the second floor to the fifteenth floor, a routine desk move&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;design-sense&#34;&gt;Design sense
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;migration&#34;&gt;Migration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Packing up and moving on, setting up my new workstation – adjusting cables and finding a comfortable posture before starting work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh no! The internet connection is up, but I can&amp;rsquo;t access the usual servers in our group. Switching to Wi-Fi works fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I thought it was a server network segment issue. The new workstation&amp;rsquo;s wired network wasn’t in the firewall configuration, so I figured an IT colleague could adjust it. However, this network segment hosts multiple servers, and accessing others worked fine, which raised my suspicions. Professional matters should be handled by professionals; eventually, the operations team identified the problem: the server deployed &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt;，服务的默认网络__INLINE_CODE_1__和办公室有线网络配置的网段冲突了，导致发过去的数据包，都收不到应答，被路由给了__INLINE_CODE_2__ services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not unusual for addresses starting with &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0__服务，也就这台，我比较常用，偶尔用容器部署一些测试服务，没想到还能碰到这个场景。后来细想想，由于整个集团都在一个办公大楼里面，IT部门的同事划分网段，用到了__INLINE_CODE_1&lt;/strong&gt; to not be deployed on other servers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;docker0&#34;&gt;docker0
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# vim /etc/docker/daemon.json
{
    &amp;quot;bip&amp;quot;:&amp;quot;172.200.0.1/24&amp;quot;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Restart the service, switch to a new network, and the server will return to normal access&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
