<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Xin-Dong-Fang on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xin-dong-fang/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Xin-Dong-Fang on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xin-dong-fang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Decline of Capital Monopoly and the Online Education Industry</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The stock market has fallen sharply over the past two trading days, giving new investors a taste of market risk. Our country is about to enter an aging phase, and birth rate data is grim—the decline significantly exceeded expert estimates. Industries hindering birth rates will be cracked down on by the Party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-workload&#34;&gt;Reducing student workload
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We, born in the 90s, didn&amp;rsquo;t have so many extracurricular classes or tutoring sessions. After school, we’d just run wild and play – partly due to family circumstances and partly because tutoring hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet established a brand reputation to convince parents. Twenty years have passed. Starting in 2019, K12 education began its capitalization trend, with companies like Yuanfudao emerging as leading online tutoring platforms. Fueled by capital, they concentrated resources to create various prestigious tutoring programs, and even exorbitant fees couldn&amp;rsquo;t contain parental enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amidst urbanization, many parents have escaped poverty and achieved upward mobility through education. As working professionals with limited time, they are highly driven themselves and want their children to keep up with their peers. With few alternative paths for families without strong educational backgrounds to maintain or advance their social standing, pursuing vocational high school is often seen as a step down – something most parents cannot accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why do extracurricular tutoring exist, and why do parents need it? Textbook knowledge and example problems are easily understood, but many subjects cover a broad range of topics, albeit superficially. Talent selection requires differentiation, creating a contradiction: textbook-based questions alone cannot effectively filter candidates and require horizontal and vertical expansion. These areas are impossible for teachers to fully cover in class, and this gap fosters the growth of extracurricular tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document contains extensive content, with thirty detailed provisions regulating various aspects. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the guiding document outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce overall homework volume and duration, easing students&amp;rsquo; excessive workload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve school after-school services to meet diverse student needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly regulate after-school tutoring activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly improve education and teaching quality, ensuring students learn well while at school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen supporting measures and enhance capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully organized and implemented, aiming for practical results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elite-education&#34;&gt;Elite education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the education sector, a growing trend is the increasing number of private schools, while public schools are struggling to provide sufficient quality resources (leading to the rise of desirable school districts). Various educational groups attract talented teachers with high salaries and establish excellent learning environments, gradually building their brands. A well-known example is &lt;strong&gt;衡水模式&lt;/strong&gt;. The average annual cost at a reputable private elementary school can range from nine thousand to ten thousand dollars. These education groups create a positive cycle: higher tuition fees are justified by skilled teachers, good student results, and continued parental enrollment. Consequently, talented public school teachers are drawn to the private sector, ultimately leading to a decline in the quality of public education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithm-exploitation&#34;&gt;Algorithm exploitation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data indicates that Meituan has nearly four million signed riders, with 400,000 to 500,000 active. Many depend on this work to support their families. Relentless algorithmic pressure squeezes delivery time, reducing people to measurable units and feeding them into calculations, constantly pushing riders to the point of collapse. It seems clever, but it is. The market is here; let&amp;rsquo;s play a good game—a sustainable one—rather than a destructive one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility&#34;&gt;Stock market volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 2021, education stocks, led by New Oriental, performed a dazzling dive, followed shortly thereafter by U.S.-listed companies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our country is gradually entering an aging population phase. Various social phenomena affecting family planning will be addressed; internet companies with monopolistic practices and excessive overtime have been fined, and the education industry where capital has concentrated has also been regulated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education should not be capitalized; any attempt at listing for financing is immediately rejected, leading to widespread outcry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental&amp;rsquo;s Severed Waist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s Plunge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
