<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Xin-Dong-Fang on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xin-dong-fang/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Xin-Dong-Fang on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/xin-dong-fang/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Capital Monopoly and the Demise of the Online Education Industry</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent two trading days have seen a significant downturn in the stock market, exposing newcomers to the risks of the market. China is about to enter an aging demographic phase, and birth rates are dismal, with the decline exceeding the estimates of relevant experts, hindering industries that are considered obstacles to fertility – the Party will take decisive action.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-burden&#34;&gt;Reducing Student Burden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 1990s didn’t have as many extracurricular classes or tutoring sessions, and we would run wild after school. This was first due to the limitations of our families&amp;rsquo; conditions, and second because tutoring companies hadn’t yet established a brand effect at the time, allowing parents to trust them. Twenty years have passed in a blink of an eye, and since 2019, the capitalization of K12 education has begun, with companies like猿辅导 (Yuancuizuo – literally “Monkey Tutoring”) emerging as online tutoring platforms based on code. With the backing of capital, these companies created various high-end tutoring centers by concentrating excellent resources. Even exorbitant fees couldn’t stop parents&amp;rsquo; enthusiasm. &amp;gt; During the process of urbanization, many parents have relied on education as a path to escape from humble backgrounds and achieve a social class leap. As wage laborers themselves, they lack the time to adequately care for their children, adding to their own intense competition and reluctance to see their children fall behind peers. “It’s difficult for nobles to become commoners,” and without the appropriate educational qualifications, ordinary families in China find it challenging to maintain their current social standing or make another class leap. Entering vocational schools would be perceived as a downward slide within the class structure, something most parents simply cannot accept in today&amp;rsquo;s environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-burden-1&#34;&gt;Reducing Student Burden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the reasons behind supplementary tutoring and why parents seek it out. Textbook knowledge and example questions are straightforward – many students can understand them easily. However, most subjects cover broad concepts superficially without delving deeply into them. The talent selection mechanism requires differentiation, which leads to a contradiction: exam questions based solely on textbook knowledge cannot effectively filter candidates. This necessitates horizontal and vertical expansion of learning. These areas are aspects that teachers simply cannot cover in the classroom, creating the fertile ground for supplementary tutoring to thrive. File content is extensive, with thirty detailed regulations covering multiple aspects. The document outline summary:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Comprehensively reduce the workload and duration of assignments to alleviate excessive academic burden on students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhance the level of after-school services offered by schools to meet diverse student needs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain strict governance while comprehensively regulating off-campus training activities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly improve educational teaching quality, ensuring that students master and excel in their studies within the school environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen supporting governance and enhance support guarantee capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully organize and implement the measures to achieve tangible results. ## Reducing Student Burden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the reasons behind supplementary tutoring and why parents seek it out. Textbook knowledge and practice questions are straightforward – many subjects are broad in scope but offer only superficial concepts without delving deeply. The talent selection mechanism requires differentiation, which leads to a contradiction: exam questions based solely on textbook knowledge cannot effectively filter candidates. This necessitates horizontal and vertical expansion of learning. These areas are aspects that teachers simply can’t cover comprehensively within the classroom, creating the fertile ground for supplementary tutoring to flourish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elite-education&#34;&gt;Elite Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within the education sector, there’s also an emerging phenomenon: increasingly powerful private schools are proliferating, rendering the resources of public schools inadequate (leading to enclaves). Various sized educational groups attract high-salaried teachers through lucrative compensation packages, establish quality learning environments, and gradually build their own brands – the most famous being the &lt;strong&gt;Hen Shuai Model&lt;/strong&gt;. Average companies in old homes have over 3000; powerful private primary schools charge between 9000 to 10000 RMB per year. Educational groups form a virtuous cycle: my tuition is expensive, but the teachers are excellent, students achieve good grades, I raise my fees, and parents still send their children there. Public school resources (teachers) are gradually drawn to private schools, ultimately becoming synonymous with substandard education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithmic-optimization&#34;&gt;Algorithmic Optimization
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There is data showing that Meituan’s contracted riders have approached 4 million, with approximately 400,000 active riders. Many people rely on this job to support their families and livelihoods. The relentless algorithmic pressure to minimize delivery times reduces individuals into measurable units, feeding them into algorithms for constant calculation, continually exploring the boundaries of delivery personnel’s collapse. Believing themselves clever, they &lt;strong&gt;violate human nature and serve capital&lt;/strong&gt;. The market operates here, allowing everyone to play and enjoy sustainable play, rather than &lt;strong&gt;monopolizing, abusing privileges, the gameplay of capitalism, and the unrestrained, barbaric growth that will inevitably come to an end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility&#34;&gt;Stock Market Volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 2021, education stocks represented by New Oriental performed a dramatic plunge, followed by Good Future in the pre-market US session. &lt;strong&gt;Stock prices plummeted by half.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China has gradually entered an aging population, and various social phenomena affecting family planning must be rectified; monopolistic and overtime internet companies were fined, and the capital-concentrated education industry was also scrutinized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility-1&#34;&gt;Stock Market Volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The education industry is not allowed to be capitalized on; a single vote directly negated related industries&amp;rsquo; IPO financing, resulting in wails of despair.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental &amp;ldquo;Sliced in Half&amp;rdquo;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/new_oriental_stock_price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;New Oriental &amp;ldquo;Sliced in Half&amp;rdquo;&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan Plummets
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/new_oriental_stock_price.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Meituan Plummets&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.infoq.cn/article/9Q1O2vWYNE8Mfhkzuyzs&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Regulatory Intensive Efforts Cause Online Education to &amp;ldquo;Brake Suddenly&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;
[The State Council Office issued the “Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Training Burden of Students in Compulsory Education”] (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.moe.gov.cn/jyb_xxgk/moe_1777/moe_1778/202107/t20210724_546576.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.moe.gov.cn/jyb_xxgk/moe_1777/moe_1778/202107/t20210724_546576.html&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
