<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ib on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/ib/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Ib on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/ib/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Special Format for Interactive Brokers Stock Codes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not common, but you&amp;rsquo;re bound to encounter it eventually; associated stock code: Berkshire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some stock codes contain &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo; or other special characters, and when submitted to Interactive Brokers (IB) via the &amp;ldquo;Fix&amp;rdquo; report, certain conversions of the stock code names are required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding Interactive Brokers, it can be analyzed to determine that the conversion rules are fixed and can be implemented through coding. When the rules are not fixed, the system generally needs to store corresponding mapping relationships, which business operation personnel update periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Trading Interrupted</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:51:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A trade disruption refers to when a trade has been executed and IB has received execution information from the exchange. Then, the exchange realizes that an error has occurred (such as pricing, electronic processing issues, obvious errors, etc.) and decides to disrupt (cancel) the trade. This process is entirely determined and controlled by the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A busted traderefers to a situation where an execution occurs and IB receives the execution messagefrom the exchange. The exchange then realizes some type of error (Pricing,electronic, obvious error, etc) and rules to bust (cancel) the trade. Theexchange makes these rulings entirely on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a trading perspective, it is equivalent to trade cancellation and trade correction on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
