<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Family-Planning on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/family-planning/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Family-Planning on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/family-planning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Multi-dimensional impacts of the family planning policy: deep transformations from social structure to economic and political changes.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/planned-parenthood-multidimensional-impact-social-structure-economic-political-transformation/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 May 2025 02:36:49 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/planned-parenthood-multidimensional-impact-social-structure-economic-political-transformation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;China’s population control policies, while limiting growth and curbing family-style development, have disrupted traditional social structures, suppressed the expansion of family-owned businesses and political dynasty power, presenting a unique case compared to Korean conglomerates and Indian family monopolies. Now that birth restrictions are being relaxed, despite facing challenges such as low fertility rates, it’s crucial to be wary of new monopoly risks and seek balance through multiple avenues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;one-the-tension-between-population-control-and-family-style-development&#34;&gt;One: The Tension Between Population Control and Family-Style Development
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The family planning policy, implemented in China for nearly forty years as a basic national strategy, has achieved significant direct results. Data shows that from 1978 to 2007, China’s natural population growth rate declined from 12‰ to 5.2‰, resulting in a reduction of over 40 million people, and the country&amp;rsquo;s share of the world’s population decreased from 22.2% to 20.1%. This sharp deceleration in population growth profoundly reshaped China’s social family structure. Taking family-owned enterprises as an example, after the implementation of the family planning policy, the number of children born by business owners significantly declined: before the policy, the proportion of those having three or more children reached 40.63%, and after the policy it plummeted to 18.46%, the proportion of single sons born increased from 6.25% to 32.31%. This structural change directly reduced the range of potential internal successors for family-owned enterprises, objectively suppressing their generational expansion capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;one-the-tension-between-population-control-and-familial-development&#34;&gt;One: The Tension Between Population Control and Familial Development
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Comparing Korea and India reveals significant differences. While Korea did not implement strict birth control measures, fertility rates have remained low for a long time (0.7 in 2023), the chaebols still firmly control the nation’s economic lifeline through cross-shareholdings and tax avoidance strategies like inheritance taxes. The top five chaebols account for over 50% of Korea&amp;rsquo;s GDP, with Samsung Group alone contributing 20%. India presents a contrasting picture: 79% of its economic output is generated by family-owned businesses, with six major conglomerates controlling key sectors such as telecommunications and steel, and the top 20 enterprises earning 80% of national corporate profits. The core difference lies in the fact that China’s population control policies limited family sizes, thereby weakening the human resources base for chaebol expansion at its source.  Due to different policy environments, familial power has continued to penetrate economic sectors in Korea and India.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-monopoly-restraint-and-social-structural-transformation&#34;&gt;II. Monopoly Restraint and Social Structural Transformation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impact of the family planning policy on the economic sector is particularly evident in its suppression of monopolistic phenomena. Due to declining birth rates, Chinese family businesses have struggled to form conglomerates akin to those in South Korea and Japan. Taking South Korea as an example, chaebols maintained their control through “circular capital” investments, with the Samsung family holding only 2% of the group’s shares while wielding overall control through complex equity structures. Conversely, in China, post-family planning, family businesses generally faced difficulties in “passing down the business” to heirs, necessitating the introduction of professional managers or implementing equity diversification reforms. According to a湃新闻 (Papare News) study, the proportion of female successors in family businesses after family planning has increased from 13.85% to 34.21%, and the education level of these successors has significantly improved, with the percentage of undergraduates rising from 43.75% to 98.46%. This transition, while not completely eliminating family control, significantly reduced the possibility of a single family monopolizing the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the social structure level, the population planning policy accelerated the breakdown of traditional family core patterns. China’s average household size decreased from 4.41 people/household in 1982 to 2.62 people/household in 2020, with smaller families weakening the family&amp;rsquo;s functions in areas such as economics, education, and social support. In contrast, India maintains an average family size of around 4 people, with the caste system deeply intertwined with family power, leading to low social mobility. China’s transformation of its family structure created space for individualism; in 2023, China had 240 million single adult citizens, and a trend of “one-person economy” emerged in the consumer market, further diminishing the influence of family economies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;three-decentralization-of-power-in-the-political-sphere&#34;&gt;Three. Decentralization of Power in the Political Sphere
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The impact of the family planning policy on the political ecology has been profound. Traditionally, family power structures had infiltrated grassroots politics through bloodlines and kinship relationships. For example, in Henan’s Xinye County, 161 political families almost controlled all government departments, with 20% of cadres at deputy-officer level or above belonging to “officer’s children.” However, after the implementation of the family planning policy, the shrinking family size limited the expansion of family networks. Research from Peking University showed that after family planning, the number of offspring of officials decreased, and the complexity of family political networks significantly declined. Furthermore, the policy-driven promotion of education (the average years of schooling increased from 5.2 in 1982 to 10.9 in 2023) facilitated social mobility, weakening the monopoly of family power over political resources. Comparing Korea and India, the deep entanglement between Korean conglomerates (like Samsung Group executives and government corruption) and India’s caste-based hereditary political lineage highlights the uniqueness of Chinese policy. China, through its population control policies, objectively reduced the possibility of power succession. While familial phenomena still exist within county-level politics, the overall trend is towards a decentralization of power structures. During the 2025 National People&amp;rsquo;s Congress (NPC) session, an NPC delegate proposed renaming “The Population and Family Planning Law” to “The Population and Reproduction Law,” fully opening up birth limits – a move that could further influence the evolution of future political ecosystems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;four-challenges-and-opportunities-following-policy-adjustments&#34;&gt;Four. Challenges and Opportunities Following Policy Adjustments
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The implementation of the 2016 nationwide two-child policy and the 2021 three-child policy marked a significant shift in China’s birth policies. However, the policy effects were limited: births in 2022 totaled only 1.18, far below the replacement level (2.1). The relaxation of birth restrictions had a dual impact on family-owned businesses: on one hand, some entrepreneurs may strengthen family succession capabilities through multiple births, such as Zong Qinghou’s daughter, Zong Fufeng, who took over as the sole heir to Wahaha Group; on the other hand, high childcare costs (the average cost of raising a child to 18 years old in first-tier cities reaching 1 million yuan) and declining fertility intentions among professional women limited family size expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the economic sphere, relaxing birth restrictions may give rise to new monopoly forms. The three-child policy has driven consolidation in the maternal and childcare industries, with the estimated market size for infant care expected to reach 1621 by 2025. - 300 million yuan&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading enterprises are utilizing mergers and acquisitions to integrate smaller manufacturers, resulting in a CR5 market concentration exceeding 55%. This increase in concentration may bring about efficiency gains, but it also warrants vigilance against new monopoly risks. The government needs to strike a balance between encouraging childbirth and preventing market consolidation, such as strengthening regulation through antitrust laws while providing childcare subsidies (e.g., Hangzhou’s three-child families receiving RMB 3,000 per month in milk powder subsidies) to alleviate household burdens.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the political sphere, relaxing birth restrictions could have subtle impacts on family power structures. While it is unlikely to restore traditional family political networks in the short term, over the long term, larger families may form new influence within grassroots politics. Therefore, refining personnel selection mechanisms and strengthening oversight (such as establishing a nepotism avoidance system for officials) remains crucial in preventing hereditary power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;five-international-mirroring-and-future-outlook&#34;&gt;Five. International Mirroring and Future Outlook
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The experiences of South Korea and India demonstrate a close correlation between the ebb and flow of family power structures and policy orientations. South Korea achieved economic takeoff by supporting conglomerates, but at the cost of social inequality; India’s failure to implement effective policies to curb family monopolies has exacerbated wealth disparity. China’s population control policy effectively controlled population growth while also suppressing the expansion of family power, yet it resulted in issues such as an aging population and labor shortages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, China needs to find a new balance between population policy and socio-economic development. On one hand, implementing fertility support policies (such as extending maternity leave and building universal childcare institutions) should boost birth rates; on the other hand, strengthening antitrust enforcement is crucial to prevent family businesses from forming new monopolies through capital operations. In the political sphere, further progress must be made in grassroots democratic construction, with enhanced oversight mechanisms to ensure transparency in governance. Ultimately, the family planning policy served as a key driver of social transformation in China; its impact extended far beyond population issues. It reshaped family structures, economic models, and the political landscape, providing a path for China to avoid falling into the trap of family monopolies like those seen in Korea and India. With the policy’s adjustment, how to balance efficiency and equity, freedom and order within the new demographic context will be a long-term challenge facing China.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
