<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Esports on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/esports/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Esports on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/esports/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Age of Barbaric Capital: The End of the League of Legends Esports Era</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid development over the past decade and a half, becoming an increasingly significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Particularly games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; (LoL), a MOBA title, have not only provided players with competitive enjoyment but also injected substantial momentum into capital investment, driving the flourishing development of various esports platforms and events. However, this all entered a phase of gradual decline alongside increased capital influx and the rise of the broader entertainment industry. The rise and fall of PandyTV, the competition between DouYu and Huya, marked the end of the “wild capitalism era,” and it seems that the favorable conditions – time, place, people, and heaven – for esports are also beginning to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Early Esports: From Grassroots to Professionalization&lt;/strong&gt;
The early esports industry started relatively grassroots, especially in the Chinese market. Many players participated in competitive games like &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; and Dota, driven by their love for gaming. However, the true rise of esports began with the release and promotion of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. Following the official entry of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; into the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community to become part of mainstream culture. Notably, starting in 2013, the LPL (China Professional League) began to form, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; became the cornerstone of China’s esports industry.
&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Capital Flood: The Rise of PandaTV and Esports Streaming Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;
2015 marked a watershed moment for China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry. The influx of capital transformed esports from purely competitive events into a much larger ecosystem. Pandahua (PandaTV), as one representative, became a product of excessive capital. Funded by Wang Sicong (one of the founders of PandaLive), Pandahua quickly rose to prominence with its innovative content and massive investment, attracting a large number of viewers and users. However, this was also a typical example of capital “barbaric” inflow – the market’s frantic pursuit of capital often lacks patience and long-term vision. Although Pandahua&amp;rsquo;s financial and human resources achieved certain results in the short term, it ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019 due to management issues and excessive reliance on capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Live Streaming Platform Competition: The “Capital War” between DouYu and Huya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decline of PandaTV did not lead to a decline in the esports live streaming industry; instead, it fueled the rise of platforms like DouYu and Huya. The two major live streaming platforms quickly became leaders in the esports industry, with competition between them intensifying. DouYu initially established itself as a benchmark for esports live streaming through its broadcasts of professional &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; tournaments and by signing top streamers. Meanwhile, Huya gradually narrowed the gap with DouYu through increased investment in esports events and its own diversified platform layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, capital played a significant role once again. In 2018, DouYu successfully went public, and Huya also completed an IPO the same year. The rapid flow of capital led to industry consolidation and resulted in intense competition between platforms regarding streamers and copyrights, forming a “capital battle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-fusion-of-mass-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Fusion of Mass Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 The Trend Towards Mass Entertainment: Capital Flows into Diversified Entertainment Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With significant capital investment in the esports industry, esports platforms are gradually moving towards mass entertainment. Esports anchors no longer limit themselves to match commentary and event broadcasts; they begin to expand into singing, dancing, live interaction, and other forms of entertainment. The content on the platform becomes more diverse, gradually forming an ecosystem centered around esports but incorporating various entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this trend towards mass entertainment has also brought problems – the original focus of esports culture is being marginalized, replaced by a trend of “entertainment above all.” This trend has caused some fans who originally loved esports culture to feel alienated, and capital is increasingly turning its attention to other entertainment fields. - Excessive capital influx and profit-seeking have gradually blurred the essence of the esports industry, with core values centered around competition weakening.
&lt;strong&gt;2.2 The Rise of Pan-Entertainment Industry: Capital Withdrawal and Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;
As short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and the entertainment industry (including K-pop) have risen, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to a broader range of entertainment content. In this process, giants such as Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance no longer rely solely on esports projects for profit, but have increased their investments in areas such as film, music, and short videos.  In particular, the rise of ByteDance, through the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin (TikTok), has overshadowed esports with other entertainment content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three-league-of-legends-yellow-doesnt-follow-yellow-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter Three: League of Legends’ “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has almost been synonymous with China’s esports industry, achieving countless professional players, teams, and events, and also spawning a massive esports ecosystem. However, after more than a decade, as a leading project in Chinese esports, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; has entered a phase of “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow.” Particularly in recent years, the influence of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is gradually declining, even exhibiting obvious signs of decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 The “Fracture” in Player Demographics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable change is the fragmentation of player demographics. Initially, the rapid development of esports relied on the support of a large number of young players who became professional players or spectators thanks to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. That generation of internet addiction teenagers almost grew up under the “timeshare dividend,” immersed in the competitive appeal of League of Legends. This, in turn, drove the rapid expansion of the entire industry. However, as time passed, these players gradually matured and entered society, shifting towards other life and career paths. Simultaneously, a new generation of young players didn’t show the same fervor for &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; as in previous years, and the esports audience has developed a noticeable age bias and decline in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-yellow-never-follows-green-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends’ “Yellow Never Follows Green”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 The “Stagnation” of Game Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, despite numerous updates and revisions, has begun to show signs of stagnation in its competitive appeal. Annual version releases, hero balance adjustments, and the introduction of new gameplay mechanics seem unable to fundamentally address players&amp;rsquo; demand for fresh content. Simultaneously, the MOBA market has become increasingly saturated, with other games (such as &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt;) rapidly rising in popularity and diverting a significant portion of League of Legends’ player base. This competitive landscape has left League of Legends perpetually playing the role of “follower,” unable to break free from its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-where-does-the-esports-industry-go-from-here&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Where Does the Esports Industry Go From Here?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that sprung up seemingly overnight. Excessive capital roams within the internet industry, searching for the next big trend, and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China’s demographic dividend, the esports industry achieved tremendous success in a short period. However, this success wasn&amp;rsquo;t built on a solid foundation. Over-investment by capital, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering the healthy development of the esports industry. Prior to university, I didn’t play many games, and the League of Legends was essentially a companion throughout my growth. I watched so many World Championships, and as an outsider, comparing Chinese and Korean players, especially Faker, domestic players always felt apprehensive and hesitant during major tournaments. I also understand that professional gamers face immense psychological pressure, but this industry has developed for over ten years, and their mental health issues should be prioritized by the teams – which they weren’t. Domestic gameplay still relies on individual player talent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
