<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Disk on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/disk/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Disk on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/disk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Occasional disk recognition issues due to too many disks installed on ASUS Z490 motherboards</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the previous discussion, I encountered a problem where the wireless network card was not being recognized. Before rebuilding the partitions, I also searched online for other solutions, such as removing the motherboard battery and disconnecting power for fifteen minutes; or upgrading to the latest BOIS driver, but all of these had issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking there were still things to deal with, I switched to a limited network and ran the ethernet cable from the living room to the room. At this point, another problem arose – the wired network couldn&amp;rsquo;t be recognized either. I tried a drastic measure of reinstalling the system, which resulted in a missing partition error. If these problems consistently occurred, I wouldn’t have bothered troubleshooting for so long. This ASUS disk conflict is intermittent and triggered by unstable system restarts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desktop computer had a new disk added last week, a 2TB solid-state drive from Yangtze Memory (YMTC), M.2 interface. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been restarted since then until yesterday when it was shut down once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk Family Portrait&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinstall-system&#34;&gt;Reinstall system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been two years since I last reinstalled the system. The C drive is full, and Windows has its usual problems – various software likes to save things on the C drive. So, I decided to reinstall the system. After reinstalling the system, the network card issues were resolved normally. The next day, I restored my development environment and prepared to back up the system. That&amp;rsquo;s when a new problem arose: after restarting the system, the boot partition was lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the steps in the previous article, I rebuilt the boot partition, but it&amp;rsquo;s not very stable. After restarting, the boot partition might fail to load at any time. I started suspecting issues with the computer case, when I noticed the hard drive cable was loose, but after checking several times, there’s no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-revival&#34;&gt;Memory revival
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, this machine had an SSD installed once. At that time, I bought a PCIe adapter (plugged into the graphics card slot) instead of installing the drive directly on the motherboard. This time, installing it directly on the motherboard might be due to a problem with the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid-state transformer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motherboard-manual&#34;&gt;Motherboard Manual
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motherboard manual has an issue: the location of the SATA ports indicated in the manual doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the actual locations. Because I have too many disks, they are all installed on the interfaces. The older SSDs use SATA interfaces. According to the motherboard manual, there is a conflict between these interfaces. After testing, this conflict is triggered unstably. When it triggers, the corresponding disk cannot be loaded. This happens to be the system disk, and the bootloader is also on that disk, so the system fails to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/20250110002401.png&#34;
	width=&#34;807&#34;
	height=&#34;847&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Z490&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;228px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reinstalled the solid-state drive onto the PCIe adapter, and at that point, there was no conflict with the SATA interface on the motherboard anymore, so the system started up normally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Building computers</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/computer-assembly-tips/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:33:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/computer-assembly-tips/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The author was fascinated by assembling computers from a young age and began learning about hardware assembly after starting university. They recommended websites for comparing hardware performance and provided purchasing suggestions, including CPU, solid-state drives, mechanical hard drives, and memory frequency. They also shared their experience and precautions regarding hardware selection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;destiny-beyond-words&#34;&gt;Destiny, beyond words
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was little, I wanted to build my own computer, but the economic conditions just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t allow it. It wasn’t until college that I finally had the chance, and for portability reasons, I got a laptop. If you want a specific time frame, when did I start wanting to build a computer? It all started at the library back home. It was a pretty decent-sized library for a city district – it had an electronic reading room (though I never went, as it charged by the hour) and a magazine reading room. That’s where I stumbled upon magazines like “大众软件” (Popular Software) and “电脑报” (Computer News). For someone with limited exposure to computers, they were essentially divine educational resources. Seeing chapters about raiding dungeons made me want to build my own computer so I could pull mobs and be a main damage dealer; seeing the &amp;ldquo;black technology&amp;rdquo; sparked fantasies of recreating what was described in the books (a discussion on using hacking tools). Though high school coursework was demanding, with my limited knowledge at the time, I felt I needed to both study and play. It was a pretty carefree time. I’d often use going to the library as an excuse, grabbing a small bag and strolling over there. The city wasn&amp;rsquo;t that big, so I usually walked. Once inside, I’d enjoy the air conditioning while reading novels, comics, and gaming magazines, occasionally glancing at some serious books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As you get older, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to forget things. This isn&amp;rsquo;t the first time something like this has happened at the library. When I was in junior high school, my relatives assembled a computer, and I don’t remember why they built that machine back then. The operating system was Windows 2003, and the games included the card game and Age of Empires. I spent all sorts of time trying to sneak the keys and play games with my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Entering junior high, the school offered basic computer training. Later, when I transferred schools, I was also introduced to the concept of computer competitions. By the time I reached high school, I participated in NOIP once. Speaking of this, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible not to mention the power of alumni – the high school’s computer building was funded by alumni donations and included a computer lab and library. It was actually during the initial wave of China&amp;rsquo;s internet boom at that time. School leaders also supported participation in computer competitions; after all, several seniors from the previous two years had been admitted to key universities through computer-related programs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve never looked back at my relationship with computers like this before. No wonder I made such a complete shift from the automation major to the computer industry after graduation – the seeds were already sown, though those involved didn’t realize it. Having been exposed to them since childhood, I thought I was quite knowledgeable, but in reality, I only understood the basics. My biggest advantage was that initial passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware-assembly&#34;&gt;Hardware assembly
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Browse Carrefour, Chiphell, and Zhihu&amp;rsquo;s computer building sections; a beginner can relatively easily create a list of the machine they need. When purchasing a CPU after 2019, if your financial situation isn’t abundant, AMD is the best choice for higher performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a translation of the provided Chinese text: I recommend a commonly used hardware performance comparison website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cpu.userbenchmark.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://cpu.userbenchmark.com/&lt;/a&gt;, which is comparable to Xianyu (闲鱼) for pricing. True experts can find great deals on used items on Xianyu, saving a lot of money. If you&amp;rsquo;re not very knowledgeable, I don’t recommend using it; I bought fake memory there myself. Although it seems to be working fine so far, I’m not entirely sure, and the model and parameters are completely mismatched.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sn550-vs-sn750&#34;&gt;SN550 VS SN750
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difference between the SN550 1TB and the SN750 1TB is that their sustained read/write speeds differ by a factor of two – one reaches 850MB, the other 1.6GB. However, there&amp;rsquo;s no noticeable difference in daily use because both have the same 4K performance. Of course, this refers to the 1TB capacity SN550; the 500GB and 250GB versions have slower sequential read/write speeds. Honestly, unless you’re not worried about cost, the SN550 is fine for everyday use. The main reason I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy it isn&amp;rsquo;t its sequential read/write speed, but rather that it only comes in a maximum of 1TB capacity, while the SN750 offers 2TB. For me, the value lies more in having an extra M.2 NVMe slot on my motherboard than in the price difference between these SSDs, without needing to expand further.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the consensus of online users, purchasing an adapter board will allow a B150 motherboard to support an M.2 SSD&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;choosing-a-mechanical-hard-drive&#34;&gt;Choosing a Mechanical Hard Drive
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, mechanical hard drives are priced stably. For users with large storage needs, it is recommended to select a suitable mechanical hard drive. Frequent downloaders are advised to consider enterprise-grade hard drives, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Western Digital Gold&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seagate Exos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s recommended to partition large-capacity mechanical hard drives. Frequent download operations should be directed to a specific partition. If bad sectors appear later, they can be concentrated in one partition, and that partition can then be discarded, effectively extending the lifespan of the mechanical hard drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seagate &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.seagate.com/cn/zh/enterprise-storage/exos-drives/exos-e-drives/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Official Introduction&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of Seagate Enterprise Hard Drives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of Seagate Enterprise Hard Drives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;memory-frequency&#34;&gt;Memory frequency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Starting from the perspective of daily work, frequency will not have a significant impact on performance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory Timing Memory (Salted Fish Memory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory timings (or RAM timings) are four parameters describing the performance of synchronous dynamic random-access memory (SDRAM): CL, TRCD, TRP, and TRAS, measured in clock cycles. They are typically written as four numbers separated by hyphens, such as 7-8-8-24. The fourth parameter (RAS) is often omitted, and a fifth parameter may be added: Command rate, usually 2T or 1T, also written as 2N or 1N. These parameters specify latency times that affect random access memory speed. Lower numbers generally indicate faster performance. The ultimate element determining system performance is the actual latency time, typically measured in nanoseconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When converting memory timings to actual delays, it&amp;rsquo;s most important to note that they are measured in clock cycles. Without knowing the duration of a clock cycle, it’s impossible to determine if one set of numbers is faster than another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the clock frequency of DDR3-2000 memory is 1000 MHz, and its clock cycle is 1 ns. Based on this 1 ns clock, a CL=7 results in an absolute latency of 7 ns. Faster DDR3-2666 (clocking at 1333 MHz with a 0.75 ns cycle) may use a larger CL=9, but still produce a shorter absolute latency of 6.75 ns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern DIMMs include a serial presence detect (SPD) ROM chip, which contains memory timings recommended for automatic configuration. The PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS may allow users to adjust these timings to improve performance (with the risk of reducing stability), or in some cases increase stability (such as using the recommended timings).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note: Memory bandwidth measures memory throughput and is typically limited by transfer rate rather than latency. It is possible to continuously transmit at peak rates by interleaving access to multiple internal banks of SDRAM. Bandwidth can be increased at the expense of increased latency. Specifically, each new generation of DDR memory has a higher transfer rate, but absolute latency does not change significantly, especially for the first batch of products in a new generation, which often have longer latencies than the previous generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with increased memory latency, increasing memory bandwidth can improve the performance of computer systems with multiple processors or multiple execution threads. Higher bandwidth will also enhance the performance of integrated graphics cards without dedicated video memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory Timing Parameter Explanation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Memory timing parameters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
