<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Harmony on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/harmony/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Harmony on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/harmony/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Celestial Realm of Medical Education and the Butterfly Effect of the Dong Xi-ying Incident</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 01:08:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/medical-education-sky-dong-xiying-butterfly-effect/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Peking Union Medical Center &amp;ldquo;4+4&amp;rdquo; program (4 years of non-medical undergraduate + 4 years of medical PhD), emphasizing interdisciplinary elite training, was exposed in 2025 due to the Dong Xiying incident. Her entry into the program allegedly leveraged family background (a lineage of medical professionals/researchers), raising questions about her educational qualifications and allegations of plagiarism. This highlights a conflict between the program&amp;rsquo;s elitist admissions practices and fairness, alongside unresolved issues regarding shortened training periods and supervised practice concerns.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompt&#34;&gt;Prompt
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Writing a blog post: The origins and development of Concordia 4+4. Key points: A corner of Heaven, seen by mortals; Miss Dong&amp;rsquo;s family background; it’s impossible for a normal medical PhD to graduate in eight years; Miss Dong&amp;rsquo;s family and educational backgrounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disintegrated-palace-of-medical-education-unionmed-44&#34;&gt;The Disintegrated &amp;ldquo;Palace&amp;rdquo; of Medical Education: UnionMed 4+4
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;4+4&amp;rdquo; program at Peking Union Medical College, launched in 2018, has been regarded as a “heavenly palace” for medical education in China. Designed to emulate the American medical education system and guided by the principles of attracting individuals with diverse backgrounds, cultivating those with a passion for medicine, and recruiting talent from across the globe, it seeks to break new ground within the traditional medical education framework. Its core logic lies in &lt;strong&gt;用4年非医学本科教育+4年医学博士培养，替代传统的5+3+3（本科5年+硕士3年+博士3年）模式&lt;/strong&gt;, aiming to cultivate leading medical professionals with interdisciplinary expertise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This pattern&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Celestial Palace&amp;rdquo; attribute is reflected in three dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially, applicants were required to have graduated from universities ranked within the top 50 by QS/Times/US News or among the top 10 US News liberal arts colleges (such as Barnard College). While later relaxed to include schools ranked in the top 100, a GPA of 3.6 or higher, or being in the top 30% of their class is still required.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizing an American organ-system integrated curriculum and PBL (Problem-Based Learning) teaching methods, students must complete core courses such as anatomy and pathology within four years, alongside clinical internships&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Although the passing rate for the licensing exam (95.2%) was slightly lower than the traditional eight-year program (98.5%), graduates largely enter Peking Union Medical Center affiliated hospitals, and their career development shows no significant difference from the traditional path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dong-xi-ying-incident-cracks-in-heavenly-palace-seen-by-a-mortal&#34;&gt;The Dong Xi-ying Incident: Cracks in &amp;ldquo;Heavenly Palace&amp;rdquo; Seen by a Mortal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In April 2025, a report of extramarital affairs involving Dr. Xiao Fei, a thoracic surgeon at the Sino-Japanese Friendship Hospital, unexpectedly exposed the &amp;ldquo;mystery&amp;rdquo; surrounding Peking Union Medical Center&amp;rsquo;s 4+4 project. The resume of the involved party, Dong Xiuying, raised three points of concern:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;学历背景的模糊性&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dong Xiyi claims to have graduated from Columbia University, but in fact attended its affiliated Barnard College (ranked 14th by US News for liberal arts colleges in 2025). Although Barnard meets the &amp;ldquo;top 20 liberal arts college&amp;rdquo; requirement, its diploma simultaneously lists “Barnard College” and “Columbia University,” which can easily be mistaken for Columbia’s main campus in the domestic recruitment market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The path of a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree in economics followed by a doctorate in clinical medicine, while meeting the &amp;ldquo;multidisciplinary background&amp;rdquo; requirement of the 4+4 program, has been questioned for lacking a foundation in pre-medical coursework. Furthermore, his doctoral dissertation, &amp;ldquo;Research on Multi-Modal Image Fusion Technology in Medical Image Analysis,&amp;rdquo; has been accused of significant similarity to a Beijing University of Science and Technology invention patent, raising concerns of academic misconduct.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;家庭背景的特殊性&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;His father is a secretary at China Metallurgical Research Institute, his mother is an associate dean at the Beihang University Engineering Technology Research Institute, his grandfather is an academician in the field of imaging at Peking Union Medical College, his maternal grandparents are foreign academicians in materials science, and his aunts and uncles are professors at Beihang University. This &amp;ldquo;medicine + research + university&amp;rdquo; family background provides him with hidden resources such as letters of recommendation (requiring two biomedical associate professors) and research collaborations (such as patents from Beihang University).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During residency, he switched from thoracic surgery to urology, with research spanning multiple fields including orthopedics, gastroenterology, and imaging, leading to accusations of &amp;ldquo;paving the way with resources.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;学制争议的放大&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Traditional medicine doctoral programs require 11 years (5+3+3), while the 4+4 program compresses this to 8 years. Despite Peking Union Medical College&amp;rsquo;s emphasis on &amp;ldquo;integrated curriculum&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;early clinical exposure,&amp;rdquo; some doctors note that its clinical internship time (12 months) is less than the traditional eight-year system (18 months), potentially impacting skill development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some training bases allow a one-year reduction in required training for 4+4 graduates, raising concerns about fairness within the industry&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-dilemma-of-medical-education-behind-the-controversy&#34;&gt;The Dilemma of Medical Education Behind the Controversy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Dong Xi-ying case reflects the deep-rooted contradictions in China&amp;rsquo;s medical education system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;精英化与公平性的冲突&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;application-review system&amp;rdquo; of the 4+4 program is essentially a transplant of the American medical school model, but China lacks standardized exams like the MCAT, and subjective evaluations such as letters of recommendation and research experience are easily influenced by family background&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data shows that among the 2023 graduates (4+4 program), 30% came from Tsinghua, Peking University, and Fudan University, 25% from overseas prestigious universities, indicating a significant influence of family background on applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;学制改革的现实困境&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Research output (e.g., publications) from 4+4 medical students is significantly lower than that of traditional eight-year programs, leading to criticism of prioritizing clinical experience over research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Top-tier hospitals prioritize the Peking Union Medical Center brand, while community hospitals are cautious about the clinical abilities of 4+4 program graduates&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;医学教育的国际接轨之惑&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US 4+4 model requires passing the MCAT and completing 3-7 years of residency, while China&amp;rsquo;s 4+4 program simplifies admission and residency, resulting in a superficial resemblance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to data from the Ministry of Education, in 2024 nationwide medical doctoral program admissions, programs following the 4+4 model accounted for less than 5%, and their widespread promotion still faces challenges&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reconstructing-the-celestial-palace-order-of-medical-education&#34;&gt;Reconstructing the &amp;ldquo;Celestial Palace&amp;rdquo; Order of Medical Education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The controversy surrounding the Union 4+4 project is fundamentally a clash between elite education and public expectations. When a corner of &amp;ldquo;heavenly palace&amp;rdquo; (referring to top-tier medical training) is glimpsed by ordinary people, it exposes not only flaws in individual cases but also deep-seated contradictions within the entire medical education system. Future reforms need to focus on three levels:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce standardized exams (like China&amp;rsquo;s version of the MCAT) to reduce the influence of subjective factors such as letters of recommendation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Restore the internship period for 4+4 graduates to 3 years to ensure clinical competency standards are met&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish an academic integrity review mechanism, with rigorous originality verification for interdisciplinary research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Medical education should not be a privilege for a few, but a true incubator for medical excellence. Only when fairness in selection, rigor in training, and standardization of career development are comprehensively ensured can this &amp;ldquo;medical education experiment&amp;rdquo; truly take root.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
