<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Finance on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/finance/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Finance on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The curtain-raising of anti-corruption in finance</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China: Efforts to combat corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector must be intensified, and addressing the “four vices” should be pursued thoroughly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-political-bureau-of-the-communist-party-of-china&#34;&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Communist Party of China (CPC) held a meeting on September 27 to review the comprehensive report on the findings of the first round of inspections by the CPC Central Commission for Discipline Inspection during the 20th CPC National Congress. General Secretary of the CPC Xi Jinping presided over the meeting. The meeting emphasized that, taking the rectification of issues identified through inspections as an opportunity, it is necessary to further strengthen the Party’s overall leadership, urge inspected Party organizations to enhance their political awareness and earnestly fulfill the responsibilities and missions entrusted by the CPC Central Committee, continuously strengthen the core functions and core competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the essential material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, increase the efforts of financial institutions in serving the real economy and national strategies, and promote high-quality development. It is necessary to balance development and security, firmly establish a bottom-line and extreme thinking mindset, take effective measures to prevent and resolve major risks, and resolutely safeguard the safety threshold. Efforts should be made to deepen the comprehensive and strict governance of the Party, tighten and implement the responsibility of Party committee secretaries as first responsible persons, the “one-post, two-responsibilities” system for members of leading bodies, and the supervisory responsibilities of disciplinary inspection and supervision organs, with a particular focus on strengthening supervision over &amp;ldquo;top leaders&amp;rdquo; at all levels. Efforts should also be increased to combat corruption in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, address issues related to “formalism and bureaucracy,” and deepen investigations and rectification efforts, promoting a system where officials dare not, cannot, and do not want to engage in corruption. It is necessary to earnestly implement the Party’s organizational principles for the new era, strengthen leading body construction, cadre and talent team building, and grassroots Party organization construction. The results of inspections should be comprehensively utilized to deepen reform, improve systems, promote source governance, and facilitate a combination of curative and preventative measures. (Xinhua)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Causing major financial risks! Liu Liange, former secretary of the Communist Party Committee and chairman of China Banking Regulatory Commission, has been expelled from the Party&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission, with the approval of the Communist Party of China Central Committee, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission has initiated an investigation into Liu Liange, former secretary of the party committee and chairman of Bank of China, for serious violations of discipline and law
After investigation, Liu Liange lost his ideals and beliefs, abandoned his original aspirations and mission, failed to resolutely implement the decisions and deployments of the Party Central Committee, neglected his responsibilities in financial risk prevention and control, extensively interfered with credit projects in violation of regulations, illegally disbursed loans, resulting in major financial risks. He performed poorly in fulfilling the principal responsibility for comprehensively strengthening discipline and governance, seriously damaged the political ecology of his unit, secretly brought prohibited books and publications into the country, and deliberately resisted organizational inspections. He disregarded the spirit of the Central Eight-point Regulation, violated regulations by accepting gifts and cash, entering private clubs, and receiving skiing and travel arrangements, and long-term borrowed vehicles belonging to those he managed. He failed to report personal matters as required, did not truthfully explain issues during organizational inquiries, and improperly appointed, adjusted, or promoted cadres based on personal considerations. He engaged in commercial activities and operated enterprises illegally; interfered with funds lending in violation of regulations and privately retained classified materials. His morals were corrupt, his family conduct was improper, and he failed to properly guide and educate his relatives. He had no bottom line for discipline and law, abused his power for personal gain, “relied on finance to make money from finance,” used his position to seek benefits for others in areas such as loan financing and project cooperation, and illegally accepted large sums of property.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Liu Liange seriously violated Party political discipline, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline, and daily life discipline, constituting serious official misconduct and suspected bribery and illegal loan disbursement crimes. He failed to restrain himself before and after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, with severe consequences and a negative impact. In accordance with regulations such as the &amp;ldquo;Regulations on Party Discipline,&amp;rdquo; the &amp;ldquo;Law on Supervision of the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China,&amp;rdquo; and the &amp;ldquo;Law on Administrative Punishment of Civil Servants,&amp;rdquo; following deliberation by the Standing Committee of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and approval by the Communist Party of China Central Committee, it was decided to impose the disciplinary action of expulsion from the Party on Liu Liange; revoke the benefits he was entitled to according to regulations; terminate his qualifications as a delegate to the 20th National Congress of the CPC; confiscate the proceeds of his violations and illegal activities; and transfer the issues involving suspected crimes to the procuratorial organ for examination and prosecution, along with all related assets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Li Xiaopeng, former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Guangda Group, has been removed from his party membership and public office due to serious violations of discipline and law. (CCTV News)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission reported, according to news from the Disciplinary Committee and Supervisory Commission of Guizhou Province: Li Zhiming, former Party Secretary and Chairman of Guizhou Bank, is suspected of serious violations of discipline and law and is currently undergoing disciplinary review and investigation by the Disciplinary Committee and Supervisory Commission of Guizhou Province&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;huijin-increases-its-holdings-in-the-four-largest-banks-after-eight-years&#34;&gt;Huijin increases its holdings in the four largest banks after eight years
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, the four largest state-owned commercial banks – Industrial and Commercial Bank of China, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, and China Construction Bank – each announced that they had received increased holdings from Huijin Capital, amounting to 27.61 million shares, 37.27 million shares, 24.89 million shares, and 18.38 million shares respectively; Huijin Capital plans to continue increasing its holdings in the four banks on the secondary market within the next six months&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
