<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:28:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>LPL’s Korean Invaders and the “All Chinese Squad” Dream: A Game About Results, Development, and Belonging</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lpls-korean-invaders-and-the-all-chinese-squad-dream-a-game-about-results-development-and-belonging/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 03 Nov 2025 04:57:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lpls-korean-invaders-and-the-all-chinese-squad-dream-a-game-about-results-development-and-belonging/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s undeniable that the surge of big data, coupled with recent news about competitive matches, always prompts me to take a look. Similar videos on TikTok have been proactively dismissed – I don&amp;rsquo;t want to keep receiving homogenous content. I also forgot about an account; unsurprisingly, TES lost decisively, and related topics were trending on Zhihu’s hot list. A highly-voted answer mentioned LPL’s Korean reinforcements and the concept of “all Chinese team.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without that year’s IG victory, League of Legends is likely already over. ldl&amp;rsquo;s strategic play, combined with multiple debuffs, contributed to LPL’s performance as a region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing article: Why does LPL, China’s League of Legends regional league, introduce Korean players? From the coaching staff to the players, reinforcements have been introduced, whether this limits the development of domestic players, and then domestically there is still hope for a Chinese all-star team to win, whether this belongs to the obsession of the Chinese people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the “Korean Wave” began flooding the LPL at the end of S4, Korean players and coaches have become an indispensable part of this region. From iG’s (Rookie, TheShy) in S8 and FPX’s (Doinb, GimGoon) in S9, to EDG’s (Scout, Viper) in S11, LPL has three times lifted the global World Championship (S-Series) trophy, with Korean players and coaches playing a crucial role in each victory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, simultaneously, a resounding slogan has consistently permeated the LPL’s public opinion – “All Chinese Team.” While audiences celebrate LPL’s championships, they also harbor almost obsessive expectations for a “Chinese team” to win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Why did LPL introduce Korean players? Does this limit the development of domestic players? And what exactly is the origin of the “All Chinese Team” obsession?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-introducing-korean-talent-a-catalyst-from-chase-to-lead&#34;&gt;Why Introducing Korean Talent: A “Catalyst” From Chase to Lead
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The LPL’s introduction of Korean talent was initially driven by a purely pragmatic goal: &lt;strong&gt;to win.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the S3 and S4 periods, LCK (South Korea&amp;rsquo;s league) dominated &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; with its impeccable operations and unparalleled individual player abilities. As a challenger, the LPL’s fastest and most direct “copywork” strategy was to bring in “teachers” – top players and coaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Demand for Battle-Ready Talent and Guaranteed Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the disintegration of Samsung White and Samsung Blue in S4, a large number of top Korean players entered the LPL. They brought with them the most advanced game understanding and the highest level of operational skill. The arrival of Rookies, Doinb, Pawn, and Mata quickly elevated the limits of teams like LNG, WE, and EDG. For clubs, this was a necessary commercial choice in pursuit of results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Introducing an Advanced “Esports Industrial System”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LPL didn’t just bring in players; it also brought in coaching staff and the underlying training system. Korean esports is renowned for its strict discipline, data-driven approach, and high-intensity training model. The arrival of coaches like Kkoma and DanDy brought LCK management experience and tactical reserves into the LPL, forcing LPL clubs to transition from “internet cafe-style” management to “professionalized” management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. &amp;ldquo;Catfish Effect&amp;rdquo;: Activating Internal Competition&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The introduction of top Korean players was like introducing a catfish into a pond. Local players had to grow faster and adapt to higher levels of competition in order to maintain their starting positions. From this perspective, Korean talent (such as TheShy, Rookie) wasn’t just an “overseas player,” but also a “senior sparring partner” and “teammate teacher” for domestic players (such as JackeyLove, Ming, Knight), collectively raising the overall average level of the entire LPL league.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-double-edged-sword-has-korean-support-been-a-limitation-or-a-catalyst-for-domestic-development&#34;&gt;A Double-Edged Sword: Has Korean Support Been a “Limitation” or a “Catalyst” for Domestic Development?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is one of LPL’s most controversial topics in history, and the answer is &lt;strong&gt;“both”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “Restrictive Viewpoint”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Occupied Survival Space:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most direct impact. When LPL&amp;rsquo;s top teams habitually reserved key C-positions (mid laner, top laner) for Korean players (like the infamous &amp;ldquo;Mid Laner Must Speak Korean&amp;rdquo; joke), it made it even harder for promising domestic rookies to get playing time. With only one position available per game, Korean players’ priority did, to a certain extent, “suppress” the rise of some domestic talents.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Communication Costs and Tactical Monotony:&lt;/strong&gt; Early &amp;ldquo;3-2&amp;rdquo; patterns (three Chinese players supporting two Korean players) often led to communication breakdowns. Team tactics sometimes became monotonous due to accommodating Korean players&amp;rsquo; habits, lacking the LPL-style &amp;ldquo;dare-to-play-boldly&amp;rdquo; style of domestic players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The “Promotional Viewpoint”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Elevated Domestic Player’s “Lower and Upper Limits”:&lt;/strong&gt; LPL domestic players (like Tian, Ming, Knight) grew up through competing with and learning from players like Rookie, Doinb, Ruler, and Viper. The opponents they faced in the S-Series were often stronger than their daily training game teammates. This intense internal competition was a key reason for the explosive growth of LPL domestic talent (especially support and jungler positions).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;LPL’s “Blood Generation” Capability is Now Number One Globally:&lt;/strong&gt; The fact is, LPL currently has the largest and most complete youth system (LDL). LPL doesn&amp;rsquo;t lack &amp;ldquo;people&amp;rdquo;; it lacks the very top &amp;ldquo;towering&amp;rdquo; players. The introduction of Korean players was precisely to fill this final piece of the &amp;ldquo;tower.&amp;rdquo; Furthermore, LPL’s “assimilation” ability is extremely strong; Rookie and Doinb eventually became “LPL domestic players.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, LPL, through introducing Korean players, &lt;strong&gt;traded “space” for “time.”&lt;/strong&gt; It sacrificed some domestic players&amp;rsquo; short-term playing opportunities but gained the rapid elevation of the entire league’s competitive level and three S-Series championships, ultimately feeding back into its own youth system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;all-chinese-team-a-near-obsessive-national-pride-sentiment&#34;&gt;“All-Chinese Team”: A Near-Obsessive National Pride Sentiment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If introducing Korean reinforcements is a &amp;ldquo;rational&amp;rdquo; competitive choice, then pursuing the “All-Chinese Team” represents an “emotional” national sentiment. Simply labeling this desire as “fanaticism” is incomplete; it has deep cultural and historical roots.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. The Essence of Sports is “Nation/Region Confrontation”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s traditional sports (like the Olympics) or esports, when it rises to the international competition stage, it naturally carries a national/regional honor color. Viewers seeking excitement while watching games are not just looking for competitive thrills; they&amp;rsquo;re also seeking an identity affirmation of “our people” winning.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. The Ultimate Proof: &amp;ldquo;We Can Win Ourselves&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LPL has already proven itself capable of winning through a combination of Chinese and Korean players. However, “All-Chinese Team winning” is another dimension of the narrative: it means that the LPL region achieved a &lt;strong&gt;holistic victory&lt;/strong&gt; – from players and coaches to tactics and youth training systems. This represents the ultimate proof of &amp;ldquo;we can stand at the top of the world without external force.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Historical Regrets and RNG’s “Deification”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obsession with the “All-Chinese Team” is deeply intertwined with the narrative of the RNG team (especially during Uzi&amp;rsquo;s time). In S8, that all-Chinese team RNG won MSI, giving countless LPL viewers hope for &amp;ldquo;All-Chinese Team winning a World Championship Series.&amp;rdquo; Although S8 ultimately failed, the regret of “just missing it” further reinforced this obsession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. The Catalyst of the Asian Games&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Jakarta and 2023 Hangzhou Asian Games both required “All-Chinese Team” lineups for the “League of Legends” project. When esports combined with the traditional sports model of &amp;ldquo;contributing to national glory,&amp;rdquo; the “All-Chinese Team” evolved from a “fan’s expectation” into a “national team standard,” further deepening viewers&amp;rsquo; identification with domestic rosters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-from-borrowing-strength-to-legitimizing&#34;&gt;Conclusion: From &amp;ldquo;Borrowing Strength&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Legitimizing&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The introduction of Korean support (韩援) into LPL was a necessary strategy in its early development, driven by the need to quickly catch up and achieve “overtaking” – a strategy that has been definitively proven successful by the championship trophies won by S8, S9, and S11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inclusion of Korean support did not &amp;ldquo;restrict&amp;rdquo; the development of LPL; instead, through the “catfish effect” (鲶鱼效应) and “internal teaching,” it &lt;strong&gt;significantly accelerated the growth of LPL’s native talent&lt;/strong&gt;, transforming LPL into the now-recognized number one region.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The obsession with a “full Chinese team” (全华班) was not narrow xenophobia, but rather &lt;strong&gt;a peak of domestic confidence leading to a desire for “ultimate glory”&lt;/strong&gt; – representing what LPL viewers hoped to see: a perfect closed loop where this region would transition from “reliance on foreign support” to “self-sufficiency and dominance.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The story of LPL is a microcosm of the intersection of globalization and localization. We enjoy the extreme operations brought by Ruler and Scout, and we will also shed tears for RNG in 2018 and the &amp;ldquo;full Chinese team&amp;rdquo; representing China at the 2023 Asian Games. This is not contradictory; it’s simply different pursuits at different stages of a region&amp;rsquo;s journey from “student” to “master.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Vacation Watching Games: When T1 Becomes an Impenetrable Mountain for the LPL – What “Macro &#43; Industry” Negative Factors Does Xiaomi Face Again?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/vacation-watching-games-when-t1-becomes-an-impenetrable-mountain-for-the-lpl-what-macro-industry-negative-factors-does-xiaomi-face-again/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/vacation-watching-games-when-t1-becomes-an-impenetrable-mountain-for-the-lpl-what-macro-industry-negative-factors-does-xiaomi-face-again/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No trading activity within the venue; we’re currently awaiting next month&amp;rsquo;s financial reports. Taking a half-day break this afternoon – nothing particularly noteworthy, just wanting to rest and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;years-have-passed&#34;&gt;Years Have Passed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last watched League of Legends (LOL) matches live, and suddenly it feels like four or five years have passed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous articles related to games, I always had a complex feeling towards LPL teams (the domestic league). The frequent low-level mistakes made by many players in major tournaments felt lacking in professional demeanor, which significantly reduced the viewing experience – this is why I gradually drifted away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This afternoon, on a whim, I took a half day off to tidy up my room, and the summer clothes were still unorganized. While doing so, I decided to watch some matches. The quarterfinals were still T1, that formidable mountain standing in front of LPL teams, seemingly impossible to overcome. Looking back, LPL hadn’t won any Bo5 (best-of-five) crucial matchups against them in the World Championship series; every team they faced felt immense pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I wrote these words, the match had entered its “classic” fifth game – the LPL team was leading 2-1 and in a great position to win, but their opponent tied it up, and both teams were about to enter a brutal final deciding game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update before publishing: The operation wasn&amp;rsquo;t too bad, but their build strategy was completely crushed. The Queen composition led to Ashe dominating early on, preventing Miss Fortune from grouping and initiating fights; it was incredibly difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; Performance was stable with minimal fluctuation, punctuated by a brief rally.
&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; This decline was largely driven by a confluence of negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro Drag:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall pullback in the Hong Kong tech sector (such as NetEase, Alibaba, and Tencent) performed poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The new energy vehicle sector experienced intensified “internal competition” (“intense competition”), with market expectations for growth in companies like BYD already peaking, and Xiaomi’s automotive future space also under pressure.
&lt;strong&gt;Industry Observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UBS&amp;rsquo;s pre-earnings report highlighted the rising prices of solid-state drives and memory. The extent to which this cost increase will erode the profit margins of mobile business remains to be revealed in the earnings report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, one thing is certain: In a market as intensely “competitive” as this, the Android smartphone ecosystem no longer has the luxury of raising prices arbitrarily.
&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Backlash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, returning to Xiaomi itself, its automotive business is facing reputation issues. The project’s early promotional volume was immense, with almost no negative feedback. Now, it seems to be experiencing a wave of public “backlash” following excessive exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The End of the Age of Wild Capitalism: The Era of League of Legends Esports Concludes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid development over the past decade and a half, becoming an increasingly significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Particularly MOBA games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; (LoL), which is often abbreviated as LOL, not only provide players with the joy of competition but also inject powerful momentum into capital, driving the flourishing development of various esports platforms and events. However, all of this has entered a phase of gradual decline with the influx of capital and the rise of the entertainment industry. The rise and fall of PandyTV, the competition between DouYu and Huya, marks the end of the “wild capitalism era,” and the favorable conditions – time, place, people, and heaven – for esports seem to be starting to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 The Early Days of Electronic Sports: From Grassroots to Professionalization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early esports industry started relatively grassroots, especially in China. Many players participated in competitive games like &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; and Dota, driven by their passion for the games. However, the true rise of esports began with the release and promotion of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. Following the official entry of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; into the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community to part of mainstream culture. Notably starting in 2013, the LPL (China Professional League) was established, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; became the cornerstone of China’s esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Capital Frenzy Influx: The Rise of PandaTV and Esports Live Streaming Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 marked a watershed moment for the Chinese esports industry. The influx of capital transformed esports from a purely competitive event into a much larger ecosystem. PandaTV, one of the representatives, became a product of excessive capital. Invested by one of its founders, Wang Sicong, PandaTV quickly rose to prominence with its innovative content and massive investment, attracting a large number of viewers and users. However, this was also a typical example of capital “barbaric” inflow – the relentless pursuit of markets often lacks patience and long-term vision. Although PandaTV’s short-term investments achieved certain results due to management issues and excessive reliance on high fever caused by capital, it ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Live Streaming Platform Competition: The “Capital War” Between DouYu and Huya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demise of PandaTV did not lead to the decline of the esports live streaming industry; instead, it propelled the rise of platforms like Douyu and Huya. Douyu and Huya became leading players in the esports industry, and their competition intensified. Early on, Douyu established itself as a benchmark for esports live streaming through the broadcasting of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; professional competitions and the signing of top streamers. Huya, meanwhile, gradually narrowed the gap with Douyu by increasing its investment in esports events and diversifying its platform layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, capital played a huge role again. In 2018, Douyu successfully went public, and Huya also completed its IPO the same year. The rapid flow of capital led to industry consolidation and intensified competition between platforms in terms of streamers and copyrights, forming a “capital war.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-fusion-of-mass-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Fusion of Mass Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 The Trend Towards Mass Entertainment: Capital Flows into Diversified Entertainment Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As capital has heavily invested in the esports industry, esports platform content is gradually becoming mass-entertained. Esports anchors are no longer limited to match commentary and event live streaming; they have begun to expand into singing, dancing, interactive live streams, and other entertainment forms. The content on platforms is becoming more diverse, gradually forming an ecosystem centered around esports but also incorporating various entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this mass entertainment trend has also brought problems – the original focus of esports culture has been marginalized, replaced by a trend of entertainment above all else. This trend has caused some fans who originally loved esports culture to feel alienated, and capital has begun to pay more attention to other entertainment fields. The excessive influx of capital and profit-seeking behavior have gradually blurred the essence of the esports industry, and the original value concept centered around competition has been weakened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2 The Rise of Mass Entertainment Industry: Capital Withdrawal and Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and the entertainment industry have risen, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to a wider range of entertainment content. In this process, giants such as Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance no longer rely solely on esports projects as sources of revenue, but are increasing their investments in areas such as film, music, and short videos.  In particular, the rise of ByteDance, through the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin (TikTok), has overshadowed the limelight of esports with other entertainment content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-yellow-not-following-yellow-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends’ “Yellow Not Following Yellow”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has almost become synonymous with China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry, achieving countless professional players, teams, and events, and also spawning a massive esports ecosystem. However, after more than ten years, as a leading project in Chinese esports, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; has entered a phase of “Yellow Not Following Yellow” – a period of decline. Particularly in recent years, the influence of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is gradually waning, even exhibiting obvious signs of recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 The “Fracture” in Player Groups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable change is the fragmentation of player groups. Initially, esports’ rapid development relied on the support of a large number of young players, many of whom became professional players or spectators thanks to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. That generation of &amp;ldquo;internet addiction&amp;rdquo; teenagers almost grew up under the “era’s advantage,” immersed in the competitive charm of LOL and thus driving the rapid expansion of the entire industry. However, as time went on, these players gradually matured, entered society, and began to shift towards other life and career paths. At the same time, a new generation of young players are not as enthusiastic about &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; as in its heyday, and the esports audience has exhibited a clear age bias and decline in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 The “Weakness” in Game Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, after multiple updates and revisions, still maintains a certain competitive charm, but the game’s own innovation in content appears somewhat lacking. Each year&amp;rsquo;s version updates, hero balance adjustments, and new gameplay introductions seem unable to fundamentally address players’ demand for freshness. Meanwhile, the MOBA market has become saturated, and other types of games (such as &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Game For Peace&lt;/em&gt;) have rapidly risen, diverting a large number of players who originally belonged to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. This competitive situation has left &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; unable to escape the role of “follower.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-where-does-the-esports-industry-go-from-here&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Where Does the Esports Industry Go From Here?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that sprung up seemingly overnight, with excessive capital roaming the internet sector, searching for the next big trend – and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China’s demographic dividend, the industry achieved tremendous success in a short period, but this success wasn&amp;rsquo;t built on a solid foundation. Excessive capital influx, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering the healthy development of the esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to university, I didn’t play many games; Alliance essentially accompanied my growth alongside generations. I watched countless World Finals, and as an outsider, comparing ourselves to Korean and Chinese players, especially Faker, domestic players always felt hesitant during major tournaments. I also know that athletes face immense psychological pressure, but this hasn&amp;rsquo;t been prioritized by teams. Over a decade of development, these mental health issues should be taken seriously, yet they weren’t. Domestic gameplay still relies on the innate talent of the players themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of gaming: the intersection of psychological development and social entertainment.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital age, games have evolved far beyond a simple form of entertainment and become an integral part of people&amp;rsquo;s daily lives. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of individuals across various age groups, while also being closely intertwined with social and recreational activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental State
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in the stage of self-exploration and identity formation. &lt;strong&gt;Games provide them with a low-cost environment to try and explore.&lt;/strong&gt; Through games, they can experiment with different roles and lifestyles, satisfying their curiosity and desire for exploration. As they grow older, individuals’ interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social Attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, the game has also become a part of social activities, particularly for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, making games a bridge for socialization. However, as people age, their social circles gradually stabilize, and social needs may be met through more mature ways, leading to a relative reduction in the role of games in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes-bringing-a-sister&#34;&gt;Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of education regarding romantic relationships, parents often simply expect you to study diligently and then immediately focus on finding a partner after graduation. This phenomenon is quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals are unable to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides them with an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, achieving emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real life, reducing fear of the uncertainties in real-life interactions. However, long-term reliance on virtual gratification within games can potentially impact their ability to build and maintain healthy emotional relationships in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-world-pressure&#34;&gt;Real-World Pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games provide a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of real life. Particularly for young people facing academic pressure, family issues, or interpersonal relationship challenges, games may become a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are typically designed to give players a sense of accomplishment and recognition when completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they can experience a feeling of being appreciated and recognized within them – a feeling that may be lacking in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dislike-playing-after-getting-older&#34;&gt;Dislike Playing After Getting Older
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face relatively fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing them more time and energy to invest in gaming. As they enter the workforce or start families and other social responsibilities increase, time and energy become more valuable, and games may be seen as a drain on resources rather than a prioritized leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests also change. They might have been interested in fast-paced, visually stunning games when younger, but with increased experience, they may prefer strategy games, those with strong storylines, or games with greater depth. If the market doesn’t meet these changing needs, interest naturally diminishes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Gaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games of the &amp;ldquo;pay-to-win&amp;rdquo; type, here we will not discuss this; within the gaming community, this is collectively referred to as “Renminbi Warriors” – requiring an affluent wallet rather than understanding game settings. Their enjoyment lies in the entourage of smaller players surrounding them and the thrill of “raid.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive games with a large audience, such as: League of Legends, DOTA, Honor of Kings, PUBG, these types of games have complete worldviews and their game competitions have entered a benign cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is indeed a key field in game design, and social psychology is particularly important. Understanding people’s behavior, needs, and motivations can help design more engaging gaming experiences. Regarding the relationship between “showing off” and social psychology, we can look at it from the following angles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Identity:&lt;/strong&gt; People often seek to establish a sense of identity within social groups. In games, if designs allow players to feel they are outstanding in some way, attracting the attention of other players, this may increase their social identity. This could manifest as boasting skills or showcasing earned rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games have adopted social competition elements, encouraging players to showcase their achievements on social networks. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate competitive psychology between players and may lead some players to perform more impressively to gain social recognition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Expression:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games allow players to express themselves through customizing characters, virtual items, etc. This self-expression is not just for showing off; it can also be a way of expressing personality and social communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games emphasize teamwork, achieving game goals through social interaction. In such situations, boasting behavior may not be encouraged but rather emphasizes collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological Reward Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design can adopt psychological reward systems to stimulate positive social behaviors in players. For example, rewarding or granting privileges to players to encourage them to actively participate in social interactions.
Overall, social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interaction and social experiences. Boasting behavior may exist in some situations, but game designers typically strive to balance this behavior to ensure that the gaming experience is positive and interesting for all players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about where I was writing, without a complete outline, it’s a bit chaotic.
The author often plays League of Legends, which is a memory of our generation. Most parents don&amp;rsquo;t like their children playing games because they haven&amp;rsquo;t deeply understood or experienced this type of game; of course, it has to do with the game settings. Each game is a new beginning, and for many children, when they play, they don’t bring much thought into it, belonging to self-exploration gameplay. Under this mode, the outcome of the game depends more on the child&amp;rsquo;s inherent gaming talent. Based on my actual experience, a large part of the players belong to this type, for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost is not money, but time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s also entertainment mode within the game, designed to cater to recreational players. League of Legends, this competitive game, for me, was more about realizing a “Three Kingdoms dream.” Starting off, you have nothing in your pockets, relying on your own understanding, farming, spending money, controlling vision, setting traps and ambushes for the opponent – it’s largely about thinking your way through the game. Without exceptional gaming talent, you can still find immense enjoyment. The feeling of commanding the overall situation, the joy of turning a losing game around. And there are also many viewers who often mention “casual players” – they no longer play the game but still watch the matches during major world events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s worth mentioning “game time.” This isn&amp;rsquo;t referring to the duration of a single match, but rather the amount of time you spend in the game – on weekends in the afternoons, or evenings between 7 pm and 10 pm after work. You’ll find that you can usually communicate normally with your teammates, and your signals are understood and responded to. If you switch to other times, such as playing through the night, you&amp;rsquo;re more likely to encounter “gaming addicts,” favorable situations where nothing happens, and in unfavorable situations, they’ll complain about you to your family – you can almost feel their resentment through the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who works in the IT industry and plays a lot of games, I’ve tried various types, always preferring to think my way through the game rather than relying on reaction speed or talent. Compared to professionals or younger players, my reactions are slower, and I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to coordinating with teammates and taking command of the team’s strategy. When I first started playing, it was during my student years, guided by older brothers from an YY guild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, regarding the current game environment, it feels quite agitated and lacks the purity of before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After graduating, playing high-level segment games was really exhausting. The entire game required intense focus, thinking about the opponent&amp;rsquo;s plans, and how to counter their setups. It’s that kind of experience where you don’t want to continue after finishing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s be honest, if you’re considered a very good player, without professional competition, it wouldn’t have much impact on your life trajectory. While it can serve as a social tool, it&amp;rsquo;s not something you can make a living from or establish yourself in society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player games and online games are two different types of games that differ significantly in their gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the differences between single-player and online games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection Method:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games (Offline/Single-player):&lt;/strong&gt; These games are played on a local device alone, without requiring an internet connection. Players can enjoy the game experience even without network connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games (Online/Multiplayer):&lt;/strong&gt; This type of game typically requires an internet connection because players need to interact with other players in real time. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online social interaction and esports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player Interaction:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players primarily interact with artificial intelligence, pre-set tasks, or opposing elements within the game. The gaming experience is generally more personalized, influenced by the in-game design and storyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include collaborating on missions, competing against each other, or participating in esports competitions, as well as social elements like chat, guild systems, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design and Content:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design focuses more on providing a complete, independent storyline and gaming experience. The game content is typically pre-designed, and players explore, solve puzzles, or fight within the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design needs to consider real-time interaction and player competition or collaboration. The game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Generally run offline, with relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Require a strong internet connection and high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Models:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically use one-time purchase or download business models, where players buy the game to play it fully on their local devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; May employ various business models such as free-to-play, advertising, item purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these differences helps players clarify their preferences when choosing games and allows game designers to better meet player expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
