<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Age of Barbaric Capital: The End of the League of Legends Esports Era</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid development over the past decade and a half, becoming an increasingly significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Particularly games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; (LoL), a MOBA title, have not only provided players with competitive enjoyment but also injected substantial momentum into capital investment, driving the flourishing development of various esports platforms and events. However, this all entered a phase of gradual decline alongside increased capital influx and the rise of the broader entertainment industry. The rise and fall of PandaTV, the competition between DouYu and Huya, marked the end of the “wild capitalism era,” and it seems that the favorable conditions – time, place, people, and heaven – for esports are also beginning to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Early Esports: From Grassroots to Professionalization&lt;/strong&gt;
The early esports industry started relatively grassroots, especially in the Chinese market. Many players participated in competitive games like &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; and Dota, driven by their love for gaming. However, the true rise of esports began with the release and promotion of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. Following the official entry of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; into the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community to part of mainstream culture. Notably, starting in 2013, the LPL (China Professional League) was established, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; became the cornerstone of China’s esports industry.
&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Capital Flood: The Rise of PandaTV and Esports Streaming Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;
2015 marked a watershed moment for China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry. The influx of capital transformed esports from purely competitive events into a much larger ecosystem. Pandahua (PandaTV), as one representative, became a product of excessive capital. Founded by Wang Sicong (one of the founders of PandaLive), Pandahua quickly rose to prominence with its innovative content and massive investment, attracting a large number of viewers and users. However, this was also a typical example of capital “barbaric” inflow – the market’s frantic pursuit of capital often lacks patience and foresight. Although Pandahua&amp;rsquo;s financial and human resources achieved certain results in the short term, it ultimately collapsed in 2019 due to management issues and excessive reliance on capital fever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Live Streaming Platform Competition: The “Capital War” between DouYu and Tiggy (虎牙)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decline of PandaTV did not lead to a decline in the esports live streaming industry; instead, it fueled the rise of platforms like DouYu and Huya. The two major live streaming platforms quickly became leaders in the esports industry, with competition between them intensifying. DouYu initially established itself as a benchmark for esports live streaming through its broadcasts of professional &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; tournaments and by signing top streamers. Meanwhile, Huya gradually narrowed the gap with DouYu through increased investment in esports events and its own diversified platform layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, capital played a significant role once again. In 2018, DouYu successfully went public, and Huya also completed an IPO the same year. The rapid flow of capital led to industry consolidation and resulted in intense competition between platforms regarding streamers and copyrights, forming a “capital battle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-fusion-of-mass-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Fusion of Mass Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 The Trend Towards Mass Entertainment: Capital Flows into Diversified Entertainment Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As capital has heavily invested in the esports industry, the content on esports platforms is gradually becoming mass-entertained. Esports anchors are no longer limited to match commentary and event live streaming; they have begun to expand into singing, dancing, interactive live streams, and other entertainment forms. The content on the platform is becoming more diverse, gradually forming an ecosystem centered around esports but also incorporating various entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, mass entertainmentization has also brought problems – the original focus of esports culture has been marginalized, replaced by a trend of entertainment supremacy. This trend has caused some fans who originally loved esports culture to feel alienated, and capital is beginning to shift its attention to other entertainment fields. - Excessive capital influx and profit-seeking have gradually blurred the essence of the esports industry, with core values centered around competition weakening.
&lt;strong&gt;2.2 Rise of the General Entertainment Industry: Capital Withdrawal and Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;
As short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and the entertainment industry (including K-pop) have risen, capital has gradually shifted from esports to a broader range of entertainment content. In this process, giants such as Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance no longer rely solely on esports projects for profit, but have increased their investments in areas such as film, music, and short videos.  In particular, the rise of ByteDance, through the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin (TikTok), has overshadowed esports with other entertainment content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three-league-of-legends-yellow-doesnt-follow-yellow-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter Three: League of Legends’ “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has almost been synonymous with China’s esports industry, achieving countless professional players, teams, and events, and also spawning a massive esports ecosystem. However, after more than a decade, as a leading project in Chinese esports, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; has entered a phase of “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow.” Particularly in recent years, the influence of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is gradually declining, even exhibiting obvious signs of decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 The &amp;ldquo;Fracture&amp;rdquo; in Player Demographics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable change is the fragmentation of player demographics. Initially, esports’ rapid development relied on the support of a large number of young players who became professional players or spectators thanks to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. That generation of internet addiction teenagers almost grew up under the “timeshare dividend.” They were immersed in the competitive appeal of League of Legends and, as a result, drove the rapid expansion of the entire industry. However, with the passage of time, these players gradually matured, entered society, and began to shift towards other life and career paths. Simultaneously, the interest of the new generation of young players in &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; was not as fervent as it once was, and the esports audience has developed a noticeable age bias and decline in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-yellow-never-follows-green-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends’ “Yellow Never Follows Green”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 The “Stagnation” of Game Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, despite numerous updates and revisions, has begun to show a lack of fundamental innovation in its game content. Annual version releases, hero balance adjustments, and the introduction of new gameplay mechanics seem unable to fundamentally address players’ demand for novelty. Simultaneously, the MOBA market is becoming increasingly saturated, with other games (such as &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt;) rapidly rising in popularity and diverting a significant portion of the player base that was once dedicated to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. This competitive landscape has left &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; perpetually in the role of “chaser.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-where-does-the-esports-industry-go-from-here&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Where Does the Esports Industry Go From Here?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that sprung up seemingly overnight. Excessive capital roams within the internet industry, searching for the next big trend, and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China’s demographic dividend, the esports industry achieved tremendous success in a short period. However, this success wasn&amp;rsquo;t built on a solid foundation. Over-investment by capital, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering the healthy development of the esports industry. Prior to university, I didn’t play many games, and the League of Legends was essentially a companion throughout my growth. I watched so many World Championships, and as an outsider, comparing Chinese and Korean players, especially Faker, domestic players always felt apprehensive and hesitant during major tournaments. I also understand that professional gamers face immense psychological pressure, but this industry has developed for over ten years, and their mental health issues should be prioritized by the teams – which they weren’t. Domestic gameplay still relies on individual player talent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Games to Home: Why We Gradually Distance Ourselves from the Virtual World as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When did I ever feel the most joy playing games? As a child, sneaking onto my parents’ TV to play Tank War, Super Mario, and Space Invaders, or secretly using our computer with my cousin to play Age of Empires – or even in college, playing Devil May Cry and League of Legends with my roommates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, there were no worries about life, and when we played, we truly immersed ourselves completely. That sense of immersion is something you can never find again as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the changes in times and societal progress, those of us who were once active in the virtual world have gradually realized that the platform filled with joy and competition seems to be drifting away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players falling out of line, is not only due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves, but also because of a shift in our center of gravity in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many people’s youth, games were more than just entertainment; they were a social way to connect. A popular multiplayer online game didn&amp;rsquo;t just offer in-game challenges and competition – it connected players from all over the world, building virtual social circles. Back then, playing dungeons together, forming teams for PvP combat, was part of life. Those late-night voice chats and sharing of daily experiences became a cherished memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as time went on, more and more players discovered that this virtual socialization experience didn’t have lasting appeal. With game updates and the diversification of social platforms, players gradually found more interactive ways to connect outside of games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-and-responsibility-the-shift-in-focus-of-adult-life&#34;&gt;Gaming and Responsibility: The Shift in Focus of Adult Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you enter adulthood, responsibilities gradually increase. Many young people once invested a significant amount of time in games, but as their careers begin or they start living with partners and forming families, these activities that previously seemed indispensable entertainment are increasingly squeezed by the demands of real-life responsibility. Marriage, having children, even caring for parents – these major life responsibilities force individuals to make choices about their energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming becomes a thing of the past, replaced by the priority of family life. Many young people who once “fought” in games gradually discover that real life is the most important subject. Especially after having children, the focus of life completely shifts towards family, and gaming is gradually pushed to the periphery of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-home-how-life-changes-influence-our-entertainment&#34;&gt;From Games to Home: How Life Changes Influence Our Entertainment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within our life experiences, the family is one of the most important components. And once we enter family life, the division of time and energy becomes more specific and limited. To care for children and spend time with spouses, many young parents find that they no longer have enough time to focus on games they used to love. They often even stop chasing updates and new features in games. Gradually, social platforms and offline interactions with friends and family have become the preferred way for more people to socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean we completely abandon entertainment activities; it simply means we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen ways that better suit our current stage of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-farewell-of-virtual-worlds-how-do-we-view-this-transition&#34;&gt;The Farewell of Virtual Worlds: How Do We View This Transition?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who were once immersed in games, saying goodbye to gaming social wasn’t easy. After all, the virtual world that had once brought us joy and accomplishment had long become a part of our memories. However, farewell doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean complete severance; it’s about making different choices as life changes, balancing our roles in real-life. As we grow older from our youthful beginnings into responsible adults, games may still have their value, but they can no longer be the main rhythm of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this transition also reflects a facet of human adaptability – our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle as different stages of life unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-gaming-perhaps-well-see-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;The Future of Gaming: Perhaps We’ll See Another Wave of “Sense of Belonging”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, as society and technology continue to develop, the forms and content of games are constantly evolving. For example, modern multiplayer online games have begun to move towards more relaxed and flexible ways of playing, with some designs even focusing on family interaction and parent-child relationships. In the future, we may see more game formats that can better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people reminisce about “games from their childhood” with nostalgia and passion, perhaps in the future we will unexpectedly rediscover those games, bringing with us new understanding and insights, and once again step into that virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-in-change-yet-still-loving&#34;&gt;Living in Change, Yet Still Loving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s games or family life, the changes in our lives always accompany us as we grow. In this process, we gradually realize that, although the virtual world brings us endless joy and excitement, ultimately, we will return to reality, back to the warmest place of all – family. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to regret leaving games behind because every stage of life has its own unique meaning. And these changes are what make us a more complete person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of gaming: the intersection of psychological development and social entertainment.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital age, games have evolved far beyond a simple form of entertainment and become an integral part of people&amp;rsquo;s daily lives. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of individuals across various age groups, while also being closely intertwined with social and recreational activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental State
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in the stage of exploring themselves and establishing their identity. &lt;strong&gt;Games provide them with a low-cost environment to try and explore.&lt;/strong&gt; Through games, they can experiment with different roles and lifestyles, satisfying their curiosity and desire for exploration. As they grow older, individuals’ interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social Attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, the game has also become a part of social activities, particularly for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, making games a bridge for socialization. However, as people age, their social circles gradually stabilize, and social needs may be met through more mature ways, leading to a relative reduction in the role of games in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes-bringing-a-sister-with-a-female-player&#34;&gt;Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister (with a female player)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of adequate dating education, parents often simply expect you to study well and then immediately want you to start a relationship after graduation. This phenomenon is very common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals are unable to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, gaining emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real life, reducing fears associated with the unpredictability of real-world interactions. ## Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister (with a female player)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of adequate dating education, parents often only taught you to study diligently and then immediately expected you to start a relationship after graduation. This phenomenon is quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, achieving emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real-life interactions, reducing fear of the uncertainties in real-world relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-world-pressure&#34;&gt;Real-World Pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games provide a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of real life. Particularly for young people facing academic pressure, family issues, or interpersonal relationship challenges, games may become a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are typically designed to give players a sense of accomplishment and recognition when completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they can experience a feeling of being appreciated and recognized within them – a feeling that may be lacking in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dislike-playing-after-getting-older&#34;&gt;Dislike Playing After Getting Older
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face relatively fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing them more time and energy to invest in gaming. As they enter the workforce or start families and other social responsibilities increase, time and energy become more valuable, and games may be seen as a time drain rather than a preferred leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests also change. They might have been interested in fast-paced, visually stunning games when younger, but with increased experience, they may prefer strategy games, those with strong storylines, or more complex and immersive experiences. If the market doesn’t meet these changing needs, interest naturally declines.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Gaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay-to-Win games, which will not be discussed here within the gaming community; a collective term for “People’s Warriors,” requiring an affluent wallet rather than understanding of game settings. Their enjoyment lies in the surrounding throng of smaller players and the thrill of “raid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive games with large audiences, such as League of Legends, DOTA, Honor of Kings, and PUBG – these types of games have complete worldviews and their esports events are in a healthy cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is indeed a key field in game design, with social psychology being particularly important. Understanding people’s behavior, needs, and motivations can help design more engaging gaming experiences. Regarding the relationship between “bragging” and social psychology, we can look at it from the following angles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Validation:&lt;/strong&gt; People often seek to establish a sense of belonging within social groups. In games, if designed to allow players to feel accomplished in certain areas and attract the attention of other players, this can increase their social validation. This may manifest as boasting skills or showcasing earned rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games employ elements of social competition, encouraging players to showcase their achievements within a social network. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate competitive psychology between players, which may lead some players to perform even more impressively in order to gain social recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Expression:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games allow players to express themselves through customization options like character avatars and virtual items. This self-expression isn’t just about showing off; it can also be a way to express personality and engage in social interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork:&lt;/strong&gt; Certain games emphasize teamwork, achieving game objectives through social interaction. In these scenarios, boasting behavior may not be encouraged but rather emphasizes collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological Reward Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design can utilize psychological reward systems to incentivize positive social behaviors. For example, rewarding players or granting them privileges to encourage active participation in social interactions.
Overall, the application of social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interaction and social experiences. Fluffing (or showing off) behavior can sometimes occur in certain contexts, but game designers typically strive to balance this behavior to ensure the gaming experience is positive and enjoyable for all players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get sidetracked when thinking about things; without a complete outline, it does tend to become a bit disorganized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author’s frequently played League of Legends is considered one of our generation&amp;rsquo;s cherished childhood memories. Most parents don’t like their children playing games, as they haven’t deeply understood or experienced this type of game, and naturally, it has to do with the game’s setting. Each match is a fresh start, and for many kids, when playing, they don’t bring much thought into it, opting for a self-exploratory style of gameplay. Under this mode, the outcome of the game often depends more on the child&amp;rsquo;s inherent gaming talent. Based on the author’s personal experience, a significant portion of players fall into this category; for them…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost isn’t money, it’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s also a casual mode within the game, designed to meet the needs of entertainment players.
League of Legends, this competitive game, for me, was more about realizing a “Three Kingdoms dream.” Starting with an empty purse, relying on my own understanding, I farmed, supplemented, spent money, controlled vision, set traps for the enemy team, and it was primarily a game played with my mind – without exceptional gaming talent, I could still have a lot of fun. The feeling of controlling the overall situation, and the joy of turning a disadvantage into a victory. There are also many viewers who often mention “ghost players” – they no longer play the game but still watch the matches during major world championship events.
Here, we must also talk about “game time.” “I’m not talking about the time of a single game, but rather the time you log in. This includes weekend afternoons and evenings between 7 PM and 10 PM during weekdays – at this time, you&amp;rsquo;ll generally find that you can communicate normally with your teammates, receiving their signals and getting responses back. If you switch to other times, such as late-night gaming sessions, you’re more likely to encounter ‘gaming addicts,’ favorable wind conditions (where nothing happens), and players who will greet you with insults when you&amp;rsquo;re behind. Even through the screen, you can feel their ‘hostility.’”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As someone working in the IT industry and having played many different types of games, I’ve always preferred to play competitive games using my brain – it’s about strategy and execution rather than reaction speed or raw talent. Compared to younger players or professionals, my response time is slower, and I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to leading a team through coordinated strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, how would you describe the current game environment? It’s quite frantic and lacks the pure essence of what it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating, playing high-level games was really exhausting – it required complete focus throughout the entire match, thinking about the opponent’s plans and how to counter their setups. It&amp;rsquo;s that feeling where you don&amp;rsquo;t want to continue after finishing a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you say you play very well, without professional competition, it wouldn’t have much impact on one’s life trajectory. While it can be used as a social tool, it cannot provide a livelihood or establish oneself in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player and online games are two different types of games with significant differences in gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the distinction between single-player and online games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection Method:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-player Games (Offline/Single-player):&lt;/strong&gt; These games are played on a local device alone, without requiring an internet connection. Players can enjoy the game experience even without network connectivity. - &lt;strong&gt;Online/Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; These games typically require an internet connection because players need to interact in real-time with other players. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online social interaction and esports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player Interaction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players primarily interact with in-game artificial intelligence, pre-set tasks, or hostile elements. The gaming experience is typically more personalized and influenced by the game’s design and storyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include collaborating on missions, competing against each other, participating in esports, and social elements such as chat, guild systems, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design and Content:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design focuses more on providing a complete and independent storyline and gaming experience. Game content is typically pre-designed, and players explore, solve puzzles, or engage in combat within the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design needs to consider real-time interaction and player competition or collaboration. Game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically can run offline with relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Require a strong internet connection and have high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Model:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically employ a one-time purchase or download model, where players buy the game to play it fully on their local devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; May utilize various business models such as free-to-play, advertising, item purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content.
Understanding these distinctions helps players clarify their preferences when choosing games and enables game designers to better meet player expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
