<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Game on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/game/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Age of Wild Capitalism: The Era of League of Legends Esports Concludes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid development over the past decade and a half, becoming an increasingly significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Particularly MOBA games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; (LoL), which is often abbreviated as LOL, not only provide players with the joy of competition but also inject powerful momentum into capital, driving the flourishing development of various esports platforms and events. However, all of this has entered a phase of gradual decline with the influx of capital and the rise of the entertainment industry. The rise and fall of PandyTV, the competition between DouYu and Huya, marks the end of the “wild capitalism era,” and the favorable conditions – time, place, people, and heaven – for esports seem to be starting to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 The Early Days of Electronic Sports: From Grassroots to Professionalization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early esports industry started relatively grassroots, especially in China. Many players participated in competitive games like &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; and Dota, driven by their passion for the games. However, the true rise of esports began with the release and promotion of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. Following the official entry of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; into the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community to part of mainstream culture. Notably starting in 2013, the LPL (China Professional League) was established, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; became the cornerstone of China’s esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Capital Frenzy Influx: The Rise of PandaTV and Esports Live Streaming Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 marked a watershed moment for the Chinese esports industry. The influx of capital transformed esports from a purely competitive event into a much larger ecosystem. PandaTV, one of the representatives, became a product of excessive capital. Invested by one of its founders, Wang Sicong, PandaTV quickly rose to prominence with its innovative content and massive investment, attracting a large number of viewers and users. However, this was also a typical example of capital “barbaric” inflow – the relentless pursuit of markets often lacks patience and long-term vision. Although PandaTV’s short-term investments achieved certain results due to management issues and excessive reliance on high fever caused by capital, it ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Live Streaming Platform Competition: The “Capital War” Between DouYu and Huya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The demise of PandaTV did not lead to the decline of the esports live streaming industry; instead, it propelled the rise of platforms like Douyu and Huya. Douyu and Huya became leading players in the esports industry, and their competition intensified. Early on, Douyu established itself as a benchmark for esports live streaming through the broadcasting of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; professional competitions and the signing of top streamers. Huya, meanwhile, gradually narrowed the gap with Douyu by increasing its investment in esports events and diversifying its platform layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, capital played a huge role again. In 2018, Douyu successfully went public, and Huya also completed its IPO the same year. The rapid flow of capital led to industry consolidation and intensified competition between platforms in terms of streamers and copyrights, forming a “capital war.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-fusion-of-mass-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Fusion of Mass Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 The Trend Towards Mass Entertainment: Capital Flows into Diversified Entertainment Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As capital has heavily invested in the esports industry, esports platform content is gradually becoming mass-entertained. Esports anchors are no longer limited to match commentary and event live streaming; they have begun to expand into singing, dancing, interactive live streams, and other entertainment forms. The content on platforms is becoming more diverse, gradually forming an ecosystem centered around esports but also incorporating various entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this mass entertainment trend has also brought problems – the original focus of esports culture has been marginalized, replaced by a trend of entertainment above all else. This trend has caused some fans who originally loved esports culture to feel alienated, and capital has begun to pay more attention to other entertainment fields. The excessive influx of capital and profit-seeking behavior have gradually blurred the essence of the esports industry, and the original value concept centered around competition has been weakened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.2 The Rise of Mass Entertainment Industry: Capital Withdrawal and Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and the entertainment industry have risen, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to a wider range of entertainment content. In this process, giants such as Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance no longer rely solely on esports projects as sources of revenue, but are increasing their investments in areas such as film, music, and short videos.  In particular, the rise of ByteDance, through the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin (TikTok), has overshadowed the limelight of esports with other entertainment content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-yellow-not-following-yellow-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends’ “Yellow Not Following Yellow”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has almost become synonymous with China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry, achieving countless professional players, teams, and events, and also spawning a massive esports ecosystem. However, after more than ten years, as a leading project in Chinese esports, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; has entered a phase of “Yellow Not Following Yellow” – a period of decline. Particularly in recent years, the influence of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is gradually waning, even exhibiting obvious signs of recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 The “Fracture” in Player Groups&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable change is the fragmentation of player groups. Initially, esports’ rapid development relied on the support of a large number of young players, many of whom became professional players or spectators thanks to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. That generation of &amp;ldquo;internet addiction&amp;rdquo; teenagers almost grew up under the “era’s advantage,” immersed in the competitive charm of LOL and thus driving the rapid expansion of the entire industry. However, as time went on, these players gradually matured, entered society, and began to shift towards other life and career paths. At the same time, a new generation of young players are not as enthusiastic about &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; as in its heyday, and the esports audience has exhibited a clear age bias and decline in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 The “Weakness” in Game Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, after multiple updates and revisions, still maintains a certain competitive charm, but the game’s own innovation in content appears somewhat lacking. Each year&amp;rsquo;s version updates, hero balance adjustments, and new gameplay introductions seem unable to fundamentally address players’ demand for freshness. Meanwhile, the MOBA market has become saturated, and other types of games (such as &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Game For Peace&lt;/em&gt;) have rapidly risen, diverting a large number of players who originally belonged to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. This competitive situation has left &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; unable to escape the role of “follower.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-where-does-the-esports-industry-go-from-here&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Where Does the Esports Industry Go From Here?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that sprung up seemingly overnight, with excessive capital roaming the internet sector, searching for the next big trend – and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China’s demographic dividend, the industry achieved tremendous success in a short period, but this success wasn&amp;rsquo;t built on a solid foundation. Excessive capital influx, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering the healthy development of the esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to university, I didn’t play many games; Alliance essentially accompanied my growth alongside generations. I watched countless World Finals, and as an outsider, comparing ourselves to Korean and Chinese players, especially Faker, domestic players always felt hesitant during major tournaments. I also know that athletes face immense psychological pressure, but this hasn&amp;rsquo;t been prioritized by teams. Over a decade of development, these mental health issues should be taken seriously, yet they weren’t. Domestic gameplay still relies on the innate talent of the players themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Games to Home: Why We Gradually Distance Ourselves from the Virtual World as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-leave-virtual-worlds-as-we-grow-up/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-leave-virtual-worlds-as-we-grow-up/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to when you feel the most joy playing games, as a child, sneaking onto your parents’ TV to play Tank War, Super Mario, or Space Invaders, or secretly using your home computer with your cousin to play Age of Empires, or even in college, playing Devil May Cry and League of Legends with roommates – those were the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, without the worries of life, when you played, you truly immersed yourself completely. That sense of immersion is something you can never find again as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the changes in society and progress, we gradually realized that the virtual world where we once thrived was becoming further away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players falling out of line, isn&amp;rsquo;t just due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves; it’s also because our focus has shifted. As we get older, we start busy with marriage and having children, and our main life path has gradually shifted from personal entertainment to family responsibilities. Today, let’s talk about the underlying reasons behind this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many people’s youth, games were more than just entertainment; they were a social way of life. A popular multiplayer online game didn&amp;rsquo;t just offer in-game challenges and competition – it connected players from all over the world, building virtual social circles. Back then, playing dungeons together with friends, forming teams for PvP combat, was part of everyday life. Those late-night voice chats and sharing of daily experiences became a cherished memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as time went on, more and more players realized that this virtual socialization experience didn’t have lasting appeal. With the constant evolution of games and the diversification of social platforms, players gradually found more interactive ways outside of gaming. Friends made in games eventually faded from view, and many formerly active social connections within games quietly fractured.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-and-responsibility-the-shift-in-focus-of-adult-life&#34;&gt;Gaming and Responsibility: The Shift in Focus of Adult Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you enter adulthood, responsibilities gradually increase. Many young people once invested a significant amount of time in games, but as their careers begin or they start living with partners and forming families, these activities that previously seemed indispensable entertainment are increasingly squeezed by the demands of real-life responsibility. Marriage, having children, even caring for parents, these major life responsibilities force individuals to make choices about their energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming becomes a thing of the past, replaced by the priority of family life. Many young people who once “fought” in games gradually discover that real life is the most important subject. Especially after having children, the focus of life completely shifts towards family, and gaming is gradually pushed to the periphery of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-home-how-changes-in-life-are-affecting-our-entertainment&#34;&gt;From Games to Home: How Changes in Life Are Affecting Our Entertainment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within our life experiences, the family is one of the most important components. And once you enter family life, the division of time and energy becomes more specific and limited. Many young parents find that they no longer have enough time to focus on games they used to love, as they dedicate themselves to caring for children and spending time with their spouses. Sometimes, they even stop chasing updates and new features in games. Gradually, social platforms and offline interactions with friends and family have become the preferred way for many people to socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean we completely abandon entertainment activities; it simply means we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen ways that better suit our current life stage. Many friends who were originally accustomed to maintaining contact through games may choose other methods of connection due to different life trajectories, such as family gatherings, dinners, short trips, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-farewell-of-virtual-worlds-how-do-we-view-this-transition&#34;&gt;The Farewell of Virtual Worlds: How Do We View This Transition?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who once immersed themselves in games, saying goodbye to gaming social wasn’t easy. After all, the virtual world that had once brought us joy and accomplishment had long become a part of our memories. However, farewell doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean complete severance; it’s about making different choices as life changes, balancing our roles in real-life. As we grow older from youthful adolescence into responsible adults, games may still hold value, but they can no longer be the main rhythm of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this transition also reflects a facet of human adaptability – our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle as different stages of life unfold. When responsibility and family become central to our lives, gaming social is no longer a priority, but rather an occasional leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-gaming-perhaps-well-see-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;The Future of Gaming: Perhaps We’ll See Another Wave of “Sense of Belonging”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, as society and technology continue to develop, the forms and content of games are constantly evolving. For example, modern multiplayer online games have begun to evolve towards more relaxed and flexible ways, with some designs even focusing on family interaction and parent-child relationships. In the future, we may see more game formats that can better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people reminisce about “games from their childhood” with nostalgia and passion, perhaps in the future we will also pick up those games again at an unexpected moment, with new understanding and insight, and step back into that virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-in-change-yet-still-loving&#34;&gt;Living in Change, Yet Still Loving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s gaming or family life, the changes in our lives always accompany us as we grow. In this process, we gradually realize that, although the virtual world brings us endless joy and excitement, ultimately, we will return to reality, back to the warmest place of all – family. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to regret leaving games behind because every stage of life has its own unique meaning. And these changes are what make us a more complete person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of gaming: the intersection of psychological development and social entertainment.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital age, games have evolved far beyond a simple form of entertainment and become an integral part of people&amp;rsquo;s daily lives. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of individuals across various age groups, while also being closely intertwined with social and recreational activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental State
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in the stage of self-exploration and identity formation. &lt;strong&gt;Games provide them with a low-cost environment to try and explore.&lt;/strong&gt; Through games, they can experiment with different roles and lifestyles, satisfying their curiosity and desire for exploration. As they grow older, individuals’ interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social Attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, the game has also become a part of social activities, particularly for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, making games a bridge for socialization. However, as people age, their social circles gradually stabilize, and social needs may be met through more mature ways, leading to a relative reduction in the role of games in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes-bringing-a-sister&#34;&gt;Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of education regarding romantic relationships, parents often simply expect you to study diligently and then immediately focus on finding a partner after graduation. This phenomenon is quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals are unable to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides them with an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, achieving emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real life, reducing fear of the uncertainties in real-life interactions. However, long-term reliance on virtual gratification within games can potentially impact their ability to build and maintain healthy emotional relationships in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-world-pressure&#34;&gt;Real-World Pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games provide a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of real life. Particularly for young people facing academic pressure, family issues, or interpersonal relationship challenges, games may become a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are typically designed to give players a sense of accomplishment and recognition when completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they can experience a feeling of being appreciated and recognized within them – a feeling that may be lacking in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dislike-playing-after-getting-older&#34;&gt;Dislike Playing After Getting Older
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face relatively fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing them more time and energy to invest in gaming. As they enter the workforce or start families and other social responsibilities increase, time and energy become more valuable, and games may be seen as a drain on resources rather than a prioritized leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests also change. They might have been interested in fast-paced, visually stunning games when younger, but with increased experience, they may prefer strategy games, those with strong storylines, or games with greater depth. If the market doesn’t meet these changing needs, interest naturally diminishes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Gaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games of the &amp;ldquo;pay-to-win&amp;rdquo; type, here we will not discuss this; within the gaming community, this is collectively referred to as “Renminbi Warriors” – requiring an affluent wallet rather than understanding game settings. Their enjoyment lies in the entourage of smaller players surrounding them and the thrill of “raid.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive games with a large audience, such as: League of Legends, DOTA, Honor of Kings, PUBG, these types of games have complete worldviews and their game competitions have entered a benign cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is indeed a key field in game design, and social psychology is particularly important. Understanding people’s behavior, needs, and motivations can help design more engaging gaming experiences. Regarding the relationship between “showing off” and social psychology, we can look at it from the following angles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Identity:&lt;/strong&gt; People often seek to establish a sense of identity within social groups. In games, if designs allow players to feel they are outstanding in some way, attracting the attention of other players, this may increase their social identity. This could manifest as boasting skills or showcasing earned rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games have adopted social competition elements, encouraging players to showcase their achievements on social networks. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate competitive psychology between players and may lead some players to perform more impressively to gain social recognition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Expression:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games allow players to express themselves through customizing characters, virtual items, etc. This self-expression is not just for showing off; it can also be a way of expressing personality and social communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games emphasize teamwork, achieving game goals through social interaction. In such situations, boasting behavior may not be encouraged but rather emphasizes collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological Reward Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design can adopt psychological reward systems to stimulate positive social behaviors in players. For example, rewarding or granting privileges to players to encourage them to actively participate in social interactions.
Overall, social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interaction and social experiences. Boasting behavior may exist in some situations, but game designers typically strive to balance this behavior to ensure that the gaming experience is positive and interesting for all players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about where I was writing, without a complete outline, it’s a bit chaotic.
The author often plays League of Legends, which is a memory of our generation. Most parents don&amp;rsquo;t like their children playing games because they haven&amp;rsquo;t deeply understood or experienced this type of game; of course, it has to do with the game settings. Each game is a new beginning, and for many children, when they play, they don’t bring much thought into it, belonging to self-exploration gameplay. Under this mode, the outcome of the game depends more on the child&amp;rsquo;s inherent gaming talent. Based on my actual experience, a large part of the players belong to this type, for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost is not money, but time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s also entertainment mode within the game, designed to cater to recreational players. League of Legends, this competitive game, for me, was more about realizing a “Three Kingdoms dream.” Starting off, you have nothing in your pockets, relying on your own understanding, farming, spending money, controlling vision, setting traps and ambushes for the opponent – it’s largely about thinking your way through the game. Without exceptional gaming talent, you can still find immense enjoyment. The feeling of commanding the overall situation, the joy of turning a losing game around. And there are also many viewers who often mention “casual players” – they no longer play the game but still watch the matches during major world events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s worth mentioning “game time.” This isn&amp;rsquo;t referring to the duration of a single match, but rather the amount of time you spend in the game – on weekends in the afternoons, or evenings between 7 pm and 10 pm after work. You’ll find that you can usually communicate normally with your teammates, and your signals are understood and responded to. If you switch to other times, such as playing through the night, you&amp;rsquo;re more likely to encounter “gaming addicts,” favorable situations where nothing happens, and in unfavorable situations, they’ll complain about you to your family – you can almost feel their resentment through the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who works in the IT industry and plays a lot of games, I’ve tried various types, always preferring to think my way through the game rather than relying on reaction speed or talent. Compared to professionals or younger players, my reactions are slower, and I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to coordinating with teammates and taking command of the team’s strategy. When I first started playing, it was during my student years, guided by older brothers from an YY guild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, regarding the current game environment, it feels quite agitated and lacks the purity of before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After graduating, playing high-level segment games was really exhausting. The entire game required intense focus, thinking about the opponent&amp;rsquo;s plans, and how to counter their setups. It’s that kind of experience where you don’t want to continue after finishing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s be honest, if you’re considered a very good player, without professional competition, it wouldn’t have much impact on your life trajectory. While it can serve as a social tool, it&amp;rsquo;s not something you can make a living from or establish yourself in society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player games and online games are two different types of games that differ significantly in their gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the differences between single-player and online games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection Method:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games (Offline/Single-player):&lt;/strong&gt; These games are played on a local device alone, without requiring an internet connection. Players can enjoy the game experience even without network connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games (Online/Multiplayer):&lt;/strong&gt; This type of game typically requires an internet connection because players need to interact with other players in real time. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online social interaction and esports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player Interaction:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players primarily interact with artificial intelligence, pre-set tasks, or opposing elements within the game. The gaming experience is generally more personalized, influenced by the in-game design and storyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include collaborating on missions, competing against each other, or participating in esports competitions, as well as social elements like chat, guild systems, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design and Content:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design focuses more on providing a complete, independent storyline and gaming experience. The game content is typically pre-designed, and players explore, solve puzzles, or fight within the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design needs to consider real-time interaction and player competition or collaboration. The game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Generally run offline, with relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Require a strong internet connection and high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Models:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically use one-time purchase or download business models, where players buy the game to play it fully on their local devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; May employ various business models such as free-to-play, advertising, item purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these differences helps players clarify their preferences when choosing games and allows game designers to better meet player expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
