<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Desktop-Pcs on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/desktop-pcs/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Desktop-Pcs on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/desktop-pcs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Upgrading from a desktop to a 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network connectivity.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-2-5g-network-card-accelerates-local-area-network-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-2-5g-network-card-accelerates-local-area-network-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktop hardware three-in-one, in the previous text we mentioned PCIe adapter for solid state drives, where did the old SSDs go? Of course they weren’t wasted – if they were damaged, they were disassembled and installed on the newly purchased ‘MechMaker Mini-3765H’ (bought a year ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new machine has powerful hardware specifications: 2.5G dual network interfaces, PCIe4.0, WiFi6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I moved house and my room doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a dedicated router for networking, so the machines are connected via wireless networks. The ASUS motherboard desktop’s wireless card performance wasn’t great, or perhaps it was the router’s wireless access, which resulted in slow upload speeds between local networks, leading to poor network speeds between the machines. I purchased a 2.5G network card and installed it on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, all the slots on the motherboard are full: graphics card, wireless card, 2.5G network card, PCIe adapter for solid state drives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network Instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both machines connect to the internet using their original wireless network cards, but are directly connected via Ethernet cables between the two, with both ends equipped with 2.5G network cards.  The specifics of how to physically connect the cables aren&amp;rsquo;t detailed here – numerous tutorials are available online; just remember to disable your firewall. You can select either machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD;
    A[Machine 1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Subnet Mask: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Default Gateway: - &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Obtain DNS Automatically] --&amp;gt;|Ethernet Cable (2.5G)| B[Machine 2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Subnet Mask: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Default Gateway: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;Obtain DNS Automatically];
    A --&amp;gt;|Wireless Card| Internet;
    B --&amp;gt;|Wireless Card| Internet;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-subnet-speed-testing&#34;&gt;Two Subnet Speed Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-lan&#34;&gt;Router LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.3.237
Connecting to host 192.168.3.237, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.3.122 port 1656 connected to 192.168.3.237 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.00   sec  9.17 MBytes  76.7 Mbits/sec
[  4]   1.00-2.00   sec  9.91 MBytes  83.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec  8.74 MBytes  73.3 Mbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec  10.2 MBytes  85.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec  9.23 MBytes  77.1 Mbits/sec

### Router LAN
[ 4 ] 4.00-5.00 sec 9.23 MB 77.1 Mbits/sec
[ 4 ] 5.00-6.00 sec 8.80 MB 73.9 Mbits/sec
[ 4 ] 6.00-7.01 sec 8.00 MB 66.8 Mbits/sec
[ 4 ] 7.01-8.00 sec 7.69 MB 64.9 Mbits/sec
[ 4 ] 8.00-9.01 sec 9.72 MB 81.1 Mbits/sec
[ 4 ] 9.01-10.01 sec 7.63 MB 63.6 Mbits/sec
--- --- --- --- --- --- --- --- ---
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[ 4 ] 0.00-10.01 sec 89.0 MB 74.6 Mbits/sec                  sender

### Router LAN
[ 4 ] 0.00-10.01 sec 89.0 MBytes 74.6 Mbits/sec                sender
[ 4 ] 0.00-10.01 sec 89.0 MBytes 74.6 Mbits/sec                receiver

### Router LAN
iperf Done.

### Direct LAN Connection
```shell
C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.4.1
Connecting to host 192.168.4.1, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.4.2 port 1524 connected to 192.168.4.1 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.01   sec   178 MBytes  1.48 Gbits/sec
[  4]   1.01-2.00   sec   204 MBytes  1.72 Gbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec   214 MBytes  1.80 Gbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec   229 MBytes  1.92 Gbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec   202 MBytes  1.69 Gbits/sec
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan&#34;&gt;Direct LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ 4 ]   4.00-5.00   sec   202 MBytes  1.69 Gbits/sec
[ 4 ]   5.00-6.00   sec   213 MBytes  1.79 Gbits/sec
[ 4 ]   6.00-7.00   sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
[ 4 ]   7.00-8.00   sec   192 MBytes  1.61 Gbits/sec
[ 4 ]   8.00-9.00   sec   220 MBytes  1.84 Gbits/sec
[ 4 ]   9.00-10.00  sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[ 4 ]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  sender&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan-1&#34;&gt;Direct LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;[ 4 ] 0.00-10.00 sec 2.06 GB 1.77 Gbps                  sender
[ 4 ] 0.00-10.00 sec 2.06 GB 1.77 Gbps                  receiver&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan-2&#34;&gt;Direct LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;iperf Done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wutongsuimeng.github.io/post/%E7%BB%99hugo%E6%B7%BB%E5%8A%A0mermaid%E6%94%AF%E6%8C%81/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Adding Mermaid Support to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Building PCs</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/computer-assembly/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jul 2020 14:33:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/computer-assembly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The author has long had an interest in building computers from a young age, and began to delve into hardware assembly after university. They recommended websites for comparing hardware performance and offered purchasing suggestions, including CPU, solid-state drives, hard disk drives, and memory frequencies. They also shared their experience and advice regarding hardware selection and important considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wonder--unspeakable&#34;&gt;Wonder – Unspeakable
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ever since I was young, I’ve dreamed of building my own computer, but unfortunately, economic conditions didn&amp;rsquo;t allow it. Finally, after a lot of hard work, I managed to get to university, and I configured a laptop for portability. If I had to pinpoint the exact time when I started thinking about assembling computers, it would be when I first visited the library in my hometown. After all, it was a sizable city-level library, with not only an electronic reading room (which I never actually went to – supposedly you were charged by the hour), but also a magazine reading room, where I browsed magazines like “Popular Science” and “Computer News.” For someone who had limited exposure to computers, these magazines were practically divine科普资料 (scientific explanation materials). - When I read about players doing dungeons, I started thinking about getting my own computer and going to pull monsters myself as the main damage dealer. Seeing the use of black technology, I fantasized about following the instructions in the book and achieving the described effect (regarding the use of hacking tools). Although my high school studies were heavy, with my limited understanding at the time, reading and playing were both necessary – it was a truly innocent and carefree experience. I would make an excuse to go to the library to read, and when nothing else to do, I’d carry a small bag and walk there; the city wasn&amp;rsquo;t that big, so I usually walked to the library.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I got there, I enjoyed the air conditioning while reading novels, comics, and game magazines, occasionally even reading some serious books.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s easy for older people to forget things, and the initial spark came from visiting the library. I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember the computer my relatives assembled during middle school – I have no idea what it was used for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;wonder--unspeakable-1&#34;&gt;Wonder – Unspeakable
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon entering junior high school, the school offered introductory computer training, and later I transferred schools, where I also gained some exposure to concepts in computer competitions. After reaching high school, I qualified for NOIP once. Speaking of which, we must mention the power of our alumni; the high school’s computer building was donated by alumni and included a computer teaching room plus a library. Back then, it was also the initial wave of China&amp;rsquo;s internet boom. School leaders supported participation in computer competitions as well, considering that several senior classmates had been admitted to key universities through computer science.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have never reflected on my relationship with computers like this before. It’s no wonder that after graduating, I resolutely switched from automation to the computer industry – the seed had already been planted, and it was simply a matter of an insider not realizing it. Having encountered many things from a young age, I thought I was very skilled, but in reality, I only understood the superficial aspects; my biggest advantage was that initial passion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hardware-assembly&#34;&gt;Hardware Assembly
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Browse sites like Carda, Chiphell, and Zhihu’s computer assembly forums to get a newbie relatively simple list of components they would need for their own machine. After 2019, when purchasing CPUs with limited financial resources, AMD is preferred for higher performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend a commonly used hardware performance comparison website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://cpu.userbenchmark.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://cpu.userbenchmark.com/&lt;/a&gt;. For pricing, it can be compared to the US versions available on Xianyu (a Chinese online marketplace). True experts can go to Xianyu to find secondhand items, which can save a lot of money. If you’re not very familiar with this, I don&amp;rsquo;t recommend buying from Xianyu; I purchased fake memory, although I haven&amp;rsquo;t found any problems using it so far, and I’m not entirely sure about it – the model and specifications don’t match at all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;sn550-vs-sn750&#34;&gt;SN550 VS SN750
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;The difference between the SN550 1TB and the SN750 1TB is that they consistently read and write slower by a factor of two – one reads at 850MB, while the other reads at 1.6GB. However, for everyday use, there’s no noticeable difference because both support 4K equally. Of course, this refers to the 1TB SN550; speeds are significantly slower in sequential read/write operations with the 500G and 250G versions. In my opinion, if you&amp;rsquo;re not a spendthrift, buying the SN550 is sufficient – my main reason for not purchasing it wasn’t its sequential read/write speed, but rather that it only comes in a 1TB capacity, while the SN750 offers 2TB. For me, considering I don’t want to expand further, the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s M.2 NVMe interface is more valuable than these SSD differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on consensus from online users, purchasing a converter board – a B150 motherboard can also support M.2 interfaces for SSDs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;hard-disk-drive-selection&#34;&gt;Hard Disk Drive Selection
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the prices of hard disk drives are relatively stable. For users with large storage needs, it is necessary to select a suitable mechanical hard drive. We recommend enterprise-grade hard drives for users who frequently download resources. Common ones include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Western Blue Discs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seagate Exos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Large capacity mechanical hard drives should be partitioned, and frequent download operations should be fixed on a specific partition. If bad sectors appear later, they can be concentrated in one partition, and the current partition can be discarded, which can effectively extend the lifespan of the mechanical hard drive.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seagate series &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.seagate.com/cn/zh/enterprise-storage/exos-drives/exos-e-drives/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;official introduction&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/SeagateExos1.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Seagate Enterprise Hard Drive Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/SeagateExos2.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Seagate Enterprise Hard Drive Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;memory-frequency&#34;&gt;Memory Frequency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a daily usage perspective, frequency will not have a significant impact on performance.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/memory.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Memory timing&#34;
	
	
&gt; &lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/yan_yu_memory.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Yan Yu memory&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Memory timings (also known as RAM timings or SDRAM timings) are four parameters that describe the performance of Synchronous Dynamic Random Access Memory (SDRAM): CL, TRCD, TRP, andTRAS, measured in clock cycles. They are typically written as four numbers separated by hyphens, such as 7-8-8-24. The fourth parameter (RAS) is often omitted, and sometimes a fifth parameter is added: Command rate (command rate), usually 2T or 1T, also written as 2N or 1N. These parameters specify the latency (delay time) that affects the speed of random access memory. Lower numbers generally indicate better performance. The final element determining system performance is the actual latency time, typically measured in nanoseconds. When converting memory timing to actual latency, it’s crucial to note that it’s measured in clock cycles. Without knowing the clock cycle time, you cannot determine if one set of numbers is faster than another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;memory-frequency-1&#34;&gt;Memory Frequency
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;For example, the clock frequency of DDR3-2000 memory is 1000 MHz, with a clock cycle of 1 ns. Based on this 1 ns clock, a CL7 value gives an absolute latency of 7 ns. A faster DDR3-2666 (clocking at 1333 MHz, with each cycle 0.75 ns) might use a larger CL9 to produce a shorter absolute latency of 6.75 ns.
Modern DIMMs include a Serial Presence Detect (SPD) ROM chip containing recommended memory timings for auto-configuration. The PC&amp;rsquo;s BIOS may allow users to adjust timings to improve performance (with the risk of instability), or in some cases, increase stability (such as using suggested timings).
Note: Memory bandwidth is measured as throughput and is typically limited by transfer rate rather than latency. By interleaving multiple internal banks of SDRAM, it’s possible to transmit data at peak rates continuously. - This may increase bandwidth at the cost of increased latency. Specifically, each new generation of DDR memory has a higher transfer rate, but absolute latency hasn&amp;rsquo;t changed significantly, particularly with the first-generation products on the market, which often exhibit longer delays than their predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even with increased memory latency, increasing memory bandwidth can improve the performance of multi-processor or multi-threaded computer systems. Higher bandwidth will also boost the performance of integrated graphics cards that don’t have dedicated video memory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;memory_timing_parameter_explanation.png&#34; &gt;Memory Timing Parameter Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Memory_time_series_parameter&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Memory Time Series Parameter Explanation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
