<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Monetary Credit on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/monetary-credit/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Monetary Credit on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/monetary-credit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is modern monetary theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The continued bull market in US stocks, aside from America&amp;rsquo;s own &amp;ldquo;hard power,&amp;rdquo; is largely due to the excessive liquidity of the dollar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system, following the &lt;strong&gt;2008 financial crisis&lt;/strong&gt;, has gradually become a key theoretical underpinning that multiple economies tacitly refer to. Its main feature is an increased emphasis on the initiative of government intervention in the market, utilizing government fiscal deficits as its primary tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are familiar with &lt;strong&gt;Keynesianism&lt;/strong&gt;, which emphasizes the government&amp;rsquo;s role in &lt;strong&gt;smoothing economic cycles&lt;/strong&gt; – suppressing during overheating and stimulating during contractions. It places great importance on the multiplier effect of government spending, that is, how much consumption can be stimulated by a given amount of money. Government spending of 1 unit of currency leads to an increase of 1 unit of income for businesses and individuals, which expands production, increases employment, and boosts consumption, thereby mitigating economic contraction. It also tends to be relatively conservative regarding fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. The &lt;strong&gt;multiplier effect&lt;/strong&gt; can drive market recovery and thus increase government revenue, especially in suppressing overheating cycles, allowing the accumulation of stimulus resources for the next cycle, such as government debt potential and interest rate levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system is more like an extension of extreme Keynesianism, but with a key difference: the limitation on government debt. Central banks should not be independent and their primary goals are &lt;strong&gt;inflation and full employment&lt;/strong&gt;, specifically inflation related to limited resources and productivity. The idea is that the government, through unlimited fiscal deficits, increases purchasing power in the market as technological advancements improve production efficiency, until it reaches an ideal state of full employment and a production bottleneck. Further increases in money supply will then lead to inflation, at which point controlling the upper limit of the fiscal deficit becomes necessary. As long as there are idle productive resources in the market, increasing the deficit will not cause inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the financial crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, reality is not an ideal world. The execution of each link involves human participation, and Keynesianism is selectively applied, leading to a situation where economic downturns are stimulated more than overheating is suppressed. Stimulus for a poor economy brings political achievements, and even overheating can be seen as such, making it fundamentally difficult to curb. This results in numerous economic problems, new financial crises that may not be inferior to the economic impact caused by traditional overcapacity. The 2008 global financial crisis was actually a bubble resulting from market self-reinforcement under extreme Keynesianism. It produced a large number of Ponzi scheme financial investment products, such as real estate and financial investment products derived from real estate as underlying assets. Even before the crisis erupted, there was insufficient risk awareness at academic, political, and market levels. They considered prosperity supported by debt to be achievements, and many benefited from it – for example, the massive financial system, where losses were borne by participants while dividends were enjoyed. It was a case of profiting handsomely even in bankruptcy; the money is impossible to return, ultimately leading to numerous participants bearing the gains from each link of the process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the shadow of the modern monetary system emerges after the financial crisis, characterized by rapid &lt;strong&gt;fiscal deficit monetization and unlimited quantitative easing by the central bank&lt;/strong&gt;, along with so-called emergency lending policies. The central bank acts as a lender of last resort, providing an endless supply of liquidity, while governments can continue to accumulate debt. With coordinated cooperation between the central bank and fiscal policy, the central bank supports government fiscal deficits through measures such as purchasing government bonds, ensuring consistency in policy objectives. This is why the boundaries between modern monetary policy and fiscal policy are becoming increasingly blurred, with money base issuance heavily reliant on the central bank&amp;rsquo;s direct participation in buying government debt – printing money with one hand and spending it with the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eurozone and the United States show similar trends. In 2008, EU government debt was approximately €6.7 trillion, with a leverage ratio of around 66%, slightly above the generally accepted warning line of 60%. By 2014, during the 5-year period of rescue measures, the debt scale reached €9.5 trillion and the leverage rose to 93%. The United States is even more exaggerated; in 2008, US government debt was approximately $10 trillion, reaching around $18 trillion by 2014, and recently again raised the government debt ceiling. Of course, each drama uses the threat of a government shutdown as leverage, but each time it breaks the government debt limit, now exceeding $36 trillion – a growth of $26 trillion compared to 2008. Considering GDP growth factors, the government leverage has also increased from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as lender of last resort, plays an important role in multiple rescue operations and is one of the main purchasers of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-drawbacks-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;The drawbacks and limitations of the modern monetary system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led economic stimulus plan, although not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the omniscience of the market and the selfless courage of all participants in every link? Take a simple example: suppose a government department increases the budget for a certain direction by 1 million – does it go to the leader’s nephew or to the more cost-effective market bidding process? Of course, in reality, interests will be transferred in more complex ways, resulting in the situation where the government expands its debt and expenditure, but the flow is completely uncontrollable. The recent uproar over establishing a government efficiency department in the United States is actually an extension of this kind of problem. Naturally, these vary across different economies with corruption indices, and we are discussing the common issues more broadly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflation-issues&#34;&gt;Inflation issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of modern information networks, governments now have a far greater grasp on market information than in the past. However, this is not omniscience; the market itself contains variables, and it always changes due to expectations, entering a self-reinforcing loop. I anticipated your anticipation. Consider actual performance as an example: although Modern Monetary Theory performed well between 2008 and 2020, genuinely achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stability—even leading to temporary deflation in the Eurozone and keeping US inflation largely within the expected range of 1–3%—it led people to believe in a more extreme tool as they once believed in Keynesianism.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, the main reason is that manufacturing in developing countries continued to show a high growth trend after 2008. For example, China, which gradually secured its position as a global production powerhouse during this period, along with emerging economies like Southeast Asia and India, maintained relatively high manufacturing value-added, effectively offsetting the biggest limitation of Modern Monetary Theory – resource constraints. This allowed Europe and America to maintain relatively stable inflation even amidst deindustrialization, over-financialization, and surging government debt and money supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the use of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States experienced significant inflation, reaching around 10% at their peaks. Even today, nearly three years after interest rate hikes began, the US job market continues to show unusual overheating, and financial markets have seen excessive prosperity diverging from economic growth due to monetary support. As the base effect fades, US inflation is heading towards 3% again. This overheating during interest rate hikes is closely related to fiscal deficits. Interest rate hikes are a contractionary measure in monetary policy, while fiscal policy has been expansionary. Combined with the massive money supply of 2020, this has made US inflation unusually persistent. A major limitation of Modern Monetary Theory is high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-debt-issues&#34;&gt;Government debt issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, the government can indefinitely finance debt repayment through borrowing to repay debt, but the prerequisite is that the central bank must completely become a puppet – that is, &lt;strong&gt;fiscal and monetary policy alignment&lt;/strong&gt; in modern monetary systems. It&amp;rsquo;s clear that the Federal Reserve isn’t prepared to fully relinquish authority to the government. Considering the accumulated government debt balance over decades, especially interest expenses, high-interest debt on top of existing debt has gradually become a massive fiscal burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal year 2023: The U.S. federal government’s fiscal revenue for fiscal year 2023 was $4.439 trillion, with interest payments on debt accounting for approximately 15% of that revenue. This high-interest trend continued in 2024, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.
For fiscal year 2024: the U.S. federal government&amp;rsquo;s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments on debt totaling $882 billion, accounting for approximately 18% of U.S. federal revenue—even exceeding Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sustainability issue of fiscal policy. If low interest rates and low inflation are maintained for a long time, with high debt (like Japan), it can indeed create an application of quasi-modern monetary theory over the long term. According to the Rule of 72, as long as the interest rate is sufficiently low, incremental borrowing under debt-funded finance is very slow. If the cost of funds is 1%, pure debt-funding can double the debt in 72 years. Assuming inflation disrupts this delicate balance, the accumulation of interest payments on the debt could lead to an uncontrolled trajectory of future debt; compound interest becomes a more significant factor than the principal itself. These issues will become even more acute if the central bank’s actions are inconsistent with the goals of the ruling party. The political agenda of the Trump administration, for example, sharply contrasts with the current hawkish stance of the Federal Reserve, which is an important source of the escalation in relations between the US government and the Fed during this term. What everyone is most concerned about is whether the current chairman can successfully reach the end of his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;Financial bubbles and monetary credit issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, government spending increases would flow to households and businesses, prompting them to increase their own spending and boosting effective demand. However, having firsthand experience of numerous financial bubbles since 2000, people will clearly show a strong preference for investment over consumption, especially when products with extremely high expectations of appreciation emerge. People rush to the financial markets seeking higher returns, even at the expense of quality of life and taking on leverage. This is similar behavior observed during periods of rapid growth in real estate in Japan, the United States, and our country. Combined with policy stimulus and practitioners pursuing their own interests, there are many issues like subprime loans. Many so-called market-saving policies actually encourage borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History consistently shows a striking pattern: when monetary and fiscal policies are aggressively implemented, they often lead to &lt;strong&gt;a boom in asset bubbles and wealth redistribution&lt;/strong&gt;. Asset bubbles come first, followed by wealth redistribution, which then leads to another problem – the economic Ponzi scheme that arises from extreme Keynesianism or prolonged use of Modern Monetary Theory (Minsky moment). As long as there is hot money, asset prices continue to rise, and as long as they continue to rise, it attracts newcomers with cash. Meanwhile, the CPI measuring changes in basic living expenses remains relatively unchanged; money stagnates in specific sectors. Newcomers eventually run out of funds, and &lt;strong&gt;after the revelry comes the crash&lt;/strong&gt; – the Minsky moment’s judgment – a pattern that has never failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, currency itself is subject to supply and demand. When the market supply is excessive, traditional investment assets cannot absorb it, or when it fails to attract capital after repeated cycles—such as real estate bubbles that have collapsed repeatedly (something Japanese people haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to touch in decades)—and policies like taxation suppress speculation, increasing taxes on property ownership to reduce speculative demand will all increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation where currency supply is excessive, the market urgently needs investment assets that are both capital-attracting and tax-free. Various virtual investment products emerge as a result. Even the U.S. President and First Lady have come in for a share. One explanation is poaching from the dollar&amp;rsquo;s domain, but it’s more accurately seen as an inevitable consequence of global currency overissuance and financial churning leading to erosion of fiat currency credit. The credibility of modern monetary theory, which relies heavily on the state&amp;rsquo;s monopoly rights over credit-based currency, may even be challenged. What kind of environment gives rise to what kind of financial games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Modern Monetary Theory and Keynesianism are more like a progressive and substitutional relationship. It places greater emphasis on government intervention in the market and adopts a more radical attitude towards fiscal deficits and central bank independence. The overuse of Keynesianism led to stagflation and financial crises. In response to this artificially overheated economy&amp;rsquo;s clearing, Modern Monetary Theory quietly took over after 2008. Amidst continued productivity gains in economic globalization, it quickly restored growth and maintained inflation levels in the countries using it in the short term, but also accumulated large government debt and financial bubbles. When inflation rebounded, and the central bank’s goals diverged from the government&amp;rsquo;s, high interest rates and high leverage exacerbated the fiscal burden caused by government debt repayment, significantly weakening fiscal sustainability. At the same time, excessive government involvement in base money issuance led to financial bubbles, while unlimited printing weakened the currency&amp;rsquo;s creditworthiness itself. The strength of the dollar appears impressive, but it is actually supported by the weakness of others. A huge demand for investment has spawned various new financial investment and speculative tools, even escaping the tax restrictions on traditional financial investment products. This is a microcosm of the global economy. Modern Monetary Theory may not be the future; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s a relic of the past, starting in 2008. Coupled with reverse globalization, the greater the financial bubbles blown, the higher the accumulation of government debt, and the more reckless the financial speculation, the higher the efficiency of distorted wealth distribution, and the greater the risk of a hard landing – including economic and social risks. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s Keynesianism or Modern Monetary Theory, no matter how much money is supplied, it cannot truly solve the problem of wealth structure; instead, it exacerbates risks in asset bubbles and moral hazard. People repeatedly fall into the same pit in different poses but never learn from their mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
