<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Password on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/password/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Password on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:28:59 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/password/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Detailed Explanation of How Passkeys Work and Their Future</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/detailed-explanation-of-how-passkeys-work-and-their-future/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 22:14:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/detailed-explanation-of-how-passkeys-work-and-their-future/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Background introduction: Tencent’s CNB platform only supports WeChat login, with no conventional email account method, leading to several guys in the group complaining about it daily – it&amp;rsquo;s getting annoying. The Tencent product manager came up with a compromise solution: support Passkey login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every day, we are repeating a dangerous action: entering passwords. Despite our complex rules (uppercase, special symbols, numbers), data breaches, phishing attacks, and the frustration of “forgotten password” issues continue to trouble everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tech giants (Apple, Google, Microsoft) along with the FIDO Alliance have provided the ultimate solution: &lt;strong&gt;Passkey (Passcode Key)&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s not just a “replacement” for passwords; it completely “eliminates” them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The login process has shifted from verifying passwords to verifying the &lt;strong&gt;current device&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rsquo;s trustworthiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Explain how Passkey works, how it can be used for login management, collect relevant content, and output an article for internet publication&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-passkey&#34;&gt;What is a Passkey?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;a Passkey is a digital credential stored on your device.&lt;/strong&gt;
It replaces the traditional “username + password.” When you log into websites that support Passkeys (such as Google, GitHub, Adobe), you don’t need to enter any characters – you just verify using facial recognition (Face ID), fingerprint (Touch ID), or device PIN, and you’re instantly logged in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; A password is a string of characters &lt;strong&gt;you remember&lt;/strong&gt; (easily stolen, guessed, or forgotten); a Passkey is an &lt;strong&gt;asset you own&lt;/strong&gt; – an encrypted key stored within the device hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-passkeys-work-asymmetric-encryption&#34;&gt;How Passkeys Work: Asymmetric Encryption
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passkey is built on the &lt;strong&gt;WebAuthn&lt;/strong&gt; standard and the &lt;strong&gt;FIDO2&lt;/strong&gt; protocol. To understand it, we need to understand &lt;strong&gt;Public Key Cryptography&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine a passkey as a pair of “keys” and “locks”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Key:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is it stored?&lt;/strong&gt; Securely stored on your device (such as iPhone’s secure enclave, computer’s TPM module, or password manager).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt; Extremely sensitive, &lt;strong&gt;never sent to the server&lt;/strong&gt;, and doesn&amp;rsquo;t leave your device.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Function:&lt;/strong&gt; It’s your “digital signature pen.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Key:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where is it stored?&lt;/strong&gt; Uploaded and stored on the website/app’s server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt; Publicly visible, not sensitive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Function:&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s used to verify your signature – like a “money checker.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;handshake-details-the-process&#34;&gt;Handshake Details (The Process)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you log in using a Passkey, a sophisticated “challenge-response” mechanism takes place:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initiate Login:&lt;/strong&gt; You click &amp;ldquo;Login,&amp;rdquo; and the website server sends a &lt;strong&gt;random mathematical problem (Challenge)&lt;/strong&gt; to your device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Local Verification:&lt;/strong&gt; Your phone/computer displays a prompt requesting you unlock it using biometrics (face recognition/fingerprint).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This step is solely for authorizing the device to use its private key; biometric data itself is not uploaded.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Digital Signature:&lt;/strong&gt; Upon successful unlocking, the device uses its &lt;strong&gt;private key&lt;/strong&gt; to “sign” the mathematical problem and sends the signature result back to the server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server Verification:&lt;/strong&gt; The server uses the &lt;strong&gt;public key&lt;/strong&gt; you previously provided to verify this signature. If it’s valid, the server confirms that &amp;ldquo;the person who has validated the key indeed holds the private key,&amp;rdquo; thereby allowing login.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-passkeys-are-significantly-more-secure-than-passwords&#34;&gt;Why Passkeys Are Significantly More Secure Than Passwords?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passkeys address the three major pain points of traditional passwords:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;completely-immune-to-phishing-attacks-anti-phishing&#34;&gt;Completely Immune to “Phishing Attacks” (Anti-Phishing)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most robust feature of Passkey. The Passkey protocol enforces the inclusion of &lt;strong&gt;Origin Binding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario:&lt;/strong&gt; A hacker creates a fake &lt;code&gt;g00gle.com&lt;/code&gt; to trick you into logging in.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Result:&lt;/strong&gt; Your browser and system will detect that the current domain does not match the domain registered for your Passkey, &lt;code&gt;google.com&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;refuse to initiate authentication&lt;/strong&gt;. You don’t even have a chance to “fall for it” and enter your password.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;server-leak-was-useless&#34;&gt;Server Leak Was Useless
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even if hackers breached Google’s servers and stole all the databases, they would only have obtained &lt;strong&gt;the public key&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The public key cannot be used to derive the private key.  Holding the public key is like holding a lock; but without the key (the private key which resides on your phone), the hacker couldn&amp;rsquo;t access your account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;no-weak-passwords&#34;&gt;No “Weak Passwords”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Users no longer need to set weak passwords like “123456,” as the keys are strong, encrypted data generated by algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-passkeys-are-changing-login-management&#34;&gt;How Passkeys Are Changing “Login Management”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, we relied on tools like 1Password, LastPass, or Chrome browser to store lengthy strings of characters. Now, login management is undergoing a fundamental shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-device-sync-passkey-sync&#34;&gt;Cross-Device Sync (Passkey Sync)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Early hardware keys (such as YubiKeys) are easily lost. Current Passkeys support cloud synchronization:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Apple Ecosystem:&lt;/strong&gt; Through iCloud Keychain sync. Passkeys you create on your iPhone are automatically available on your Mac.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Ecosystem:&lt;/strong&gt; Through Google Password Manager sync for Android and Chrome.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third-Party Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Tools like 1Password, Dashlane, etc., fully support Passkey. This means you can seamlessly sign in across ecosystems (using a Passkey stored in your iPhone on a Windows computer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-device-login-via-qr-code&#34;&gt;Cross-Device Login (via QR Code)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;What do you do if you want to log in to a PC at an internet cafe (Windows) but your Passkey is on your iPhone?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Select “Login via Another Device” on the web page.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A QR code (FIDO Cross-Device Flow) appears on the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use your iPhone’s camera to scan the QR code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your phone establishes a Near Field Connection with the computer via Bluetooth (to verify you are present) and performs biometric authentication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Login is successful on the PC.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;from-managing-secrets-to-managing-trust&#34;&gt;From “Managing Secrets” to “Managing Trust”
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Future login management will no longer be about checking individual plaintext passwords, but rather &lt;strong&gt;managing trusted devices&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can see: “My GitHub account is bound to my iPhone and MacBook.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If your phone is lost or stolen, you simply revoke the device’s public key access rights from the server (or cloud account).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-comparison-password-vs-passkey&#34;&gt;Table Comparison: Password vs. Passkey
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Password&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Passkey&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cognitive Burden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;High (Requires memorizing complex characters)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;None (No need to memorize)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-comparison-passwords-vs-passkeys&#34;&gt;Table Comparison: Passwords vs. Passkeys
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Passwords&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Passkeys&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phishing Risk&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;High (Susceptible to being tricked into entering)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Zero&lt;/strong&gt; (Domain Binding)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-comparison-passwords-vs-passkeys-1&#34;&gt;Table Comparison: Passwords vs. Passkeys
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Passwords&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Passkeys&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Server Leakage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dangerous (Requires Brute-Force / Password Reset)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Secure (Key Leakage Has No Impact)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-comparison-password-vs-passkey-1&#34;&gt;Table Comparison: Password vs. Passkey
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Password&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Passkey&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Login Experience&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Slow (typing or copy-pasting)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Fast (one-tap biometric verification)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;table-comparison-password-vs-passkey-2&#34;&gt;Table Comparison: Password vs. Passkey
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dimension&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Password&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Passkey&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reliance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Relies on memory or a password manager&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Relies on device (phone/computer)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-challenges-and-future&#34;&gt;Current Challenges and Future
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite the great potential of Passkeys, widespread adoption still requires time:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Platform Barriers:&lt;/strong&gt; While standards are unified, Apple, Google, and Microsoft offer the smoothest experiences within their respective ecosystems. Cross-ecosystem transitions (such as an Android phone paired with an iPad) are feasible but still involve some friction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Device Dependency:&lt;/strong&gt; Losing all trusted devices without a cloud backup can make account recovery difficult (typically requiring a backup recovery code).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Legacy System Compatibility:&lt;/strong&gt; Many older websites and internal corporate networks do not yet support the WebAuthn standard.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Passkey isn’t an upgrade to passwords; it&amp;rsquo;s a &lt;strong&gt;fundamental reconstruction&lt;/strong&gt; of internet identity verification. It leverages modern device biometric capabilities and public-key cryptography, elevating security to a financial level while simplifying the user experience to the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For average users, enabling Passkeys on supported platforms (Google, Apple, Microsoft, Amazon, etc.) is the highest return on investment for improving personal digital security.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
