<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Customized on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/customized/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Customized on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/customized/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Customizing Hugo Themes with Modules: An Explanation of Ideas</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hugo-module-custom-theme-ideas/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2024 22:01:17 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hugo-module-custom-theme-ideas/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The site has switched themes many times, with custom modifications made each time. Here&amp;rsquo;s a record of the ideas behind customizing my themes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugos-modules&#34;&gt;Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Modules
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When people think of modularity, they often consider things like Nginx modules or IDEA plugins. Typically, it allows me to meet my differentiated needs by uploading certain modules. The popularity of this approach stems from its flexibility – it easily satisfies individual requirements without much effort. Often, while the overall functionality is similar, there are always some subtle differences. This highlights the complexity of software, which includes not only technical complexities but also business complexities. Most often, we face business complexities. This perfectly illustrates the saying &amp;ldquo;like a mountain between different professions.&amp;rdquo; Nowadays, modularity isn&amp;rsquo;t just used in the internet industry; it’s adopted by finance and even traditional manufacturing to support enterprise production and management through information systems. Even for something as simple as a leave request system, companies within the same industry can have significant differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This module differs from what people typically expect—it&amp;rsquo;s not organized by function to meet diverse needs, but rather based on directory structure to identify common patterns&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://medium.com/@sunwei.xyz/07-hugo%E6%9E%B6%E6%9E%84-hugo%E7%9A%84%E6%A8%A1%E5%9D%97-8ef5a520a822&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;07. Hugo架构 — Hugo的模块&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-toml&#34;&gt;[[imports]]
path = &amp;quot;github.com/CaiJimmy/hugo-theme-stack/v3&amp;quot;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method still works, but is not recommended in this article. If the theme has been updated, maintaining it will be more complicated and require a separate Git repository for management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-just-paste-the-text-here&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With a foundational understanding of modularity, grasping custom themes becomes much easier. Current themes are also assembled from multiple different modules; to modify one, simply locate the corresponding template file and make your changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extracted from official documentation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using this method, there won&amp;rsquo;t be any file under &lt;code&gt;themes&lt;/code&gt; directory. In order to modify the theme, you will have to copy the file you want to modify to the same directory under &lt;code&gt;layouts&lt;/code&gt; directory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in order to modify the &lt;code&gt;themes/hugo-theme-stack/layouts/partials/head/custom.html&lt;/code&gt; file, you will have to copy it to &lt;code&gt;layouts/partials/head/custom.html&lt;/code&gt; and modify it there (copy the code from theme&amp;rsquo;s repository). The same applies to &lt;code&gt;assets&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; directories。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-find-the-template-file&#34;&gt;How to find the template file
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;orthodox-approach&#34;&gt;Orthodox approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Examine the theme&amp;rsquo;s source files, understand its design, locate the relevant template files, and make your changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;brute-force-approach&#34;&gt;Brute force approach
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As I&amp;rsquo;m not very familiar with front-end code, I sometimes use a brute-force approach: opening the relevant page in my browser, locating what needs modification, searching for it using &lt;code&gt;审查元素&lt;/code&gt;的方式，定位到__INLINE_CODE_1__ within the theme source code, finding the corresponding file, copying it to the site directory, and then making changes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;little-tips&#34;&gt;Little tips
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The platform provides a default file for custom styling. We can split the modifications into multiple files and use &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; to import them, which allows for better style management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.ttf248.life/p/hugo-module-custom-theme-ideas/image.png&#34;
	width=&#34;141&#34;
	height=&#34;375&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;alt text&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;37&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;90px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-of-changes-6h&#34;&gt;Summary of Changes (6h)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anything is easily manageable now&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overall: Global text style, maintains the display style of previous &lt;code&gt;even&lt;/code&gt; 融合 &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_1&lt;/strong&gt;, and is friendly to Chinese&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homepage: Add mouse interaction animation to the right navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Homepage: Article summaries added (implementation was quick, using a shortcut method)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scrollbar: Styled the appearance of the scrollbar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The code highlighting plugin &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; has been introduced to style code blocks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Partial content is reprinted; original author and link information have been added&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archive page: Remove the theme&amp;rsquo;s color overlay from the top category image, displaying the original image&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archive page: Added statistical display panel categorized by year&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Archive page: Two-column layout&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The script uses custom special variables to achieve summary previews&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, excessive code reuse can also be a problem, leading to changes in one area affecting others. Therefore, when modifying the theme, be sure to avoid disrupting existing logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;comments-section&#34;&gt;Comments section
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This guy&amp;rsquo;s revisions are more complete: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://blog.reincarnatey.net/2024/0719-better-waline/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://blog.reincarnatey.net/2024/0719-better-waline/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;STRIKE_11&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recommended homepage, email contact. This site does not have a comments section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
