<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Statements on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/financial-statements/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Statements on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:06:17 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/financial-statements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review Log 20251118</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:50:44 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent inactivity; Xiaomi’s third-quarter financial report was released, with nothing out of the ordinary – the US situation remains turbulent, Hong Kong stocks have recently experienced liquidity stagnation, and the Hang Seng Tech Index has retreated significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major participant in the delivery war, Alibaba is most closely linked to e-commerce taxes, and there isn’t much discussion about it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomi&#34;&gt;Xiaomi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember if I’d written about this company before in previous articles, but when I bought into Xiaomi, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really thought much about what was supporting its market capitalization at the time. Having watched a lot of videos related to Douyin (TikTok)? Recently, HSBC Tech has been falling, and the Hong Kong electric vehicle sector is also declining, yet Xiaomi benefits from multiple buffs layered on top of each other, with negative news flying everywhere, and consequently, its stock price has fallen significantly. Recently, they’ve also replaced the head of their public relations department – conspiracy theories suggest they&amp;rsquo;d been planning this for a while, but the stakes are too high, and there are still many KOLs (Key Opinion Leaders) involved; it would be difficult to wrap up the situation if they suddenly made false claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-supports-xiaomis-stock-price&#34;&gt;What Supports Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Stock Price?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a very good question, as it touches on the fundamental differences in &lt;strong&gt;valuation logic&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;premium valuation capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; for different types of companies within the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideal Auto (2015.HK / LI.US) and Zoox (9863.HK / LEAP.US), as specialized manufacturers of new energy vehicles, their market capitalization (particularly Zoox) appears to be relatively undervaluing compared to the expected valuation of Xiaomi’s automotive business; however, Xiaomi Group (01810.HK) is able to achieve a massive boost in its market capitalization due to the success of Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s automotive ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-xiaomi-valuation-surge-the-underlying-logic--platform-premium-vs-vertical-manufacturing&#34;&gt;🚀 Xiaomi Valuation Surge: The Underlying Logic – Platform Premium vs. Vertical Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s soaring valuation is driven by the capital market assigning it a &lt;strong&gt;“platform-type company”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“ecosystem enablement”&lt;/strong&gt; premium, which is something that companies like Ideal and OPPO – &lt;strong&gt;“vertical manufacturers”&lt;/strong&gt; – do not possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation Anchor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Tech Platform”&lt;/strong&gt;: Core is its &lt;strong&gt;smartphone x AIoT smart ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;. The automotive business is viewed as an expansion of the ecosystem and a key step towards premiumization, representing a new species empowered by the platform.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Vertical Manufacturer”&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation anchor is based on &lt;strong&gt;vehicle sales, gross margin&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unit profitability&lt;/strong&gt;, directly linked to industry cycles and competition.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-1&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scarcity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Scarcity:&lt;/strong&gt; It is the &lt;strong&gt;only one globally&lt;/strong&gt; that can deeply integrate smartphones, AIoT ecosystems and smart electric vehicles, with its “human-vehicle-home ecosystem” story possessing uniqueness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relatively Common:&lt;/strong&gt; In the new energy vehicle sector, there are many competitors; they are &lt;strong&gt;followers&lt;/strong&gt;, lacking disruptive business models.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-2&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;: The automotive business provides support if it encounters setbacks, with a massive volume of mobile and high-margin internet businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentrated Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation is almost entirely dependent on vehicle sales and market performance, which is highly volatile.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-ecosystem-empowerment-and-user-conversion-efficiency&#34;&gt;2. Ecosystem Empowerment and User Conversion Efficiency
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s success wasn&amp;rsquo;t an isolated event; it was a reflection of &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s powerful ecosystem empowerment capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massive Potential Customer Base:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi possesses hundreds of millions of active users, who are &lt;strong&gt;existing, highly engaged, and recognize the Xiaomi brand and ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; as potential car buyers. Ideal and ZAP! needed to start from scratch acquiring users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Marketing Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can directly reach its target audience through channels like smartphones, apps, and Mi Home, achieving &lt;strong&gt;extremely high marketing efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;. The SU7’s astonishing order conversion rate demonstrates the immense value of its ecosystem traffic and word-of-mouth effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentiation in Intelligent Driving and Cockpit:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can achieve &lt;strong&gt;seamless collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; between smartphones, car infotainment systems, and smart homes.  The market believes that this ecosystem integration will deliver a &lt;strong&gt;superior experience to the industry average&lt;/strong&gt; for intelligent cockpit features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-market-expectations-and-pe-logic&#34;&gt;3. Market Expectations and P/E Logic
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The capital market does not simply add an idealized or “easy” valuation when calculating Xiaomi’s market capitalization; instead, it:&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Xiaomi Valuation} = \text{(Smartphone + IoT + Internet) Business Mature P/E Valuation} + \text{EV Business **High-Growth Premium**}$$
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idealized/Easy Valuation:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to its relatively single business, the market primarily examines its &lt;strong&gt;short-term profitability and sales volume&lt;/strong&gt;, and valuations have shifted from high growth to more conservative $P/E$ or $P/S$ valuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi’s success with its electric vehicle (EV) business has convinced the market that Xiaomi can successfully enter the trillion-dollar new sector over the next ten years. Therefore, the market views Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s EV business as a &lt;strong&gt;brand new, high-growth entry point&lt;/strong&gt;, granting it a very high premium. &lt;strong&gt;This premium is for the “access to the track” and “ecosystem synergy value.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s EV business is not an isolated valuation project; it is a key milestone validating Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;platform strategy&amp;rdquo; success.&lt;/strong&gt; The achievement of this milestone has reshaped Xiaomi’s overall valuation logic, leading to a significant increase in its market capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituan&#34;&gt;Meituan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Encountering Meituan was entirely unexpected, fortunately, the available shares weren&amp;rsquo;t excessive. The statement that “Meituan can link everything” resonated deeply within me. It will undoubtedly be a rising star for Meituan’s stock price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When buying, there was no thought about why Meituan had fallen so much. We’ll wait to see the Q3 financial report and then decide. Selling off shares isn&amp;rsquo;t out of the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alibaba-the-origin-and-impact-analysis-of-recent-e-commerce-tax-policies-in-china&#34;&gt;Alibaba: The Origin and Impact Analysis of Recent E-commerce Tax Policies in China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s recent “e-commerce tax” primarily focuses on &lt;strong&gt;adjustments to the tax policy for cross-border e-commerce retail imports&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;the standardization of tax information reporting for domestic e-commerce platform enterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, which has had varying degrees of impact on different types of e-commerce and merchants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-e-commerce-tax-policy-evolution&#34;&gt;📜 E-commerce Tax Policy Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-cross-border-e-commerce-retail-import-tax-adjustment-e-commerce-tax&#34;&gt;1. Cross-Border E-commerce Retail Import Tax Adjustment (“E-Commerce” Tax)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily focuses on tax policies for goods purchased through overseas e-commerce platforms.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Policy (Mail Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Previously processed under “mail tax,” with tax exemption for amounts below 50 yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Policy (Comprehensive Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopts a “customs duty + VAT + consumption tax” comprehensive tax model. Within the personal transaction limits (e.g., currently 5,000 RMB per transaction and 26,000 RMB annually for individuals), customs duties are temporarily set at 0%, but VAT and consumption taxes are levied at 70% of the statutory taxable amount, and the tax exemption benefit below 50 yuan has been cancelled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; This has resulted in many previously low-priced goods (such as baby products, food, and health supplements) needing to pay an additional approximately 11.9% VAT (17% x 70%) due to the cancellation of the tax exemption benefit, &lt;strong&gt;leading to a general increase in the prices of e-commerce goods and accelerating industry compliance and consolidation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-domestic-e-commerce-tax-reporting-and-enhanced-compliance-supervision&#34;&gt;2. Domestic E-commerce Tax Reporting and Enhanced Compliance Supervision
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background &amp;amp; Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; With the implementation of the &lt;em&gt;E-Commerce Law&lt;/em&gt; and the recent issuance of regulations such as the &lt;em&gt;Internet Platform Enterprise Tax Information Reporting Provisions&lt;/em&gt;, tax authorities have increased their regulatory scrutiny of merchants on e-commerce platforms (particularly C2C individual sellers).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; Platforms are now required to report merchants’ sales revenue and other information. This has made it impossible for past business models that evaded taxes through concealing income and using private accounts for payments to continue, &lt;strong&gt;ushering in a phase of ecological reshaping centered around compliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax Regulations:&lt;/strong&gt; Emphasize that e-commerce operators (including Taobao sellers and micro-merchants) &lt;strong&gt;must register as legal entities in accordance with the law and pay taxes&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring they start on an equal footing with other brick-and-mortar businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, standardized tax policies have had a complex impact on the &lt;strong&gt;platform business&lt;/strong&gt; of Alibaba and JD.com, but a generally positive long-term impact on &lt;strong&gt;their self-operated or B2C businesses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Taobao/C2C)&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Challenges &amp;amp; Consolidation&lt;/strong&gt; | In the past, many unregistered and untaxed individual sellers existed on platforms like Taobao. Compliance requirements will &lt;strong&gt;weed out unprofitable or unwilling-to-comply small merchants&lt;/strong&gt;, which may lead to a reduction in platform merchant numbers and a decrease in product price advantages in the short term. However, in the long run, it will improve the &lt;strong&gt;overall compliance, quality, and consumer trust of products and services&lt;/strong&gt; on the platform. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-1&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Tmall/B2C) &amp;amp; JD.com (Self-operated/B2C)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive for Compliant Businesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most merchants on Tmall and JD.com, especially B2C companies and self-operated businesses, &lt;strong&gt;are already regular tax payers&lt;/strong&gt; (general taxpayers). The new regulatory policies have eliminated the price advantage gained by small merchants who previously exploited tax evasion, creating a more &lt;strong&gt;fair competitive environment&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a &lt;strong&gt;long-term positive&lt;/strong&gt; for large, compliant platforms and B2C retailers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-2&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-border E-commerce Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rising Costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The cross-border e-commerce tax reform has led to increased prices for “haotai” (imported) goods, which may affect the sales and growth rate of this business segment. However, the industry is generally moving towards &lt;strong&gt;standardization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact on Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-some-merchants-experiencing-losses-or-unprofitability&#34;&gt;📉 Impact on Some Merchants Experiencing Losses or Unprofitability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You mentioned that some stores were experiencing losses and unprofitability after paying taxes, and this phenomenon is a &lt;strong&gt;necessary result of the compliance process&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily concentrated in the following categories of merchants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Originally Relying on Tax Evasion to Achieve “Price Advantages”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These merchants passed on tax costs to consumers, resulting in product prices lower than those of brick-and-mortar stores. Once required to comply with legal taxation, their cost structure changed, eliminating price advantages, and &lt;strong&gt;if products and services lack core competitiveness, they will naturally be eliminated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Meeting Small Microenterprise Standards (But Not Receiving Preferential Treatment):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to China’s current tax policies, there are VAT exemptions for &lt;strong&gt;small-scale taxpayers&lt;/strong&gt; (such as quarterly sales revenue not exceeding 300,000 yuan exempt from VAT). &lt;strong&gt;Currently, over nine out of ten operators on the platform are small and microenterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, and under existing preferential policy support, &lt;strong&gt;they pay little or no tax.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; This may be due to a lack of understanding of policies, or although they meet eligibility criteria but have not previously conducted compliant reporting and enjoyed benefits. Now that they are required to “comply with reporting,” they need to re-examine their taxes, but if sales volume is inherently low, tax liability should remain low or be exempt after compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants with Extremely Low Profit Margins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some cross-border e-commerce merchants or domestic merchants may have an average profit margin of only &lt;strong&gt;around 10%&lt;/strong&gt;. After adding the new tax costs (whether cross-border taxes or domestic VAT), if they cannot raise prices or optimize supply chains to absorb them, they could indeed transition from profitability to losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion is:&lt;/strong&gt; E-commerce taxation compliance is not “one-size-fits-all” that burdens all businesses. It primarily targets &lt;strong&gt;tax evasion and tax leakage behaviors&lt;/strong&gt;. For merchants who were originally compliant or eligible for small microenterprise benefits, the tax level remains unchanged or very low. For those whose survival space depends on non-compliance and whose profit margins rely on tax evasion, &lt;strong&gt;being eliminated is an inevitable step in the industry’s move towards fair competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
