<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Self-Awareness on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/self-awareness/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Self-Awareness on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:37:51 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/self-awareness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Sometimes you need to learn how to interrupt.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 13:14:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/sometimes-you-need-to-learn-how-to-interrupt/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone has their own life trajectory, so the concept of “being a good teacher” often seems superfluous in adult circles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;worldview&#34;&gt;Worldview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Our life’s journey begins with vastly different formative experiences, these experiences converging and flowing like rivers to ultimately shape our unique life paths. Each story, each choice, weaves together and merges within our minds, solidifying into our perception of the world – our &lt;strong&gt;worldview&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What you&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed as tragedy may be merely a story in a book to another person. What you disdain as a lifestyle may be precisely the ideal someone else desperately pursues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding and respecting each other’s differences is the first step in comprehending this diverse world. Sometimes, &lt;strong&gt;remaining silent is also a form of understanding&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I prefer to share my experiences and insights rather than engage in empty chatter. However, inevitably, you will encounter moments where observing the slow flow of water is a worthwhile strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-philosophy&#34;&gt;Investment Philosophy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My choice of &lt;strong&gt;fixed income plus&lt;/strong&gt; as the primary investment approach is driven by its emphasis on &lt;strong&gt;stable returns&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;low risk&lt;/strong&gt;. Therefore, I will allocate a significant portion of my asset allocation to this type of product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding stocks, I differentiate between short-term and long-term investments. In my view, &lt;strong&gt;short-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; carries a strong speculative nature, resembling more of a &lt;strong&gt;gambit&lt;/strong&gt;; while &lt;strong&gt;long-term investing&lt;/strong&gt; is genuine &lt;strong&gt;value investing&lt;/strong&gt;. It’s like founding your own company, from fundraising to IPO – you not only reap stock dividends but also gain a profound understanding of economic laws and foresight for the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve recognized since childhood that I have a &lt;strong&gt;gambling addiction&lt;/strong&gt;, however, studying allows me to rationally control my irrational desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of digital currencies is something I generally dislike from an investment perspective – I haven’t found any real value, but we need to understand its principles and risks. There have previously been articles discussing stablecoins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-eggs&#34;&gt;Easter Eggs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;WeChat can fold group chats, and &lt;strong&gt;your private conversations with friends can also be folded&lt;/strong&gt;, from a design perspective, all conversations belong to the same level and are only differentiated in display.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
