<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mirror-Proxy on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/mirror-proxy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mirror-Proxy on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/mirror-proxy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Docker domestic image proxy failure</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/docker-domestic-mirror-failure/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jan 2025 18:29:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/docker-domestic-mirror-failure/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Deploying Docker on domestic servers. If the company doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide an image registry, developers must first configure a domestic mirror acceleration address. Today, I configured a mirror acceleration address on a server, but it consistently fails to pull images.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error message:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;troubleshooting-and-repair-attempts&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting and Repair Attempts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, I attempted to switch to an alternative mirror address hoping to resolve the issue, but it proved ineffective; the problem persists&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Immediately, I began modifying the local DNS configuration, attempting to find a breakthrough at the network resolution level; unfortunately, after some debugging, the fault persisted&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The local network&amp;rsquo;s stability is now questionable, so I switched to my phone’s hotspot to bypass potential issues. However, the problem persists unchanged – a frustrating result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;problems-spreading&#34;&gt;Problems spreading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We have several servers available, all with Docker environments installed. Attempting to pull images from them proved unsuccessful; the error messages were identical across all devices, indicating a systemic issue rather than a problem with a single server.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further investigation revealed that the mirror proxy appeared to have failed instantly. Switching quickly to an overseas machine proved successful, and thankfully, image pulling resumed normally. This suggests the issue likely lies within the domestic network link or related configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strategic-adjustment-circumventing-solutions&#34;&gt;Strategic adjustment: Circumventing solutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To overcome obstacles in accessing domestic images, and with foreign mirrors accessible, we&amp;rsquo;ve decided on a workaround to expedite project progress. We will first switch to a foreign server to pull the necessary images, then push them to a domestic mirror repository, effectively creating a &amp;ldquo;data bridge.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the Dockerfile was modified to replace the image address with one suitable for domestic environments, and the image was rebuilt and successfully deployed&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
