<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Digital Currency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/digital-currency/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Digital Currency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:18:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/digital-currency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Over-the-Counter (OTC) Clearing and Settlement of Digital Currencies: Unveiling the Mechanisms Behind 7x24 Continuous Trading</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:03:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional stock markets with defined opening and closing times, the digital currency market has attracted the attention of global investors due to its 7x24-hour continuous trading feature. This characteristic has also raised a core question: how are digital currencies cleared and settled in a world without a “market close” concept? Does it completely overturn these concepts in traditional finance? The answer is that digital currencies not only have clearing and settlement, but the way they are implemented and their system design are key to supporting all-day trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-difference-from-t2-to-real-time-settlement&#34;&gt;Core Difference: From T+2 to Real-Time Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional stock trading follows a “T+N” settlement system (e.g., T+1 in China, T+2 in the US), meaning that the actual transfer of funds and securities after a trade is executed (on day T) takes one or more business days to complete. During this period, clearing agencies conduct offsetting, calculate the receivables and payables of each party, and settle differences.
Digital currencies have completely changed this model. Its core settlement and delivery can be summarized as &lt;strong&gt;“Trade-to-Clear, Clear-to-Deliver,”&lt;/strong&gt; primarily due to its underlying blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-a-natural-real-time-full-settlement-system&#34;&gt;Blockchain: A Natural Real-Time Full Settlement System
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockchain itself can be considered a decentralized, immutable public ledger. Each transaction is recorded in a “block” and linked to the previous block through cryptographic methods, forming an irreversible “chain.” This process has the following key characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a transaction is validated by nodes on the network and packaged into a block, the transfer of assets is completed. Although confirmation times vary depending on the congestion and block generation speed of different blockchain networks (such as Bitcoin and Ethereum), ranging from seconds to several minutes, this is a qualitative leap compared to traditional finance’s “T+N.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike net settlement in traditional clearing systems, each transaction on the blockchain is independent and fully executed. When A transfers a bitcoin to B, it is clearly recorded in the ledger as A&amp;rsquo;s address decreasing by one and B&amp;rsquo;s address increasing by one, without any netting of multiple transactions before transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finality:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a block has been confirmed by enough subsequent blocks, this transaction is considered “final” and irreversible. This means that once settled, no one can undo or modify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, fundamentally, &lt;strong&gt;asset settlement occurs on the blockchain, automatically completed through network consensus, without the need for traditional central clearing counterparties (CCPs) or custodians.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-vs-decentralized-exchanges-different-clearing-and-settlement-pathways&#34;&gt;Centralized vs. Decentralized Exchanges: Different Clearing and Settlement Pathways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the underlying technology is decentralized, the primary venues where users conduct digital currency transactions – exchanges – are divided into two types: centralized (CEX) and decentralized (DEX), which have different clearing and settlement mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;centralized-exchanges-cex-internal-clearing--on-chain-settlement&#34;&gt;Centralized Exchanges (CEX): Internal Clearing + On-Chain Settlement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When users trade on centralized exchanges like Binance and Coinbase, they are actually operating within the exchange’s internal centralized ledger, rather than directly on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Clearing (Ledgering):&lt;/strong&gt; When users deposit digital currencies or fiat currency into an exchange, the exchange records corresponding balances in its database for the user&amp;rsquo;s account. All buy and sell actions a user takes on the platform, such as buying BTC with USDT, essentially just represents increases and decreases in numbers within different accounts in the exchange’s database. This process is completed quickly by the exchange’s &lt;strong&gt;“matching engine,”&lt;/strong&gt; which can be considered a real-time internal clearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Settlement (Withdrawal/Deposit):&lt;/strong&gt; The actual settlement that occurs on the blockchain only happens when users &lt;strong&gt;“deposit”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer from an external wallet into the exchange) and &lt;strong&gt;“withdraw”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer out of the exchange to an external wallet). At this point, the exchange initiates a chain transaction to truly transfer asset ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Performance Matching Engine:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures rapid order matching under high concurrency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold &amp;amp; Hot Wallet Separation:&lt;/strong&gt; Most user assets are stored in offline “cold wallets” to ensure security, while a small amount of assets is kept in online “hot wallets” to meet users’ daily withdrawal needs. This is the core design for ensuring 7x24 hours of asset safety operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Ledger Database:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizes a high-performance distributed database to ensure the accuracy and immediacy of internal transaction records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralized-exchanges-dexs-on-chain-atomic-swaps&#34;&gt;Decentralized Exchanges (DEXs): On-Chain Atomic Swaps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In decentralized exchanges like Uniswap and SushiSwap, the trading process is radically different. Users always maintain control over their own wallet private keys, and transactions are executed directly on-chain through “smart contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic Swap:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the core of how DEXs clear and settle trades. A smart contract is a program that automatically executes on a blockchain, ensuring that the exchange of assets is &amp;ldquo;atomic&amp;rdquo;—either both parties successfully exchange their assets, or neither does—preventing one party from sending assets without receiving confirmation from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing and Settlement Synchronized:&lt;/strong&gt; Users authorize interactions with smart contracts through their wallets. Once a transaction is triggered and confirmed on the blockchain, clearing and settlement are instantly completed in a single step. The entire process requires no trust in any centralized intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts:&lt;/strong&gt; The core logic of the exchange, including trading pairs, liquidity pools, and pricing algorithms (such as Automated Market Makers - AMMs) are all hardcoded into the smart contract, making them public and transparent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Oracles:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to securely feed external market price information onto the blockchain, providing price references for certain types of DEXs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a web or app interface that allows users to connect their wallets and interact with the backend smart contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-the-new-paradigm-for-digital-currency-clearing-and-settlement&#34;&gt;Summary: The New Paradigm for Digital Currency Clearing and Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In essence, digital currencies are not without the concepts of clearing and settlement; rather, they have transformed from a multi-party, time-consuming back-office process into an efficient, transparent, and even real-time automated one through blockchain technology and innovative system designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing Concepts Remain:&lt;/strong&gt; This is evident in CEXs as real-time matching and ledger accounting, and in DEXs, smart contracts incorporate clearing rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement is the Core Transformation:&lt;/strong&gt; Finality of settlement is guaranteed by blockchain consensus, enabling near real-time asset transfers – a cornerstone supporting 7x24 uninterrupted trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Serves Uninterrupted Operation:&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s CEX cold and hot wallet architectures or DEX automated smart contracts, the primary design objective is to achieve a transaction environment without manual intervention and never closed, while ensuring security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This disruptive clearing and settlement mechanism is not only a significant distinguishing feature of digital currency markets compared to traditional finance but also provides important insights into the future evolution of financial infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Digital Currency Fundamentals</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/digital-currency-fundamentals/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/digital-currency-fundamentals/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We use an easy-to-understand analogy to explain the relationship between digital currency “mining” and “accounting,” as well as why Bitcoin and Ethereum have different supply caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s use an easy-to-understand analogy to explain the relationship between digital currency “mining” and “accounting,” as well as why Bitcoin and Ethereum have different supply caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mining-and-accounting-a-public-participation-ledger-competition&#34;&gt;Mining and Accounting: A Public Participation Ledger Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the entire Bitcoin network as a massive, public, and transparent electronic ledger. Every Bitcoin transaction (such as Zhang San sending a Bitcoin to Li Si) that occurs anywhere in the world needs to be recorded onto this large ledger for the transaction to be considered successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who records these transactions? If anyone could just write them down arbitrarily, it would become chaotic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, the Bitcoin system has designed an ongoing “accounting competition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accounting (Bookkeeping)&lt;/strong&gt;: This involves bundling all transactions that have occurred in the past approximately 10 minutes into a &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo; (which can be understood as a page of the ledger). This block not only includes transaction records but also contains a link to the previous &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo; (the previous page of the ledger), linking one page after another to form an immutable chain, which is called “blockchain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mining&lt;/strong&gt;: The core issue is: who has the right to record this page? The answer is: whoever first solves an extremely complex mathematical problem gets the accounting rights for that time. This solving process is形象地称为“mining”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it called &amp;ldquo;Mining&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt; Because this process requires a large amount of computing resources (mining machines) and energy (power), just like real-world mining requires equipment and labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the purpose of solving the problem?&lt;/strong&gt; This mathematical problem itself has no practical meaning; its sole purpose is to increase the difficulty of accounting, ensuring that an average person (or a mining pool) can solve it approximately every 10 minutes. This guarantees stable ledger update speed and ensures system security. Anyone who wants to tamper with the ledger must have twice the computing power of the entire network, which is practically impossible economically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore, the relationship between mining and accounting can be summarized as:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Mining” is the process of competing for “accounting rights,” while “Accounting” is the reward and responsibility after successfully “mining.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mining-and-accounting-a-public-participation-ledger-competition-1&#34;&gt;Mining and Accounting: A Public Participation Ledger Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Successful “miners” who successfully mine a block will perform two tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package the latest transactions into a new block and connect it to the blockchain (completing the accounting).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receive rewards granted by the system.&lt;/strong&gt; This reward consists of two parts:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block Reward:&lt;/strong&gt; The system automatically generates a batch of newly created Bitcoins as a reward. This is the only way that new Bitcoin is created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction Fees:&lt;/strong&gt; The fees paid by the payers of all transactions within the block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-does-bitcoin-have-a-cap-while-ethereum-doesnt&#34;&gt;Why Does Bitcoin Have a Cap, While Ethereum Doesn&amp;rsquo;t?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This involves fundamental differences in the design philosophy and objectives of these two cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitcoin-digital-gold-limited-supply&#34;&gt;Bitcoin: Digital Gold, Limited Supply
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was designed from the outset to be a &lt;strong&gt;value storage&lt;/strong&gt; tool like gold. Gold is valuable for one key reason: its scarcity – the amount on Earth is finite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mimic this scarcity, Satoshi Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin, established two immutable rules during design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Supply:&lt;/strong&gt; The total supply of Bitcoin is permanently limited to &lt;strong&gt;21 million coins&lt;/strong&gt;. Not a fraction more, not a fraction less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halving Production:&lt;/strong&gt; Approximately every four years (or with every 210,000 blocks mined), the block reward earned by miners will be reduced in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2009 began at 50 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 halving to 25 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 halving to 12.5 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 halving to 6.25 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024 halving to 3.125 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…and so on, until approximately 2140, when the new reward will approach zero indefinitely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design gives Bitcoin &lt;strong&gt;deflationary&lt;/strong&gt; characteristics. Over time, the output of new coins decreases, and if demand remains constant or increases, its value theoretically rises. This reinforces its positioning as “digital gold.” Once all bitcoins have been mined, miners’ income will depend entirely on transaction fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ethereum-decentralized-application-platform-more-flexible-supply-strategy&#34;&gt;Ethereum: Decentralized Application Platform, More Flexible Supply Strategy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ethereum’s goals differ from Bitcoin. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a digital currency; it’s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;world computer,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; a platform designed to run smart contracts and decentralized applications (DApps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine Ethereum as a decentralized “app store” and “operating system.” Within this system, you need to pay “gas fees” to run your programs or make transactions, and this gas is Ether (ETH).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maintain this vast and complex system, Ethereum continuously incentivizes miners (now validators) to protect the network’s security. If a hard cap were set like Bitcoin’s, with no new coins being mined after it&amp;rsquo;s finished, whether transaction fees alone would be sufficient to guarantee the network’s long-term security is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Ethereum chose a &lt;strong&gt;no-hard-cap&lt;/strong&gt; strategy. However, this doesn’t mean it will experience unlimited inflation. Ethereum’s monetary policy has undergone several significant adjustments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early (Proof-of-Work PoW)&lt;/strong&gt;: Similar to Bitcoin, new coins were generated through mining, but there was no fixed total limit or set halving cycle. This resulted in a relatively high inflation rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Upgrade (EIP-1559)&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduced an “burn fee” mechanism. A portion of the base fees paid by users for transactions would be directly “burned” (permanently removed from circulation) instead of going to miners. This meant that when the network was active with transactions, the amount of ETH burned could exceed the newly issued amount, leading to &lt;strong&gt;deflation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Merge (The Merge)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ethereum transitioned from “mining” (Proof-of-Work PoW) to “staking” (Proof-of-Stake PoS). No longer do miners expend electricity solving problems; instead, “validators” earn accounting rights and rewards by staking their own ETH. This shift &lt;strong&gt;significantly reduced the issuance rate of new ETH&lt;/strong&gt; (over 90%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary, here are Ethereum’s key characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Hard Cap&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides flexibility for the network&amp;rsquo;s long-term security and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Supply&lt;/strong&gt;: Through “burn mechanisms” and “staking rewards,” its total supply can be mildly inflationary or experience deflation during periods of high transaction activity. Its goal isn’t absolute scarcity, but rather to &lt;strong&gt;maintain sufficient security while ensuring ETH remains available as “fuel.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Digital Gold, Value Storage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;World Computer, Decentralized Application Platform&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-1&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Supply Limit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, 21 Million coins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-2&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin (BTC)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum (ETH)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monetary Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deflationary (Fixed supply, halving production)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dynamic Supply (Minting + Burning, potentially inflationary or deflationary)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-3&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issuance Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reward miners until the block is mined&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Long-term, continuous security and operation of the network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-4&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this straightforward explanation will help you understand their relationship and differences!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is a Stablecoin?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-is-a-stablecoin/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 23:43:19 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-is-a-stablecoin/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins have already gained legal status in the United States and Hong Kong. This allows for more efficient capital flows globally, and gray areas are bound to exist if not regulated – similar to how the US manages opioid addiction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins are crypto assets pegged to fiat currencies (such as the US dollar or Hong Kong dollar) or precious metals, designed to maintain their value stability. They are primarily divided into three categories: fiat-backed (such as USDT, USDC), commodity-backed (like stablecoins backed by gold reserves), and algorithmic (which do not rely on physical reserves but instead use algorithms to maintain their peg)([zh.wikipedia.org][1])&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-why-should-legislation-support-stablecoins&#34;&gt;🛠️ Why Should Legislation Support Stablecoins?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-enhance-payment-efficiency-and-reduce-costs&#34;&gt;1. &lt;strong&gt;Enhance Payment Efficiency and Reduce Costs&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stablecoins can provide instant, low-cost cross-border payment services, particularly in areas where banks are not covered. Their settlement speed is fast, fees are low, and they offer significant value for international trade and remittances ([ft.com][2]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-strengthening-the-internationalization-of-the-us-dollar--currency&#34;&gt;2. &lt;strong&gt;Strengthening the Internationalization of the US Dollar / Currency&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;From an American perspective, the rise of stablecoins can increase demand for short-term assets like U.S. Treasuries, thereby solidifying the dollar’s position and simultaneously driving financial innovation. The EU is also taking advantage of this opportunity to accelerate the launch of a digital euro.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-addressing-regulatory-gaps-and-mitigating-risks&#34;&gt;3. &lt;strong&gt;Addressing Regulatory Gaps and Mitigating Risks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Historically, stablecoins have largely operated in the “shadow financial” system, lacking transparency and plagued by market irregularities, even involving risks such as money laundering and fraud. The U.S. proposed STABLE Act and GENIUS Act require clear regulation, disclosure of reserves, and capital/liquidation rules to ensure financial security and investor protection ([morganlewis.com][3]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong, meanwhile, has begun implementing the “Stablecoins Ordinance” from August 2025, requiring stablecoin issuers to obtain a license from the Hong Kong Monetary Authority (HKMA) and meet standards for reserves, redemptions, and anti-money laundering (AML/CFT), as well as prohibiting unlicensed institutions from advertising promotions ([morganlewis.com][4]).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-do-stablecoin-companies-make-money&#34;&gt;How Do Stablecoin Companies Make Money?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interest Income on Reserve Assets&lt;/strong&gt;
For example, Circle’s USDC reserves are largely held in short-term US Treasury bonds, benefiting from current interest rates. In 2023, profits increased significantly, and approximately $5 billion in profit was projected for 2025 (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/eb588992-ece3-4254-b2ea-721a20bf1180?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  title=&#34;Lessons from a stablecoin IPO: tech turns on a dime&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ft.com&lt;/a&gt;) . Tether’s report showed earnings of $5.2 billion in the first half of 2024.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction Fees and Developer Tool Revenue&lt;/strong&gt;
In addition to minting/redemption fees, stablecoin platforms generate stable revenue by providing APIs, SDKs, settlement tools, etc., for DeFi, wallets, and corporate clients (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.marketwatch.com/story/stablecoin-supply-is-growing-fast-heres-how-it-compares-to-cash-66f12bc1?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  title=&#34;Stablecoin supply is growing fast. Here&amp;#39;s how it compares to cash.&#34;
     target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;marketwatch.com&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Expansion Services&lt;/strong&gt;
Some stablecoin issuers profit through additional products (such as interest redemption, investment features, corporate settlements, etc.), but this may lead to regulatory restrictions on “interest-bearing stablecoins.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;-summary&#34;&gt;✅ Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stablecoins&lt;/strong&gt; are payment tools designed to mitigate the volatility of cryptocurrencies, maintaining value through reserves or algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regulatory legislation&lt;/strong&gt; aims to promote compliance, protect consumers, maintain financial stability, and foster innovation and international competitiveness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revenue models&lt;/strong&gt; primarily derive from interest on reserve assets, fees, and value-added services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, if regulated effectively, stablecoins could play a significant role in global payment systems and compete with Central Bank Digital Currencies (CBDCs).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ft.com/content/b69f304c-798e-4dc3-9f17-6f7a7c8d3ac0?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;ft.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/ant-unit-plans-apply-stablecoin-issuer-license-hong-kong-2025-06-12/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.reuters.com/world/asia-pacific/hong-kong-passes-stablecoin-bill-one-step-closer-issuance-2025-05-21/?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;reuters.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://markets.businessinsider.com/news/currencies/stablecoins-becoming-mainstream-dollar-gold-stable-genius-act-2025-5?utm_source=chatgpt.com&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;markets.businessinsider.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
