<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Starting Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/starting-point/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Starting Point on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/starting-point/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Night Naming Technique</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character for “fate” or &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; (命) is unique, without a single homonym. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life is only lived once, irreplaceable and unrepeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flipping through the rankings on Qidian Chinese Network during my leisure time, &amp;ldquo;The Naming of Night&amp;rdquo; has an overwhelming lead in monthly votes, firmly holding the top spot and leaving a huge gap between it and second place – practically unattainable. In the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly read works by well-known authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Er Gen, but this time I decided to try out a new author and experience a different reading feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, &amp;ldquo;Naming Night&amp;rdquo; had reached two million monthly tickets, while the second-place novel only had eighty thousand, a staggering difference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;rsquo;m not well-versed enough to evaluate the writing of this book. However, after reading through more than a dozen chapters, the plot is tightly paced and intricately connected, captivating readers. It’s truly deserving of such high monthly votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that, just like the character for &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo; (命), the character for &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; (死) also has no homophones in Chinese. Does this perhaps imply that the end of life is equally unique and irreplaceable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
