<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Taiwan on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/taiwan/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Taiwan on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/taiwan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pelosi visits Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 22:57:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Without understanding politics or offering commentary, documenting this &amp;ldquo;carnival&amp;rdquo; on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random-thoughts&#34;&gt;Random thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The recent &lt;strong&gt;唐山打人事件&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;人教小学教材文化入侵事件&lt;/strong&gt;, I wonder how many still remember. These hot topics in the news have become numbing; there&amp;rsquo;s little feeling, just watching shows as usual after work, a mere spectacle. The economic situation is already like this—an outbreak of war won’t make things better. No political commentary, just recording this &amp;ldquo;celebration&amp;rdquo; online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-just-paste-the-text-here&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2022 visit by Nancy Pelosi to Taiwan, often referred to as Pelosi&amp;rsquo;s trip to Taiwan, was part of a larger tour of Asian countries undertaken by the then-Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives, Nancy Pelosi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese side strongly protested, dispatching naval destroyer formations to the northeast waters of the Taiwan Strait and mobilizing two carrier strike groups – Shandong and Liaoning – while the Eastern Theater Command and Southern Theater Command conducted large-scale live-fire exercises in the East China Sea and South China Sea respectively. The U.S. responded by deploying the Ronald Reagan Carrier Strike Group to the waters near Taiwan to protect a potential visit by Pelosi, and has also deployed multiple reconnaissance aircraft and aerial refueling tankers to Marine Corps Air Station Kadena in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden held a video conference prior to the visit, discussing the Taiwan issue. Reports indicate that Speaker Nancy Pelosi and a congressional delegation are expected to arrive at Taipei Songshan Airport on August 2nd, spend the night, and meet with Taiwanese President Tsai Ing-wen and other high-ranking government officials on August 3rd. Some observers believe Pelosi’s visit could trigger a new Taiwan Strait crisis, the first since the 1996 missile crisis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-11&#34;&gt;08-11
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s essentially settled now. Headlines have been dominated by naval exercises, and Zhihu has been working hard to update its trending topics daily—all about this subject. The editor appreciates the effort.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
