<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Taiwan on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/taiwan/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Taiwan on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/taiwan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pelosi visits Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 22:57:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not understanding politics, not making comments, just recording this &amp;ldquo;carnival&amp;rdquo; on the internet&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;random-thoughts&#34;&gt;Random thoughts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Tangshan beating incident and the elementary school textbook cultural invasion incident from a while ago, I wonder how many people still remember. These hot topics in the news have become numbing; there&amp;rsquo;s no much feeling, just watching dramas as usual after work, treating it like entertainment. The economic situation is already like this, and an outbreak of war won’t make things better. I don’t understand politics, and I won’t comment on it, just recording this &amp;ldquo;carnival&amp;rdquo; online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview-of-the-2022-sichuanyaan-earthquake&#34;&gt;Overview of the 2022 Sichuan–Ya’an earthquake
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The 2022 visit to Taiwan by Nancy Pelosi, often referred to as Pelosi&amp;rsquo;s visit to Taiwan, refers to the trip to Taiwan during a tour of Asian countries by Nancy Pelosi, the 52nd Speaker of the U.S. House of Representatives, in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the US House of Representatives Speaker being considered the third most powerful figure in the United States and planning a visit to Taiwan, with the date approaching China&amp;rsquo;s People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army Foundation Day on August 1st in the short term and the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, the 2022 US elections, and the 2022 local elections in Taiwan in the long term, the Chinese government has expressed strong protests. The People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army dispatched destroyer formations to the northeast waters of the Taiwan Strait and mobilized two carrier strike groups, Shandong and Liaoning. The Eastern Theater Command and Southern Theater Command conducted large-scale live-fire exercises in the East China Sea and South China Sea respectively. On the US side, the Ronald Reagan Carrier Strike Group has arrived near the Taiwan Strait to protect a possible visit by Pelosi, and multiple batches of reconnaissance aircraft and aerial refueling tankers have been deployed to the US military base at Kadena Air Force Base in Japan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden had a video conference before the visit, which involved the Taiwan issue. Taiwanese and international media reported that Speaker Nancy Pelosi and a congressional delegation are expected to arrive at Taipei Songshan Airport on August 2, spend the night there, and meet with Republic of China President Tsai Ing-wen and other high-ranking government officials on August 3. Some observers believe that Pelosi’s visit to Taiwan could trigger a new crisis in the Taiwan Strait, the first since the 1996 Taiwan Strait Missile Crisis over two decades ago.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-11&#34;&gt;08-11
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s basically settled today, and the headlines for this period have mostly been about various naval exercises. Zhihu has also been working hard, changing up the way they update the trending topics every day, all talking about this same thing. The editor worked hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
