<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>C# on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/c/</link>
        <description>Recent content in C# on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/c/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>WPF UI Thread Blocking Issues and Solutions</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wpf-ui-thread-and-freezing-solutions/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 07:12:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wpf-ui-thread-and-freezing-solutions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When developing desktop applications, particularly when using the Windows Presentation Foundation (WPF) framework to build rich client applications, properly handling the user interface (UI) thread is crucial for ensuring the application’s smoothness and responsiveness. The UI thread, also known as the main thread, is the core thread responsible for processing window and control events, layout calculations, and rendering the UI. Any interaction with UI elements should be executed on the UI thread; this is a fundamental principle followed by WPF and most other GUI frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-ui-thread&#34;&gt;What is the UI Thread?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The UI thread is created by the operating system when a WPF application starts and initializes the main application window. It’s the only thread within the application that can directly access and modify the state of UI components. This means all user interactions, such as button clicks, text box input, and window size changes, are processed in this thread context. Furthermore, WPF&amp;rsquo;s dependency property system, data binding mechanism, and layout logic are all synchronized on the UI thread.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;screen-stuttering-and-its-causes&#34;&gt;Screen Stuttering and Its Causes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When the UI thread is heavily occupied or blocked for an extended period, such as when performing time-consuming calculations, loading large amounts of data, database queries, or other I/O-intensive tasks, it becomes unable to promptly respond to user interaction requests. This results in the UI freezing – what we commonly refer to as &amp;ldquo;stuttering.&amp;rdquo; In this situation, users will noticeably feel the application&amp;rsquo;s lag and lack of fluidity, and in severe cases, an “Application Not Responding” (ANR) warning may appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-basic-rules-for-the-ui-thread&#34;&gt;Two Basic Rules for the UI Thread
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To avoid the above scenarios, WPF developers should adhere to the following two key rules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not perform time-consuming operations on the UI thread:&lt;/strong&gt; Any operation that could cause the UI thread to block should be moved to a background thread as much as possible to ensure the UI thread can promptly respond to user input and render screen changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Do not directly update UI elements from non-UI threads:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to WPF’s security mechanism design, only the UI thread has permission to modify UI elements. Attempting to change UI state directly from another thread will throw an exception. Therefore, even if a background thread completes calculations or data preparation, you must use appropriate cross-thread communication mechanisms to display the results on the UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions-asynchronous-programming-and-thread-safe-updates&#34;&gt;Solutions: Asynchronous Programming and Thread-Safe Updates
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To execute time-consuming tasks while maintaining UI fluency, WPF provides various asynchronous programming models and tools to assist developers in achieving this goal:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dispatcher Object:&lt;/strong&gt; The WPF Dispatcher class allows you to schedule work items into the UI thread&amp;rsquo;s task queue for execution. You can use the &lt;code&gt;Dispatcher.Invoke&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Dispatcher.BeginInvoke&lt;/code&gt; methods to safely update the UI from a background thread.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;async/await Keywords:&lt;/strong&gt; Leveraging C#’s asynchronous features, you can write asynchronous methods and utilize the &lt;code&gt;await&lt;/code&gt; keyword within them to wait for background tasks to complete, automatically returning to the UI thread to execute subsequent UI update code upon completion.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-studies&#34;&gt;Case Studies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;updating-the-ui-using-dispatcherinvoke-method&#34;&gt;Updating the UI using &lt;code&gt;Dispatcher.Invoke&lt;/code&gt; method
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-csharp&#34;&gt;private void Button_Click(object sender, RoutedEventArgs e)
{
    // Assume this is a time-consuming operation
    Task.Run(() =&amp;gt;
    {
        var result = LongRunningOperation(); // This is a simulated long-running calculation method
        
        // When the time-consuming operation is complete, update the UI on the UI thread
        Application.Current.Dispatcher.Invoke(() =&amp;gt;
        {
            LabelStatus.Text = $&amp;quot;Calculation Result: {result}&amp;quot;;
        });
    });
}

private string LongRunningOperation()
{
    // Simulate a long-running operation
    Thread.Sleep(5000);
    return &amp;quot;Completed&amp;quot;;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-the-asyncawait-keyword-with-taskrun&#34;&gt;Using the &lt;code&gt;async/await&lt;/code&gt; keyword with &lt;code&gt;Task.Run&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-csharp&#34;&gt;private async void Button_ClickAsync(object sender, RoutedEventArgs e)
{
    Button button = sender as Button;
    button.IsEnabled = false; // Prevent duplicate clicks by the user

    try
    {
        // Start a background task
        var result = await Task.Run(() =&amp;gt; LongRunningOperation());

        // Automatically switch back to the UI thread to update the UI after the background task completes
        LabelStatus.Text = $&amp;quot;Calculation Result: {result}&amp;quot;;
    }
    catch (Exception ex)
    {
        MessageBox.Show($&amp;quot;An error occurred: {ex.Message}&amp;quot;);
    }
    finally
    {
        button.IsEnabled = true; // Re-enable the button
    }
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
