<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Family on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/family/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Family on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/family/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>From Games to Family: Why We Gradually Disconnect from Virtual Worlds as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking about when gaming is most enjoyable, is it sneaking away as a child to play Tank Battle, Super Mario, and Contra on the family TV, or secretly playing Age of Empires with my cousin on the family computer, or perhaps later in college, playing games like Devil May Cry and League of Legends with my roommates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you were a child, free from life&amp;rsquo;s worries, when you played, you really put your whole heart into it – that sense of immersion is something you can never find again as an adult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As times change and society progresses, we who were once active in the virtual world are gradually realizing that the gaming platform, once full of joy and competition, seems to be drifting away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players gradually moving on, is not only due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves, but also because of a shift in the center of our lives. As we grow older, we become busy with marriage and having children, and the main focus of life gradually shifts from personal entertainment to family responsibilities. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the deeper reasons behind this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many people&amp;rsquo;s youth, games were more than just entertainment; they were a way to socialize. A popular online multiplayer game not only provided in-game challenges and competition but also connected players from all over the world, building virtual social circles. In that era, playing dungeons and team PKing with friends was part of life. Those late-night voice chats and sharing daily experiences became part of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as time passed, more and more players discovered that this virtual social experience didn&amp;rsquo;t have lasting appeal. With game updates and the diversification of social platforms, players gradually found more ways to interact outside of games. Friends made in games slowly disappeared from our lives, and many connections once active within the games were silently severed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;games-and-responsibility-a-shift-in-lifes-focus-after-adulthood&#34;&gt;Games and Responsibility: A Shift in Life&amp;rsquo;s Focus After Adulthood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering adulthood, the responsibilities in life gradually increase. Many young people once invested a lot of time in games, but with the start of their careers or living together with partners and starting families, these previously seemingly essential leisure activities begin to be squeezed by the responsibilities of real life. Marriage, having children, or even caring for parents – these major responsibilities in life force people to make choices about energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming has become a thing of the past, replaced by the prioritization of family life. Many young people who once &amp;ldquo;struggled&amp;rdquo; in games are gradually realizing that real-life is the most important subject. Especially after having children, the center of gravity in their lives completely shifts towards family, and gaming is gradually squeezed to the periphery of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-family-how-changes-in-life-affect-our-entertainment-habits&#34;&gt;From Games to Family: How Changes in Life Affect Our Entertainment Habits
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our life experiences, family is one of the most important components. Once we enter family life, the allocation of time and energy becomes more specific and limited. To take care of children and spend time with their partners, many young parents find that they no longer have enough time to focus on the games they once loved. Sometimes, they even stop pursuing game updates and new features. Gradually, social platforms and offline interactions with friends and family become the preferred choice for socializing for more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we’ve completely abandoned entertainment, but rather chosen ways that are more suitable for our current life stage. Many friends who used to maintain connections through games may now choose other ways to stay in touch due to different life paths, such as family gatherings, meals together, and short trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;farewell-to-the-virtual-world-how-do-we-view-this-transition&#34;&gt;Farewell to the virtual world: How do we view this transition?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who once immersed themselves in gaming, saying goodbye to game-related social interactions isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. After all, that virtual world that once brought us joy and a sense of accomplishment has long become part of our memories. However, farewell doesn’t mean severing ties completely; instead, as life changes, we begin to make different choices to balance our roles in real life. As we grow older, we transition from inexperienced youths into responsible adults, and while gaming still holds value, it can no longer be the main theme of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this shift also reflects an aspect of human adaptability—our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle according to different stages. When responsibility and family become the core of life, gaming socialization is no longer a priority but rather a form of occasional leisure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-gaming-perhaps-it-will-usher-in-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;The future of gaming: perhaps it will usher in another wave of &amp;ldquo;sense of belonging.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, with social development and technological advancements, the forms and content of games are also constantly evolving. For example, current online multiplayer games have begun to move towards more relaxed and flexible approaches, and some even emphasize family interaction and parent-child relationships in their design. In the future, we may see more game formats that better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people still feel nostalgia and passion when talking about &amp;ldquo;childhood games,&amp;rdquo; perhaps in the future, we too may unexpectedly pick up those old games again, entering that virtual world once more with new understanding and insights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-is-changing-but-love-remains&#34;&gt;Life is changing, but love remains
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s games or family, the changes in life always accompany our growth. In this process, we gradually realize that although the virtual world brings us endless joy and excitement, ultimately, we return to reality, to that warmest place – family. We don’t need to regret leaving games behind, because every stage of life has its own unique meaning. And these changes are precisely what make us become more complete individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
