<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Hkex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/hkex/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Hkex on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/hkex/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hong Kong Exchange, History of Virtual Currency Development</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Binance again elected as US President, also bringing virtual currencies back into the public eye. The Hong Kong Exchange has been actively deploying related business, here’s a simple record of the Hong Kong Exchange&amp;rsquo;s virtual currency development history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the details of relevant contract lists, we found that the initial introduction wasn’t spot contracts but futures – which is reasonable, as futures markets have better liquidity and are easier to attract institutional investors. The subsequent introduction of spot ETFs was also reasonable, as ETFs are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-currency-list&#34;&gt;Virtual Currency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange’s market data does not provide identifiers to distinguish between contracts that are virtual currencies. However, they can be determined by the contract name. The official trading list provides corresponding subcategories &lt;code&gt;virtualasset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-stock-exchange-welcomes-the-first-batch-of-crypto-asset-etfs-listed-in-asia&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Stock Exchange Welcomes the First Batch of Crypto Asset ETFs Listed in Asia
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (Hong Kong Stock Exchange) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of the first batch of crypto asset ETFs listed in Asia, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for investors in Hong Kong and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two new ETFs listed today – Southern East One Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Southern East One Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) – are managed by Southern East One Asset Management Co., Ltd., and track standardized, cash-settled bitcoin futures contracts and ether futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The two crypto asset ETFs listed today add another layer of richness and diversity to Hong Kong’s increasingly vibrant exchange trading product ecosystem,” said Mr. Yao Jia Ren, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Market Linkage at the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. These new products will provide investors with the opportunity to participate in digital asset investments for the first time in Asia, and reflect our focus on the digital economy and market demand. “We look forward to bringing more thematic ETFs and new digital assets products in the coming months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETF is one of Hong Kong Exchange’s fastest-growing business areas, and its product range has continued to expand and diversify in 2022, including the launch of the first metaverse ETF, the first carbon futures ETF, and the first blockchain ETF, as well as the first time incorporating ETFs into the Hong Kong–Shenzhen–Guangzhou (HSG) Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-exchange-and-clearing-hkex-welcomes-the-first-batch-of-crypto-asset-etfs-listed-in-asia&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing (HKEX) Welcomes the First Batch of Crypto Asset ETFs Listed in Asia
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, HKEX’s exchange-traded products (ETPs – including ETFs and leveraged and inverse products) saw an average daily trading volume of HK$118 billion in the first ten months of this year, a 50% increase from HK$78 billion in the same period last year. This reflects the growing popularity of ETPs among investors. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on HKEX with a total market capitalization of HK$3,735 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-batch-of-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes the Listing of the First Batch of Spot Virtual Asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (Hong Kong Exchange) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs, adding to the variety of products in the Hong Kong market and providing investors with more choices, further solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Robert Lin, Head of Securities Product Development at the Hong Kong Exchange, “The newly listed spot virtual asset ETFs will enrich the diversified and dynamic ETF market ecosystem of the Hong Kong Exchange, offering investors new investment opportunities in asset classes. Following the successful launch of virtual asset futures ETFs a year ago, Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs will further enhance the product variety and liquidity traded by the Hong Kong Exchange. We look forward to continuing to work closely with stakeholders in the market to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.” “The first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs listed in 2022 were highly favored by investors, with robust trading volumes. The average daily trading volume of the three virtual asset futures ETFs listed on the Hong Kong Exchange increased from HK$890 million in 2023 to HK$5.13 billion in the first quarter of 2024, while attracting HK$5.29 billion in inflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchange-traded products (ETFs, leveraged and inverse products included) are one of the fastest-growing markets at the Hong Kong Exchange, with the number of product types continuously increasing over the past year. The 16 new ETF products launched in 2023 and the first quarter of 2024 include the first APAC-listed Saudi Arabian ETF and the first batch of callable options ETFs in Hong Kong. Currently, there are 179 ETFs listed on the Hong Kong Exchange.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (Hong Kong Exchange) announced today (Monday) that it will launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series (the Index Series) on November 15, 2024, providing a reliable benchmark price for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong’s development as a leading digital asset hub in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will provide transparent and reliable benchmarks for the pricing of Bitcoin and Ethereum within the Asian time zone, aiming to offer a unified reference price for virtual assets and address price discrepancies between this asset class across global exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Group Chairman Chen Yiting said: “We are delighted to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series to meet the demand for this rapidly growing asset class in the region.” “By providing transparent and reliable real-time benchmarks, we aim to help investors make informed investment decisions, thereby supporting the healthy development of the virtual asset ecosystem and consolidating Hong Kong’s position as an international financial center.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this index series is part of the Hong Kong Exchange’s commitment to exploring emerging areas. It supports the development of Hong Kong Fintech while also providing investors with important benchmarks and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment.
The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series-1&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benchmark index will be based on the 24-hour weighted average spot prices of Bitcoin and Ethereum, calculated according to the aggregated market prices from major virtual asset exchanges. The index will be denominated in US dollars in real time. The reference rate is designed for financial product settlement and is calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will be the first compliant virtual asset index series in Hong Kong that meets European Union Benchmark Regulation (EUBMR) standards, managed and calculated jointly by a benchmark management company registered in the UK and virtual asset data and index provider CCData.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region issued a policy statement on the development of virtual assets, aiming to cultivate a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Assets Index Series will provide public access to real-time data and daily reference prices in Asian time zones, helping to increase understanding of trends in virtual asset investment. More details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be released as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange Interface Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent five years developing financial software, I’ve become most familiar with various exchange APIs. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly well-versed in the Hong Kong Exchange documentation, and recently while handling some aspects of the Zhongtong business, I also reviewed materials from the Shanghai Stock Exchange (SSE) and Shenzhen Stock Exchange (SZSE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Trading-Hour,-Trading-and-Settlement-Calendar?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Hours, Trading and Settlement Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Mechanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/hkex-market/mutual-market/stock-connect/reference-materials/resources/glossary_c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong-Mainland China Financial Terminology Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_pdf_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_csv_c.csv&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar CSV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-1&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;glossary_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Financial Glossary PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/vcm/vcmtriggersecurity_c.aspx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Brokerage Trigger Cooling Period Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/services/trading/securities/securitieslists/ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Closing-Auction-Session-%28CAS%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Closing Auction Session (CAS) Securities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-2&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Volatility-Control-Mechanism-%28VCM%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Volatility Control Mechanism (VCM) Securities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Designated-Securities-Eligible-for-Short-Selling?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Designated Securities Eligible for Short Selling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34; &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###行情 Interface Documentation: H Shares + China Fortune Securities
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Interface Documentation Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;
Frequently Asked Questions, Guidance on Development Manuals, Historical Interface Documentation can be obtained by downloading through the search bar by searching for historical version numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/HKEX-Orion-Market-Data-Platform-Securities-Market-OMD-C?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;H Shares Securities Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Technical-Documents/OMD_CC-Specifications?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;China Fortune Securities Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-fortune-securities&#34;&gt;Trading Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Fortune Securities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-conchoneship&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Conchoneship
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-fortune-huachutong&#34;&gt;Trading Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Fortune (HuaChuTong)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Interface Documentation Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Dual Pricing Agreement Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Reason_Text_List.xlsx&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Exchange Error Code List XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Fortune FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Fortune Binary Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sse-shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;SSE (Shanghai Stock Exchange)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.sse.com.cn/services/tradingservice/tradingtech/technical/data/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data and Trading Link Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
Error Interface Documentation can be found in other menus
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;SSE_IS111_ErrorCode_CV3.15.xlsx&#34; &gt;Trading Error Interface Documentation XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.szse.cn/marketServices/technicalservice/interface/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Query Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
The Stock Exchange does not provide separate error message explanations; supplementary information can be found in Chapter 6 of the Market Data Query Interface Documentation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;P020201229686784934466.pdf&#34; &gt;Shenzhen Securities Trading Center Binary Transaction Data Interface Specification (Ver1.18) PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;Nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nyse.com/markets/hours-calendars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Holiday Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/ipos?tab=upcoming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;New Issue Listings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-price&#34;&gt;Closing Price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://eoddata.com/stocklist/NASDAQ.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Global Market Closing Prices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
