<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Huya on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/huya/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Huya on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/huya/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Era of Wild Capitalism: The League of Legends Esports Era Concludes</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid growth over the past decade, becoming a significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Games like League of Legends (LOL) have not only provided players with competitive entertainment but also fueled capital investment, driving the development of various esports platforms and events. However, this trajectory is now entering a gradual decline alongside the influx of capital and the rise of the pan-entertainment industry. The rise and fall of Panda TV, as well as the competition between Douyu and Huya, mark the end of an era of &amp;ldquo;wild capitalism,&amp;rdquo; suggesting shifts in the favorable conditions for the esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-investment&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early esports industry had humble beginnings, particularly in China. Many players participated in competitions for games like StarCraft and Dota fueled by their passion. However, esports truly began to rise with the release and promotion of League of Legends. After League of Legends officially entered the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community into part of mainstream culture. Especially starting in 2013, the LPL (Chinese professional league) steadily developed, making League of Legends the cornerstone of China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 marked a turning point for the esports industry in China. The influx of capital transformed esports from simple competitions into a much larger ecosystem. Panda TV, as one example, became a product of excess capital. Founded with investment from Wang Sicong, Panda TV rapidly gained popularity by attracting viewers and users with its innovative content and substantial investments. However, this also exemplified the &amp;ldquo;barbaric&amp;rdquo; influx of capital – a relentless pursuit that often lacks patience and long-term vision. While significant short-term achievements were made through considerable financial and human resources, Panda TV ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019 due to management issues and overreliance on capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fall of Panda TV did not lead to a decline in the esports streaming industry, but rather spurred the rise of platforms like Douyu and Huya. These two giants quickly became leaders in the esports sector, with increasingly fierce competition between them. Douyu initially gained prominence through livestreaming League of Legends professional matches and signing top streamers, setting a benchmark for esports broadcasting. Huya, by increasing investment in esports events and diversifying its platform, gradually narrowed the gap with Douyu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital played a significant role in this process. Bilibili successfully went public in 2018, and Huya also conducted an IPO that same year. The rapid flow of capital led to high industry concentration and intense competition between platforms for streamers and copyrights, resulting in a &amp;ldquo;capital war.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-convergence-of-pan-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Convergence of Pan-Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With increased investment in the esports industry, esports platforms are gradually diversifying their content. Esports hosts are expanding beyond game commentary and event streaming to include various entertainment formats such as singing, dancing, and interactive live streams. This has resulted in a richer content ecosystem centered around esports but incorporating diverse entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the trend towards broad entertainment has brought problems—the originally focused gaming culture of esports is gradually being marginalized, replaced by a trend prioritizing entertainment above all else. This shift has caused some viewers who were deeply passionate about esports culture to feel alienated, and capital is increasingly turning its attention to other entertainment sectors. Excessive investment and profit-seeking are blurring the essence of the esports industry, weakening the core value proposition centered on competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and other pan-entertainment industries, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to broader entertainment content. Consequently, giants like Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance are no longer solely reliant on esports projects for profit but have increased investment in areas such as film, music, and short videos. Notably, ByteDance&amp;rsquo;s rise, fueled by the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin, has overshadowed esports’ prominence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-generational-shift-the-fading-era-of-dividends&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Generational Shift&amp;rdquo;: The Fading Era of Dividends
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since League of Legends entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has become synonymous with the esports industry, fostering countless professional players, teams, and events, and driving a massive esports ecosystem. However, over a decade later, as a leading project in Chinese esports, League of Legends is entering a stage of generational transition. Notably, its influence has been gradually declining in recent years, even showing signs of significant decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
The most noticeable change is a generational shift in the player base. Initially, esports&amp;rsquo; rapid growth was fueled by a large cohort of young players, many of whom became professional players or viewers thanks to League of Legends. This generation grew up during a period of &amp;ldquo;demographic dividend,&amp;rdquo; immersed in the game’s competitive appeal and driving industry expansion. However, as time passed, these players matured, entered society, and shifted their focus towards other aspects of life and careers. Simultaneously, younger generations show less enthusiasm for League of Legends, resulting in an evident age gap and declining interest within the esports audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
Despite numerous updates and revisions, League of Legends&amp;rsquo; content innovation is struggling to keep pace. Annual version updates, hero balance adjustments, and the introduction of new gameplay features have failed to fundamentally address players’ need for novelty. Simultaneously, the MOBA market is becoming saturated, and other game genres like Honor of Kings and Peacekeeper Elite have rapidly gained popularity, diverting a significant number of players away from League of Legends. This competitive landscape has left League of Legends perpetually in a “chaser” role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-what-is-the-future-of-the-esports-industry&#34;&gt;Conclusion: What is the future of the esports industry?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that seemingly sprung up overnight. Excessive capital wanders within the internet sector, seeking the next opportunity, and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China&amp;rsquo;s demographic dividend, the industry achieved rapid success, but this success lacks a solid foundation. Over-investment in capital, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering healthy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before college, I didn&amp;rsquo;t play many games. League of Legends accompanied a generation’s growth; I watched so many finals. As an outsider, comparing Chinese and Korean players—especially Faker—Chinese players always felt hesitant during major tournaments. I understand the psychological pressure on players, but after more than ten years of development in this industry, mental health should be prioritized by teams. However, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been, and gameplay still relies on players’ innate talent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
