<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Repost / Share on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/repost-/-share/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Repost / Share on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:49:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/repost-/-share/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review Log 20251122</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still doing nothing, Xiaomi didn’t fall below my current price level. It has fallen consecutively for two days, and was finally stabilized by a buyback. The US market last night was interesting – it started to rally, but the next day it completely crashed. Today, both A-shares and Hong Kong stocks are basically worthless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, falling so much is actually good; I didn’t continue following the broader market, just laid back and relaxed, letting it play out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-decline&#34;&gt;Why the Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&lt;/a&gt;
Other viewpoints may or may not be correct; quantitative funds are increasingly influencing domestic stock markets. Many individual stocks often closely align with overall market trends. The original article is lengthy, and BeanJuice (豆包) has extracted the core content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2025, global risk assets will experience a major decline.  According to Rich Privorotsky, a senior trader at Goldman Sachs, this downturn resulted from a layered transmission of multiple factors culminating in systemic selling pressure. The key drivers include four main areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fed-shifts-to-hawks-the-beginning-of-the-downtrend-chain&#34;&gt;Fed Shifts to Hawks: The Beginning of the Downtrend Chain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent employment data presents contradictory signals: job growth remains robust, but the unemployment rate has risen to 4.44% (primarily due to a surge in labor force participation among 16-24 year olds), and three-month average new hires only totaled 62,000, with potential new hires at just 39,000. August data was also revised downwards. Adding to the trend of corporate layoffs, the market had expected the Fed to adopt a dovish stance, but the Fed has stubbornly maintained a hawkish tone, effectively canceling any bets on December rate cuts, with the probability of cuts now essentially zero. This triggered the first domino in the downward slide. Privorotsky bluntly stated that this hawkish position in light of the employment backdrop is a “policy error.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-narrative-restructuring-google-drives-a-winner-takes-all-landscape&#34;&gt;AI Narrative Restructuring: Google Drives a Winner-Takes-All Landscape
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key logical divisions are emerging within the AI sector, with Nvidia’s strong financial results no longer making it the core investment focus. Google&amp;rsquo;s breakthrough progress with the Gemini-3 model is reshaping the AI investment ecosystem. This “disruptive model” has forced other companies to delay product cycles and increase capital expenditures, leading to increased uncertainty regarding returns on investment, resulting in companies like Oracle failing to follow the upward trend. A distinct &amp;ldquo;winner-takes-all&amp;rdquo; landscape is forming within the market, shifting AI from a broad “adoption” phase to one dominated by a select few, triggering adjustments across related sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-flash-crash-retail-investor-risk-appetite-declines&#34;&gt;Crypto Flash Crash: Retail Investor Risk Appetite Declines
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volatile swings in the cryptocurrency market triggered a chain reaction. Retail investors, who had steadfastly held their positions over the past two years – often referred to as “diamond hands” – have transitioned into “selling hands” due to factors such as large-scale dumps by whale accounts. This panic sentiment spilled over into non-profit tech stocks and AI-related equities, exemplified by Palantir, which plummeted 6% during trading hours after rising 5.5%, marking a significant downgrade in retail risk appetite and signaling a fundamental shift in market structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantitative-funds-selling-off-the-key-driver-of-accelerated-decline&#34;&gt;Quantitative Funds Selling Off: The Key Driver of Accelerated Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since August, trend-following funds (CTAs) have held over $500 billion in long positions. Following a break below key levels, the index triggered concentrated liquidations. Simultaneously, rising volatility prompted volatility control strategy funds to sell off, compounded by capital flows from VIX ETN positioning creating a “short-tailed, short-convex” configuration, which amplified the downward effect. The previously stable “low volatility structure” collapsed, with quantitative and systematic funds initiating a “mechanical selling,” leading to a sudden and significant plunge in the market without any major events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamental-concerns-and-stabilization-conditions&#34;&gt;Fundamental Concerns and Stabilization Conditions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a fundamental perspective, AI investment faces a “capital bottleneck”: a wave of corporate bond issuance is imminent, with AI data centers relying on debt expansion, while rising capital costs may slow down the pace of AI expansion. This risk has not been fully priced in previously. Goldman Sachs predicts that the S&amp;amp;P 500 mini contract could fall to 6500 points, and believes that the long-term value of AI remains unchanged; true winners are labor-intensive companies that achieve margin expansion through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market stabilization requires fulfillment of three conditions: CTA positioning cleanup is complete, retail investors with excessive long positions have been squeezed out, and at least two of the following are met: cryptocurrency stability, a dovish Fed policy shift, and AI capital expenditure support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>All the gifts of AI have already been marked up with prices in the shadows.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/all-the-gifts-of-ai-have-already-been-marked-up-with-prices-in-the-shadows/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 19:09:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/all-the-gifts-of-ai-have-already-been-marked-up-with-prices-in-the-shadows/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The frequency of article releases has noticeably increased with the use of AI, and I intend to differentiate this in the tags within the text as well. The author’s column will also note the names of large models. However, the issue persists: articles generated by AI have significantly reduced my level of involvement, with many articles being forgotten after a month or so. This occurs similarly when writing code – instead of analyzing problems based on existing knowledge, I instinctively turn to AI for analysis and troubleshooting, leading to a clear increase in “laziness.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative AI may boost work efficiency, but its &amp;ldquo;gift&amp;rdquo; comes at a huge cost. A research study at Peking University analyzed 410,000 papers and longitudinal experiments, finding that AI accelerates knowledge production but leads to severe homogenization; a Harvard study showed that AI causes “credential bias,” with junior positions decreasing by 7.7%, exacerbating the Matthew effect. On a personal level, the creativity boost brought about by AI is a fleeting &amp;ldquo;illusion&amp;rdquo; – it disappears when deactivated, but ideological homogenization persists, forming “creative scars.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;current-situation&#34;&gt;Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is not only reshaping industries across the board but fundamentally altering how humans write, think, and reason. &lt;strong&gt;Following the release of ChatGPT3.5, an optimistic expectation spread widely: AI would bring about “work leveling.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2023, two MIT economics PhDs published empirical research on this claim in the &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; journal, providing evidence to support it: that generative AI significantly boosts the performance of low-performing employees, potentially bridging the gap with high-performing ones and reducing inequality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;Science&lt;/em&gt; journal editors summarized this as, “Weaker participants benefited most from ChatGPT, a finding with important implications for policies aimed at reducing productivity inequalities through AI.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, &lt;strong&gt;two years later, reality seems to have not fully followed this ideal path.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2025, two Harvard economics PhDs, analyzing recruitment and employment data covering over 6.2 million employees and more than 1.5 billion instances between 2015 and 2025, revealed a stark truth: &lt;strong&gt;Generative AI is reshaping the labor market in a “credential-biased” way.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data showed that between 2015 and 2022, the employment growth curves for junior and senior positions were roughly consistent, but starting in 2023, they began to diverge: Senior positions continued to rise, while junior positions started to decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For companies deeply embracing AI, the number of their junior-level positions decreased by approximately 7.7% over six quarters, while senior positions remained largely unaffected and even saw slight growth. This phenomenon was primarily due to a reduction in hiring rather than mass layoffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AI has not brought about equitable leveling but has instead exacerbated the Matthew effect – “the rich get richer.”&lt;/strong&gt;  Cheng Travel CEO Liang Jianzhang commented on the paper: &amp;ldquo;AI will replace basic intellectual labor, exacerbating the difficulties faced by young people in education, marriage and early career stages.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The structural changes in the labor market are just the tip of the iceberg. &lt;strong&gt;A deeper question then arises: as AI is integrated into our workflows, what impact is it having on human creativity itself? Is the efficiency boost brought about by AI truly internalized individual capabilities? Is it shaping – or even “homogenizing” – our thoughts in ways we haven’t yet perceived? Once individuals become overly reliant on AI, is their independent, original thinking ability enhanced, or is it subtly being weakened?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, Professor Li Guiquan&amp;rsquo;s research group at Peking University published a paper in the social science top journal &lt;em&gt;Technology in Society&lt;/em&gt;, addressing these key issues head-on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core of the research comprised two parts. The first was a large-scale natural experiment that analyzed over 41,000 academic papers across all 21 disciplines before and after the release of ChatGPT3.5, dissecting AI’s true impact on global knowledge production. The second was a longitudinal behavioral experiment conducted over several months, exploring AI&amp;rsquo;s long-term causal effects on individual cognitive abilities in a laboratory setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining breakpoint regression design and machine learning techniques, the research team revealed generative AI’s long-term and genuine impacts on both individual creativity and group homogeneity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This journal is JCR 1-star, with an impact factor of 12.5, ranking 271 out of 271 journals in the socialscience, Interdisciplinary category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;410000-papers-collective-unconscious&#34;&gt;410,000 Papers&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Collective Unconscious&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most terrifying thing isn’t the noise, but the chorus of voices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;410000-papers-collective-unconscious-1&#34;&gt;410,000 Papers’ “Collective Unconscious”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The study was a large-scale natural experiment.
The research team extracted academic outputs spanning all 21 disciplines – physics, life sciences and biomedical sciences, applied sciences, social sciences, arts and humanities – from the authoritative Web of Science Core Collection database. Through random sampling of over 17,000 scholars, the team ultimately collected all 419,344 papers published before and after the release of ChatGPT-3.5, constructing a massive dataset to analyze the true impact of AI on global knowledge production.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/all-the-gifts-of-ai-have-already-been-marked-up-with-prices-in-the-shadows/20251010191749.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;493&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Large Dataset&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;207&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;498px&#34;
	
&gt;
Illustration of homogeneity and creativity in academic papers before and after the release of Generative AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As shown in the figure above, prior to 2022, global academic output (red/blue lines) exhibited steady growth alongside homogeneity (gray line). However, following the release of ChatGPT3.5, both curves experienced a sharp increase in slope.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, after GPT3.5’s release, academia not only accelerated knowledge production (creativity) at an unprecedented rate but also intensified the homogenization of its content at an even faster pace, clearly demonstrating the “double-edged sword” effect of generative AI on knowledge production.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To demonstrate that the observed changes were caused by AI and not due to chance, the research team employed a causal inference method called “Regression Discontinuity Design” (RDD).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-do&#34;&gt;How to Do
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;They viewed the release of ChatGPT-3.5 in December 2022 as a natural “time breakpoint.” Whether a paper was published before or after that date posed numerous uncontrollable factors for individual scholars (such as review cycles), effectively creating a randomized “experimental group” (with the opportunity to use AI) and a “control group” (unable to use AI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-its-reliable&#34;&gt;Why it’s Reliable
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This “pseudo-randomness” allows researchers to effectively isolate other long-term confounding factors and precisely identify the causal effects brought about by AI. To ensure the rigor of this method, the team also conducted a series of specialized statistical tests, confirming that scholars did not engage in strategic behaviors such as “delaying publication” or “early release” before or after the “breakpoint,” thereby guaranteeing the reliability of the research results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-quantify-creativity-and-homogeneity-metrics&#34;&gt;How to Quantify “Creativity” and “Homogeneity” Metrics?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the confirmation of causality, the research team conducted a quantitative analysis of these 40+ thousand papers across two dimensions: “creativity” and “homogeneity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity:&lt;/strong&gt; Evaluated based on the number of paper publications and the quality of those publications (JCR Quartiles).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Number: The total number of papers published by an author.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quality: The JCR Quartile score of the journal in which the paper was published. This is a prestigious journal ranking system, with Q1 representing the top 25% of journals in a field and Q4 representing the bottom 25%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Homogeneity:&lt;/strong&gt; Evaluated through content similarity and language style similarity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content Similarity: Utilizing an SBERT deep learning model to convert paper abstracts into numerical “vectors,” then calculating the “cosine similarity” between these vectors to determine the degree of similarity in their core meaning.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Language Style Similarity: Employing a character-level matching algorithm to scan and calculate repeated phrases and sentence structures between paper abstracts, thereby measuring the similarity of writing styles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-double-edged-sword-more-efficient-yet-more-monotonous&#34;&gt;A Double-Edged Sword: More Efficient, Yet More Monotonous
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As shown, the analysis results clearly reveal a “double-edged sword” effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On one hand, the emergence of AI has become a powerful “accelerator” for academic output: the average annual publication volume per scholar increased by 0.9 papers, and the quality of published journals averaged an increase of 6%. This effect is particularly prominent in fields such as technology and physical sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on the other hand, the gains in efficiency are coming at the cost of diversity in thought and expression. Data show that the average annual similarity of writing styles in papers increased surprisingly by 79%, while the thematic content of papers also showed a significant convergence, with the most serious phenomenon being homogenization in physics, arts, and humanities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/all-the-gifts-of-ai-have-already-been-marked-up-with-prices-in-the-shadows/20251010192022.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;688&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Breakdown Regression Results Chart&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;148&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;357px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This large-scale natural experiment conducted by Peking University researchers provides us with real-world macro evidence: Generative AI is indeed a powerful “accelerator” for academic output, helping scholars to produce and publish faster in better journals. However, this increase in efficiency comes at the cost of diversity in thought and expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global knowledge production seems to be becoming more efficient and more “monotonous” in this “great exchange.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, research two also left a deeper question: what does this macro trend mean for individuals who are immersed in it? Does the creativity boost brought by AI represent genuine personal cognitive growth?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To answer this question, the research team conducted a longitudinal behavioral experiment tracking over several months in a controlled laboratory environment in research two to explore the long-term causal effects of AI on individual cognitive abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;scars-of-creativity-left-by-ai&#34;&gt;Scars of Creativity Left by AI
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once ideas submit to habit, they lose the possibility of creation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ais-creative-scars&#34;&gt;AI&amp;rsquo;s Creative Scars
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In fact, there have already been numerous laboratories using small-sample empirical studies from different angles to confirm the trends revealed by macro data. For example, research at Cornell University found that AI writing assistants sacrifice cultural uniqueness and cause users’ expressions to tend towards “Western paradigms”; research at Santa Clara University also showed that individuals who used ChatGPT were more similar in their creativity semantically.
Notably, a research team from MIT directly observed the brains of individuals using electroencephalography (EEG) technology, finding that the brain activity level of the group of students who used ChatGPT was significantly lower than that of the group that relied solely on their own thinking or used search engines.
These studies point to one conclusion: AI is sacrificing cognitive input and diversity to enhance efficiency.
However, most research focuses on the immediate impact of using AI, with little exploration of whether the effects of AI “leaving the field” can be sustained and whether its long-term negative impacts will diminish.
This study by Peking University made a new attempt in this area.
It not only observed the immediate effect of AI in a seven-day experiment, but also systematically tested the long-term consequences of AI dependence through two independent tracking tests after the end of the experiment – on day 30 and day 60. This allowed us to truly see whether what AI brought was a transferable “ability” or a fleeting, uninternalizable “illusion.”
Specifically, the Peking University research team randomly divided 61 college students into two groups: “AI experimental group” (able to use ChatGPT-4) and “pure brainpower control group.”
The experiment design consisted of three key stages: first, all participants completed a creativity baseline test on day one without using AI; then, from days two to six, the “AI experimental group” completed daily creativity tasks with AI assistance, while the “pure brainpower control group” completed the tasks without assistance; finally, and most importantly, on day seven, day 30, and day 60, all participants had to complete the final tracking test without any AI assistance.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/all-the-gifts-of-ai-have-already-been-marked-up-with-prices-in-the-shadows/20251010192137.png&#34;
	width=&#34;1024&#34;
	height=&#34;656&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Experimental Design Illustration&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;156&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;374px&#34;
	
&gt;
To comprehensively evaluate “creativity,” the study used a composite task mode covering multiple dimensions. These tasks included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Divergent Thinking Test:&lt;/strong&gt; The classic “Alternative Uses Task” (AUT), requiring participants to come up with as many novel uses as possible for everyday items (such as “a pen”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creative Problem Solving:&lt;/strong&gt; More realistic business scenario questions, such as asking participants to design innovative features for a “smart bicycle.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Convergent Thinking Test:&lt;/strong&gt; The “Remote Association Test” (RAT) added during the tracking phase, requiring participants to find a word that can connect three unrelated words simultaneously.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Insight Question:&lt;/strong&gt; The classic “Candle Problem,” requiring participants to fix a candle on the wall with a box of nails, a candle, and a box of matches, without letting the wax drip onto the table.
To ensure the scientificity of the assessment, the study used the “gold standard” in the field – expert consensus evaluation (CAT). Multiple expert judges independently scored thousands of creative outputs (including divergent thinking tasks and complex problem solutions) on multiple dimensions such as novelty, practicality, and flexibility in a “blind” condition where they were unaware of the grouping situation and research purpose. High data consistency (rating agreement ICCs &amp;gt; 0.90) ensured the scientific and fairness of the assessment results.
The homogeneity measurement method used in Study II adopted the same technical methods as Study I to ensure consistency between the two studies’ evaluation standards.
The experimental results clearly revealed a stark asymmetry:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creativity Enhancement is Transient and Unsustainable:&lt;/strong&gt; During the AI usage phase (days 2-6), the “AI experimental group”’s creativity indicators were indeed far beyond that of the “pure brainpower group.” However, once the AI was removed, this advantage instantly disappeared. Starting from day seven until day 60, there was no significant difference in creativity performance between the two groups. More alarmingly, in the 60-day convergent thinking test, the participants in the experimental group’s performance was even significantly worse than that of the control group who had never used AI, what AI brought was not a transferable “ability,” but rather an uninternalizable “illusion.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Homogenization of Thoughts is Long-lasting and Leaves &amp;ldquo;Creative Scars&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong&gt; In contrast to the fleeting creativity enhancement, the homogenization of thought demonstrated surprising “stickiness.” Even after two months of not using AI, the output content from the “AI experiment group” – regardless of whether it was measured in terms of semantics or language style – still exhibited significantly higher similarity compared to the control group.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This longitudinal study provided direct causal evidence confirming the long-term impact of AI on individual creativity. The potential brought by AI may only be a “creative illusion” that cannot be internalized, while the resulting tendency towards homogenization of thought could become an enduring “creative scar,” persistently embedded in our cognitive and expressive habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-the-world-had-no-new-creativity&#34;&gt;If the world had no new creativity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is the best of times, it is the worst of times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;if-the-world-lacked-new-creativity&#34;&gt;If the World Lacked New Creativity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This research from Tsinghua University, concluding that we shouldn’t abandon AI entirely just because of our own frustration, instead aims to remind us that we must consciously understand and address the long-term impact of prolonged reliance on AI on individual thinking and cognitive habits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The “homogenization” trend revealed in the study is rooted in profound principles of cognitive science: AI outputs easily trigger a powerful “anchoring effect” in users. When AI quickly generates an apparently “decent” answer or framework, our minds become anchored to this initial solution, making it difficult for subsequent thought and creativity to significantly deviate, ultimately leading to the convergence of ideas at the group level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In July of this year, when Huang Renjun made a calm assessment during an interview with CNN: &amp;ldquo;If the world lacks new creativity, then the productivity gains brought about by AI will translate into unemployment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As generative AI is increasingly used, the internet’s information and human knowledge base are becoming more homogenized at an unprecedented speed. Tsinghua University&amp;rsquo;s research cold-heartedly confirms that this trend exists. If society can continuously generate new ideas, AI will create more diverse employment opportunities; if it only repeats old tasks, AI can complete them in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI amplifies creativity but also accelerates the expulsion of “those with dry ideas.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-age-of-ai-how-to-maintain-sharp-thinking&#34;&gt;In the Age of AI, How to Maintain Sharp Thinking
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI alleviates our workload, but we need to establish a thinking system capable of deep thought, one that can interact with AI, articulate the problems we want AI to solve, and also engage in reasoning about those problems. Simultaneously, we must evaluate whether AI has answered correctly – we need dialectical thinking. —Huang Renfu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;in-the-age-of-ai-how-to-maintain-sharp-thinking-1&#34;&gt;In the Age of AI, How to Maintain Sharp Thinking
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As individuals navigating the age of AI, how should we position ourselves? How can we enjoy the convenience of AI while avoiding creative barrenness? Combining insights from research, here are some specific action recommendations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Treat AI as a “Thinking Drill”:&lt;/strong&gt; Consider it an tireless companion that provides unlimited perspectives. Use it for brainstorming, generating multiple possibilities, and challenging your ingrained assumptions. However, the final filtering, deepening, decision-making, and accountability for the results must always be yours.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deliberately Practice &amp;ldquo;Cognitive Friction&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong&gt; The most effective way to combat “anchoring bias” is to actively create “cognitive friction.” Don’t readily accept the AI&amp;rsquo;s first answer. Intentionally challenge it, find its logical flaws, and question aspects it hasn’t considered. This practice of critical thinking is key to maintaining our independent thinking abilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish &amp;ldquo;AI-Free Time&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong&gt; Just as we need regular exercise to prevent muscle atrophy, we also need to regularly allow our brains to exercise without AI assistance. Regularly designate a weekly period of “AI-free time” for thinking, planning, and creating using the most basic tools – paper and pen or a blank document. This deliberate &amp;ldquo;cognitive detox&amp;rdquo; ensures that our core creative and reasoning abilities won’t deteriorate in comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Is Modern Monetary Theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. stock market’s sustained bull run is largely driven by the “watering” of the dollar, rather than America’s inherent “hard power.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The modern monetary system has gradually become an important theoretical cornerstone for many economies worldwide since the 2008 financial crisis, emphasizing the subjective initiative of large governments in intervening in markets and utilizing government fiscal deficits as a primary tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;large government&amp;rdquo; is most commonly associated with Keynesianism, which highlights the government’s role in “smoothing peaks and troughs” during economic cycles – for example, suppressing overheating and stimulating contraction. It places great emphasis on the multiplier effect of government spending, i.e., how much an increase in monetary stimulus can amplify consumer multipliers; a 1-unit increase in government expenditure stimulates an equivalent increase in corporate and individual income, leading to business expansion and job creation, and ultimately mitigating economic downturns.  Furthermore, it adopts a relatively conservative approach to fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. The multiplier effect will drive market recovery, thereby increasing government revenue, especially during periods of overheating, where government debt potential and interest rate levels can be accumulated as stimulus funds for the next cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The modern monetary system is more like an extreme extension of Keynesianism, but with differences; its biggest characteristic is the limitation on government debt, which means the central bank should not have independent autonomy, primarily focused on inflation and full employment.  With limited resources and productivity, inflation refers to the government continuously increasing purchasing power through unlimited fiscal deficits as technological progress improves production efficiency, until it reaches the ideal level of full employment and production bottlenecks; continuing to increase monetary supply will lead to inflation, at which point it chooses to set a limit on fiscal deficits, as long as there are idle production resources, increased debt will not trigger inflation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the Financial Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, reality is not an ideal world, and execution in each stage involves human participation. Keynesianism is also selectively applied, leading to more economic stimulus during downturns and less overheating suppression. Economic imbalances generate achievements, while overheating also does, making it extremely difficult to suppress them. The numerous economic problems brought about, even a new financial crisis, are not inferior to the economic shocks caused by traditional overcapacity. The 2008 global financial crisis was actually a market self-reinforcement resulting from extreme Keynesianism, leading to the proliferation of speculative structural financial investment products such as real estate and financial investment products derived from real estate as their underlying assets. Even before the crisis erupted, there was a lack of risk awareness at academic, political, and market levels, treating debt-fueled prosperity as achievements, and more people benefited from it, such as the enormous financial system: losses are yours, dividends are ours, it’s bankruptcy – we made a fortune, money cannot be spat out. Ultimately, this led to massive investment by participants, bearing the profits of previous stages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, the shadow of the modern monetary system entered the financial crisis, characterized by rapid monetization of fiscal deficits and central banks&amp;rsquo; unlimited quantitative easing, as well as so-called emergency central bank lending policies. As the final lender, the central bank supplied bullets endlessly, allowing governments to continue borrowing debt. The central bank coordinated with fiscal policy, supporting government fiscal deficit spending through methods such as purchasing bonds, ensuring consistency of policy objectives. This is also why the boundaries between modern monetary and fiscal policies are becoming increasingly blurred – the base money injection relies heavily on the central bank’s direct participation in bond purchases, with one hand printing money and the other buying bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eurozone and the United States exhibited similar trends. In 2008, the EU government debt was approximately €6.7 trillion, and the government leverage ratio was around 66%, slightly above the generally recognized warning line of 60%. By 2014 – the five years of saving the market – the debt scale reached €9.5 trillion, and the leverage rose to 93%. The United States was even more exaggerated: in 2008, US government debt was approximately $10 trillion, reaching about $18 trillion by 2014, and recently again raising the government debt ceiling. Of course, each farce is staged with a government shutdown, but it will always break through the government debt limit. Currently exceeding $36 trillion, compared to $26 trillion growth in 2008, considering GDP growth factors, the government leverage has grown from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as the final lender, played an important role in multiple rescue operations and is one of the main purchasers of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaws-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;Flaws and Limitations of the Modern Monetary System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led stimulus scheme, though not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the market’s omniscience and all participants’ selfless dedication at every stage? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a simple example: if a government department increases its budget for a particular direction by 1 million, is it going to go to the mayor’s nephew or a more cost-effective market auction? Of course, in reality, interests will form in increasingly complex ways, leading to the result that even though the government has expanded debt and spending, it flows completely out of control. The recent American establishment of a Government Accountability Office is an extension of this type of problem. These issues manifest differently across varying corrupt economies; we’re focusing on discussing the more prevalent problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-inflation-issues&#34;&gt;1. Inflation Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of the modern information network, governments have a much greater grasp on market information than in the past, but this is not omniscience; markets inherently contain variables and are always subject to change based on expectations, leading to nested loops (or “Russian dolls”). I anticipate your predictions. Taking actual performance as an example, while between 2008 and 2020, the practice of Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) performed well, achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stabilization – even the Eurozone experienced phase-wise deflation, and U.S. inflation remained roughly within the expected 1-3% range, leading people to believe in extreme tools like Keynesianism again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we look back, it was primarily due to continued high growth in manufacturing in developing countries after 2008, such as our country gradually securing its position as a global production base and Southeast Asian and Indian economies following suit, all maintaining relatively high industrial value added, which offset the biggest limitation of MMT – resource supply constraints. Even under de-industrialization and excessive financialization in Europe and America, they simultaneously experienced increased government debt and monetary supply surges, while maintaining relatively stable inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the use of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States saw more significant inflation, peaking at around 10% – even today, despite rising interest rates for nearly three years, the U.S. labor market continues to exhibit abnormal overheating, and financial markets experience divergence from economic growth supported by monetary support, with inflation running towards 3% as the base effect disappears. This overheating performance during rate hikes is closely related to fiscal deficits. Raising interest rates is a contractionary monetary policy, while fiscal policy remains expansionary, compounded by the ultra-massive money injection in 2020, which has made U.S. inflation remarkably persistent. The biggest limitation of MMT is high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-government-debt-issues&#34;&gt;2. Government Debt Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, governments can indefinitely finance debt repayment through borrowing, but this is only possible if &lt;strong&gt;the central bank becomes a complete puppet&lt;/strong&gt;, meaning full alignment of monetary and fiscal policy – a key element of modern monetary systems known as &lt;strong&gt;policy coherence&lt;/strong&gt;. The Federal Reserve has no intention of granting the government completely unfettered authority, especially considering the accumulated government debt balance over many years, particularly interest expenses, which are increasingly becoming a significant burden on finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2023: In fiscal year 2023, the United States generated $4.439 trillion in revenue. The proportion of interest payments on its debt to this revenue was approximately 15%.  In 2024, this high-interest environment continued, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2024: The U.S. federal government’s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments on debt totaling $882 billion – approximately 18% of U.S. revenue. This even exceeded Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This highlights the sustainability issues within fiscal policy. If persistently maintained at low interest rates and low inflation, high levels of debt (such as in Japan) could theoretically lead to a slow, incremental increase under a quasi-modern monetary system.  According to the 72 rule, if interest costs are sufficiently low, debt repayment can double over 72 years – assuming inflation breaks this delicate balance, the accumulation of interest payments on debt will lead to runaway debt levels, with principal becoming a secondary factor. If the central bank subsequently diverges from the government’s objectives, these issues will become even more acute.  Furthermore, Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s political agenda starkly contrasted with the current Federal Reserve&amp;rsquo;s hawkish stance, contributing significantly to tensions between the U.S. government and the Fed during his term. The primary focus of observers is whether the current chairman can successfully complete his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;3. Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, government-expanded spending enters the household and corporate sectors, leading everyone to expand their spending, thereby boosting the increase in effective demand. However, given that people are all experienced from numerous financial bubbles since 2000, it’s clear that investment and consumption choices will exhibit a strong tendency towards large investment appreciation, especially when one or more products with extremely high expected appreciation appear, people will flock to the financial market seeking higher appreciation, even willing to compress living standards and leverage up. This is similar to what happened in Japan, the United States, and China during periods of high real estate growth. Combined with policy stimulus and the pursuit of maximum self-interest by practitioners, issues such as subprime loans are rampant. Many so-called bailout policies are actually encouraging borrowing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, historical performance shows an astonishing consistency: when monetary and fiscal policies are deployed on a large scale, it often leads to &lt;strong&gt;asset bubbles and wealth redistribution frenzies&lt;/strong&gt;. The asset bubble comes first, followed by wealth redistribution. This results in another problem – the extreme Keynesianism or Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) frequently encountered – leading to economic Ponzi schemes (Minsky Moment). As long as there is hot money, asset prices continue to rise; as long as they keep rising, latercomers will flock to hold cash; while the CPI measuring changes in basic living expenses doesn&amp;rsquo;t change significantly, money circulates within specific areas, and latercomers have no way out. &lt;strong&gt;After the frenzy comes the collapse&lt;/strong&gt;, which is the judgment of the Minsky Moment – repeatedly proven effective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, currency itself has a supply and demand relationship. When market supply exceeds demand, traditional investment products cannot accommodate it, or when it harvests too much capital that cannot attract investment, such as repeated real estate bubbles (Japanese people haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to touch real estate investments for decades), tax policies like increasing property holding taxes to reduce speculative demand will increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation of excessive monetary supply, the market urgently needs investment-and-tax-exempt investment products, and various virtual investment products emerge accordingly, even including the US President and First Lady joining in. One saying is to dig into the dollar, but it’s actually the inevitable result of global currency issuance and financial circulation under the damage of fiat currency credit. MMT relies most on countries with monopoly rights over credit money, which are also challenged. What kind of soil breeds what kind of financial game?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and Keynesianism are more like a progression and replacement relationship, emphasizing greater government intervention in the market and adopting a more aggressive attitude towards fiscal deficits and central bank independence. Excessive use of Keynesianism leads to stagflation and financial crises; MMT quietly took over after 2008 to clear out this artificially overheated economy. Under global economic globalization, productivity continues to improve, it quickly restored growth in the short term while maintaining inflation levels in the country using it, but also accumulated large government debt and asset bubbles. When inflation rebounded, with inconsistent goals between the central bank and the government, high interest rates and high leverage coexist, further exacerbating the fiscal burden brought about by government bond issuance. Fiscal sustainability is significantly weakened. Furthermore, excessive government participation has led to monetary base expansion, creating asset bubbles, while unlimited printing of money weakens the creditworthiness of the currency itself. It may appear that the dollar is strong, but it’s just a reflection of others. The massive investment demand creates fertile ground for various new types of financial investment and speculative tools, even escaping tax restrictions on traditional financial investment products – this is a microcosm of the global economy. MMT may not be the future, but it&amp;rsquo;s more like the past used after 2008, superimposed on the decline of economic globalization, the larger the financial bubble blown by governments, the higher the accumulated government debt, and the more frantic the financial speculative tools, the higher the efficiency of distorting wealth allocation. The greater the risk of a hard landing – including economic and social risks. Whether it’s Keynesianism or MMT, no matter how much monetary supply is provided, it cannot truly solve the problem of wealth structure; instead, it exacerbates risks in asset bubbles and Ponzi schemes. People are repeatedly falling into the same pit in different postures, but never learn anything from it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Fee reduction, fee reduction! Domestic mega-ETFs are experiencing a large-scale fee reduction.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-fees-cut-china/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 03:08:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-fees-cut-china/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hua Tai Bei Rui HongShan 300 ETF and related funds issued a notice lowering the overall fee rate to the lowest among peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 19th, Hua Tai Bei Rui Fund announced that, in order to better meet the investment and financial needs of investors, starting from November 22nd, Hua Tai Bei Rui HongShan 300 ETF and its related funds will lower their management fees and custodial fees, and revise relevant fund contract contents.
&lt;strong&gt;After the adjustment, the annual management fee for Hua Tai Bei Rui HongShan 300 ETF and its related funds is reduced to 0.15%, and the annual custodial fee is reduced to 0.05%, all set to the lowest rate among index funds.&lt;/strong&gt;
Almost simultaneously, other leading industry ETFs such as Huaxia HongShan 300 ETF, Huaxia ShangZheng 50 ETF, Nanfang ZhongCheng 500 ETF, JiaShi HongShan 300 ETF, and YiFangDa Entrepreneurial Board ETF also issued notices lowering management and custodial fees, with all rates reduced to 0.15% and 0.05%.
Unlike previous ETF rate reductions, this reduction was initiated by market-leading products with significant scale advantages, which will have a substantial impact on the industry’s subsequent developments. Exchange data showed that as of November 18th, Hua Tai Bei Rui HongShan 300 ETF had a scale exceeding 370 billion yuan, making it currently the largest ETF in terms of size.
The largest batch of super ETFs leading the way in reducing fees demonstrated their proactive willingness to benefit investors and allowed investors to invest in popular and liquid products at higher value for money.
Industry analysts believe that ETFs with significant scale advantages lowering fees will, on one hand, facilitate the public fund’s role in providing inclusive financial services, helping investors reduce holding costs and enhance returns and investment satisfaction across a wider area;
On the other hand, low rates will also further improve the competitiveness of the products themselves. With the added benefits of liquidity diversion effects and cost operation advantages, the products are expected to attract more medium-to-long term incremental funds into the market, helping build a good ecosystem for “long money long investment.”
In recent years, thanks to its flexible trading, high transparency, strong liquidity, low investment barriers, and other unique advantages, broad-based ETFs have become the main channel for capital entering at low levels and “long money long investment.”
This reduction in fees may serve as an &amp;ldquo;accelerator,&amp;rdquo; making it easier for long-term funds to enter the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the Tianhong Fund that I invested in hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet released an announcement, it should be followed up on. If no update is provided, I will consider switching funds.
Original Management Fee: 0.5%, Custody Fee: 0.1%. New Management Fee: 0.15%, Custody Fee: 0.05%. This reduction is quite significant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Increased scrutiny of third-party advisor regulation, and the beneficiaries behind the ‘Douyin (TikTok) stock trading’ phenomenon face a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following the surge of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In late September, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, Douyin (TikTok) recommendations for stocks garnered attention from various parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous financial commentators have risen to prominence on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behind these rapidly rising financial commentators lies a significant force: third-party investment advisory service companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s understood that many third-party advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (投流) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are even rumors that one third-party advisory firm achieved revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, “good times” are facing more uncertainties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since November, multiple departments have issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliance management of self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On November 15th, Futu Securities (300033.SZ) announced that a subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in suggestive stock recommendations through livestreaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be signaling a stricter regulatory environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The expansion of third-party investment advisory service firms like Fangyuan Intelligence Investment (9636.HK) is likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring-by-regulators&#34;&gt;Close Monitoring by Regulators
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant Network, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the “stirring up” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulatory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment advisors recommending stocks through live broadcasts constitutes a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took measures to suspend new clients for a company’s livestreaming that presented “implicit stock recommendations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14th evening, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued an announcement titled &amp;ldquo;Live Streaming Control Lacking Effectiveness, Institutions Suspended Business,&amp;rdquo; directly addressing situations where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate controls during live streaming operations and engaged in recommending stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association stated: “Strictly prohibit livestreaming stock recommendations. Livestreaming is a public media dissemination platform, and livestreaming personnel, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, shall not recommend stocks during live broadcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau disclosed a penalty notice involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated professional norms by publishing misleading videos through WeChat Video No., which contradicted industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau subsequently issued a supervisory management measure to issue a warning letter to Wang Yong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wind (ID:TradeWind01) information, some unqualified investment advisory firms have been using “rented” brokerage accounts to promote stocks on Douyin and have since been suspended from broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people are livestreaming in the industry, but they are actually renting under a brokerage firm, which gives them investment advisor qualifications, then they use live streaming to generate leads, and sell investment advisory product bundles offline,” said a consultant from South China to Wind (ID:TradeWind01). “However, because they recommended stocks during the livestreaming, they were discovered and subsequently suspended.” Regular brokerages typically discuss sector trends but do not involve individual stock recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that some institutions or individuals were using self-media to illegally recommend stocks, in order to further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies in the辖区, all institutions should further strengthen company self-media operation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for the business development of various third-party investment advisory service firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors who were attracted by short videos made a profit remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “China’s first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence’s market capitalization rose from 2.878 billion yuan at the beginning of September to 12.464 billion yuan on November 13, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report showed that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by the end of June, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhuxi” has 2.26 million fans on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on users, and synergistically promote the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products,” JiuFang Intelligence stated. “By deeply integrating live streaming, short videos, and other new media tools, leveraging AI technology to build a fan network, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory course packages cover price ranges from tens of yuan to more than ten万元. The most expensive package, “Super Investor,” is priced at 139,600 yuan per six months, including exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory product refund rate is above 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for JiuFang Intelligence’s flagship series and JiuFang Intelligence’s Qionglong Series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, under regulatory scrutiny, whether JiuFang Intelligence&amp;rsquo;s business development will be affected remains to be further observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports said that accounts belonging to third-party investment advisory companies such as JiuFang Intelligence have been impacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a media report stated that “Hongbangzhuxi” was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th, XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the appointment for “Hongbangzhuxi’s” livestream on November 18th was still available in the livestream interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market sources said that relevant departments have entered JiuFang Intelligence for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a close source to JiuFang Intelligence told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection belonged to routine inspections and had already ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company involved in this round of regulatory storm rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities was investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may suspend business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th, “There were no illegal stock recommendation cases, and there was no investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that same evening, Tianhong Securities announced that its subsidiary Zhejiang Tianhong Cloud Software Co., Ltd. was penalized with a three-month new customer suspension due to inadequate compliance controls in the promotion of livestreaming business and the existence of scenarios suggesting recommendations of stocks, by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also mean that regulatory departments are further focusing on荐股 (recommendation of stocks) content on social media platforms such as Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the cake of short videos has also attracted many securities firms, but due to compliance requirements, securities firms are currently cautious about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the company is exploring methods for short video operations and lead generation, and it has organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning, but due to compliance requirements, it is still in an exploratory stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements is because the content on short video platforms has a distinct emotional color, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality, and the two exist in a natural conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If uncontrolled emotions influence the capital market, it can easily trigger violent fluctuations in the market, which goes against the long-term healthy development of the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What manner should securities holding institutions embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “stepping on red lines”? This is clearly a difficult question for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why do computers generally use little-endian storage?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:43:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding byte order: A layman&amp;rsquo;s explanation &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://example.com/post/2023/01-10-%e4%b8%bb%e6%9c%ba%e5%ba%8f%e3%80%81%e7%bd%91%e7%bb%9c%e5%ba%8f%ef%bc%8c%e9%80%9a%e8%bf%87%e8%b0%83%e8%af%95%e5%99%a8%ef%bc%8c%e7%9b%b4%e6%8e%a5%e8%a7%82%e5%af%9f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Host Order, Network Order, observed directly via debugger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the field of computer science, certain design habits have formed due to historical reasons, just like the width of a hip dictates the width of a rocket&amp;rsquo;s thrusters – there’s no need to rigidly analyze their “advantages” and “disadvantages”; it’s simply a matter of historical convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-link&#34;&gt;Original Link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author: Beiji (North Pole)
Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/637413724/answer/3346032134&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.zhihu.com/question/637413724/answer/3346032134&lt;/a&gt;
Source: Zhihu
Copyright belongs to the author. For commercial reprints, please contact the author for permission. Non-commercial reprints must indicate the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-translation&#34;&gt;Text Translation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the translation of the provided text into English:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data Mining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the current situation is a result of historical habits plus commercialization, and it has little to do with technology itself. ARM can be set up as big-endian or little-endian. The TCP/IP header still uses big-endian (network byte order). There are also many storage protocols/specifications that use big-endian to store data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the three questions posed by the user seem incorrect in today&amp;rsquo;s view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do computers generally adopt little-endian storage? –&amp;gt; Incorrect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is storing the low byte in a little-endian manner more efficient than in a big-endian manner? –&amp;gt; Efficiency will not be higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any argument about these three questions using current technology is like shooting an arrow first and then drawing the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, if we say that the choice of big-endian or little-endian did have some objective factors in the history of computer development: The advantage of host-byte order (little-endian) is that a 8-bit * 4 adder can be easily made, requiring only an 8-bit adder to sequentially add all bytes from low to high, and the carry circuit is very simple. If it were big-endian, it would require loading 32 bits once, which cannot perform calculations. Nowadays, the difference between loading 8 bits or 32 bits is not significant, but in the early days when storage prices were expensive, simplicity was always preferred, so the host-byte order chose little-endian based on cost considerations. The advantage of network byte order (big-endian) is that early devices had very small caches. Taking the high byte first could quickly determine the message information: packet length (need to prepare how much cache), address range (IP addresses are matched from front to back). Early network devices&amp;rsquo; caches were at the byte level, and taking the high byte was indeed a little faster. Therefore, network devices used big-endian based on cost considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, the choice of byte order has historically been more influenced by application scenarios and costs (such as PPC/MIPS being more suitable for network devices), and the configuration of big-endness and little-endness has been carried over to this day due to compatibility reasons. In today&amp;rsquo;s view, these advantages no longer exist, they are merely historical habits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What we have been seeking throughout our lives is…</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang Yi-zi said: Human relationships, spanning a lifetime of mutual support and dependence, may be held within one’s embrace, understood in the confines of one room; or they may arise from entrusted messages, dissolving into the vastness beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a lifetime, like a fleeting flower. Like grass and trees blossoming and withering, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet, in this life, desires are numerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a child, I lay under lotus plants and hemp in the stream, busy catching the east wind to fly kites, chasing yellow butterflies in haste,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also learned to grow gourds by the shade of mulberry trees, returning home with a full meal after dusk, not shedding my cloak to lie beneath the moonlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I grew older, I hoped to be inscribed on the gold list, to have a beautiful woman accompany me, to have endless wealth, to rise continuously, to have a full table of guests, to sing and play every night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When old, I wanted health and longevity, welcome childhood servants, young children waiting at the door, a chessboard, a confidant, a bottle of wine, a courtyard, enjoying family harmony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see people rushing about in a panic, only seeking a few taels of broken silver. Yet, this broken silver, can it dispel all kinds of melancholy in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half the people are still struggling with their lives, where do they have time to seek meaning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, human life is just an experience, like plants, sun and moon – experiencing the cycle of desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t understand it, you’ll feel like a fleeting moment in the vastness of the world, a tiny grain of sand on the Yangtze River. When you understand it, you’re happy with what you encounter, temporarily possessing yourself, content and self-sufficient, unaware of your approaching old age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, flowers, and tea. You can pursue the clear breeze on the river or the bright moon in the mountains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But don’t overly concern yourself with the results; they will all eventually pass away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a lifetime of hardship, when you arrive in this world, try to experience the joys and sorrows, birth, old age, sickness, and death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the quote from The Tale of the Sea Deer:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are short, and we will eventually lose them, so why not be a little bolder – love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream – there are many things with no answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed &lt;em&gt;The Analects of Zan Gong&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Cliff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the rise of past generations, one feels a sense of longing; if only they could be brought together as one, never to have lamented or mourned, unable to convey it within my heart. I know that dying in one’s lifetime is an absurdity, and the tragedy of Zang and Peng is a false fabrication. Those who look upon us now are like we look upon them then. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The future of China will undoubtedly be a China of good elders and good old people.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that twenty years from now, I’ll be a cute old man, spending time with a cute old woman. I don&amp;rsquo;t seek great wealth or status; just to be healthy and strong enough to travel and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I said that in 10 years, I’ll be a charming old man, and I will work hard to become a charming old man. The future of China must be one with good old men and good old women. Even if I am 60 years old in 10 years, I will be the youngest person in this world&amp;rsquo;s third kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly speaking, if everyone sees the 50-year-old Chinese man with this physique, it’s quite impressive. But behind this physique is a phrase I believe in: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! When it rains, I want to go for a run; tomorrow afternoon, I will play soccer. At 50 years old, I can still play big games, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a joke. Moreover, I often play with professionals. But what’s behind this? It’s discipline. I spend my remaining days running, and people might find running very monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I can run freely, without listening to music – because I think my own breathing is the most beautiful music while running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically don&amp;rsquo;t run on a treadmill. And many people in Beijing experience severe smog; I run 5 days a week, and two days are left for the smog. Then, jokingly, I say it might be because I never stop. Every month, I draw one day of my running experience in my diary – at least 18 days each month, and when I run, they just flash by. When I run, I also take off my glasses, but more importantly, I still play soccer every week. My graduate students’ last lecture is always held at our home on that particular day, with a theme called “Fun.” I think fun is very important. I never deal with people who lack any joy or hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather avoid such people – they are too frightening; if you don&amp;rsquo;t have fun, you feel like you have nothing to enjoy. You like what kind of job? In early January this year, one of my graduate students wrote for &lt;em&gt;China Weekly&lt;/em&gt;, and we had a special issue called “Looking Ahead.” Ten years from now, my graduate students will, at the end of each graduation year, write an essay for me – and I keep those essays. Then, ten years later, I’ll continue to develop them, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also write one as a 50-year-old to a 60-year-old; 60 is a distant land that I never thought of before, but it’s just another stop on my way to 20 – writing to my students who are 30. That’s like a love letter from spring to summer. But when I&amp;rsquo;m 50 and write to 60, it’s like autumn whispering to fall. Now, I’m writing to myself ten years from now, from the whole world, about my bed, a meal, and the company of my family – this is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what will I be at 60? My title is very clear: in this long article, I said that in 10 years, I’ll be a charming old man, and China wants to be charming not just because there will be more young people like citizens who become citizens, no longer just ordinary people; energetic young people, young people who understand rules. The future of China must be one with good old men and good old women. Currently, over 60-year-olds in China exceed 2.3 billion – and that number will definitely exceed three billion in 10 years, meaning that if you consider only the population over 60, China would be among the top five countries in the world, or even the third. Imagine how frightening that is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t find it frightening. I wonder if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen online a table of the average life expectancy in various provinces and municipalities of China – Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years, including men and women. Men naturally occupy a larger share of the female population. That means even if I am 60 years old in 10 years, I will be one of the youngest people in this world&amp;rsquo;s third kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to the future. If women retire at 55 with an average life expectancy of 80 years, and they continue for 25 years after retirement; if men retire at 60 with an average life expectancy of 80, and they continue for 20 years after retirement! You won’t do anything but dance square dances. And I can say that the older ladies and gentlemen who are dancing square dances today are cultural habits and entertainment styles brought to them by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty - I was one of the youngest members of the team when I was 60 years old, and I should be what kind of person? Chinese painting says that at 60, your ears become attuned, and I believe I wouldn’t listen to anything then, always happy, still annoyed by things I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mention, and even happiness would turn into unhappiness. More importantly, I need to figure out what to do for the young people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should we do for good things? Don’t be lazy, don’t easily compromise, speak up when you need to oppose, because young people might harm their interests, can you stand in front of them and block their way? I often look at myself in the mirror now. My good friend, Tao Wei, passed away – he used to gather with us at our home, and once told me a true story. We collectively mourned together, and back then, the older generation like Chen Lao would hoard things at home, spilling everything out of the box, hiding 30-odd items under the bed. You need to tell him how much that piece of clothing cost – over 500 yuan – and then support it, lighting incense every day. Therefore, this generation of ours is used to fighting with our parents, arguing about knowledge and ideas. How much did we buy back for 700 yuan?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;220&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it’s risky. Once, Tao Wei bought a T-shirt for his father for over 400 yuan. That shirt was really good – how much did it cost? 99, I wore it. The next day, disaster struck. When he came back from work, he praised Tao Wei and gave him 400 yuan to buy four more shirts for me. After I wore it out, Zhang Shu Li Da Ye all thought it was great, and later said the risk of lying like this is very large. Don’t do such things in the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mention a specific person – in the hospital orthopedic department, an elderly man broke his bone, and the most important reason was that he bought shoes from a street vendor. Of course, I’m only talking about this on a material level. Even when you get old, you still need spiritual life and curiosity, and you should be willing to shield young people from the wind and rain, live one day happily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious and excitedly waiting for my 60th birthday to arrive. I think it’s the beginning of a beautiful time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18 years old is probably different from yours.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very common phrase &lt;strong&gt;information fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – since graduating from high school, aside from the time I spent reading novels, I haven’t really taken the time to sit down and read a book quietly and attentively for a long time. Sometimes, looking back, after so many years of work, I still remember what I did each year? Often, by the middle of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten a lot of things from the first half. Writing a blog is a good habit, even though much of what I write isn’t appropriate and doesn’t matter – it was originally written for myself to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal readers are myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of my own 18 years was like a gaze of anticipation and questioning, and each person occasionally asks themselves, &amp;ldquo;Are you the way you wanted to live back then?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that everyone now has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, no one to have a heart-to-heart conversation with, unlimited knowledge acquisition, yet far from wisdom. Everyone should use your 18 years to ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;Are you the way you wanted to live back then?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think each of my own 18 years was like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. You can deceive others, but you cannot deceive your 18-year-old self. Is today you the way you were supposed to be at 18? I feel it&amp;rsquo;s okay. Today, material fame and many other things have been obtained, which is much more than what I thought when I was 18, but on the other hand, we are always on the road. When I was in journalism school at the Broadcasting Academy, I wanted to become a top reporter like Faraway, and today I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path. But this is exactly what many people say about Mr. Bai – &amp;ldquo;How have you stayed on CCTV because you want to be a good journalist?&amp;rdquo; News is still there. This is my 18-year-old gaze, so I think everyone occasionally asks themselves, “Are you the way you wanted to live back then?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is truly impossible to deceive others. This is my appearance at 18, but it’s gone in a blink of an eye. Twenty-eight years have passed. Every person who comes to Beijing to study will have such a photo album. In that era, the wrinkled suit on Tianmen Square, and the school badge pinned to the chest, because at that time there were few college students, no school badges, feeling very proud. Their hair was long back then, but they still liked their 18-year-old appearance. Many years later, I suddenly realized I was grateful for the things I faced at 18, because it silently shaped me. In 1986, on May 8th, I bought a selection of Misty Poems at Wangfujing Bookstore. That year, I listened to Cui Jian’s “One and All” at the Workers&amp;rsquo; Stadium. Today, I suddenly realized that my writing style was most influenced by it, including my personality being influenced by Misty Poetry, Rock Music, and Lu Guhong’s martial arts novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you experience at 18? You can carry that with you. I especially want to know what the 18-year-olds today are experiencing? Are they being carved up like a knife chopping wood? What tools are they using? What kind of appearance are they shaping? I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that everyone now has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, no one to have a heart-to-heart conversation with, unlimited knowledge acquisition, yet far from wisdom, knowing nothing and seemingly everyone is talking about individuality. But as an observer, I find that today’s young people are very similar. What should I do? What should I let the 18-year-old experience? I really like 1986 because 1986 was the best way to solve 1966.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1966 Cultural Revolution was ended by 76 in 1986, which had a degree of chance; it could only be ended by the enlightenment and awakening of human nature and the growth of every individual. This truly allows you to dig up the concerns you have. I think we still need enlightenment, we still need to fully understand human nature. No matter how much economic progress or changes China has made, if we don’t truly fill in the understanding of human nature, and then respond to the good side of human nature and control the bad side, there will still be many things that worry us in the future. So my 18 years were also this era&amp;rsquo;s 18 years, it&amp;rsquo;s gone too far, don’t forget why you started in the first place, now condensed into four big words: “初心”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think no matter how far you go, everyone should use your 18 years to ask yourself. So taking a photo at 18 is good, and often take it out to ask yourself. What others say doesn’t matter? It&amp;rsquo;s too difficult to deceive yourself. I just said to today’s 20-year-olds, “You should always let your 18-year-old be the eyes that watch you.”  I also mentioned earlier that in my twenties, you should try many doors, because you don’t know which one is most suitable for you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalist does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This excerpt recounts the author’s perspective on the profession of journalism, emphasizing that reporters should possess a social conscience, a broad knowledge base, and perseverance. The author also shares their reflections at age 50, including maintaining curiosity, achieving balance between material and spiritual pursuits, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best journalist is first, having a social conscience; second, possessing knowledge; and third, being able to run long distances. I couldn’t handle running 100 meters – I ran it. I believe these three things combined, people expect the safety concerns surrounding vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the melamine scandal. We always move forward in a logic loop of problems arising, solving problems, and completely resolving them. Otherwise, what is there for a journalist to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe the best journalist first has a social conscience, second has knowledge reserves, and third can run long distances – I’ve outrun the 100 meters, so it’s no problem. I think these three things combined, at 50 years old, you’ll understand that I seem to be well-suited for journalism. I&amp;rsquo;m naturally intertwined with China’s 40 years of reform, and on my 30th birthday, standing by the banks of the Songhua River, when I was 40, my birthday coincided with the 2008 Olympics, and I came out of the Olympic broadcast in which I went in. At 50 this year, as China commemorates 40 years of reform and opening up, there’s certainly a corresponding connection – whether the “Great Era” is at forty or China’s reform is at fifty-five?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that after walking through 40 years of road, China has already given people enough in terms of material things, and to the country enough. However, anxiety and confusion have increased, not decreased. We thought we were strong and wealthy, so everything was OK, but we discovered that material wealth is just a foundation; it’s difficult to become spiritually rich and truly a great power. The United States is already attacking your high-tech, we need to attack agricultural products. There&amp;rsquo;s always been a saying in the world: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s hard for second place to be achieved!&amp;rdquo; How many Second Place countries has America fixed? Therefore, we must go through a long period of time to transform “not one” into surpassing ourselves. I can’t get everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate that I started doing television at 25, first from figure interviews, and I contacted hundreds or thousands of figures with various halos. At that time, young people thought that these halos must make them very happy, but when they got closer, they found no, the halos have little to do with their happiness, and sometimes they are inversely proportional. Recently, I just finished reading about Guo Moruo’s last 29 years – Guo Moruo barely escaped persecution, serving as Deputy Minister of State Council, Vice Chairman of CPPCC, Vice Chairwoman of National People&amp;rsquo;s Congress, etc. But his two sons committed suicide, and the other may have been thrown to death from a building? Would he be happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? When you are in your sixties, two of your sons leave you in a few years; even if you’re a Deputy Minister, can you be happy? Many famous paintings can make people happy, and spending many years safely is enough to make you happy. What do you want? So I think looking at people is the best mirror. To say something more important, I think much of our anxiety now comes from thinking too much and reading too little books. This is Yang Geng’s reply to a young person – if you don&amp;rsquo;t read books, you rely on fast food; you pick up a mobile phone and plan to find a miracle pill. How can that be? I learned cleverness through the slow process of more and more books; subtraction comes from reading more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I don’t expect everyone to achieve it, but I hope the proportion increases – more and more Chinese people can read themselves better in books, which is the most important thing. No one sits on the ground and looks up at the stars, trying to figure out everything. I can&amp;rsquo;t do that. But I can look in a mirror. A few years ago, when a BBC news anchor came to Beijing, claiming to be the “most awesome” news anchor in BBC, he had someone organize a dialogue between him and a Chinese news anchor; we talked. That guy asked me during the conversation, &amp;ldquo;What do you think BBC should learn from CCTV?&amp;rdquo; I first made a joke and said, of course, they should first learn Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, after making a joke, I said, “I think BBC most needs to learn from CCTV is their curiosity about this world.” We’ve been observing the world with great curiosity these years as we quickly reach out to the world; we have more than 70 correspondents now, and we feel that when a student sees something new in foreign countries, he feels very curious. We carry a huge sense of curiosity and observe the world, while BBC has already considered Britain itself as the world. You don’t need to be curious anymore. The brother slapped the table and said, “What we lack is this thing.” In 2007, when I interviewed a Japanese writer, he told me, &amp;ldquo;Japan&amp;rsquo;s country besides lacking hope, has everything else.&amp;rdquo; Later I realized that this sentence was really deep; from another angle, ten years ago, I thought China Okay, here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m very worried that China will one day end up on the downside – feeling truly impoverished even when everything is available. I fear that by the time I’m 50, I’ll become a person who, despite having all material comforts, is incredibly poor. The problem in our reality is that there are many highly educated people with no culture, and many impoverished individuals with countless numbers on their bank accounts. That&amp;rsquo;s really what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this era. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t frightening because there’s a forward direction and hope. This is why I say that a lack of morality and human failings are the root cause. Therefore, I believe scientists invented so much not because they initially carried great missions, but out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to figure it out myself. So I&amp;rsquo;ve always encouraged myself to be curious, especially around 50 years old. That’s why I’m happy now. One thing that bothers me is persistence – as you were saying you’re still persisting. I said don’t say that persistence leads to death. In the past, we used to say ‘persistence equals success,’ and ‘China football will persevere even during the black minutes,’ or ‘persevere,’ but it loses its fun and method, so we rely on perseverance. Sometimes persistence is important, but often it has an opposite side. I’m afraid that when I do something, like chatting with people, I&amp;rsquo;ll persist in finishing what I started – which is now too late for my time, but I’m curious to see how these conversations will turn out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give myself a small keyword and engage in conversation with others. At 50 years old, as long as you can still maintain a great deal of curiosity, there&amp;rsquo;s no problem. I like all fun things, but not necessarily the most popular things today. Trendy terms change quickly – do you remember some of them? Will a media outlet on the internet 10 years from now become a traditional media outlet? So fun things always have their own intrinsic appeal. I respect everyone’s preferences; there must be a reason behind it, but when viewed over the long term, we see that Chinese people most enjoy playing mahjong. If you also like eating fast food, then restaurants serving large meals will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things aren&amp;rsquo;t just about expressing an emotion and moving on. How much fragmented reading do you get from your daily mobile phone use? How much longer-form reading do you have? But this is also a process – the mobile phone is becoming our handcuffs. So, seeing shorter content more often leads to short-sightedness. However, I don’t worry about ‘content is king.’ It will always return. You won&amp;rsquo;t keep entertaining yourself until your 40s, like I see teenagers drinking soda and telling them to drink less, but you know they will still drink it. On the other hand, I’m optimistic – he’ll eventually return to a tea-drinking lifestyle. This is the life of a Chinese person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s normal, but I hope the transformation will happen faster. We just express an emotion, and there are fewer investigative reporters now. You don&amp;rsquo;t read investigations. Thank you everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will Chinese football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The supplementary reader responses were mostly hastily written in 2021. The time it took to transcribe Wang Yi’s speeches at the beginning of the pandemic was still when things were just starting – don&amp;rsquo;t say twenty years later, or even a year or two later; the world is always beyond people’s expectations. Now that the epidemic has ended domestically in China, the overseas ones are still making a fuss. Regarding football, Chinese national team played quite well over the past few years; the coach dared to give them free rein and attack, which was much better than when they were just starting out and accompanying Grandpa to watch games was somewhat interesting. What kind of experience is it that a national team’s game makes even an old man unwilling to change channels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Curious, very curious, what could be the difference? So you find that Chinese football plays badly because everyone is afraid to lose the ball in their own area and pass it to others, leaving themselves out; there&amp;rsquo;s no such way of playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one of many small reasons. When talking about 20 years of football, 20 years from now China’s football seems so distant – the first expansion became 48 teams, and China might go or not go; the best age for a national team is 26-30, so 20 years later, those children aged 6 to 10 will be considered optimistic, but 20 years later it’s definitely going to be fine. When I mention children aged 6-10 today, you immediately look serious. Therefore, cause and effect – what are we planting today? What will grow if we plant soybeans today? We almost planted soybeans that would make the national team play in the league, and what would come out of it? Whoever initiates this action will be prepared to be dismissed; this goes against the rules, so I didn’t think about it too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you should really think about those children aged 6-10 today – are they playing football? If you know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ethical deficit, erosion of humanity</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To do things properly, first and foremost, you need to have a clear conscience. This allows you to sleep soundly, without minor ailments or major issues. It&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid making mistakes in the first place. If you do make a mistake, it should be about trying to rectify it, not concealing it or hoping to forget it yourself – humans are also capable of excellent memory. Inner peace is the destination; being able to answer your own questions with integrity allows you to live more lightly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjQ4NA==.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;. If there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this text; this document is solely for translating the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight words to say that are quite heavy, and I feel we’re currently experiencing a moral deficit, a depletion of humanity, and the times are constantly presenting problems that require solutions – a completely resolved logical cycle forward. You need patience to wait for its shuffling. For a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic about change; it&amp;rsquo;s being shuffled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These past few days, China has been battling two typhoons: one was intangible, and the other was tangible. The intangible typhoon is the vaccine, which is impacting our inner security dam. The other typhoon rarely landed in Shanghai, and then caused trouble for Beijing and Tianjin – a rare occurrence over several decades. This is an aside; next, you need to consider whether you can improve yourself, whether you’ve undergone significant changes, and whether you have many answers. If the surrounding environment remains unchanged, will you be happy? I have eight words to say that are quite heavy: I feel we currently have a moral deficit and a depletion of humanity – this is the biggest deficit and the greatest loss at present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, people expect the vaccine’s safety risks to be completely resolved. This is like the case with melamine milk powder, so sometimes you need to look at history and understand that you know about the establishment and formation of the US Food and Drug Administration, which is closely related to the initial unsafe milk and dairy products. The Sanlu Milk Powder incident forced China to undergo significant changes in the dairy industry. While vaccines are not happening one after another, I hope this time it’s a halt. You need to know that times always present problems, solve them completely – this is the logical cycle forward; otherwise, what do reporters do? What do citizens do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I believe that each of us can do is to be concerned. But the problem is that Chinese people are easily forgetful, like I just said, after bumping into someone’s car, we stop on the side of the road and run away; no one blocks us. Our neighbors and colleagues have a large proportion of these kinds of people. So we need to change slowly. And as ordinary citizens, what we can do is to pay attention and not forget. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it’s a lack of something; when you’re hungry and cold, you talk about ideals all the time – that doesn’t have persuasive power. But when he’s full and warm, he turns himself into China’s number one country for diabetes and high blood pressure, etc., you realize that Chinese people start running and dieting, and you ask the ladies present here, who hasn&amp;rsquo;t experienced the hardship of not being able to lose weight because they didn&amp;rsquo;t eat a good meal? This is a small change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are talking about the spiritual level, which must be the same principle. When you’re full and warm, you start running and dieting, then your spiritual needs will gradually increase. For example, I used to smoke, but after I started running, I unconsciously found that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t smoked for 20 days. I haven’t smoked since. Of course, I wouldn’t deliberately say, “I completely quit smoking,” because it feels too ritualistic; it doesn’t rule out occasionally smoking two or three cigarettes during the year. When your lifestyle changes, many things will change with it. I think for Chinese people, you need patience to wait for its shuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more people feel unhappy and unwilling to indulge themselves. Although depression is increasing, on the other hand, isn’t there also an increasing number of people seeking positive ways to live? At this time, spiritual things will grow. Don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic; look at the same thing in different ways. I often see drivers cutting people off in traffic, and I feel frustrated. But then I realize that the queue on the other side is longer than before – this is how it is. You are sitting here on a rainy evening, willing to chat about useless things, isn’t that fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also a transformation; therefore, many things need to be thought of in a different way. Of course, I think there will be more and more things to grow in the future, such as when you start a business, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t start a business? Everyone&amp;rsquo;s life is starting a business. Su Shi wasn’t starting a business? Li Bai wasn’t starting a business? - Data Mining&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the English translation of the text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There will be countless failures throughout a lifetime, and ultimately, creating your own brand is what matters. Most failures don&amp;rsquo;t matter if you don’t create them, as long as you live a life full of flavor and believe it’s worth it. I feel that China particularly lacks a good value system: failure is another form of success. People only accept the successful outcome, but failing well is also a success – they don’t accept this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I find it difficult; you see many reasons why Chinese football isn’t playing well, and one of them is that everyone is afraid to lose possession and pass it to someone else. There’s no such strategy. Of course, this is just a small part of the problem. As I get older, at 30 years old, writing about the preface and happiness doesn&amp;rsquo;t come quickly; now at 50, there’s some urgency because time is passing too fast, and you expect many things to become reality. But on the other hand, I understand that for a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process. You see older generations – some were once nothing more than traffic lights, but occasionally you&amp;rsquo;ll see children pulling their fathers along as they change. They’re changing and being shuffled; so I think you need to be patient.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Regarding time, you need to read many books to find the answers.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In general, the country is getting better and stronger, richer – and that’s without diminishing the importance of individual vanity. Looking back from the 1990s to now, within the families I’ve encountered, people&amp;rsquo;s lives have undeniably improved significantly. Simultaneously, the number of wealthy individuals has increased. As market-oriented economic development inevitably leads to widening income inequality, issues like class solidification and blocked upward mobility are prevalent globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often discussed – such as rigid social strata and limited opportunities for advancement – are common problems worldwide. However, it’s important to acknowledge the Communist Party&amp;rsquo;s contributions to people’s basic welfare and social security, something everyone should take note of. Life will continue to improve; if you don’t want to buy a house, you can rent one. There are still inequalities in educational resources for children, requiring choices between better job opportunities, improved work environments, or more time with family. Don&amp;rsquo;t impose your own ideas on others, including your children and family members. Sit down and talk it through – life will inevitably get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;, if there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this article; this text is only for the translation of the transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/30%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;503&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;30 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;
I’m now exactly 50 years old this year, and in the past I never thought about it; I felt that this was an old man. Now I realize it&amp;rsquo;s truly an old man – this is what I looked like at 30. When I was 30, I didn’t feel very young, good-looking, and when I was 50 years old, looking back, it’s not bad; the biggest life lesson at 30? Looking back. I think it&amp;rsquo;s subtraction – the key word is subtraction.  Somehow, &amp;ldquo;painfully happy&amp;rdquo; is also a kind of subtraction, letting you experience and write down many things, then leave them there on a new blank sheet, or running; but for me, at 30, I really feel that whether it’s about myself or reminding others, subtraction is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently guiding college students from China Central Television (CCTV), and I often remind them to &amp;ldquo;go all out&amp;rdquo; to add before they turn 30 – to try things, you don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of possibilities you have, you don’t know what opportunities fate will give you. It’s not about knowing; but some people work hard in their twenties, adding everything, but forget to stop when it’s time for subtraction. I think 30 is a very important period in life – after doing a series of additions and running around everywhere, you need to do a significant subtraction; otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s too late. Why do you need to subtract? Not everything suits you, not everything is suitable for you; you should do all things, but not necessarily &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How far can 8 lines of rope hold you if they’re tangled?
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/%E5%BB%89%E4%BB%B7.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;505&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cheap&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;425px&#34;
	
&gt;
By the time I was 30, I had been promoted to a full professor – in other words, academically speaking, it&amp;rsquo;s called a professor; as for journalism, it&amp;rsquo;s a senior journalist. I was promoted at 29, and this kind of thing is rare now, but I started to feel a huge confusion when I did the Sydney Olympics in 2000.  I suddenly felt that everything wasn’t right. I had to ask myself, “What exactly do you want to do? Which things should be discarded?” That year, I made an important subtraction – I stopped my show for a year, without appearing anywhere, and at that time people told me, &amp;ldquo;As a host, if you don&amp;rsquo;t appear on screen for a month, it’s okay; if you don’t appear for six months, no one will remember you.” I said, “My face is really cheap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, I started to develop new programs. This was after finishing “Painfully Happy” in 2001 – I stopped for a whole year. Everything I see today is a reflection on that time of subtraction. At that time, I could do many things – I could do sports, I could do E (likely referring to the internet), I could do many other fun things, and be a producer; but I said no, I realized I could only do news, and I should do news most of all.  Then I was the producer for three programs, and I quit them overnight, and that’s what I am today. I became simpler. Just recently, I was chatting with a colleague, and I said, “When I was in my 30s, I made a very important decision – not just because there were many things I could do, but I felt like I was just doing news; this deep well is something that might promote you to deputy director; I refused it, and returned to a normal level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E7%94%9F.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;502&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Undergraduate Student&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;428px&#34;
	
&gt;
Now, I’m a central television station&amp;rsquo;s senior editor – not someone who graduated from university (undergraduate). You know our system, but I refused. I wanted to see how far a bachelor’s degree could go, and why a bachelor’s degree shouldn’t constantly learn and take students as assistants? Yes, now I have 11 students under my guidance, this is the result of subtraction.  Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection looking back. It’s also easy to feel in your youth that everything should be obtained – if anything hasn’t been obtained, if something has a defect, you’ll feel very uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don’t learn to subtract yourselves; when you’re about to turn 30, at 28, when I saw the Olympics in 1996, I came up with a sentence: “Defect is an important part of “The moon is best when it’s not yet full. But for ordinary people, it will always be seen as a flaw, not perfect enough, not reaching the extreme. The worst way to ruin someone is to make them pursue perfection and reach the ultimate goal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;flower-not-fully-open.jpg&#34; &gt;Flower Not Fully Open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This world isn’t like that; the most wonderful time is when the flower hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully bloomed. When it’s full, it’s close to falling; when the moon starts to become full, it’s close to becoming a waning crescent. Therefore, I think this was a very important boost and inspiration for me at 30. 40 wasn’t as beautiful then. But I felt relaxed. More free. Why not stop dressing in suits and ties, why not always be black and white? Let&amp;rsquo;s start asking about happiness?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/40%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;894&#34;
	height=&#34;499&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;40 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese say that 40 is not confused, while 30 is about subtraction. 40 is about confusion, not wisdom. I think in today’s era, 40 is likely the most confused age. My midlife crisis started surprisingly early, around thirty-six or seventy, when I began to question whether everything I had done was valuable and meaningful. I wondered what happiness I truly desired. This book was born out of this confusion – you&amp;rsquo;ll find that at 30, many of your happiness goals are tied to material possessions. “Thirty and established” refers to having your education firmly in place. You need a car and a house; otherwise, your mother-in-law won’t consider marrying off your wife to you—it’s very materialistic. However, &amp;ldquo;40 is not confused&amp;rdquo; is difficult to achieve. I think ancient people had longer life expectancies than we do now, so they condensed 40 years into one, hence the lack of confusion. I&amp;rsquo;m currently 40 and feeling confused, &lt;strong&gt;and material things haven’t brought me happiness as I thought they would.&lt;/strong&gt; Similarly, when many people ask me at 40, “Are you happy?” My book title is &amp;ldquo;Happiness Waves,&amp;rdquo; which represents a question—it reflects my inner turmoil. The emergence of the midlife crisis: at 40, you need to answer yourself many questions, talk to yourself frequently, and read extensively to find answers. I’m fortunate that when I was thirty-six or seventy, I entered the world of the &lt;em&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;White Talk&lt;/em&gt;, I already discussed this; at 40, if your surroundings don&amp;rsquo;t change, especially the soft environment – if you can stroll out of the house with a good mood and encounter countless red lights—buying something is often fake, getting vaccinated is questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said that recently China has been battling two typhoons, one visible and one tangible. The invisible typhoon is vaccines, which attacks our inner security dam. The other typhoon, Chinese typhoons rarely land in Shanghai – this is a tangent; next, you need to think about whether you can focus on your own well-being. If your surroundings don’t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;I have an eight-character idiom that I find quite heavy: we are currently experiencing a deficit of morality and a loss of humanity—this is the biggest deficit and loss at present.&lt;/strong&gt; Recently, I witnessed two cars colliding; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too serious. The responsible party was because he had stopped on the side of the road, and the other driver was preparing to stop. But the car in front sped away without stopping him. Is that a responsible father? Is that a responsible son? Never mind how he would be a responsible citizen—he might even be your colleague. This is the deficit of morality and loss of humanity, which inevitably affects you. No matter how great a person you are, unless you haven’t left your home, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent your children from getting vaccinated, or sending takeout that may have problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, how can Chinese people learn to transform from an ordinary citizen into a citizen—this might be at my 40, both asking myself and posing an important question to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 30 is about subtraction, 40 is about confusion, I think 50 should be about curiosity. 50 is awkward; you’re neither in the village nor out of it – you can attack if you go forward, retreat if you go back, and blend in if you stay put. If you lie down for ten years on something you&amp;rsquo;ve achieved, perhaps until retirement, that seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I read a book that said that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley are often older—50s or 60s. This is different from our concept. How can China stop treating entrepreneurship as a young career—just like how China doesn’t treat youth volunteers as youth volunteers. Last week, I did a program to recruit retired primary and secondary school teachers; they receive a subsidy of two or three hundred thousand yuan per year and go teach in rural areas – and must be excellent. This is truly opening the door for retirees to find new employment—of course, it’s not just charity, but getting back to 50 is still a distance away. How do you move forward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/50%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;899&#34;
	height=&#34;506&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;50 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for a 50-year-old person, there are two challenges: the first is yourself – are you still curious about many things? What is your outlook on life? I think my biggest gain at 50, or the way I’m living now, is to treat every today well. Twenty years old tends to live in tomorrow, and at 50, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dwell on yesterday. But I try to restrain myself, neither living in tomorrow nor in yesterday; I treat every today well. A 50-year-old shouldn’t always say “we’ll talk about it tomorrow” or “it was better back then!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, I realize I was young once too, I had so many hair, so I should cherish every day of today, because when you look back two years later, it&amp;rsquo;s best to see yourself as you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Shen Shing said, &amp;ldquo;When my legs couldn’t walk anymore, I sat in a wheelchair and constantly reminisced about the time when I could run and play basketball. Every day was filled with pain in my memories.&amp;rdquo;
Years later, I developed bedsores on my wheelchair and felt miserable. At that time, I always remembered those peaceful moments of sitting quietly on the wheelchair.
After even more years, I got kidney failure and had to go dialysis. At that time, I would always remember the days when I only had bedsores on the wheelchair. If I hadn’t reached the point of treating every today well at 50, those next 50 years would have been wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually feel that it’s not until you reach 50 to truly understand this principle; you should grasp it in your 30s or 40s, as all things are easily missed if you wait. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a meal during a trip – if you don’t eat it, you can still have it thirty years later, and even then, it might not be the same taste. Therefore, I believe treating every day with kindness is my first feeling at 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point is curiosity. I’ve realized that I can stop being curious about many things at any time, because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so much and experienced so much, but I encourage myself to remain curious. So when I do a lot of things now, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – can you hold your phone up for a shot? Yes, you can. You can do live reporting, attend seemingly large and solemn conferences, and even make the connection easier. It’s more fun and makes a bigger impression. You can then use new media to disseminate it. I believe curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress. Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be the most important driving force for individual progress? A nation will wither if it loses its curiosity. On a broader level, 50 is an important test. What kind of vested interests do you become at forty or fifty years old in China? I’m very worried that many people around me had dreams when they were young and went to achieve them, but once they achieved their dreams and became vested interests, they turned into those who blocked others from achieving their dreams, right? They would suddenly treat young people and things in the way they used to dislike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, several years ago, I started recruiting one graduate student each year as a volunteer, and they’ve stayed for two years; now five groups have graduated, with 55 pure graduate students. I believe it&amp;rsquo;s a happy thing to become a vested interest – you have certain insights, you can also guide them. After every class, I invite them to dinner, which doesn’t cost much. But this is what a good vested interest should do: a vested interest can be two aspects—one is to pave the way again. I once said that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to say thank you too often to those who helped me, because I want to repay them tenfold with new young people. This is how I express my gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re constantly saying “thank you” and then become a blocker…&lt;/strong&gt; The next thing is to pave the way for others. I hope that in China, whether it&amp;rsquo;s material, economic, ideological, or cultural, all vested interests – when you become one, what should you do? Yesterday, someone was pushing a cart; today they’re blocking the train. This has happened throughout Chinese history. It won’t be like this; sometimes it will even be worse, so I call on all vested interests to return to how they felt when they were young – to do things as they did then. Perhaps I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, but I thought about it, did it, and said it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
