<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Repost / Share on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/repost-/-share/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Repost / Share on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 08:00:57 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/repost-/-share/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is Modern Monetary Theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. stock market’s sustained bull run is largely driven by dollar liquidity rather than America&amp;rsquo;s inherent “hard power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the 2008 financial crisis, the modern monetary system has gradually become an important theoretical cornerstone for many global economies, primarily emphasizing the subjective agency of large governments in intervening in markets. It utilizes government fiscal deficits as its main tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation. &amp;ndash;more&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the public is more familiar with regarding large government is &lt;strong&gt;Keynesianism&lt;/strong&gt;, which emphasizes the government’s role in smoothing out cyclical fluctuations – for example, suppressing overheating and stimulating contraction when it’s slowing down. It places a strong emphasis on the multiplier effect of government spending, namely how one unit of monetary stimulus can increase consumer multiplier expansion by a certain amount. When government expenditure 1 opens money, businesses and individuals increase income by 1 unit, businesses expand production and employment, and individuals expand consumption to resist economic contraction. Simultaneously, it is relatively conservative regarding fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. The &lt;strong&gt;multiplier effect&lt;/strong&gt; will drive market recovery, thereby increasing the government’s revenue, especially during the suppression of overheated cycles, which can accumulate funds for stimulating the next cycle, such as the potential debt burden and interest rate levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern monetary systems are essentially an extension of extreme Keynesianism, but with key differences. The biggest characteristic is the limitation on government debt. Central banks should not have independent autonomy; their primary objectives should be &lt;strong&gt;inflation and full employment&lt;/strong&gt;. Given that inflation is constrained by limited productive resources and technological advancements – meaning the government continuously increases purchasing power into the market through unlimited fiscal deficits as production efficiency rises with technology, ultimately reaching an ideal point of full employment and a production bottleneck – further monetary expansion would trigger inflation. At this point, they choose to cap fiscal deficits, provided there are still idle productive assets available; increasing deficits will not cause inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the Financial Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, reality is far from an ideal world; execution in each stage involves human participation, and Keynesianism is selectively applied. This leads to more economic stimulus than effective suppression, with economic overheating being used for political gains while suppressing excessive growth is lacking. It’s fundamentally difficult to restrain these issues, resulting in numerous economic problems, and even new financial crises that are no less severe than the economic shocks caused by traditional overcapacity. - The 2008 global financial crisis was, in essence, a market self-reinforcement bubble driven by extreme Keynesianism. It resulted in the proliferation of “odd-shaped” structured financial products – such as real estate and financial investments derived from it – and, crucially, a lack of risk awareness across academia, government, and markets. Debt-fueled prosperity was viewed as an achievement, and many profited from it, including massive financial systems that declared losses were the responsibility of others while announcing profits for themselves. The infamous phrase “you don’t get your money back until it’s gone” ultimately led to widespread investment and the assumption of risk by those who had benefited from earlier stages, culminating in a catastrophic outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis-1&#34;&gt;After the Financial Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was after the financial crisis that the shadow of the modern monetary system entered, characterized by rapid &lt;strong&gt;monetization of fiscal deficits and central banks’ unlimited quantitative easing&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as so-called emergency central bank lending policies. The central bank acted as the ultimate lender, supplying an endless supply of bullets, allowing governments to continue incurring debt, and coordinating with fiscal policy. The central bank supported government fiscal deficit spending through purchases of bonds, ensuring consistency of policy objectives. This is also why the boundaries between modern monetary and fiscal policies are becoming increasingly blurred – relying heavily on the central bank’s direct participation in purchasing sovereign debt, a “printing money while buying bonds” approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eurozone and the United States exhibited similar trends; in 2008, the government debt of the European Union was approximately €6. - 7 trillion euros, with a government leverage ratio of approximately 66%, slightly above the generally recognized warning line of 60%. As of 2014 – that is, during the 5-year period of the bailout – the debt scale reached 9.5 trillion euros, and the leverage rose to 93%. The United States was even more exaggerated; in 2008, U.S. government debt was approximately $10 trillion, which by 2014 had risen to around $18 trillion, and recently it again raised its government debt ceiling. Of course, each drama always used the threat of a government shutdown as a gimmick, but each time it broke through the government debt limit. Currently exceeding $36 trillion, compared to $26 trillion growth since the 2008 financial crisis. Considering the GDP growth factor, the government leverage has grown from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as the ultimate lender, played an important role in multiple rescue operations and is one of the main buyers of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaws-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;Flaws and Limitations of the Modern Monetary System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led stimulus scheme, though not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the market’s omniscience and all participants’ selfless dedication at every stage? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a simple example: if a government department increases its budget for a particular direction by 1 million, is it going to go to the mayor’s nephew or a more cost-effective market bidding process? Of course, in reality, interests will form in increasingly complex ways, leading to the result that even though the government expands debt and spending, it flows completely out of control. The recent American establishment of an Office of Efficiency is an extension of this type of problem. These issues manifest differently across varying corrupt economies; we’re focusing on discussing the more prevalent problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-inflation-issues&#34;&gt;1. Inflation Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of the modern information network, governments have a much greater grasp on market information than in the past. However, this isn’t omniscience – markets inherently contain variables and are constantly subject to change based on expectations, entering a recursive loop (“the ouroboros”). I anticipate your predictions. Taking actual performance as an example, despite the relatively successful implementation of Modern Monetary Theory between 2008 and 2020—achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stabilization, with even the Eurozone experiencing phase deflation and US inflation largely remaining within the expected 1-3% range—this led people to believe in increasingly extreme tools, much like they once believed in Keynesianism. Looking back, this was primarily due to the continued high growth trend of manufacturing in developing countries after 2008. For example, China, which gradually established itself as a global production powerhouse during this period, along with other emerging economies like Southeast Asia and India, maintained relatively high levels of industrial value added. This effectively offset the largest constraint within the Modern Monetary Theory – resource supply limitations – allowing both Europe and the United States to sustain comparatively stable inflation even amidst de-industrialization and excessive financialization, alongside increased government debt and a surge in monetary supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-inflation-issues-1&#34;&gt;1. Inflation Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the use of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States experienced relatively significant inflation, peaking at around 10%, even today, despite interest rate hikes lasting nearly three years, the U.S. labor market continues to show an abnormal overheating, and financial markets have seen a divergence from economic growth supported by monetary support, with inflation running towards 3% as the base effect disappears. This overheating phenomenon during interest rate hikes is closely related to fiscal deficits. Interest rate hikes are a contractionary monetary policy, while fiscal policy remains expansionary, compounded by the ultra-massive monetary injection of 2020, which has made U.S. inflation remarkably persistent. The biggest limitation of Modern Monetary Theory is high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-government-debt-issues&#34;&gt;2. Government Debt Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, governments can indefinitely finance debt repayment through borrowing, provided that the central bank becomes a complete puppet – meaning full alignment of monetary and fiscal policy objectives within a modern monetary system. However, the Federal Reserve is unlikely to fully cede control to the government, given the accumulated government debt balance over many years, particularly interest expenses, which are increasingly becoming a significant burden on finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2023: In fiscal year 2023, U.S. revenue totaled $4.439 trillion, with interest expense on the debt accounting for approximately 15% of that revenue.  In 2024, this high-interest environment continued, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2024: The U.S. federal government’s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments totaling $882 billion – approximately 18% of U.S. federal revenue, even exceeding Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-government-debt-issues-1&#34;&gt;2. Government Debt Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the issue of fiscal sustainability. If low interest rates and low inflation, combined with high debt (such as Japan’s), are maintained over the long term, it can indeed form an application of modern monetary theory in this way. According to the 72 rule, as long as interest rates are sufficiently low, incremental debt financing will be very slow. If the cost of capital is 1%, debt-funded growth can reach twice the debt level in 72 years. Assuming inflation breaks this delicate balance, interest payments on debt accumulate, leading to compound interest and causing future debt trajectories to spiral out of control. Principal becomes a secondary factor. If the central bank then deviates from the goals of the ruling party, these issues will become even more acute. “The Trump administration’s policy stances sharply contrasted with the Fed’s hawkish stance at the time, which was also a key factor in the escalation of relations between the government and the Fed during his term. The focus for most observers is likely whether the current chairman can successfully complete his term.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;3. Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the government’s expanded spending enters both households and businesses, leading to increased expenditure and a boost in effective demand. However, given that people are all experienced participants in numerous financial bubbles since 2000, individuals tend to exhibit a significant investment appreciation bias in their choices between investing and consuming, particularly when one or more products with extremely high expected returns appear. People will flock to the financial markets seeking higher gains, even willing to compress living standards and take on additional leverage. This is similar to what occurred during periods of high real estate growth in Japan, the United States, and China. Combining policy stimulus with the pursuit of maximum self-interest by practitioners, issues such as subprime loans are prevalent. Many so-called “rescue” policies actually encourage borrowing. Therefore, history has shown a remarkable consistency: when large-scale monetary and fiscal policies are deployed, it often results in &lt;strong&gt;a frenzy of asset bubbles and wealth redistribution&lt;/strong&gt;. Asset bubbles occur first, followed by wealth redistribution, which leads to another problem – extreme Keynesianism or Modern Monetary Theory’s persistent tendency towards economic Ponzi schemes (Minsky Moment). As long as there is hot money, asset prices continue to rise. As long as they continue to rise, it attracts later entrants holding cash, while the CPI, measuring changes in basic living expenses, doesn&amp;rsquo;t change significantly. Money circulates within specific sectors and becomes worthless for later entrants. &lt;strong&gt;After the frenzy comes the collapse&lt;/strong&gt;, which is Minsky Moment’s relentless vindication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, money itself has a supply and demand relationship. When the market supply is excessive, and traditional investment assets cannot accommodate it, or when it has been harvested too many times and cannot attract investment, such as repeatedly collapsing real estate bubbles (Japanese people haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to touch real estate investments for decades), tax policies that increase property holding taxes to reduce speculative demand, will increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation of excessive monetary supply, the market urgently needs investment assets that are &lt;strong&gt;tax-free&lt;/strong&gt;, and various virtual investment products have emerged. Even U.S. President and First Lady have come in to share a cup, one saying is to dig into the dollar wall, but in fact it&amp;rsquo;s the inevitable result of currency abuse and financial emptiness under global monetary issuance and currency credit damage, challenging the modern monetary theory’s reliance on national monopoly rights-based credit money status, even facing challenges. What kind of soil breeds what kind of financial games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, modern monetary theory and Keynesianism are more like progressive and substitutional relationships, placing a greater emphasis on government intervention in markets and adopting a more radical attitude towards fiscal deficits and the independence of central banks. Excessive use of Keynesianism led to stagflation and financial crises. Following this artificial economic overheating, modern monetary theory quietly took over after 2008. Under globalization, continued productivity gains allowed for rapid growth recovery and maintained inflation levels in using countries, but it also accumulated massive government debt and financial bubbles. When inflation rebounded, with inconsistent goals between central banks and governments, high interest rates and high leverage coexisted, significantly increasing the fiscal burden of government monetization. Fiscal sustainability was drastically reduced, and due to excessive government participation, base monetary injections led to financial bubbles. Unending money printing weakened the currency itself, appearing strong but merely a reflection of others. This also created fertile ground for various new types of speculative financial investment tools, even escaping traditional financial investment tax restrictions. This is a microcosm of the global economy. Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) may not be the future, but rather a past tense used from 2008 onwards, layered with reverse economic globalization. The more financial bubbles were inflated, the higher government debt accumulated, the more frantic the financial speculation tools became, and the greater the efficiency in achieving distorted wealth distribution – the greater the risk of a hard landing, including economic and social risks. Whether Keynesianism or MMT, no matter how much monetary supply is increased, it cannot truly solve the wealth structure problem; instead, it exacerbates risks within asset bubbles and financialization. People are constantly falling into the same pit in different postures repeatedly, but they never learn anything from it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Fee reduction, fee reduction! Domestic mega-ETFs are experiencing a large-scale fee reduction.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 03:08:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ping An Blockchain ETF et al. announced a reduction in the overall fee rate to the lowest level among peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 19th, China Merchants Bank Fund announced that, to better meet the investment and financial needs of investors, starting from November 22nd, it will reduce the management fees and custodian fees of Huatai Baorong Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its affiliated funds, and revise relevant content in the fund contracts.
&lt;strong&gt;After the adjustment, the annual management fee for Huatai Baorong Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its affiliated funds is reduced to 0.15%, the annual custodian fee is reduced to 0.05%, all set to the lowest fee level among index funds.&lt;/strong&gt;
Almost simultaneously, leading in size in the industry, China Merchants HuRun Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, China Merchants Shanghai Stock 50 ETF, Nanfang Zhongce 500 ETF, Guangxi Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, Yifada Entrepreneurial Board ETF et al. also announced a reduction in management and custodian fees, with all rates reduced to 0.15% and 0.05%. Unlike most ETFs experiencing fee cuts, this time the reduction was spearheaded by market-leading actively-traded products with significant scale advantages. This is expected to have a substantial impact on the industry going forward. Exchange data shows that as of November 18th, the size of Greater China Fund’s CSI 300 ETF exceeded 370 billion yuan, making it currently the largest ETF in terms of assets under management. The largest batch of super ETFs initiated fee cuts, demonstrating their willingness to offer value to investors and allowing investors to invest in popular and liquid funds at a higher cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry experts believe that the reduction in expense ratios for large-scale ETFs will, on one hand, facilitate the public fund industry’s role in providing inclusive financial services, enabling investors to reduce holding costs and enhance their potential returns and investment satisfaction on a larger scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, low fee rates will also further improve the competitiveness of the products themselves. With the added benefits of liquidity diversion and cost operation advantages, these products are expected to attract more medium-to-long-term incremental capital into the market, helping to build a healthy ecosystem for “long money, long investment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, broad-based ETFs have become the primary channel for funds entering at low levels and engaging in “long money, long investment” due to their unique advantages such as flexible trading, high transparency, strong liquidity, and low investment barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fee reduction may serve as an &amp;ldquo;accelerator,&amp;rdquo; making it easier for long-term capital to enter the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the Tianhong Fund that I invested in hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet released an announcement, it should be followed up on. If no update is provided, I will consider switching funds.
Original Management Fee: 0.5%, Custody Fee: 0.1%. New Management Fee: 0.15%, Custody Fee: 0.05%. This reduction is quite significant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Third-party custodian regulation is intensifying, and the behind-the-scenes winners of the ‘Douyin Stock Trading’ incident are facing a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.
Following the wind of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.
In late September this year, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, recommendations on Douyin (TikTok) have attracted attention from various parties.
Leading financial commentators on Douyin have risen to prominence, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.
However, the rapid rise of these financial commentators is not to be ignored – it’s largely driven by third-party investment advisory firms.
According to reports, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (PV) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding advisory products.
There are even rumors that one third-party investment advisory firm generated revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half revenue this year.
But “good times” are facing more uncertainties. Since November, multiple departments have successively issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliant management of their self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 15th, Tianhong Securities (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in behavior such as hinting at recommending stocks through livestreaming operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be signaling to the market a stricter regulatory approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion prospects of third-party investment advisory service institutions, such as JiuFang ZhiTu (9636.HK), are also likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tight-regulation-monitoring&#34;&gt;Tight Regulation Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant League of Finance’s monitoring, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under such circumstances, the “pushing and pulling” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of investment advisors recommending stocks through various means during live broadcasts is a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend new clients for a company that was found to be “hinting at stock recommendations” during a livestream. On November 14th, the Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 (Guangdong Securities and Futures Association) issued a notice titled “Live Streaming Control Lapses, Institutions Suspended Business,” directly addressing instances where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications exhibited inadequate control during live streaming operations. The notice also cited instances of recommending individual stocks within the live streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The practice of recommending stocks through live streaming is strictly prohibited. Given that live streaming constitutes public media dissemination, all livestream presenters – regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors – shall not recommend individual stocks during live broadcasts.” The Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Stock Exchange also disclosed a penalty notice detailing one case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated industry norms by publishing misleading videos via WeChat Video Account, which contradicted professional standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tight-regulation-monitoring-1&#34;&gt;Tight Regulation Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to information obtained by Wind (ID: TradeWind01), some ineligible investment advisory firms were using “front-running” brokers (ID:TradeWind01) on Douyin (TikTok) to recommend stocks, and they have since been suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Industry insiders are livestreaming, but in reality, they’re operating under the umbrella of a broker, which granted them investment advisor qualifications. They then use these livestreams to generate leads and sell advisory product bundles,” said a consultant from South China who spoke to Wind (ID: TradeWind01). “However, because they were recommending stocks during the livestream, it was discovered, leading to their suspension. Regular brokers typically discuss sector trends in investor education livestreams but wouldn’t delve into individual stocks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are maintaining close scrutiny of illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms. For example, recent notices from the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Commission have revealed that some individual institutions or individuals are engaging in illegal stock promotion through self-media, among other violations. To further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies within its jurisdiction, all institutions must strengthen their company’s self-media management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for third-party wealth management service providers&amp;rsquo; business expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-a-scam&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is a Scam
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors attracted by short videos have made money remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As China’s “first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence has seen its market capitalization rise from 2878 million yuan on September 9th to 12464 million yuan as of November 13th, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report shows that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by June 30th, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhu” (commonly known as “Hong”) has amassed 2.26 million followers on Douyin (TikTok).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on the user-centric approach and synergistically promoting the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products.” “Nine Fang Intelligence Investment pointed out, “By deeply integrating new media tools such as live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant course packages cover a price range from several hundred yuan to over ten hundred thousand yuan. The most expensive package, ‘Super Investor,’ priced at 1396,000 yuan for six months, includes exclusive insights and private consulting services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant products have a return rate of over 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the return rates for the flagship series and ‘Nine Fang Intelligent Dragon’ series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the impact of regulatory headwinds on Nine Fang Intelligence Investment&amp;rsquo;s business development remains to be observed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports have stated that accounts belonging to third-party custodians such as Jiu Fang Zhi Tu have been affected recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a report by a media outlet stated that &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; (洪帮主) was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th at 3:00 PM, Xin Feng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the “Hong Bangzhu” livestream interface still allowed bookings for a livestream on November 18th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market news indicated that relevant departments have intervened in Jiu Fang Zhi Tu’s inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a source close to Jiu Fang Zhi Tu told Xin Feng (ID:TradeWind01) that the investigation was a routine check and had already concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company caught up in the rumors surrounding this regulatory storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities has been investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may be suspended from operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th that “there was no illegal stock recommendation situation and no investigation.” “However, that evening, Tianhe Securities announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tianhe Securities Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau for violations during its livestreaming promotional activities, specifically due to inadequate compliance controls and instances of hinting at recommended stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also signify a further escalation in regulatory scrutiny regarding stock recommendations on social media platforms like Douyin (TikTok) Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the short video market is attracting many brokerage firms, but due to compliance requirements, brokers are currently being cautious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-forbidden&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is Forbidden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told Wind Info (ID:TradeWind01) that the company was exploring short video operations and lead generation methods, and had organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning. However, due to regulatory compliance requirements, it is currently in an exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements, is because short video content has a distinctly emotional color. But investors need to maintain rationality when dealing with it, and there is a natural conflict between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If emotional forces influence capital markets, it can easily trigger violent market fluctuations, which goes against the long-term healthy development of capital markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What way should securities firms embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “crossing the red line”? It’s clearly a difficult question for all parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why do computers generally use little-endian storage?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 10:43:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/little-endian-storage-why/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Regarding byte order: A layman&amp;rsquo;s explanation &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://example.com/post/2023/01-10-%e4%b8%bb%e6%9c%ba%e5%ba%8f%e3%80%81%e7%bd%91%e7%bb%9c%e5%ba%8f%ef%bc%8c%e9%80%9a%e8%bf%87%e8%b0%83%e8%af%95%e5%99%a8%ef%bc%8c%e7%9b%b4%e6%8e%a5%e8%a7%82%e5%af%9f&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Host Order, Network Order, observed directly through debugger&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the field of computer science, certain design habits have formed due to historical reasons, just like the width of a person&amp;rsquo;s buttocks determines the width of a rocket’s thrusters – there’s no need to rigidly analyze their “advantages” and “disadvantages”; it’s simply a matter of historical convention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;original-link&#34;&gt;Original Link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Author: Beiji (North Pole)
Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zhihu.com/question/637413724/answer/3346032134&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.zhihu.com/question/637413724/answer/3346032134&lt;/a&gt;
Source: Zhihu
Copyright belongs to the author. For commercial reprints, please contact the author for permission. Non-commercial reprints must indicate the source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text-translation&#34;&gt;Text Translation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nowadays, the current situation is a result of historical habits + commercialization, and has little to do with technology itself. ARM can be set up in big-endian or little-endian format. The TCP/IP header still uses big-endian (network byte order). There are also many storage protocols/specifications in the storage field that save data in a big-endian manner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the three questions posed by the user seem to be incorrect in today&amp;rsquo;s view:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why do computers generally adopt little-endian storage? –&amp;gt; Incorrect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why is low-byte storage more efficient in a little-endian way than in a big-endian way? –&amp;gt; Efficiency will not be higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Any argument about these three questions using current technology belongs to shooting first and drawing the target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;translated-text&#34;&gt;Translated Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, when it comes to the choice between big-endian and little-endian, there were indeed certain objective factors in the history of computer development: The advantage of host byte order (little-endian) is that little-endian adders are easier to implement. If you create an 8-bit * 4 adder, you only need one 8-bit adder and sequentially add all bytes from low to high. The carry circuit is very simple. In contrast, if using big-endian, you would need to load a 32-bit value at once, otherwise it wouldn’t be possible to perform calculations. Looking back now, the difference between loading 8 bits or 32 bits is not significant; however, in the decades of the past, memory prices were high, so simplicity was paramount. Therefore, the host byte order selection for little-endian was based on cost considerations. The advantages of network big-endian byte order: In the early days, caches on devices were very small. Receiving the high byte first allowed for a quick determination of message information: packet length (how much cache to prepare), address range (IP addresses are matched from front to back). Early network devices’ caches were at the byte level; taking the high byte first was indeed slightly faster. Therefore, network devices used big-endian due to cost considerations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the choice of byte order was primarily influenced by application scenarios and costs (such as PPC/MIPS being more suitable for networking equipment), while later technological developments were driven by compatibility reasons, leading to the continued use of big-endian. In today’s view, these advantages no longer exist; they are simply historical habits.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The future of China will undoubtedly be a China of good elders and good old people.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that twenty years from now, I’ll be a cute old man, spending time with a cute old woman. I don&amp;rsquo;t seek great wealth or status; just to be healthy and strong enough to travel and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I said that in 10 years, I’d be a charming old man, and I would work hard to become a charming old man. The future of China will definitely have good old men and women. Even if I&amp;rsquo;m 60 in 10 years, I’ll be the youngest in the world’s third-rate society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, if everyone sees 50-year-old Chinese men with this physique, it would be pretty impressive. But behind this physique is a saying I believe: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! When the rain stops, I want to go running; tomorrow afternoon I’ll play soccer. At 50 years old, I can still play big games – it&amp;rsquo;s not a joke, and I often play with professionals. But what’s behind all of this? “Behind it is autonomy. The remaining days I spend running, and people might find that very monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I can run freely, never listening to music – because I feel my own breath is the most beautiful music while running.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I rarely run on the treadmill. Also, many people in Beijing experience smog as severe as that, so I run five days a week, with two days dedicated to the smog. And unlike others, I jokingly say it’s probably because I never stop. Each month, I record my runs in my journal – drawing one day for every day of experience, at least 18 days per month. When running, they just flash by; I don&amp;rsquo;t even wear glasses while running, but more importantly, I still kick a ball every week. My graduate students’ last lecture was always held at our home—on the theme of “fun.” I find fun incredibly important, and I never engage with people who lack joy or hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I first started teaching a few years ago, one of my graduate students was featured in &lt;em&gt;China News Weekly&lt;/em&gt;. We had a special issue called “Zhi” (致 – meaning “letter to”), and ten years later, when my student graduated each year, the final assignment he would complete was writing an article for me ten years down the line. I’d keep it, and then I’d gradually develop it with them as they progressed, including writing one myself at 50 for those turning 60 – something I never imagined happening so far away, beyond the map. But suddenly, it became my next stop: writing to 20-year-olds for 30-year-olds. That was a love letter written in spring, but my 50-year-old piece for 60 was more like summer’s farewell whispered to autumn – a private monologue. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m writing to them ten years later, slowly constructing it from all over the world, as if crafting it for their own bed, a meal, and the presence of their family. This feels entirely natural.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what kind of person will I be at 60 years old? My topic is very clear: In a pleasant introduction, this article is long. I say that in 10 years, I will be a lovable old man, and I want to work hard to become a lovable old man. China wanting to be lovable isn&amp;rsquo;t just about having more like-minded citizens who become citizens, not just ordinary young people, energetic young people who understand the rules, young people who will make a good China in the future. Currently, over 60 million people in China have already exceeded 2.3 billion, and it will definitely exceed three billion within 10 years. That means that solely based on the population of those over 60, China could be among the top five or even third countries in the world. Think about how frightening that is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel that way myself. - I don’t know if everyone has seen the online table today listing the average lifespans of all provinces and municipalities in China. Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years, including an average for both men and women. Naturally, men still have a significant disadvantage in terms of lifespan. That means that even if I&amp;rsquo;m 60 years old in ten years, I’d be one of the youngest in this world. Looking ahead… If women retire at 55 and live another 25 years until an average age of 80, and men retire at 60 and live another 20 years until an average age of 80! You need to do something other than just dancing square dances. And I can say that the grandmothers and uncles who dance square dances today are cultural habits and entertainment methods brought about by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even in 20 years, the next generation may still have many people dancing square dances, but they will be significantly reduced. This is because the next generation are no longer active participants in collective activities, just like older generations who enjoy traveling in tour groups – now young people are increasingly choosing independent and self-guided travel. Square dancing will continue to exist in the future, but its scope will undoubtedly shrink; there’s neither good nor bad about this, it&amp;rsquo;s simply a reshuffling of the times as it constantly evolves. When I was 60, I was one of the youngest members of the team. What kind of person should I be? The Chinese saying goes that 60 is when your ears become attuned – I believe I wouldn’t have listened to anything and been happy, even when I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been, and even then I would have felt unhappy. More importantly, what should I do for the young people! What should we do for good things? - Not lazy, not easily compromising; it’s important to oppose when necessary. Young people could harm his interests – can you stand in front of them? I&amp;rsquo;ve been constantly looking at this mirror lately. My good friend, Tao Wei, used to often gather with us, including at our home, and he once told me a genuine story. We collectively mourned together. The older generation, like Chen Lao Dai, kept everything stored within their homes, saying things out of the blue, hiding 30-odd items under the bed – you need to tell him that this garment cost over 500 yuan, and then we started supporting him financially, lighting incense every day. Therefore, this generation has grown accustomed to battling our parents for knowledge and wisdom; how much did a garment costing over 700 yuan cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-4&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;220&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it’s easy to get into trouble. Tao Wei once bought a T-shirt for his dad for over 400 yuan. That T-shirt was really good, how much did it cost? “99,” I wore it. The next day, disaster struck. When he came back in the evening, he praised Tao Wei for taking a picture and giving him 400 yuan, asking him to buy four more for me. Afterwards, everyone who saw me wearing it, including Zhang and Li Da Ye, thought it was great, and then said that the risk of lying like this was very large. In the future, you shouldn’t do this. I don&amp;rsquo;t specifically mention which person was in the orthopedic department of the hospital when an elderly person fractured a bone, and the most important reason was discovered – they bought shoes from a street stall. Of course, I’m only talking about this on a material level; even as we get older, we still need mental stimulation, curiosity, and a willingness to shield young people from the wind and rain, living each day happily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious and excitedly waiting for my 60th birthday to arrive, because I think it’s the beginning of a beautiful time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18 years old is probably different from yours.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very common phrase &lt;strong&gt;information fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – since graduating from high school, aside from the time I spent reading novels, I haven’t really taken the time to sit down and read a book quietly and attentively for a long time. Sometimes, looking back, after so many years working, I still remember what I did each year? Often, by the middle of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten a lot of things from the first half. Writing a blog is a good habit, even though much of what I write isn’t appropriate and doesn’t matter – it was originally written for myself to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal readers are myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of one’s 18 years is like a gaze of expectation and questioning. Each person occasionally takes their own 18th birthday to ask themselves, “Are you the way you wanted to live back then?” I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that nowadays everyone has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, nobody to have a heart-to-heart conversation, knowledge acquisition is endless, but far from wisdom. Everyone should use your 18th birthday to ask yourself, it’s too easy to deceive others, but very difficult to deceive yourself!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think each of one’s 18 years is like a gaze of expectation and questioning. You can deceive others, but you cannot deceive your 18-year-old self. Is today you the way you were going to be at 18? I think it&amp;rsquo;s okay. - Today, material fame and countless other things are valued far more than what I, at 18, could have imagined. However, on the other hand, we’re always moving forward. When I was 18, I was studying journalism at the Broadcasting Academy, and I wanted to become like Farquhar – the best journalist. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path, which is why many people say, “How can White still be on CCTV?” because I want to be a good journalist. The pursuit of news continues. This is my 18-year-old perspective, so I think everyone should occasionally ask themselves: Are you the person you originally wanted to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is something you can’t fool anyone with. This is what I looked like at 18, and it&amp;rsquo;s just gone in an instant – 32 years have passed. Every student who came to Beijing to study at that time would have this same photo. Back then, the crumpled suits on Tianmen Square, the school badge pinned to your chest – because there were so few university students back then, no badges, you felt incredibly proud. We had long hair back then, but we still loved our 18-year-old selves. Looking back after all these years, I suddenly realize that I’m grateful for the things I faced at 18, because they shaped me silently. It was May 8th, 1986, and I bought a selection of Misty Poems at Wangfujing Bookstore that year. And today, I suddenly realized that my writing style has been most influenced by Cui Jian’s “One Evening,” which I heard at the Workers&amp;rsquo; Stadium. It’s had the biggest impact on me – including the fact that my personality was shaped by Misty Poetry, rock music, and Lu Guofu’s martial arts novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you go through at 18? Here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You might carry what essentials you need for a trip. I especially want to know what 18-year-olds are experiencing today? Are they being carved away like with an axe, relentlessly shaping themselves? But what tools did he use? What kind of image did it create? I’m afraid that everyone now has countless social media circles, yet no one has a genuine friend to talk to. Knowledge acquisition is limitless, but far from wisdom – knowing everything and yet knowing nothing. It seems like everyone is claiming to be unique, but as an observer, I find that young people are remarkably similar. What should I put them through at 18? I really admire 1986 because it’s the best way to resolve 1966.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1966, the Cultural Revolution ended after 76 years of defeating the Gang of Four – it was largely accidental. It could only be truly achieved through the enlightenment and awakening of human nature and the growth of every individual. I believe we still need to go through a period of enlightenment and fully understand human nature. Regardless of how much economic progress China makes, if we don’t genuinely fill in this understanding of humanity – then guide it, control its darker side, and activate its good side – there will continue to be many things to worry about in the future. So my 18th year was also representative of that era; it went too far, but we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget why we started out. It’s now been condensed into these four words: “Don’t Lose Your Original Intent.” So, I think regardless of how far you go, everyone should ask themselves what their 18-year-old self would think. It’s good to keep a photo from that time and often ask yourself, “What do others say? Does it matter?” It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to fool others than to fool yourself. I just said to a 20-year-old today, based on my own 18 years, you should always let your 18-year-old be the eyes watching you. And as I also mentioned earlier, in your twenties, go try many doors – you don’t know which one is right for you. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising in China now to often see older people in their twenties and lots of younger people in their seventies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalist does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This excerpt recounts the author’s perspective on the profession of journalism, emphasizing that reporters should possess a social conscience, extensive knowledge, and perseverance. The author also shares their reflections at age 50, including maintaining curiosity, balancing material and spiritual pursuits, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best journalist is first, having a social conscience; second, possessing knowledge; and third, being able to run long distances. I couldn’t handle running 100 meters – I ran it. I believe these three things combined, people expect the safety concerns surrounding vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the formula milk scandal. We always solve problems after they arise, completely resolving them, and moving forward in this logical cycle. Otherwise, what is there for a journalist to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe the best journalist first has a social conscience, second has knowledge reserves, and third can run long distances – I’ve stopped being intimidated by 100 meters; I&amp;rsquo;ve been running. I think these three things combined explain why I feel suited to journalism at my age of 50. I’m naturally intertwined with China’s reform for the past 40 years. When I turned 30, standing on the banks of the Songhua River, and when I turned 40, my birthday coincided with the 2008 Olympics – I went in during the live broadcast and came out during the broadcast. Now at 50, as the nation commemorates 40 years of reform and opening up, it’s certainly a corresponding moment: if the “Great Era” is at 40, what about China&amp;rsquo;s reform at 40 – is it a period of confusion or enlightenment? “Looking at China after 40 years of development, it has already given people and the country a tremendous amount in terms of material wealth. However, anxiety and confusion have increased rather than decreased. We thought that becoming strong and wealthy meant everything was okay, but we realized that material prosperity is just a foundation. It’s easy to escape poverty materially, but truly becoming prosperous spiritually and emerging as a major power is incredibly difficult. The United States is now targeting our high-tech industries – we need to target agricultural products. There&amp;rsquo;s always this saying in the world: it&amp;rsquo;s hard for number two to become number one! How many ‘second’ iPhones did America fix? Therefore, we must undergo a long period of time transforming ‘number two’ into something that surpasses ourselves. I can’t get everything; I need to focus on what I can truly achieve.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to start working in television at 25, beginning with person interviews. I came into contact with hundreds or even thousands of figures who carried various halos and reputations. Back then, as a young man, I thought these halos must have made them incredibly happy. But when I got closer, I realized no, the halos had little to do with their happiness, and sometimes they were even inversely proportional. Recently, I finished watching Guo Mo’er&amp;rsquo;s last 29 years. Guo Mo’er barely escaped persecution throughout his life, holding positions like Deputy Vice Premier, Vice Chairman of the CPPCC, and Honorary Vice Chairman. But did he find happiness? Did he have a happy life considering his two sons committed suicide and another was possibly pushed to death from a building?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? When you’re in your sixties or seventies, if you lose two sons in a few years, can that make you happy? “Having many famous calligraphy and paintings can bring happiness, allowing oneself to spend many years safely – what do you need? I think reading people is the best mirror. To put it briefly, I feel that much of our current anxiety comes from thinking too much and not reading enough books. This is Yang Geng Lan’s reply to a young man: if you don&amp;rsquo;t read books, you rely on fast food; just pick up a phone and try to find a quick fix. How can that be possible? I learned how to be clever through the slow, cumbersome process of reading a book; subtraction comes from reducing the number of books one reads – the more one reads, the less one needs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I don’t expect everyone to be able to read the best version of themselves through reading, but I hope the proportion increases – that more and more Chinese people can develop themselves better through reading. No one sits on the ground and looks up at the sky, trying to figure out everything; I cannot do that. But I can look in a mirror. A few years ago, a BBC news anchor came to Beijing, claiming to be the BBC’s most outstanding news anchor, and a well-meaning person organized a dialogue between him and a Chinese news anchor at the International Hotel. During our conversation, he asked me a question: “Do you think the BBC should learn from CCTV?” I first made a joke and said, &amp;ldquo;Of course, they should first learn Chinese.&amp;rdquo; Then, after making the joke, I said, &amp;ldquo;The BBC should most of all learn the world’s curiosity. We&amp;rsquo;ve rapidly gone to the world in recent years…&amp;rdquo; Here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have various bureaus, currently exceeding 70. We feel that whenever a student sees something new from abroad, they are incredibly curious. We observe the world with this immense curiosity, and BBC has already considered Britain itself to be global – you&amp;rsquo;ve lost that sense of wonder. Older brother is right, what we lack is precisely this. In 2007, when I interviewed a Japanese writer for him, he said about Japan, ‘Besides lacking hope, it has everything else.’ Later, I realized the depth of his words. From another angle, ten years ago, I felt that China lacked everything except hope – everyone believed there was a future ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-4&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But won’t one day we also become a wealthy nation that only desires everything? To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m very worried that China will end up being a negative one – when you have everything, you realize how truly poor you are. When I’m 50 years old, I fear becoming someone who can satisfy all material conditions but is incredibly impoverished. In our reality, there are many highly educated people with no culture, and there are many poor people with countless numbers on their bank accounts – this is the problem of this era. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t frightening because there’s a forward direction and hope. This is why I say that a lack of morality and human flaws are the root causes. That’s why I think scientists invented so much not because they initially carried great missions, but out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I figure out how to make it? “So I’ve always started to urge myself to be more curious around the age of 50, so I’m very happy. The one thing that’s currently bothering me is persistence. When you were just talking about ‘you’re still persisting,’ I said, ‘Don’t say that – once you persist, you’re close to death.’ We used to say that persistence equals success, and if Chinese football just persisted through the ‘black three minutes’ – if they just kept at it – it was all about perseverance. But without method or fun, it became a matter of simply persisting. Sometimes persistence is important, but often this saying has two sides. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that when I do something, like talking to people, I’ll persist and finish what I started, even though my time is now up. But I’m curious, and I want to see how my conversations with others will turn out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-5&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Give yourself a very small keyword, but engage in conversations with people. I think that at 50 years old, as long as you can maintain a great deal of curiosity, there’s no problem, I like all fun things, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to be the most popular thing today. Today’s trends might disappear overnight. There are always trending words every year; do you remember some of them? Could some media on the internet 10 years from now become traditional media? So, fun things will always have their own inherent appeal, and I respect everyone&amp;rsquo;s likes – there must be a reason for it. But when you look at it in the long run, you’ll find that Chinese people still like to play mahjong the most. When you also like eating fast food, then restaurants serving large meals will naturally start to close down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things are not just about expressing feelings and moving on. How much fragmented reading do you get from your daily mobile phone use? How much longer-form reading do you have? But this is also a process, and the phone is becoming our handcuffs. So I feel that people are increasingly consuming shorter things, which leads to people gradually becoming short-sighted, but this is also a process – I never worry about content being king. It will always return. You’ll keep entertaining yourself to death every day, until you&amp;rsquo;re 40 years old, just like when I see teenagers drinking soda, and I try to tell them to drink less, but you know they will inevitably drink it. However, on the other hand, I’m optimistic – he will eventually return to the world of tea. This is a typical Chinese life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly normal, but I hope this transition happens faster. We’re just expressing an observation: investigative journalism has become so rare these days, and people don’t read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will Chinese football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The supplementary reader responses were largely written on a whim in 2021. The timing of Wang Yi’an’s speeches being transcribed was just as the pandemic was beginning. Don&amp;rsquo;t say twenty years later, or even one year or two later – the world is always beyond people’s expectations. Now that China’s epidemic has ended, overseas epidemics are still causing trouble. Regarding football, Chinese national team played quite well in recent years; the coach dared to give them free rein and attack, which was much better than when they were just starting out. Watching a national team game made even grandpa bored enough to change channels – what kind of experience is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Curious, very curious, what could be any different? So you find that Chinese football plays badly because many people are afraid to lose the ball in their own area and pass it to others, so they’re done for themselves – there&amp;rsquo;s no such way of playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one of many small reasons. When talking about 20 years of football, 20 years from now China football seems incredibly distant. The first expansion became 48 teams, and it&amp;rsquo;s possible China might go, but it’s still possible they won’t. The best age range for a national team is 26-30; so 20 years from now that would be children aged 6 to 10 – I find that very optimistic, but 20 years later it will definitely work. When I talk about children aged 6-10 today, you immediately become serious. It’s cause and effect: what are we planting today? What kind of beans are we growing if we plant them today? We almost planted soybeans for the national team – what would they grow into? Whoever initiates this action, they should prepare to be removed from the game – it’s a violation of the rules, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t dwell on it. But you really should think about today’s children aged 6-10; are they playing soccer? You just know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ethical deficit, erosion of humanity</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the English translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To do things properly, first and foremost, you need to have a clear conscience. This allows you to sleep soundly, without minor ailments or major issues. It&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid making mistakes in the first place. If you do make a mistake, it should be about trying to rectify it, not concealing it or hoping to forget it yourself – humans are also capable of excellent memory. Inner peace is the destination; being able to answer your own questions with integrity allows you to live more lightly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjQ4NA==.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;. If there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this text; this document is solely for translating the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight words to say that are quite heavy – I feel we’re currently experiencing a moral deficit, a depletion of human nature, and a logical cycle where problems arise and need to be solved, ultimately resolved completely. You need patience to wait for this process of upheaval. For a country like China, many things are a slow process of sorting out. So don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic about change; it’s undergoing a cleansing/reshuffle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, China has been battling two typhoons – one is intangible and the other is tangible. The intangible typhoon is the vaccine, which is impacting our inner security dam. The other typhoon hasn’t frequently landed in Shanghai, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t caused Beijing and Tianjin to suffer; it’s a rare event for three directly-administered cities to face a storm together that hasn’t occurred in decades. This is off-topic. What you’re going to be thinking about next is whether your own self-improvement and significant changes – having many answers – will make you happy if the surrounding environment remains unchanged. I have eight words to express this heavily: we currently suffer from a moral deficit and a loss of humanity, which is the biggest deficit and greatest loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, people were expecting the safety risks of vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the initial formula scandal. So sometimes you need to look at history and understand that you know about the establishment and formation of a complete legal framework for the US Food and Drug Administration, which is closely related to the initial unsafe formula and dairy products. Therefore, the Sanlu milk powder incident forced China to undergo significant changes in the dairy industry. While vaccines aren&amp;rsquo;t going to be one after another, I hope this time it’s a halt. You need to know that times always move forward through a logical cycle of problems being identified and completely resolved, otherwise what do journalists do? What do citizens do?
I think we can all do is care. But the problem is that Chinese people are too easily forgetful. “As I just said, after hitting someone’s car and then speeding off the side of the road, a whole vehicle of people didn&amp;rsquo;t stop to intervene. A large proportion of our neighbors and colleagues are like that – people who behave this way. So we need to gradually change that. And as ordinary citizens, the things we can do is pay attention, not forget. I don’t think it’s a lack of something; when you’re hungry and cold, and you spend your days talking about ideals, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have any persuasive power. But once they’ve eaten and are warm, if they let themselves become the world’s number one country for diabetes, number one for hypertension, and so many other ‘number one’ countries… then you’ll see Chinese people starting to run and start dieting. And when you ask the ladies in this audience, who hasn&amp;rsquo;t experienced the brutal experience of not being able to lose weight because I couldn’t afford a decent meal?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spiritual aspect we’ve been discussing is also the same. When you’re well-fed and warm, and start running or dieting, your need for spirit will gradually increase as well. For example, I used to smoke, but one day after starting to run, I suddenly realized I hadn&amp;rsquo;t smoked in 20 days – not at all. I haven’t smoked since. Of course, I wouldn’t deliberately say, “I’ve completely quit!” because I think it lacks a certain ceremony; it doesn’t rule out smoking two or three cigarettes during the year. When your lifestyle changes, many things will change along with it. I believe that for Chinese people, you need to be patient and wait for the upheaval. More and more people feel unhappy and unwilling to indulge themselves in unhappiness. “While depression is increasing, on the other hand, isn’t it also seeing more and more people seeking positive ways to live? At this time, things related to the mental aspect will grow, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic; how you look at the same thing matters. I often see people cutting in line while driving, and I feel frustrated, but then I quickly become optimistic because the queue on the other side is longer than before. This is a process like this – all of you, gathered here tonight after the rain has stopped, willingly engaging in so much pointless conversation… isn’t that a wonderful thing?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is also a transformation, so there are many things that need to be thought about in a different way. Of course, I think there will be much to learn in the future, such as when you talk about starting a business – is everyone an entrepreneur? Everyone’s life is an entrepreneurial one. We’re giving too much of a time-sensitive element to entrepreneurship, but entrepreneurship has always been around. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Su Shi (Su Dongpo) an entrepreneur? Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Li Bai an entrepreneur? Everyone will have many innovations throughout their lives, and ultimately they created their own brand. It doesn’t matter if most innovations don’t come to fruition, as long as you live a life that is rich in flavor and you believe it’s worth it. I think China particularly lacks good failure as another value of success. People only accept successful outcomes, but a good failure is also a success, and we don&amp;rsquo;t accept that. “I think that’s going to be very difficult, so you see why Chinese football isn&amp;rsquo;t played well has many reasons, and one of those reasons is that everyone is afraid to lose the ball after passing it to someone else – they just let it go. If there wasn’t this kind of play, of course, that’s only a very small part of the reason. So I think as I get to my age, by 30, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to write about ‘Transparent Happiness’ and can’t be rushed, and now at 50, there’s a bit of urgency because time is passing so quickly, and you expect many things that haven’t become reality. But on the other hand, I also understand that for a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process. You see older generations – some were completely oblivious to anything, but occasionally you&amp;rsquo;ll see children pulling their fathers along as they change. They’re changing, they’re being shuffled around, so I think you need to be patient.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Regarding time, you need to read a lot of books to find the answers.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In general, the country is getting better and stronger economically, becoming wealthier. This wouldn’t be true without the diminishing of personal vanity. Looking back from the 1990s to now, in the families I&amp;rsquo;ve encountered, people’s lives have generally improved significantly. Simultaneously, the number of wealthy individuals has increased. During the development of market-oriented economics, it is unavoidable that wealth gaps have widened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commonly discussed phenomena like class solidification and blocked upward mobility are global trends. The Communist Party’s contributions to basic welfare benefits and social security should also be noted. Things will get better and better, you don’t need to buy a house; you can rent one. Children&amp;rsquo;s education also faces issues with unequal resource allocation, sometimes requiring compromises – do you want better job opportunities, a better work environment, or more time to spend with family? Don’t impose your own ideas on others, including your child and family members. Sit down and talk it over; life will inevitably get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;, if there is any infringement, please contact the author to delete this article, this text is only for the translation of the transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/30%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;503&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;30 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now 50 years old this year, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about it in the past. I felt like an old man. Now I realize that I really am an old man. This is what I looked like at 30. When you’re 30, you don’t feel very young or beautiful, but when you look back at 50, it&amp;rsquo;s actually pretty good. What was the biggest life lesson at 30? Looking back. I think it’s subtraction – the key word is subtraction.  Some pain and happiness are also a kind of subtraction; you want to experience and write down many things, then leave them there, on a new blank sheet, or go for a run. But for me, at 30, I really feel that whether it&amp;rsquo;s for myself or for others, doing subtraction is very important. I’m currently a student carrying heavy loads – I often remind them, “Before you turn 30, you need to be adding relentlessly, trying things out; you don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of possibilities you have, and you don&amp;rsquo;t know what opportunities fate will offer.” So it’s not about knowing, but some people are working tirelessly in their twenties, constantly adding, but they forget to subtract when they reach a certain point. I think around 30 is a very important time in life – after doing a series of additions and wandering around everywhere, you should take the time to subtract; otherwise, it’s too late. Why do you need to subtract? Not everything suits you, and not everything is suitable for you. You should try to do everything.
Eight lines are tethering you – how far can you run? They might hinder each other.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;%e5%bb%89%e4%bb%b7.jpg&#34; &gt;Cheap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At thirty years old, I had been promoted to a full professorship – in academic terms. For journalism, it’s equivalent to a senior reporter. I was promoted to a full professorship at 29, and such promotions have become rare these days. However, at that time, I began to feel a tremendous sense of confusion. When the Sydney Olympics were held in 2000, I received a lot of applause, but suddenly I realized something wasn’t right. I started asking myself, “What exactly do you want to do? What things need to be discarded?” That year, I made a very important subtraction – I stopped my show and didn&amp;rsquo;t appear on television for a year, without any external appearances. People told me that as a host, you can get by if you don’t appear on screen for a month, but if you don’t appear for six months, no one will remember you. I said, “My face is quite valuable.” That year, I began to develop new programs. “This was after going through immense pain and joy, and in 2001, I stopped for an entire year. Everything I’m doing today is a reflection of that time – a process of simplification (doing less). Back then, I could do so much: I could pursue sports, I could get into E [likely referring to electronic music/entertainment], and many other fun things, even produce shows. But I said no. I realized I could only do journalism, and it was what I was truly meant to do. At the time, I was producing three segments, and I quit them all overnight, which led to who I am today. I became simpler. A few days ago, talking with colleagues, I even mentioned how a very important decision I made when I was in my thirties – not just because of all the opportunities available, but because I felt that I should simply stick to journalism, and this deep well [likely referring to dedication to the profession]… many positions could have promoted me to deputy director. I rejected it, and returned to a common citizen’s level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/undergraduate.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Undergraduate&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, I’ve been working with provincial-level cadres and party officials, none of whom are exclusively graduates of undergraduate programs – they aren&amp;rsquo;t all solely from bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degrees among the masses. You understand our system, but I refuse to participate. I wanted to see how far a bachelor’s degree could take someone, and why a bachelor’s degree shouldn’t be limited to continuous learning and mentoring graduate students. Yes, I currently mentor 11 graduate students per year – this is a reduction in numbers. I think it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection on that feeling of looking back. Furthermore, when you&amp;rsquo;re young, you easily develop a sense of entitlement: “Everything I deserve, if something isn’t received, if something has a flaw, I feel particularly uncomfortable.” Please don’t any of you learn to cut corners either – that is, at the time when you’re about to turn 30 or 28 years old, watching the 1996 Olympics, I came up with a sentence: “Defects are an important part of perfection; there is no perfect world.” In Zeng Qianfen&amp;rsquo;s long novel, it actually wrote down a very important saying: what is the best state in life? Zeng Qianfen wanted to name his study room &amp;ldquo;Qiu Que Ting&amp;rdquo; – the flower hasn’t fully bloomed yet is the best. The moon hasn’t been completely round yet is the best. But for ordinary people, they will feel this is a defect, not perfect enough, not reaching the extreme, and the best way to ruin someone is to let them pursue perfection and reach the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/flower_hasnt_fully_bloomed.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Flower hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully bloomed&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-3&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This world isn’t like that. Flowers are most beautiful when they aren&amp;rsquo;t fully open; once they bloom completely, they’re close to falling. The moon is most beautiful when it’s full and round; as it slowly transforms into a waning crescent, it’s also approaching that point. Therefore, I feel this was a very important boost and revelation for me at 30. Forty isn&amp;rsquo;t as good-looking as that time. But I think I relaxed, became freer. Why shouldn’t I start asking about happiness instead of dressing in suits and ties or always looking formal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/40%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;894&#34;
	height=&#34;499&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;40 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese people have a saying that 40 is not confused; 30 is subtraction, and 40 is confusion. It’s not about being unconfused, and I think in today&amp;rsquo;s era, 40-year-olds are the most confused. My midlife crisis came surprisingly early, starting around 36 or 37 years old when I began to question whether everything I had done was valuable and meaningful. What do I really want for happiness? This book was born out of this confusion. When you&amp;rsquo;re 30, you often find that your happiness goals are tied to material possessions. “Thirty and established” (三十而立) refers to having a solid education. You need a car, a house, otherwise your mother-in-law won’t consider marrying you off – it’s very materialistic, but 40 is difficult to be unconfused. I think ancient people likely had a longer average lifespan than we do now, so when they condensed it to 40 years, he wouldn’t be confused. I feel that way myself – at 40, I&amp;rsquo;m bewildered. &lt;strong&gt;Material things haven&amp;rsquo;t brought me happiness as I thought they would.&lt;/strong&gt; Similarly, when people ask you at 40, “Are you happy?” it’s often a question mark, representing the confusion within my heart. The emergence of midlife crisis: at 40, you need to answer yourself many questions, you need to talk to yourself more at around 40, you need to read a lot and give yourself some answers. I was very fortunate to have entered the world of the &lt;em&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/em&gt; when I was thirty-six or seventy years old. In &lt;em&gt;White Say&lt;/em&gt;, I had already discussed it, and at forty years old, when one is still contemplating things, if the surrounding environment doesn’t change, especially the soft environment – if you’re feeling relaxed and happy enough to step out of the house and wander around freely, like running through red lights – you’ll find that everything you buy is fake, and even getting a vaccine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been saying that China has been battling two typhoons these past few days – one typhoon was intangible, and the other was tangible. The intangible typhoon is vaccines; it’s attacking our inner security dam. The other typhoon, China rarely sees typhoons landing in Shanghai – that&amp;rsquo;s a distraction. Next, you need to think about whether you are only focusing on your own well-being, if you’ve undergone significant changes, and if you have many answers. If the surrounding environment doesn’t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;I have eight characters I say are quite heavy – I feel that we currently suffer from a moral deficit and a loss of humanity; this is the biggest deficit and greatest loss.&lt;/strong&gt; A few days ago, I witnessed a car accident not far from here. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t that serious of a collision, and he was responsible for hitting another vehicle. He tried to explain to the other driver that we were planning to pull over to the side of the road, and the other driver slowly began preparing to do so. However, the lead vehicle sped off without stopping to help. There weren’t any people in it trying to restrain him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would that be a responsible father? Would that be a responsible son? And what about his responsibility as a citizen – it inevitably impacts you. You might be a big shot, but unless you haven&amp;rsquo;t stepped foot outside your home, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent your children from getting vaccinated. Even delivery services can have issues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If 30 is subtraction and 40 is confusion, I think 50 should be the word I give myself: curiosity. Fifty is awkward; neither forward nor backward has a village or shop to reach – advance, attack; retreat, blend in – it can also work. Spending ten years on something you’ve achieved, lingering until retirement, seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a book that contains some very interesting writing: it says that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley are often older, 50s and 60s. This is different from our concept. How can China ever stop viewing entrepreneurship as a young endeavor, just like how China shouldn’t view volunteers as youth volunteers? Last week I did a program about China recruiting retired primary and secondary school teachers – with an annual stipend of two or three hundred thousand yuan – to teach in rural areas, and they must be outstanding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/50%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;899&#34;
	height=&#34;506&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;50 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for a 50-year-old person, there are two challenges: the first is yourself – are you still curious about many things? What is your worldview? I feel that my biggest gain at 50, or the way I’m living now, is to treat every day well. When you&amp;rsquo;re 20 years old, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to live in tomorrow; if you&amp;rsquo;re not careful, a 50-year-old tends to dwell on yesterday. But I try to restrain myself, neither living in tomorrow nor in the past. I treat each day well – a 50-year-old shouldn’t always say “we’ll talk about it tomorrow” or “things were better back then!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s best to watch Cai Qin’s concert discs today. Cai Qin said something that was quite profound: whenever he looks at old photos, he thinks he looked good two years ago. But on that particular day two years ago, he never thought he looked good before. That’s a really flavorful saying. “I didn’t realize it when I was 30, at that time I felt quite handsome. I thought I had a lot of flaws, but now, when I look back after 20 years, I realize… I was young once too. I had so much hair then, so cherish every day you have, and it would be best to see how you are two years from now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Yu Shi-sheng said, when my legs first couldn’t walk, I sat in a wheelchair, constantly yearning for the time when I could run and play basketball. Every day, consumed by these memories, I was incredibly painful.
Years later, I developed bedsores on my wheelchair and felt all over the body ache. At that time, I constantly reminisced about the days when just a few years ago, I didn’t feel any pain, and could spend peaceful moments sitting in a wheelchair.
After even more years, I was diagnosed with uremia, and I had to go for dialysis. At this point, I would always yearn for the time when I only had bedsores on my wheelchair. If I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live to reach a state where every day was treated kindly, those next 50 years would have been wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually feel that you shouldn’t wait until 50 to understand this principle; it should be understood in your 30s or 40s, because all things are easily missed if you wait. Like a meal during a trip – if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat it, you can still have it 30 years later, and it might not even taste the same. So I think treating every today is my first feeling at 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing is curiosity. I’ve realized that I can stop being curious about many things at any time because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so much and experienced so much, but I encourage myself to remain curious. Therefore, when doing a lot of things now, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – whether a phone can be held vertically to take pictures, it can; whether you can do live reporting, whether you can attend seemingly large and very formal events, can you make the connection easier? It’s more fun and more impressive for everyone. And how can you then use new media to spread the word? All of this is possible. I believe curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress, and why can’t it be the most important driver for individual advancement? A nation that loses its curiosity is doomed. On a broader level, 50 is a crucial test. When you&amp;rsquo;re in your fifties in China, what kind of entrenched interests do you hold? I’m very concerned that many people around me pursue countless dreams when they’re young because of their aspirations, but once they achieve those dreams and become entrenched beneficiaries, they transform into those who obstruct others from realizing their own. Am I right? Looking back, they treat young people and matters in the way they used to dislike most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-3&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a few years ago I started recruiting 11 graduate students each year as volunteers, and after spending two years with them, they have now all graduated. There are five graduating classes, totaling 55 pure graduate students who have already finished their studies. I think it’s a very happy thing to create such a system – you gain some experience, and you have the ability to guide them. After each day of class, I invite them for dinner, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much. However, this is what a good vested interest should do – a vested interest can be two aspects: one is to become paving stones again. I once said that I don’t want to say thank you too much to those who have helped me, because I want to treat new young people ten times over. This is the way I express my gratitude.
&lt;strong&gt;If you constantly say “thank you” and become a blocker…&lt;/strong&gt; The next thing is to pave the road for others. I hope that, no matter whether it’s material, economic, ideological, or cultural – across all fields – when you become a vested interest group in China, you will consider how you should act. Yesterday’s pusher of the train has become today’s person blocking the train; looking back at Chinese history, this is everywhere. It won&amp;rsquo;t be like that; sometimes it even becomes more so. Therefore, I call on all vested interests to return to the way they were when they were young – to act as they wished to encounter such people. Even if I may not do well in that role, I at least want to think about it, do it, and speak about it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
