<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Novel on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/novel/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Novel on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/novel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Echoes of bygone years, offering unconventional fantasies and emotional solace.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:12:57 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the earliest web novel readers entered middle age, the type of “revenge” stories catered to them also evolved. The protagonists often appeared as fathers, mentors, or elderly figures, meeting the different needs and demands of middle-aged readers for life and emotion. These works no longer solely focused on upgrades and reversals; instead, they emphasized emotional resonance and life reflections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience-shifting-reader-base-amidst-the-passage-of-time&#34;&gt;Target Audience: Shifting Reader Base Amidst the Passage of Time
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former web novel readers have largely transitioned into middle age. They’ve experienced the trials and tribulations of life, leading to shifts in their mindset and values. The passionate, adventurous elements they once chased are no longer the sole focus for them. Instead, they seek emotional resonance with their current lives and a sense of nostalgia for past years, as well as aspirations for the future. Middle-aged爽文 (shuangwen - a popular genre) emerged specifically to meet this psychological need. It utilizes plot settings that closely align with the lives and attitudes of middle-aged readers, attracting this particular demographic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-shift-from-young-hero-to-middle-aged-guardian&#34;&gt;Role Shift: From Young Hero to Middle-Aged Guardian
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Students Are All Villains:&lt;/strong&gt; The protagonist, Lu Zhou, after becoming a master, faces a group of disciples with diverse personalities and formidable strength. They teeter between good and evil, and Lu Zhou needs to guide them towards the right path. This novel showcases the challenges and confusion faced by middle-aged individuals when educating the next generation through interactions with their disciples. Furthermore, the growth and transformation of the disciples offer hope and a glimpse into the future, mirroring expectations for one’s children or younger generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emotional-resonance-life-reflections-and-family-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Emotional Resonance: Life Reflections and Family Responsibilities
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sixty-Year-Old Birthday System:&lt;/strong&gt; The protagonist gained a system upon turning sixty, embarking on a new life journey. This setting allows middle-aged readers to feel a sense of “it’s never too late” hope and inspiration. Even having reached old age, the protagonist can still realize their value and dreams through the system. This plot encourages readers to reflect on missed opportunities and unfulfilled dreams in their own lives, while also conveying an optimistic attitude, encouraging them not to give up pursuing their goals at any age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-design-aligning-with-the-rhythm-and-humor-of-middle-age-life&#34;&gt;Plot Design: Aligning with the Rhythm and Humor of Middle Age Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plot designs for middle-aged “revenge” novels often place a greater emphasis on the details of life and the nuanced expression of emotions. Unlike young adult revenge novels that prioritize rapid upgrades and adventures, they focus more on relationships between characters and emotional entanglements. For example, in &lt;em&gt;The Greatest Master Craftsman&lt;/em&gt;, the protagonist’s friendship with his apprentice, their brotherhood with fellow disciples, etc., are all depicted in detail. This plot design allows middle-aged readers to feel a sense of warmth and familiarity, as if they were seeing their own family relationships, friendships, and love lives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Onomatopoeia of the Night</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/nights-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is utterly unique; there isn’t even a single homophone. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person’s life has only one opportunity, cannot be replicated, and cannot be relived.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with an overwhelming number of monthly votes, far surpassing the second-place book – a gap that was truly daunting. For many years, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jiaqian and Ergen. This time, I decided to try a new author’s work and experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed a staggering two million monthly votes, while the second book only garnered eight hundred thousand – the disparity was astonishing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I acknowledge my own lack of knowledge and ability to critically evaluate the author&amp;rsquo;s writing style. However, after reading through more than fifteen chapters, I found that the plot was tightly woven and intricately connected, captivating and engaging. Given such high monthly vote numbers, it’s undeniably well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like “命,” the character “死” (death) also has no homophones within the Chinese character system. Does this similarly imply a unique and irreplaceable depth regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
