<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Novel on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/novel/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Novel on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/novel/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Echoes of Time – Alternative Fantasies and Emotional Refuge</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:12:57 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the earliest web novel readers entered middle age, the types of “revenge” stories catered to them also evolved. The protagonists increasingly appeared as fathers, mentors, or elderly figures, reflecting the different needs and desires of middle-aged readers regarding life and emotion. These works no longer solely focused on upgrades and triumphs; instead, they emphasized emotional resonance and life lessons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience-shifting-reader-base-amidst-the-passage-of-time&#34;&gt;Target Audience: Shifting Reader Base Amidst the Passage of Time
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Former online novel readers have largely transitioned into middle age. They’ve experienced the trials and tribulations of life, leading to shifts in their mindset and values. The passionate, adventurous elements they once chased are no longer the sole focus for them. Instead, they seek emotional resonance with their current lives and a sense of nostalgia for past years, as well as aspirations for the future. Middle-aged “comfort reads” emerged precisely because of these psychological needs. They utilize plot settings that closely align with the lifestyles and attitudes of middle-aged individuals, attracting this specific demographic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;role-shift-from-young-hero-to-middle-aged-guardian&#34;&gt;Role Shift: From Young Hero to Middle-Aged Guardian
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;My Students Are All the Villains:&lt;/strong&gt; The protagonist, Lu Zhou, after becoming a master, faces a group of disciples with diverse personalities and formidable strength. They teeter between good and evil, and Lu Zhou must guide them towards the righteous path. This novel showcases the challenges and confusion faced by middle-aged individuals when educating the next generation through interactions with their disciples. Furthermore, the growth and transformation of the disciples offer hope and a glimpse into the future, mirroring expectations for one&amp;rsquo;s children or younger generations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emotional-resonance-life-reflections-and-family-responsibilities&#34;&gt;Emotional Resonance: Life Reflections and Family Responsibilities
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Sixty-Year-Old Birthday System:&lt;/strong&gt; The protagonist gained a system upon turning sixty, embarking on a new life journey. This setting allows middle-aged readers to feel a sense of “it’s never too late” hope and inspiration. Even having reached old age, the protagonist can still realize their value and dreams through the system. This plot encourages readers to reflect on missed opportunities and unfulfilled dreams in their own lives, while also conveying an optimistic attitude, encouraging them not to give up pursuing their goals at any age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-design-aligning-with-the-rhythm-and-humor-of-middle-age-life&#34;&gt;Plot Design: Aligning with the Rhythm and Humor of Middle Age Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plot designs for middle-aged “revenge” novels often place a greater emphasis on the details of life and the nuanced expression of emotions. Unlike young adult revenge novels that prioritize rapid upgrades and adventures, they focus more on relationships between characters and emotional entanglements. For example, in &lt;em&gt;The Greatest Master Craftsman&lt;/em&gt;, the protagonist’s friendship with his apprentice, their brotherhood with fellow disciples, and other bonds were depicted in detail. This plot design allows middle-aged readers to feel warmth and familiarity, as if seeing their own family, friendships, and love in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>nights-naming-art</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character “命” (life/fate) is unique; there isn’t even a single homophone. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life has only one opportunity, cannot be replicated, and cannot be relived.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During leisure time, I browsed the rankings on Qidian Chinese Net, and “The Nomenclature of Nights” consistently topped the charts with over two million monthly votes, a significant gap from the second-place ranking. Previously, I had primarily read works by well-known authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Ergen; this time, I decided to try a new author’s work to experience a different reading sensation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, “The Nomenclature of Nights” had amassed two million monthly votes, while the second-place ranking stood at only eight hundred thousand – a staggering disparity that left me speechless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize my knowledge is limited and I lack the ability to critically evaluate the author’s writing style. However, after reading through over a dozen chapters, the book’s plot is tightly paced and intricately linked, captivating readers and earning such high monthly votes – it&amp;rsquo;s truly well-deserved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly, just like the character “ming” (life/fate), the character “si” (death) also doesn’t have any homophones in Chinese characters; does this perhaps also contain a similarly unique and irreplaceable depth of meaning regarding the end of life?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
