<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Redhat on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/redhat/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Redhat on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Red Hat and CentOS lifecycles</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 20:02:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Online production environments typically use Red Hat and CentOS as their operating systems. Links to the official websites documenting the lifecycles of these two systems are provided, along with shared experiences upgrading from CentOS 8 to CentOS 8 Stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In online production environments, Red Hat and CentOS are currently the mainstream choices in China. Following the retirement of Red Hat 6 in recent years, here are links to the official websites for the lifecycles of these two systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://access.redhat.com/support/policy/updates/errata&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux Life Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CentOS Product Specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) and CentOS are popular choices for enterprise-grade server operating systems. RHEL offers a stable support and update cycle, suitable for enterprise applications. CentOS, as the community version of RHEL, provides similar functionality and stability but lacks official support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chase-for-more&#34;&gt;Chase for more
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I published this article, I never thought I would update it two years later. Just the other day, I upgraded my daily-use virtual machine from CentOS 8 to CentOS 8 Stream. I won&amp;rsquo;t say much about how to choose for production environments, but I still prefer the latest versions for local environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS 8 Stream is a rolling release version that offers faster updates and new features compared to traditional CentOS, making it suitable for development and testing environments&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
