<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Redhat on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/redhat/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Redhat on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:10:34 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/redhat/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Red Hat and CentOS Lifecycle</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 20:02:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Production environment operating systems, with Red Hat and CentOS being the mainstream choices. The documentation includes links to two system lifecycles and shares experience upgrading from CentOS 8 to CentOS Stream 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the current domestic environment, Red Hat and CentOS are the mainstream choices for production online operating systems. After experiencing the retirement of Red Hat 6 two years ago, this record specifically documents the official website links for the lifecycles of these two systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-content&#34;&gt;Main Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://access.redhat.com/support/policy/updates/errata&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux Life Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wiki.centos.org/zh/About/Product&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CentOS Product Specifications&lt;/a&gt;
Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) and CentOS are the mainstream choices for enterprise servers. RHEL provides stable support and update cycles, suitable for enterprise applications. CentOS as RHEL&amp;rsquo;s community edition, offers similar features and stability but without official support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;follow-up&#34;&gt;Follow-up
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When publishing this article, I didn’t expect to update it two years later. Just a few days ago, I upgraded my daily virtual machine from CentOS 8 to CentOS 8 Stream. I can&amp;rsquo;t say much about what to choose in production – I prefer to keep the latest version in my local environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS 8 Stream is a rolling release version that offers faster updates and new features than traditional CentOS, making it suitable for development and testing environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
