<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Software on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/software/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Software on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 18:06:57 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A Unexpected Software Uninstall Journey</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-unexpected-software-uninstall-journey/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Aug 2025 17:55:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-unexpected-software-uninstall-journey/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;After reinstalling my system, I’ve consistently been missing a decent PDF reader. Within the 360 Software Center, I saw &lt;strong&gt;Xundu PDF&lt;/strong&gt; recommended, even with a “special edition.” I had already formed a slight impression of this brand at that point, wondering how a niche software like a PDF reader could possibly generate profits – surely the promotional costs wouldn’t pay off. Later, I encountered it again through Xunlei’s promotion, and my computer did indeed need one, so I conveniently installed it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;everything-was-fine-until-the-weekend&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Everything was fine&amp;hellip; until the weekend&amp;hellip;&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After installing the software, it worked perfectly without issue. I noticed some AI features within it, but they required a paid subscription – which wasn’t useful for me, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t purchase them. Back then, I naively thought, “How much money could those paid features really earn?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until this weekend, when &lt;strong&gt;QQmusic&lt;/strong&gt; suddenly and inexplicably froze and crashed while I was developing locally. Instinctively, I opened Task Manager to see if there were any lingering processes. I discovered that the QQmusic process was still running but unresponsive, so after forcibly ending it, QQmusic could start up normally again.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, I inadvertently discovered a process named &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;PDF Engine&lt;/strong&gt;,&amp;rdquo; which was consuming nearly 10% of CPU usage – while the entire system’s resource utilization was only 19%. Curious, I checked the file path and found that it was actually my previously installed &lt;strong&gt;Xoon PDF!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;loss-of-trust&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loss of Trust&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is a defect in the software, but I’ve completely lost trust in it at this point.
Considering its widespread promotion, I can’t help but wonder where all those high promotional costs are coming from – they must be earned somehow. The clandestine running of strange tasks in the background seems almost “reasonable” in retrospect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
