<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Byte on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/byte/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Byte on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 22:07:37 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/byte/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>ByteDance AI’s SOLO encoding new paradigm</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/bytedance-ais-solo-encoding-new-paradigm/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Aug 2025 21:49:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/bytedance-ais-solo-encoding-new-paradigm/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously used products, during code development, were largely satisfactory, but Byte’s SOLO introduced significant differences. Initially, participation in beta testing was through invitation codes, and now it involves submitting an email address for review. After approval, the product can be used. I’ve forgotten when I submitted the application, but today I received a notification from Trae indicating that my application had been approved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bytesolos-advantages&#34;&gt;ByteSolo’s Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following a standard project development process, it incorporates UI design, requirements analysis, functional design, technical solution implementation, and finally code development. In other words, the overall interaction logic is more friendly for beginners. For complex projects, the traditional approach remains more effective – AI as an auxiliary tool to modify and optimize existing code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong--us-stocks-app-development&#34;&gt;Hong Kong &amp;amp; US Stocks App Development
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s right, the title is exactly what I wrote in the prompt statement, with no additional descriptions. In SOLO mode, first a requirements document and a technical architecture document were outputted. If the user confirms they are okay with it, code development will proceed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/ai-coding-trae-solo/blob/master/.trae/documents/%E6%B8%AF%E7%BE%8E%E8%82%A1APP%E4%BA%A7%E5%93%81%E9%9C%80%E6%B1%82%E6%96%87%E6%A1%A3.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Requirements Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/ai-coding-trae-solo/blob/master/.trae/documents/%E6%B8%AF%E7%BE%8E%E8%82%A1APP%E6%8A%80%E6%9C%AF%E6%9E%B6%E6%9E%84%E6%96%87%E6%A1%A3.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Technical Architecture Document&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I said, while the design isn&amp;rsquo;t particularly perfect, it can be used as a draft.  Due to my lack of UI design experience and not having tested the functionality of importing Figma design drafts, it’s perfectly acceptable as a first draft.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the code construction process, some documents were also discovered. In SOLO mode, the AI attempts to handle any existing issues on its own, such as needing to increase the field design in my local database, it first generates the corresponding script and then writes a js script to execute the database script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There were also some highlights that I didn&amp;rsquo;t find while researching materials. The task decomposition feature was taken from a previous comic reading project. Byte is not short of money; one request can execute a lot of tasks, but this scenario doesn’t occur frequently, new projects will consume a large number of tokens. It’s only when users develop dependencies that they become profitable here.
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/bytedance-ais-solo-encoding-new-paradigm/20250814215722.png&#34;
	width=&#34;571&#34;
	height=&#34;236&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Task Decomposition Function&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;241&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;580px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
