<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Style-Sheets on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/style-sheets/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Style-Sheets on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:38:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/style-sheets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to Copy Webpage Stylesheets (CSS): Element Inspector</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/how-to-copy-webpage-css-element-inspection/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 23:36:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/how-to-copy-webpage-css-element-inspection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Static blog themes, the mainstream is based on foreign templates, modified and adjusted without much consideration for Chinese content layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-text&#34;&gt;Main Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;About half a month ago, I adjusted the blog’s stylesheet – as I’ve been developing backend services for many years, I’m a pure newbie in frontend. After struggling with it for half a day, the design wasn&amp;rsquo;t very reasonable. Suddenly an idea struck me: I looked at the technical blogs I often read – infoq and OpenChina – and their layouts look really good. Could I borrow some of those? After reviewing the source files, I got lost trying to locate the relevant elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontend developers might be laughing at this point… I didn’t understand how to locate the specified elements, but that&amp;rsquo;s okay; I have plenty of free time on weekends, so I stopped to think about it. It reminded me of when I wrote Python crawlers – I had used something similar then.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;element-inspection&#34;&gt;Element Inspection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That’s right, it’s the built-in element inspection tool in the browser – copying style sheets, locating specific elements, all done in minutes. &lt;code&gt;selector&lt;/code&gt; to locate elements, &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; to create a ‘user define css’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy element&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy outerHTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy selector&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy JS path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Copy styles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy XPath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy full XPath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
