<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Style-Sheets on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/style-sheets/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Style-Sheets on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/style-sheets/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>How to Copy Webpage Style Sheets (CSS): Element Inspection</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/how-to-copy-webpage-css-element-inspection/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 23:36:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/how-to-copy-webpage-css-element-inspection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Static blog themes predominantly rely on foreign templates with minor modifications, without much consideration for typesetting Chinese content&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;About two weeks ago, I made some adjustments to my blog&amp;rsquo;s stylesheet. Having worked in backend service development for many years, I’m a complete novice when it comes to frontend. After fiddling with it all day, the design still wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite right. Then I had an idea – inspired by technical blogs like InfoQ and Open Source China, whose layouts are excellent. Could I borrow some of their techniques? I looked at the source code for a while, trying to locate the relevant elements, but ended up completely confused.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontend developers seeing this might be laughing&amp;hellip; don&amp;rsquo;t understand how to locate specific elements. No worries, I have plenty of time on the weekend; thinking back, I seem to have used something similar when writing crawlers before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;elemental-review&#34;&gt;Elemental Review
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Indeed, it&amp;rsquo;s the browser&amp;rsquo;s built-in element inspection tool—copying style sheets and locating specific elements are quick tasks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy element&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy outerHTML&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy JS path&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy XPath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Copy full XPath&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
