<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Backup on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/backup/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Backup on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 23:25:23 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/backup/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>WeChat Backup Tool Local Network Recognition Failed</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-backup-tool-local-network-recognition-failed/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 23:04:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/wechat-backup-tool-local-network-recognition-failed/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I regularly clear out data on my phone, including photos and WeChat chat logs, backing them up to my computer. Previously, it worked seamlessly, allowing me to easily identify both my mobile phone and desktop PC within the same local network and directly back up the chat records to my computer. However, today everything has been failing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tried-solutions&#34;&gt;Tried Solutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Computer connected to WIFI, phone connected to WIFI, both devices are within the same local network, but still cannot be recognized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Phone turned on hotspot, computer connected to phone hotspot, still cannot be recognized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Desktops use a wired network, mobile phones use a wireless network, and when restoring WeChat backups, it cannot recognize this as a local area network. I have tested it, and the desktop can normally access the mobile phone&amp;rsquo;s IP address.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions-1&#34;&gt;Solutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, I thought it was something from Tencent, so I asked “Junhun,” to see if he had any ideas. The results he provided were not helpful. I casually tossed it over to “Dubao,” and he offered a surprise – prompting me to realize that my local environment might have many virtual networks or multi-NIC environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was indeed correct; my desktop has several virtual network cards, such as VMware, ZeroTier, Hyper-V, and Docker Desktop. My desktop also has multiple physical network cards, the primary network card connected to the router and a 2.5G network card forming a sub-local network for another machine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I disabled all virtual network cards and extra physical network cards on my desktop, retaining the primary network card, and reattempted the backup – it was successful!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
