<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Too much AI, a bit of a side effect</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the new &lt;code&gt;AI Inspiration Hub&lt;/code&gt; was established, a lot of trivial things have been tried to be recorded and published using AI. As a result, there&amp;rsquo;s less time for quiet reflection and contemplation. It would be good to slightly control the output of this column in the future and integrate it into a monthly publication format, releasing one article per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a kind of aftereffect, or perhaps a side effect – efficiency is improved, but the depth and breadth of thinking have declined&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-improvement-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency improvement: undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Seven Seconds of Fish&amp;rdquo; column hasn&amp;rsquo;t been well-maintained previously. Due to laziness, I didn’t search for information or compile records on some trending events. Now that various AI tools are available, outlining is sufficient; the AI can automatically connect to the internet, search for related event records, and generate articles as needed. A simple formatting adjustment, and it&amp;rsquo;s ready for publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a godsend for lazy people, it significantly improves efficiency, and you could even say it achieves results with half the effort&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throwing aside the need to write articles, when writing code, the efficiency boost is real. Many coding tasks used to require detailed reading of API interface documentation, but now you can skip them directly – and this skipping is quite necessary. Familiarity with APIs is a &lt;code&gt;physical labor&lt;/code&gt;, not a &lt;code&gt;mental labor&lt;/code&gt;; AI handling this part is just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;garbage-content&#34;&gt;Garbage content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the submissions are low in quality; they aren&amp;rsquo;t entirely without merit, but they lack a sense of life and warmth. It’s a style I used to dislike – dry and lifeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, AI-generated content does feel a bit like something produced on an assembly line – lacking soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet junk of the new era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetfulness&#34;&gt;Forgetfulness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of article is all AI-generated, and I don’t know the readers&amp;rsquo; situation, but over time, my own impressions will become blurred, or even forgotten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar issues arise when writing code as well. Without checking the commit history, you have no idea what you were thinking at the time and why you wrote it that way. This is especially true for code generated after repeated communication with yourself and AI – the final version can be very different from the initial idea, even completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant decrease in how often I open Google and Baidu recently. Many questions are now searched for using AI, and the interaction and search results are much better than traditional search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pay our respects to &lt;code&gt;bing ai&lt;/code&gt;, a tool from a major company that was among the first released with internet search capabilities, whether it’s still alive or not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are using Google less, and visiting &lt;code&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; less frequently too. Many questions can now be directly asked to AI, so this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blog I’m still maintaining didn&amp;rsquo;t have much traffic to begin with, and now even less so; it’s more of a place for keeping records, writing for myself&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
