<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Too much AI, some side effects</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the establishment of &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;, there&amp;rsquo;s been a surge in recording and publishing trivial things using AI. Consequently, time for quiet reflection has diminished. It would be better to slightly control the output of this column and consolidate it into a monthly publication, releasing one article per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a lingering effect or side effect – efficiency increases, but depth and breadth of thought decrease&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-improvement-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency improvement: Undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, this column wasn&amp;rsquo;t well-maintained. Due to laziness, I didn’t search for information or compile records on some trending events. Now, with various AI tools, outlining is sufficient; the AI can automatically search and record related events, generate articles, and after simple formatting, they can be published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is like a dream come true for those who don&amp;rsquo;t want to put in too much effort; it significantly boosts efficiency, almost achieving results with half the work&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Efficiency significantly improves when coding instead of writing articles. Many code sections previously required detailed review of API documentation; now, this step can be skipped – a necessary shortcut. Familiarity with APIs is best left to AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;junk-content&#34;&gt;Junk content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the submissions lack substance; they feel lifeless and stale, like chewing wax—not a style I previously enjoyed&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, AI-generated content often feels like mass-produced work, lacking soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet junk of the new era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetfulness&#34;&gt;Forgetfulness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of article is AI-generated. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the readers, and over time, my own memory will fade or even disappear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar issues arise when coding – without reviewing the commit history, it&amp;rsquo;s impossible to know your original thought process or rationale for a particular implementation. This is especially true with code generated after extensive revisions and discussions with AI, which can significantly diverge from the initial idea, even becoming entirely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant decrease in how often I use Google and Baidu recently; searching with AI is much better than traditional search engines, both in terms of interaction and results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s commemorate &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;, one of the earliest AI tools connected to the internet released by a major company&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are using Google less; visits to &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; have decreased as well. Many questions can now be answered directly by AI, and this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blog I&amp;rsquo;m still maintaining doesn&amp;rsquo;t get much traffic anyway, and certainly won&amp;rsquo;t now; it’s more of a personal journal for my own reference&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
