<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Internet on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/internet/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>AI overuse can lead to some lingering effects.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since we’ve launched “AI Inspiration Collision Forum,” there’s been a lot of random content being recorded and published, with people rushing to use AI to document and release everything. Quiet reflection and independent thought have become increasingly scarce. Moving forward, it would be beneficial to slightly control the output of this section and consolidate it into a monthly magazine format – releasing one article per month would suffice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This feels like a kind of aftereffect or side effect; efficiency has increased, but the depth and breadth of thinking have declined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-boost-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency Boost: Undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “Seven-Second Fish Sightseeing” column used to be poorly maintained, with only a few hot events covered. Due to laziness, I hadn’t searched the internet for relevant materials or compiled records. Now that various AI tools are available, all it takes is outlining the key points, and AI can automatically search for related events, generate articles as needed, simply format them, and publish them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a blessing for lazy people – efficiency has increased significantly, almost to the point of doubling effort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond writing articles, efficiency gains are real when coding. Previously, writing code often required detailed reading of API interface documentation. Now, I can skip this entirely. This is incredibly valuable because familiarizing oneself with APIs is “physical labor,” not “mental labor.” AI handles this part perfectly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spam-content&#34;&gt;Spam Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many articles have poor quality content, not to say that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing there, but it’s difficult to read, lacking a sense of reality and what people actually experience. This is a style I didn’t enjoy in the past – like chewing wax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternatively, AI-generated content truly feels like products of a流水线 (liú shuǐ liàn - assembly line) production, lacking soul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spam of the New Internet Era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetting&#34;&gt;Forgetting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of document is entirely AI-generated, and the reader’s context is unclear. However, over time, my own impressions will become blurred, or even forgotten.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar problems occur when writing code – without reviewing commit records, I can&amp;rsquo;t remember how I originally thought about it or why I wrote it that way. This is particularly noticeable with code generated through repeated communication with AI, where the final code differs significantly from the initial ideas, sometimes to the point of being completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, the number of times I’ve opened Google and Baidu has noticeably decreased. Many questions are now being answered by AI for searching and interaction, and the results are much better than traditional search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s mourn the &lt;code&gt;bing ai&lt;/code&gt;, which may no longer be active, a pioneering AI tool from a major company that could connect to the internet and search.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m using Google less, and I’ve reduced my visits to &lt;code&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; as well. Many questions are now simply asked of AI – this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My maintained blog, originally with very little traffic, is now even less expected of; it’s primarily a place for self-reflection and recording.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
