<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Virtual-Currency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/virtual-currency/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Virtual-Currency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/virtual-currency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Hong Kong Stock Exchange, History of Cryptocurrency Development</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election as US President, virtual currency has once again entered the public consciousness. Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) has also been actively developing related businesses; here’s a brief overview of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s virtual currency development history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the contract details, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that futures were initially introduced, which is reasonable given their better liquidity and ease of attracting institutional investors. The subsequent introduction of spot ETFs was also logical, as ETFs are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptocurrency-list&#34;&gt;Cryptocurrency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Stock Exchange&amp;rsquo;s market data doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a tag to distinguish whether a contract is for virtual currency, but it can be determined by the contract name. The official transaction list does provide corresponding subcategories &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-asia-based-crypto-etfs-listing&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Asia-Based Crypto ETFs Listing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first cryptocurrency ETFs, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for Hong Kong and international investors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two new ETFs launched today — China Southern East Funds Management’s Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) — are managed by China Southern East Asset Management Co., Ltd. They track standardized, cash-settled Bitcoin futures contracts and Ethereum futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Chief Operating Officer and Co-Head of Markets, Nicole Yau, stated: &amp;ldquo;The two newly listed cryptocurrency ETFs add to Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s increasingly rich and diverse ecosystem of exchange-traded products. These new products will provide investors in Asia with their first opportunity to participate in digital asset investments, reflecting our focus on the digital economy and market demand. We look forward to welcoming more thematic ETFs and digital asset products in the coming months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETFs are one of the fastest-growing businesses under Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a constantly expanding and increasingly diverse range of products. In 2022, this included the launch of its first Metaverse ETF, first carbon futures ETF, and first blockchain ETF, as well as the inclusion of ETFs in the Shanghai–Hong Kong Stock Connect scheme for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average daily turnover of Exchange Traded Products (ETPs), including ETFs and leveraged/inverse products, on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange for the first eleven months of this year was HK$11.8 billion, a 50% increase from HK$7.8 billion in the same period last year, reflecting growing investor demand. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange with a total market capitalization of HK$373.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange welcomes the listing of the first spot virtual asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first spot virtual asset ETFs, expanding Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s product range and providing investors with greater choice, solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Head of Securities Product Development Robert Lo said, &amp;ldquo;The newly launched virtual asset spot ETF will enrich Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s diverse and vibrant ETF market ecosystem, providing investors with investment opportunities in a new asset class. Following the successful launch of virtual asset futures ETFs a year ago, Asia’s first virtual asset spot ETFs will further enhance the variety and liquidity of products traded on Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing. We look forward to continuing to work closely with market participants to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investor demand for the first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs launched in 2022 has been strong, with robust trading volume. The daily turnover of Hong Kong-listed virtual asset futures ETFs increased from HK$8.9 million in 2023 to HK$51.3 million in Q1 2024, accompanied by net inflows of HK$529 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exchange trading of products (including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products) is one of the fastest-growing markets on Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a continuously expanding range of product types. Sixteen new ETF products were added in 2023 and Q1 2024, including Asia’s first Saudi Arabia ETF and Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s first exchange-traded options ETFs. There are currently 179 ETFs listed in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchanges-and-clearing-is-launching-a-series-of-virtual-asset-indices&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing is launching a series of virtual asset indices
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Monday) announced the launch of the HKEX Virtual Asset Index Series on November 15, 2024. This index series will provide a reliable benchmark for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s development as Asia’s leading digital asset hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will provide a transparent and reliable benchmark for the pricing of Bitcoin and Ethereum in Asian time zones, aiming to establish a unified reference price for virtual assets and resolve price discrepancies across global exchanges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing CEO Nicolas Aguzin said, &amp;ldquo;We are pleased to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series to meet regional demand for this rapidly growing asset class. By providing a transparent and reliable real-time benchmark, we aim to help investors make informed decisions, support the healthy development of the virtual asset ecosystem, and solidify Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as an international financial center.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this index series is part of Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring emerging areas, supporting the development of Hong Kong’s financial technology while also providing investors with important benchmark tools and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference rate is calculated based on a weighted average of 24-hour trading volumes in Bitcoin or Ethereum, aggregated from major cryptocurrency exchanges and priced in USD. It&amp;rsquo;s designed for the settlement of financial products and calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will be the first in Hong Kong to comply with EU Benchmark Regulation (BMR), co-managed and calculated by a UK-registered benchmark administrator and virtual asset data and index provider, CCData&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region government issued a policy statement in 2022 aiming to foster a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange’s Virtual Asset Index series will help increase public understanding of virtual asset investment trends by providing real-time data and daily reference prices in the Asian time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be released as appropriate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
