<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Tangping on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/tangping/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Tangping on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/tangping/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>County-level Brahmin: Big Shots in Small Towns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Teacher Da Bing has become very popular on Douyin. You often see accounts sharing clips from her livestreams. During one livestream, a listener asked, &amp;ldquo;Teacher Da Bing, I want to sell my house in Xi&amp;rsquo;an and return home to relax.&amp;rdquo; Da Bing replied, &amp;ldquo;At your age, in your thirties, you can’t just ‘lie flat.’ Your parents are aging, your children aren&amp;rsquo;t established yet, and even returning to your hometown, you’ll still have to deal with the complexities of a small county town.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether the view is right or wrong, what does this word mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many small county towns, people often talk about &amp;ldquo;county Brahmin&amp;rdquo; – their existence feels like a symbol of the local society. They are not necessarily religious figures or individuals with impressive titles, but rather seemingly ordinary yet influential people. They represent “power, status, and voice” in a small place, symbolizing a certain stratum within that county town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-1&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, we need to understand that &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; originally referred to the highest stratum of Indian society, representing wisdom, authority, and spiritual supremacy. However, in Chinese county towns, the term “county town Brahmin” lacks such complex religious connotations; it&amp;rsquo;s more a metaphor for a social phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmin&amp;rdquo; refers to individuals who hold cultural authority within a county, such as teachers, doctors, prominent local merchants, and officials. Although their positions may seem ordinary, in the relatively closed environment of a county, they possess a comparatively high social status or, more accurately, considerable influence on local opinions and actions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-2&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the county town, almost every industry has these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins.&amp;rdquo; They might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Especially teachers with decades of experience in local areas, who may not be graduates of prestigious universities, but deeply understand how to build credibility through knowledge and are widely respected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Officials in county-level cities, such as deputy county commissioners and section chiefs, control certain resources and power. Despite their relatively low positions, due to the limited scope of their authority, they can become influential figures within their localities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Owners in some county-level cities, though their businesses may not be large, hold considerable wealth and local influence. They might run a couple of well-known small enterprises and have significant sway within the county.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These individuals, though not prominent compared to elites or officials in big cities, hold a status almost equivalent to &amp;ldquo;cultural elders&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;power centers&amp;rdquo; within this small county-level society&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-3&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the meaning of &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins,&amp;rdquo; we must consider the unique environment of county towns. Here, information flows more slowly than in big cities, and social mobility is relatively fixed. These &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; often gain influence through long-term engagement with the locality, accumulating reputation, knowledge, and networks. They impact various aspects of local politics, economy, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In smaller areas, particularly where the education system may not be well-developed and ordinary people have limited choices, local &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; figures subtly shape the cultural atmosphere through knowledge imparted in classrooms, media explanations, and even social interactions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the limited population and resources in county-level towns, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often key controllers of local resources. Their influence is pervasive, affecting everything from social welfare and policy implementation to project approvals. Their power of speech and decision-making allows them to hold a significant position within the local community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a relatively closed small society, interpersonal relationships are often crucial. These &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; control the flow of information and allocation of resources by establishing strong social networks, allowing them to play a decisive role at critical moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-4&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often respected and revered, this elevated status is not without its problems. In modern society, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see that many of these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may lack genuine ability and innovative spirit, instead maintaining their position through hereditary relationships and resource monopolies. With the development of informatization, their power is gradually being eroded, and new social mobility is beginning to reshape the landscape of small counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;ldquo;County-Level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; is a fascinating social phenomenon that reflects the power and cultural structures within local societies. While their “power” may not directly threaten national governance, they are undoubtedly influential figures within their localities. In this era of rapid information flow and accelerating social change, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may be facing unprecedented challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-5&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have existed at all, but out of curiosity—and that’s how this article came to be&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
