<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>New Oriental on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/new-oriental/</link>
        <description>Recent content in New Oriental on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/new-oriental/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Decline of Capital Monopoly and the Online Education Industry</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jul 2021 14:59:08 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/capital-monopoly-and-the-fall-of-online-education/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The stock market has fallen sharply over the past two trading days, and new investors have experienced the risks of the market. Our country is about to enter an aging stage, and the birth rate data is bleak – the decline far exceeded estimates from relevant experts. Industries hindering the birth rate will be cracked down on by our party.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reducing-student-workload&#34;&gt;Reducing student workload
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;We, born in the 90s, didn&amp;rsquo;t have so many extracurricular classes or tutoring sessions. After school, we would just run wild and play – partly because our families couldn’t afford it, and partly because tutoring services hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet established a brand reputation to convince parents. Twenty years have passed. Starting in 2019, the capitalization of K12 education began, with companies like Yuanfudao emerging as leading online tutoring platforms. With capital backing, they concentrated resources to create various prestigious tutoring programs, and even exorbitant fees couldn&amp;rsquo;t deter parental enthusiasm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the process of urbanization, many parents have broken free from poverty and achieved upward mobility through education. Their work as office workers leaves them with little time to care for their children; they are under immense pressure themselves and don&amp;rsquo;t want their children to fall behind their peers. It’s difficult for someone from a humble background to rise above it without an appropriate education. In China, ordinary families find it hard to maintain or further advance their social class without one. If a child enters vocational high school, the perceived decline in social status is something most parents cannot accept.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s look back at why extracurricular tutoring exists, and why parents need it. The knowledge and example questions in textbooks are easy to understand, but many subjects cover a broad range of topics, though they are mostly superficial concepts without much depth. Talent selection mechanisms require a certain degree of differentiation, which leads to a contradiction: test questions based solely on textbook knowledge cannot achieve the screening effect and need to be expanded horizontally and vertically. These areas are impossible for teachers to cover in class, and this space has fostered the growth of extracurricular tutoring.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document contains a large amount of content, with thirty detailed provisions regulating various aspects. Here&amp;rsquo;s a summary of the guiding document outline:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reduce overall homework volume and duration comprehensively, alleviating students&amp;rsquo; excessive workload&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Improve the quality of schools’ after-school services to meet students&amp;rsquo; diverse needs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strictly regulate and govern off-campus tutoring activities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Significantly improve the quality of education and teaching, ensuring that students learn well and master their studies while at school&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Strengthen supporting measures and enhance capabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Carefully organized and implemented, striving for practical results&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;elite-education&#34;&gt;Elite education
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the education industry, there&amp;rsquo;s another phenomenon: an increasing number of private schools are emerging, and public schools are struggling to provide sufficient high-quality resources (leading to the rise of academic district housing). Various large-scale education groups attract quality teachers with high salaries, establish excellent teaching environments, and gradually build their own brands. The most famous example is the &lt;strong&gt;Yancheng Model&lt;/strong&gt;. In my hometown, the average company salary is around 3,000 yuan, while a good private elementary school can cost between 9,000 to 10,000 yuan for an entire year of tuition. Education groups create a virtuous cycle: I charge high tuition fees, but the teachers are excellent, and the students achieve good grades. This allows me to raise tuition fees, and parents will still send their children here. Public school resources (teachers) will gradually be attracted to private schools, eventually becoming synonymous with inferior education.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;algorithm-squeezing&#34;&gt;Algorithm squeezing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Data indicates that Meituan has nearly four million signed-up riders, with 400,000 to 500,000 active riders. Many rely on this work to support their families. Endless algorithmic pressure squeezes delivery time, reducing people to quantifiable units and feeding them into calculations. It constantly explores the breaking point of delivery personnel. They think they&amp;rsquo;re clever, &lt;strong&gt;disregarding human nature to serve capital&lt;/strong&gt;. The market is here; let’s play it well, sustainably, rather than &lt;strong&gt;monopolizing and granting special privileges – a capitalist game where reckless growth will inevitably end.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-volatility&#34;&gt;Stock market volatility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On July 24, 2021, education stocks represented by New Oriental performed a fancy dive, and the good future followed in American trading before the market opened, &lt;strong&gt;halving its stock price&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our country has gradually entered an aging population phase, and various social phenomena affecting family planning must be addressed; internet companies with monopolistic practices and excessive overtime have been fined, and the education industry where capital is concentrated has also been regulated&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is no allowing for the capitalization of the education industry; one vote directly rejects companies in that sector from going public and seeking financing, resulting in widespread lamentations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;New Oriental&amp;rsquo;s Severed Waist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Waist-cutting New Oriental&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pinduoduo&amp;rsquo;s Plunge&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s Plunge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regulators Intensify Scrutiny, Online Education Industry Suddenly &amp;ldquo;Brakes&amp;rdquo;
The General Office of the State Council issued the &amp;ldquo;Opinions on Further Reducing the Homework Burden and Off-Campus Tutoring Burden for Students in Compulsory Education Stage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
