<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fixed-Income on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fixed-income/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Fixed-Income on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fixed-income/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Fund and fixed income wealth management</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For those of us born in the 90s, we didn&amp;rsquo;t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis because we were young and not yet focused on investing. The bull market of 2015 was dramatic, with a significant correction before government intervention stabilized it. This brought the concept of investment funds into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alipay, as a natural traffic entry point under Ant Group, was initially positioned as a payment tool. Most people chose Alipay for buying funds compared to WeChat. Alipay successfully transformed fund sales into ordinary shopping. The bull market starting in 2019 and the mutual support among fund managers were ultimately driven by pandemic-induced monetary easing. Those who entered (the market) profited, while those who watched became envious and rushed to enter. The speed at which new funds surpass 10 billion yuan is accelerating. With even older generations now buying funds, trillion-dollar funds are within reach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before the rise of Ant Group&amp;rsquo;s internet-based fund sales platform, ordinary people typically encountered fund sales only when depositing money at banks, where branch managers would enthusiastically promote various financial products. The packaging and promotional information on the internet, along with the exorbitant advertising fees paid by fund sales institutions, have made Alipay’s fund advertisements completely detached from reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The provided growth data only shows the returns for the past three years on the table, and only the annualized average return for legacy funds. Why don&amp;rsquo;t they publish the annual average return separately? Is it difficult to calculate? No, it’s because the data is unfavorable and doesn&amp;rsquo;t easily encourage customers to buy the fund.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investments&#34;&gt;Fixed income investments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China has not yet entered the era of negative interest rates. Bank deposits and government bonds are the most reliable fixed-income products; pure bond funds are also a good option. You can easily find China&amp;rsquo;s average salary by checking data released by local statistical bureaus. Here’s a simple scenario: with 2 million yuan in assets, an annualized return of 4% would generate annual income exceeding the average salary in most cities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s a lot I could write. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading books on economics; don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow trends. For ordinary families, the core of financial management is preservation of value, not chasing get-rich-quick schemes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Doing the right thing at the right time yields the greatest value. Studying diligently and obtaining a good education is better than earning pocket money distributing flyers. Working hard after graduation brings substantial returns in salary increases. When starting a family, learn to care for your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those interested can check out this speech: Regarding time, you need to read many books to find the answer; the full text is available on this site&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
