<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Motherboard on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/motherboard/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Motherboard on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/motherboard/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Occasional disk recognition issues due to too many disks installed on ASUS Z490 motherboards</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the previous discussion, I encountered an issue where the wireless network card was not being recognized. Before rebuilding the partitions, I also researched other solutions online, such as removing the motherboard battery and disconnecting power for fifteen minutes; or upgrading to the latest BIOS driver—but all of these proved problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking there were still things to deal with, I switched to a limited network and ran the ethernet cable from the living room to the room. Then the problem reappeared – the wired network wasn&amp;rsquo;t recognized either. I tried a drastic measure: reinstalling the system, which resulted in a missing partition error. If this had been happening consistently, I wouldn’t have bothered troubleshooting for so long. This ASUS disk conflict seems intermittent and triggered by unstable system restarts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, a new disk was added to the desktop – a 2TB solid-state drive from Yangtze Memory (YMTC), M.2 interface. The machine hasn&amp;rsquo;t been restarted since then until it was shut down yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinstall-system&#34;&gt;Reinstall system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been two years since I last reinstalled the system. The C drive is full, and Windows has its usual issues – various software likes to store things on the C drive. So, I decided to reinstall the system. After reinstalling, the network card issue was resolved, and I restored my development environment the next day. Just as I was preparing a system backup, a new problem arose: the boot partition is missing after restarting the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the steps from the previous article, I rebuilt the boot partition, but it&amp;rsquo;s unstable. It might not load after a reboot. I initially suspected issues with the case, then checked the hard drive cable connections several times, but everything seems fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-revival&#34;&gt;Memory revival
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, this machine had an SSD installed using a PCIe adapter (plugged into the graphics card slot) instead of directly connecting it to the motherboard. This time, installing it directly on the motherboard might indicate a motherboard issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motherboard-manual&#34;&gt;Motherboard manual
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motherboard manual contains an error: the labeled SATA port locations do not match the actual locations. With multiple disks installed in all available ports (many of which are older SSDs using SATA), and according to the manual, there&amp;rsquo;s a conflict between these ports. Testing revealed this conflict is triggered intermittently, causing the affected disk to fail to load. This is problematic as it’s the system disk with the boot files, resulting in boot failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/20250110002401.png&#34;
	width=&#34;807&#34;
	height=&#34;847&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Z490&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;228px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reinstalling the solid-state drive on the PCIe adapter resolves conflicts with the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s SATA ports, allowing the system to boot normally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
