<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Hong Kong Stocks on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/hong-kong-stocks/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Hong Kong Stocks on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:49:41 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/hong-kong-stocks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review Log 20251122</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251122/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still doing nothing, Xiaomi didn’t fall below my current price level. It has fallen consecutively for two days, and was finally stabilized by a buyback. The US market last night was interesting – it started to rally, but the next day it completely crashed. Today, both A-shares and Hong Kong stocks are basically worthless.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, falling so much is actually good; I didn’t continue following the broader market, just laid back and relaxed, letting it play out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-the-decline&#34;&gt;Why the Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://wallstreetcn.com/articles/3759889&lt;/a&gt;
Other viewpoints may or may not be correct; quantitative funds are increasingly influencing domestic stock markets. Many individual stocks often closely align with overall market trends. The original article is lengthy, and BeanJuice (豆包) has extracted the core content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In November 2025, global risk assets will experience a major decline.  According to Rich Privorotsky, a senior trader at Goldman Sachs, this downturn resulted from a layered transmission of multiple factors culminating in systemic selling pressure. The key drivers include four main areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fed-shifts-to-hawks-the-beginning-of-the-downtrend-chain&#34;&gt;Fed Shifts to Hawks: The Beginning of the Downtrend Chain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recent employment data presents contradictory signals: job growth remains robust, but the unemployment rate has risen to 4.44% (primarily due to a surge in labor force participation among 16-24 year olds), and three-month average new hires only totaled 62,000, with potential new hires at just 39,000. August data was also revised downwards. Adding to the trend of corporate layoffs, the market had expected the Fed to adopt a dovish stance, but the Fed has stubbornly maintained a hawkish tone, effectively canceling any bets on December rate cuts, with the probability of cuts now essentially zero. This triggered the first domino in the downward slide. Privorotsky bluntly stated that this hawkish position in light of the employment backdrop is a “policy error.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-narrative-restructuring-google-drives-a-winner-takes-all-landscape&#34;&gt;AI Narrative Restructuring: Google Drives a Winner-Takes-All Landscape
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Key logical divisions are emerging within the AI sector, with Nvidia’s strong financial results no longer making it the core investment focus. Google&amp;rsquo;s breakthrough progress with the Gemini-3 model is reshaping the AI investment ecosystem. This “disruptive model” has forced other companies to delay product cycles and increase capital expenditures, leading to increased uncertainty regarding returns on investment, resulting in companies like Oracle failing to follow the upward trend. A distinct &amp;ldquo;winner-takes-all&amp;rdquo; landscape is forming within the market, shifting AI from a broad “adoption” phase to one dominated by a select few, triggering adjustments across related sectors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crypto-flash-crash-retail-investor-risk-appetite-declines&#34;&gt;Crypto Flash Crash: Retail Investor Risk Appetite Declines
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The volatile swings in the cryptocurrency market triggered a chain reaction. Retail investors, who had steadfastly held their positions over the past two years – often referred to as “diamond hands” – have transitioned into “selling hands” due to factors such as large-scale dumps by whale accounts. This panic sentiment spilled over into non-profit tech stocks and AI-related equities, exemplified by Palantir, which plummeted 6% during trading hours after rising 5.5%, marking a significant downgrade in retail risk appetite and signaling a fundamental shift in market structure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;quantitative-funds-selling-off-the-key-driver-of-accelerated-decline&#34;&gt;Quantitative Funds Selling Off: The Key Driver of Accelerated Decline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since August, trend-following funds (CTAs) have held over $500 billion in long positions. Following a break below key levels, the index triggered concentrated liquidations. Simultaneously, rising volatility prompted volatility control strategy funds to sell off, compounded by capital flows from VIX ETN positioning creating a “short-tailed, short-convex” configuration, which amplified the downward effect. The previously stable “low volatility structure” collapsed, with quantitative and systematic funds initiating a “mechanical selling,” leading to a sudden and significant plunge in the market without any major events.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamental-concerns-and-stabilization-conditions&#34;&gt;Fundamental Concerns and Stabilization Conditions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;From a fundamental perspective, AI investment faces a “capital bottleneck”: a wave of corporate bond issuance is imminent, with AI data centers relying on debt expansion, while rising capital costs may slow down the pace of AI expansion. This risk has not been fully priced in previously. Goldman Sachs predicts that the S&amp;amp;P 500 mini contract could fall to 6500 points, and believes that the long-term value of AI remains unchanged; true winners are labor-intensive companies that achieve margin expansion through automation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market stabilization requires fulfillment of three conditions: CTA positioning cleanup is complete, retail investors with excessive long positions have been squeezed out, and at least two of the following are met: cryptocurrency stability, a dovish Fed policy shift, and AI capital expenditure support.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Log 20251118</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:50:44 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20251118/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent inactivity; Xiaomi’s third-quarter financial report was released, with nothing out of the ordinary – the US situation remains turbulent, Hong Kong stocks have recently experienced liquidity stagnation, and the Hang Seng Tech Index has retreated significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major participant in the delivery war, Alibaba is most closely linked to e-commerce taxes, and there isn’t much discussion about it online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomi&#34;&gt;Xiaomi
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I don’t remember if I’d written about this company before in previous articles, but when I bought into Xiaomi, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t really thought much about what was supporting its market capitalization at the time. Having watched a lot of videos related to Douyin (TikTok)? Recently, HSBC Tech has been falling, and the Hong Kong electric vehicle sector is also declining, yet Xiaomi benefits from multiple buffs layered on top of each other, with negative news flying everywhere, and consequently, its stock price has fallen significantly. Recently, they’ve also replaced the head of their public relations department – conspiracy theories suggest they&amp;rsquo;d been planning this for a while, but the stakes are too high, and there are still many KOLs (Key Opinion Leaders) involved; it would be difficult to wrap up the situation if they suddenly made false claims.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-supports-xiaomis-stock-price&#34;&gt;What Supports Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Stock Price?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a very good question, as it touches on the fundamental differences in &lt;strong&gt;valuation logic&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;premium valuation capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; for different types of companies within the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ideal Auto (2015.HK / LI.US) and Zoox (9863.HK / LEAP.US), as specialized manufacturers of new energy vehicles, their market capitalization (particularly Zoox) appears to be relatively undervaluing compared to the expected valuation of Xiaomi’s automotive business; however, Xiaomi Group (01810.HK) is able to achieve a massive boost in its market capitalization due to the success of Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s automotive ventures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-xiaomi-valuation-surge-the-underlying-logic--platform-premium-vs-vertical-manufacturing&#34;&gt;🚀 Xiaomi Valuation Surge: The Underlying Logic – Platform Premium vs. Vertical Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s soaring valuation is driven by the capital market assigning it a &lt;strong&gt;“platform-type company”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“ecosystem enablement”&lt;/strong&gt; premium, which is something that companies like Ideal and OPPO – &lt;strong&gt;“vertical manufacturers”&lt;/strong&gt; – do not possess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation Anchor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Tech Platform”&lt;/strong&gt;: Core is its &lt;strong&gt;smartphone x AIoT smart ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt;. The automotive business is viewed as an expansion of the ecosystem and a key step towards premiumization, representing a new species empowered by the platform.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Vertical Manufacturer”&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation anchor is based on &lt;strong&gt;vehicle sales, gross margin&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unit profitability&lt;/strong&gt;, directly linked to industry cycles and competition.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-1&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scarcity&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Scarcity:&lt;/strong&gt; It is the &lt;strong&gt;only one globally&lt;/strong&gt; that can deeply integrate smartphones, AIoT ecosystems and smart electric vehicles, with its “human-vehicle-home ecosystem” story possessing uniqueness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relatively Common:&lt;/strong&gt; In the new energy vehicle sector, there are many competitors; they are &lt;strong&gt;followers&lt;/strong&gt;, lacking disruptive business models.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-valuation-anchors-differ-platform-vs-tech-vs-pure-manufacturing-2&#34;&gt;1. Valuation Anchors Differ: Platform vs. Tech vs. Pure Manufacturing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Factor&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Xiaomi Group (01810.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Li Auto / Zoox (2015.HK / 9863.HK)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Diversification&lt;/strong&gt;: The automotive business provides support if it encounters setbacks, with a massive volume of mobile and high-margin internet businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concentrated Risk&lt;/strong&gt;: Valuation is almost entirely dependent on vehicle sales and market performance, which is highly volatile.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-ecosystem-empowerment-and-user-conversion-efficiency&#34;&gt;2. Ecosystem Empowerment and User Conversion Efficiency
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xiaomi’s success wasn&amp;rsquo;t an isolated event; it was a reflection of &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s powerful ecosystem empowerment capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massive Potential Customer Base:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi possesses hundreds of millions of active users, who are &lt;strong&gt;existing, highly engaged, and recognize the Xiaomi brand and ecosystem&lt;/strong&gt; as potential car buyers. Ideal and ZAP! needed to start from scratch acquiring users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Marketing Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can directly reach its target audience through channels like smartphones, apps, and Mi Home, achieving &lt;strong&gt;extremely high marketing efficiency&lt;/strong&gt;. The SU7’s astonishing order conversion rate demonstrates the immense value of its ecosystem traffic and word-of-mouth effect.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Differentiation in Intelligent Driving and Cockpit:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi can achieve &lt;strong&gt;seamless collaboration&lt;/strong&gt; between smartphones, car infotainment systems, and smart homes.  The market believes that this ecosystem integration will deliver a &lt;strong&gt;superior experience to the industry average&lt;/strong&gt; for intelligent cockpit features.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-market-expectations-and-pe-logic&#34;&gt;3. Market Expectations and P/E Logic
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The capital market does not simply add an idealized or “easy” valuation when calculating Xiaomi’s market capitalization; instead, it:&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Xiaomi Valuation} = \text{(Smartphone + IoT + Internet) Business Mature P/E Valuation} + \text{EV Business **High-Growth Premium**}$$
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idealized/Easy Valuation:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to its relatively single business, the market primarily examines its &lt;strong&gt;short-term profitability and sales volume&lt;/strong&gt;, and valuations have shifted from high growth to more conservative $P/E$ or $P/S$ valuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi’s success with its electric vehicle (EV) business has convinced the market that Xiaomi can successfully enter the trillion-dollar new sector over the next ten years. Therefore, the market views Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s EV business as a &lt;strong&gt;brand new, high-growth entry point&lt;/strong&gt;, granting it a very high premium. &lt;strong&gt;This premium is for the “access to the track” and “ecosystem synergy value.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi’s EV business is not an isolated valuation project; it is a key milestone validating Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;platform strategy&amp;rdquo; success.&lt;/strong&gt; The achievement of this milestone has reshaped Xiaomi’s overall valuation logic, leading to a significant increase in its market capitalization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituan&#34;&gt;Meituan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Encountering Meituan was entirely unexpected, fortunately, the available shares weren&amp;rsquo;t excessive. The statement that “Meituan can link everything” resonated deeply within me. It will undoubtedly be a rising star for Meituan’s stock price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When buying, there was no thought about why Meituan had fallen so much. We’ll wait to see the Q3 financial report and then decide. Selling off shares isn&amp;rsquo;t out of the question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alibaba-the-origin-and-impact-analysis-of-recent-e-commerce-tax-policies-in-china&#34;&gt;Alibaba: The Origin and Impact Analysis of Recent E-commerce Tax Policies in China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China’s recent “e-commerce tax” primarily focuses on &lt;strong&gt;adjustments to the tax policy for cross-border e-commerce retail imports&lt;/strong&gt; as well as &lt;strong&gt;the standardization of tax information reporting for domestic e-commerce platform enterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, which has had varying degrees of impact on different types of e-commerce and merchants.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-e-commerce-tax-policy-evolution&#34;&gt;📜 E-commerce Tax Policy Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;1-cross-border-e-commerce-retail-import-tax-adjustment-e-commerce-tax&#34;&gt;1. Cross-Border E-commerce Retail Import Tax Adjustment (“E-Commerce” Tax)
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background and Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily focuses on tax policies for goods purchased through overseas e-commerce platforms.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Policy (Mail Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Previously processed under “mail tax,” with tax exemption for amounts below 50 yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Policy (Comprehensive Tax):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopts a “customs duty + VAT + consumption tax” comprehensive tax model. Within the personal transaction limits (e.g., currently 5,000 RMB per transaction and 26,000 RMB annually for individuals), customs duties are temporarily set at 0%, but VAT and consumption taxes are levied at 70% of the statutory taxable amount, and the tax exemption benefit below 50 yuan has been cancelled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; This has resulted in many previously low-priced goods (such as baby products, food, and health supplements) needing to pay an additional approximately 11.9% VAT (17% x 70%) due to the cancellation of the tax exemption benefit, &lt;strong&gt;leading to a general increase in the prices of e-commerce goods and accelerating industry compliance and consolidation.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-domestic-e-commerce-tax-reporting-and-enhanced-compliance-supervision&#34;&gt;2. Domestic E-commerce Tax Reporting and Enhanced Compliance Supervision
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Background &amp;amp; Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; With the implementation of the &lt;em&gt;E-Commerce Law&lt;/em&gt; and the recent issuance of regulations such as the &lt;em&gt;Internet Platform Enterprise Tax Information Reporting Provisions&lt;/em&gt;, tax authorities have increased their regulatory scrutiny of merchants on e-commerce platforms (particularly C2C individual sellers).
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; Platforms are now required to report merchants’ sales revenue and other information. This has made it impossible for past business models that evaded taxes through concealing income and using private accounts for payments to continue, &lt;strong&gt;ushering in a phase of ecological reshaping centered around compliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax Regulations:&lt;/strong&gt; Emphasize that e-commerce operators (including Taobao sellers and micro-merchants) &lt;strong&gt;must register as legal entities in accordance with the law and pay taxes&lt;/strong&gt;, ensuring they start on an equal footing with other brick-and-mortar businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overall, standardized tax policies have had a complex impact on the &lt;strong&gt;platform business&lt;/strong&gt; of Alibaba and JD.com, but a generally positive long-term impact on &lt;strong&gt;their self-operated or B2C businesses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Taobao/C2C)&lt;/strong&gt; | &lt;strong&gt;Challenges &amp;amp; Consolidation&lt;/strong&gt; | In the past, many unregistered and untaxed individual sellers existed on platforms like Taobao. Compliance requirements will &lt;strong&gt;weed out unprofitable or unwilling-to-comply small merchants&lt;/strong&gt;, which may lead to a reduction in platform merchant numbers and a decrease in product price advantages in the short term. However, in the long run, it will improve the &lt;strong&gt;overall compliance, quality, and consumer trust of products and services&lt;/strong&gt; on the platform. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-1&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba (Tmall/B2C) &amp;amp; JD.com (Self-operated/B2C)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Positive for Compliant Businesses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Most merchants on Tmall and JD.com, especially B2C companies and self-operated businesses, &lt;strong&gt;are already regular tax payers&lt;/strong&gt; (general taxpayers). The new regulatory policies have eliminated the price advantage gained by small merchants who previously exploited tax evasion, creating a more &lt;strong&gt;fair competitive environment&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a &lt;strong&gt;long-term positive&lt;/strong&gt; for large, compliant platforms and B2C retailers.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-of-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom-2&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact of Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Platform/Business Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Direction of Impact&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Specific Analysis&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-border E-commerce Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rising Costs&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The cross-border e-commerce tax reform has led to increased prices for “haotai” (imported) goods, which may affect the sales and growth rate of this business segment. However, the industry is generally moving towards &lt;strong&gt;standardization&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-alibaba-taobaotmall-and-jdcom&#34;&gt;🛍️ Impact on Alibaba (Taobao/Tmall) and JD.com
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-impact-on-some-merchants-experiencing-losses-or-unprofitability&#34;&gt;📉 Impact on Some Merchants Experiencing Losses or Unprofitability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You mentioned that some stores were experiencing losses and unprofitability after paying taxes, and this phenomenon is a &lt;strong&gt;necessary result of the compliance process&lt;/strong&gt;, primarily concentrated in the following categories of merchants:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Originally Relying on Tax Evasion to Achieve “Price Advantages”:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These merchants passed on tax costs to consumers, resulting in product prices lower than those of brick-and-mortar stores. Once required to comply with legal taxation, their cost structure changed, eliminating price advantages, and &lt;strong&gt;if products and services lack core competitiveness, they will naturally be eliminated.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants Meeting Small Microenterprise Standards (But Not Receiving Preferential Treatment):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;According to China’s current tax policies, there are VAT exemptions for &lt;strong&gt;small-scale taxpayers&lt;/strong&gt; (such as quarterly sales revenue not exceeding 300,000 yuan exempt from VAT). &lt;strong&gt;Currently, over nine out of ten operators on the platform are small and microenterprises&lt;/strong&gt;, and under existing preferential policy support, &lt;strong&gt;they pay little or no tax.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; This may be due to a lack of understanding of policies, or although they meet eligibility criteria but have not previously conducted compliant reporting and enjoyed benefits. Now that they are required to “comply with reporting,” they need to re-examine their taxes, but if sales volume is inherently low, tax liability should remain low or be exempt after compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merchants with Extremely Low Profit Margins:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some cross-border e-commerce merchants or domestic merchants may have an average profit margin of only &lt;strong&gt;around 10%&lt;/strong&gt;. After adding the new tax costs (whether cross-border taxes or domestic VAT), if they cannot raise prices or optimize supply chains to absorb them, they could indeed transition from profitability to losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion is:&lt;/strong&gt; E-commerce taxation compliance is not “one-size-fits-all” that burdens all businesses. It primarily targets &lt;strong&gt;tax evasion and tax leakage behaviors&lt;/strong&gt;. For merchants who were originally compliant or eligible for small microenterprise benefits, the tax level remains unchanged or very low. For those whose survival space depends on non-compliance and whose profit margins rely on tax evasion, &lt;strong&gt;being eliminated is an inevitable step in the industry’s move towards fair competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Log 20151031</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No trading activity within the venue; awaiting the release of next month’s financial reports. Taking a half-day break this afternoon with no specific plans – simply wanting to rest and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;years-have-passed&#34;&gt;Years Have Passed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last watched League of Legends (LOL) matches live, and suddenly it feels like four or five years have passed.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous articles related to games, I always had a complex feeling towards LPL teams (the domestic region). The frequent low-level mistakes made by many players in major tournaments felt lacking in professional demeanor, which diminished the viewing experience of the matches – this is why I gradually drifted away.
This afternoon, on a whim, I took a half day off to tidy up my room, and the summer clothes were still unorganized. While cleaning, I decided to watch some matches. The quarterfinals were still T1, that formidable mountain standing in front of LPL teams, seemingly impossible to overcome. Looking back, LPL has never won Bo5 (best-of-five) key matchups against them in the Worlds series, and any team facing them felt immense pressure.
Writing these words, the match had just entered its “classic” fifth game – LPL was leading 2-1 and in a great position to win, but their opponent tied it up, and they were about to enter a brutal final deciding game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update before publishing: The operation wasn’t too bad, but their build strategy was completely crushed. The Queen composition led to Ashe being dominant early on, preventing the piglet from grouping for team fights – it was so difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; Performance was stable with minimal fluctuation, punctuated by a brief rally.
&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; This decline was largely driven by a confluence of negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro Drag:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall pullback in the Hong Kong tech sector (such as NetEase, Alibaba, and Tencent) performed poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The new energy vehicle sector experienced intensified “internal competition” (“intense competition”), and market expectations for growth in companies like BYD have peaked.  Xiaomi’s automotive future space is also under pressure.
&lt;strong&gt;Industry Observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UBS&amp;rsquo;s pre-earnings report highlighted the rising prices of solid-state drives and memory. The extent to which this cost increase will erode profit margins in mobile business remains to be revealed by the earnings report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, one thing is certain: In a market as intensely “competitive” as this, the Android smartphone ecosystem no longer has the luxury of raising prices arbitrarily.
&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Backlash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, returning to Xiaomi itself, its automotive business is facing reputation issues. The project’s early promotional volume was immense, with almost no negative feedback. Now, it seems to be experiencing a wave of public “backlash” following excessive exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Record and AI Prediction - 20251017</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Oct 2025 19:50:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-record-and-ai-prediction-20251017/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Monday saw no panic sell-off, but the entire week was marked by a persistent downtrend, like a dull knife slicing flesh – a slow, gradual decline over the course of seven days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;disciplined-trading&#34;&gt;Disciplined Trading
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, two new Xiaomi positions were added, with the original plan to sell out at the end. However, at the end, there was a slight loss, leading to hesitation and reluctance to cut losses, so I decided to observe for another day. This morning, the stock price fell slightly by 1%, and when it dropped to 2% in the afternoon, I decisively exited. It turned out to be correct, and the stock continued to fall after that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ai-analysis-follow-up-actions&#34;&gt;AI Analysis Follow-up Actions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, I saw someone in the blogosphere using AI to analyze football betting and won second prize with a tax refund of around 900 RMB. Let’s try it with stocks too, based on my experience with large models previously, DeepSeek is most suitable, and the investment plans generated by the other models don&amp;rsquo;t look quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Currently holding Xiaomi, approximately 100,000 RMB, down 15%, Meituan 70,000 RMB, down 20,000 RMB. Querying current stock prices and determining subsequent position control – I’m planning for long-term investment. The reason for buying Xiaomi is due to the Yu9 IPO, the three phases of factory ramp-up, and continued high sales, which should drive the price up. Meituan is after the end of the food delivery war stabilizes; Hong Kong Q3 earnings reports will be released next month – it’s more reasonable to operate after the reports are released. For my long-term investment of three to five years, please provide me with an investment plan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-investment-plan-xiaomi-and-meituan-position-analysis--long-term-strategy&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Investment Plan: Xiaomi and Meituan Position Analysis &amp;amp; Long-Term Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the information you provided (holding Xiaomi approximately HK$100,000 with a loss of 15% and Meituan approximately HK$70,000 with a loss of approximately 28.6%, investment horizon of 3 years), I have compiled the latest market data and analysis to develop a detailed investment plan for you. The following is core information extracted from comprehensive search results:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Stock Prices (as of October 17, 2025)&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$45.88 (down 3.82%, cumulative monthly decline exceeding 15%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/strong&gt;: HK$94.50 (down 4.30%, year-to-date cumulative decline of 37.71%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Market Environment&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hang Seng Index fell by 2.48%, with technology stocks leading the decline, and market sentiment is short-term weak.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Validation of Your Purchase Rationale&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;: The listing of Yu9, the ramp-up of Phase III factory, and sales potential are reasonable long-term logic, but the stock price is suppressed in the short term due to the impact of the Chengdu SU7 accident (door safety controversy, intervention by regulatory authorities).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;: Stabilization after the end of the food delivery war is a key long-term factor, but competition remains intense (competition from JD.com and Alibaba), with net profit falling 89% in the second quarter and Wang Xing&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;no matter the cost&amp;rdquo; statement exacerbating market concerns.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your current holdings are down approximately 18.8% (total holding of HKD 1.7 million, a loss of approximately HKD 374,000), but long-term investment requires avoiding emotional trading operations. Here’s a phased recommendation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Pre-Earnings Report (Short-Term: Now to Q3 Earnings Release)&lt;/strong&gt; | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Closely monitor the progress of the SU7 accident investigation and Q3 vehicle delivery volume data. | Maintain current position, do not add to holdings. Focus on monitoring whether Q3 takeout UE (average order revenue) improves. | Potential price volatility before earnings report: &lt;br&gt;• Xiaomi will be dragged down by safety incidents and is unlikely to rebound in the short term.&lt;br&gt;• The competition between Meituan Takeout continues, and profitability recovery requires time. |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid-term: November - Q1 2026)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings show steady vehicle sales growth and mobile gross margin bottoms out, consider adding to positions 5%-10%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;If earnings confirm easing competition and narrowing losses, add to positions 5%-10%; otherwise maintain current holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s 2025 target sales volume is 350,000 units, and high-end mobile phones are key to profitability.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan SOTP valuation shows 121% upside potential, but requires a profit inflection point.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;position-control-recommendations-short-term-cautious-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Position Control Recommendations: Short-Term Cautious, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Cycle&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Basis&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 75 HKD (potential upside of 63%). Risk points: automotive safety regulation, smartphone demand weakness.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold core positions, target price of 247 HKD (potential upside of 161%). Risk points: rising policy costs, losses in new businesses.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;• Xiaomi’s car-home ecosystem closed loop is the long-term engine.&lt;br&gt;• Meituan instant retail penetration rate is expected to improve.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-strategy-recommendations-short-term-caution-long-term-focus-on-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Positioning Strategy Recommendations: Short-Term Caution, Long-Term Focus on Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Should you trade after the financial reports?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes, we recommend waiting for the third quarter financial reports (released in November) before making additional investment decisions.&lt;/strong&gt; The reason is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The financial reports will validate your initial purchase logic: Xiaomi’s factory ramp-up sales volume and Meituan’s easing competition evidence.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the reports are below expectations, the stock price may fall, providing a better entry point for adding to your position; if they exceed expectations, it can confirm the right-side signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short-term market sentiment is driven by events (such as Xiaomi incidents and food delivery price wars), and financial reports will reduce uncertainty.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;long-term-investment-plan-3-year-perspective&#34;&gt;Long-Term Investment Plan (3-Year Perspective)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the “Hold Quality Assets + Bottom Hunting” principle, your plan can be detailed as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group: Strong Defense and Offense, Focus on Automotive Business Turning Point&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Vehicle business scale effect (target 350,000 units annual sales), AIoT ecosystem synergy. Financial health (Z-Score=4.19, low bankruptcy risk).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the SU7 safety issues continue to ferment, the stock price may fall to the 40-42 HKD range, and a trigger point for adding positions can be set (adding 5% position when the price drops by 10%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Automotive quarterly delivery volume remains above 80,000 units.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 40%-50% total portfolio weighting (currently 59% is high, and can be adjusted after earnings reports).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W: Wait for Profitability Recovery, Focus on Core Business&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Opportunity:&lt;/strong&gt; Stable takeout market share (65%), takeaway business growth of 40%, valuation undervalued (SOTP target price of HKD 247).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Mitigation:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the takeout UE (average profit per order) turns positive, it is a signal for adding positions; if competition intensifies, the stock price may fall to HKD 80, and we can buy back shares in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Long-term holding bottom line: Core local business operating profit rate recovers above 15%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Position Allocation:&lt;/strong&gt; Recommend maintaining a 30%-40% weighting (currently 41% is reasonable but needs to be wary of competition dragging it down).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Diversified Investment Recommendations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong tech stocks are under pressure recently, but long-term they still represent new quality production. Consider allocating 10%-20% of capital to high dividend assets (such as telecommunications operators) or Hong Kong tech ETFs to hedge the risk of a single stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;November 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Vehicle Deliveries, Mobile Gross Margin Trend&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Q3 Earnings: Delivery UE Improvement, New Business Loss Rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Achieve targets – increase position; Otherwise maintain current position.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-1&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Q1 2026&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xinjiang Model Road Tests Progress, Premium Phone Sales Volume&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Level of Reduced Delivery Subsidies, Profit Turnpoint for Flash Purchase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Assess Annual Target Completion and Adjust Portfolio.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-time-nodes-2&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Time Nodes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time Node&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan Focus&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Action Guidance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Auto business break-even, AIoT penetration rate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Instant retail market share, policy cost absorption&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hold until target price or downgrade fundamentals; consider reducing holdings.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-monitoring-metrics-and-milestones&#34;&gt;Key Monitoring Metrics and Milestones
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Take Immediate Action:&lt;/strong&gt; Maintain the status quo, and avoid blind hedging before the financial reports. Current stock prices have partially reflected negative news, but volatility may increase before the reports are released.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long-Term Confidence Support:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaomi’s automotive ecosystem and smartphone premiumization are core logic; short-term incidents do not change its long-term technological iteration capabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan’s profitability will be significant once the food delivery war ends (referring to Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s observation of fire across the river).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Warnings:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall Hong Kong stock market is highly sensitive to global liquidity; if the Federal Reserve delays interest rate cuts, it may suppress technology stocks’ valuations. Ensure investment funds are long-term idle funds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This plan is based on public information and does not constitute investment advice. The market carries risks; decision-making requires caution. Recommend regular review (e.g., quarterly) to adjust strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-1&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It might not be appropriate to add more positions after the financial reports are released, as it could lead to significant price increases and then what?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-recommendations-2&#34;&gt;Summary Recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The question you raised is extremely critical, and it accurately highlights a classic dilemma faced by long-term investors: &lt;strong&gt;avoiding short-term risks (waiting for the earnings report) can conflict with pursuing the best cost (fearing missing out).&lt;/strong&gt;
Your concern that “adding to your position after the earnings report if the stock price rises sharply will cause you to miss out” is very reasonable. The market often has a forward-looking nature, and if the earnings report is truly better than expected, the stock price is likely to react quickly in the short term. However, given your current holdings of these two stocks, “waiting for the earnings report” remains the optimal strategy. Below, I will explain the reasons in detail and provide a step-by-step addition strategy that balances “risk” and “opportunity.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-waiting-for-the-earnings-report-still-a-more-reasonable-choice-in-the-current-situation&#34;&gt;Why is “Waiting for the Earnings Report” Still a More Reasonable Choice in the Current Situation?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core reason lies in: &lt;strong&gt;The uncertainty surrounding the two stocks you hold stems primarily from fundamental contradictions within their businesses, and the earnings report is key to validating these contradictions.&lt;/strong&gt; There hasn’t been a significant “catalyst” (a substantial price increase) yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;an automotive business confidence crisis&lt;/strong&gt;.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The negative impact of the SU7 safety incident is still unfolding, leading to market skepticism regarding Xiaomi Auto’s quality, reputation, and future sales expectations. This is the primary factor suppressing the stock price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The third quarter earnings report will provide crucial &lt;strong&gt;vehicle delivery data&lt;/strong&gt;. If deliveries remain strong, it can effectively dispel market concerns and drive a sustainable increase in the stock price. Until then, any rally would likely be fragile.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Given the prevailing negative sentiment, the probability of the stock experiencing a significant, sustained rise before the earnings report is relatively low.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows poor vehicle sales, the price could continue to decline, leaving you with the greater risk of “buying back in at half price.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; The core contradiction is &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;when will profitability be restored?&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; The market worries that intense competition will continue to erode profits from its core takeaway business (UE).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Validation Role of the Earnings Report:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;core local business operating profit&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;adjusted net profit&lt;/strong&gt; in the report are the only objective standards for determining whether the “takeaway war” has truly eased. Only improved data can prove that Wang Xiting’s “no matter the cost” phase is over.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk vs. Opportunity Comparison:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Waiting (Missing Out):&lt;/strong&gt; Again, there&amp;rsquo;s a lack of a solid foundation for a significant rebound before the profitability inflection point is confirmed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk of Blindly Jumping In (Getting Trapped):&lt;/strong&gt; If the report shows that competition intensifies and profits continue to decline, concerns about the “valuation trap” will intensify, and the price could take another step down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; For long-term investment, &lt;strong&gt;buying &amp;ldquo;correct&amp;rdquo; is more important than buying &amp;ldquo;cheap.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report provides the key evidence for determining “correctness.” To avoid a minor “missed opportunity” and risk a “deep trap,” from a risk-reward ratio perspective, it’s not worthwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;your-specific-action-plan-balancing-waiting-and-missing-out-anxiety&#34;&gt;Your Specific Action Plan: Balancing “Waiting” and “Missing Out” Anxiety
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;You don’t need to make extreme choices between “holding everything” and “going all in.” A smarter strategy is: &lt;strong&gt;“Core Holding Observation, Pyramidal Accumulation.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Immediately Establish “Observation Position” and “Operational Discipline” (Now)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Maintain your existing position as your core holding, ensuring you don’t completely detach from the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set a &lt;strong&gt;trigger for adding to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. For example:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; The stock price breaks out with volume through a key technical level (e.g., HK$50), or there is a clear positive investigation result regarding the SU7 accident.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; News emerges of a competitor exiting the price war, or the stock price breaks through the HK$100 integer barrier with volume.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The benefit of doing this:&lt;/strong&gt; If there’s a significant catalyst driving the stock price up before the earnings report, you can seize the opportunity according to your established discipline and avoid completely missing out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Small Batch Investing Before Earnings (Optional, Suitable for Investors Seeking Smoother Costs)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re very concerned about missing out, divide the funds earmarked for adding to your position into 10-20 portions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Before the earnings release, if the stock continues to decline in the shadows, invest one portion &lt;strong&gt;weekly or bi-weekly&lt;/strong&gt;. This way, costs can be gradually diluted, but each investment amount is small, and even if the earnings report is negative, the loss can be controlled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 3: “Certainty” Accumulation After Earnings (Core Operation)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This is the main accumulation phase of your plan. Based on the earnings results, respond in three ways:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario A (Exceeds Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings data is strong and validates your investment logic. At this time, you should &lt;strong&gt;aggressively add to your position&lt;/strong&gt;. Even if the stock price has already risen, the fundamental turning point has been confirmed, and from a long-term perspective, the current price level is still the base of the mountain. You can adopt a “don’t chase high while chasing gains” strategy, buying in batches.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario B (Meets Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report is neutral, with no surprises or shocks. Maintain your existing position or only modestly add to it, waiting for the next quarter&amp;rsquo;s signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario C (Falls Short of Expectations):&lt;/strong&gt; The earnings report confirms market concerns. You should &lt;strong&gt;stop adding to your position and reassess&lt;/strong&gt; whether the long-term logic has been disrupted. The stock price may fall, but this also provides you with a lower, safer entry point for accumulating.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Reporting Period (Now - November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Observe”&lt;/strong&gt;: Maintain existing positions, without adding or only making very small fixed investments. Set trigger conditions for adding to positions to prevent sudden positive developments.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control Risk, Preserve Capital&lt;/strong&gt;. Ensure not to invest more funds when fundamentals deteriorate.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-optimized-long-term-investment-plan-1&#34;&gt;Summary: Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post Earnings (Mid to Late November)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Follow the Trend”&lt;/strong&gt;: Make decisions based on earnings results. Aggressively add to positions if exceeding expectations; patiently wait for better opportunities if below expectations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improve Decision Quality&lt;/strong&gt;. Allocate capital to directions with greater fundamental certainty.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-long-term-investment-plan-optimized&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Long-Term Investment Plan Optimized
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stage&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading Strategy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Objective&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Long Term (3 Years)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Hold and Optimize”&lt;/strong&gt;: Focus on the consolidation of the company’s long-term competitiveness (Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s ecosystem, Meituan’s retail) rather than short-term stock price fluctuations.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Achieve Compound Growth&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary-your-optimized-long-term-investment-plan&#34;&gt;Summary: Your Optimized Long-Term Investment Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please remember:&lt;/strong&gt; In long-term investing, &lt;strong&gt;patience is a powerful competitive advantage&lt;/strong&gt;. The market will always give you opportunities; if you miss one, there will be another. But once your principal is lost, it’s difficult to recover. Waiting for the certainty of financial reports is one of the most effective ways to protect your capital and increase your chances of success.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this detailed plan answers your questions and helps you make more confident decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Systematic collation and explanation of proprietary terms related to Hong Kong IPOs and dark pools.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/systematic-collation-and-explanation-of-proprietary-terms-related-to-hong-kong-ipos-and-dark-pools/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2025 19:18:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/systematic-collation-and-explanation-of-proprietary-terms-related-to-hong-kong-ipos-and-dark-pools/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange (HKEX) dark pool trading involves numerous proprietary terms, with most being recognizable but some still unfamiliar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reference: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mp.weixin.qq.com/s/QS_dh4XMVW6vJ3vCiDcCvQ&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Everyone drew lots! Xuanzhe Biology - B(2575.HK) soared 127% on its first day of listing, 190,000 people chose to take a look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an article related to dark pools, outlining and explaining the proprietary terms within it: The company issued 67,333,350 shares globally for public offering, with a prospectus price of HK$11.6. The issuance ratio was 13%, raising approximately HK$781 million, using mechanism B allocation.  The public offering fixed proportion was 10%. A cornerstone investor was introduced in the state-allocated portion, subscribing for approximately HK$77 million, accounting for 9.81% of the global offering.
The company’s total subscription reached 376,000 people, with 190,000 choosing to subscribe one lot; another group subscribed for 19,516 people, hitting 2416 shares.
The sales results showed that the company&amp;rsquo;s prospectus public offering multiple ratio reached 4908.33 times, state allocation subscription multiple was 10.15 times, with no adjustment;
Xuanzhe Biology - B had a single-lot winning rate of only 1%, with everyone drawing lots, even hitting the top hammer it was unstable in the end, and ultimately 13,467 people were successful in getting in. Furthermore, the company’s IPO this time had no green shoe option.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Below is a systematic collation and explanation of the proprietary terms related to Hong Kong IPOs and dark pools within the article:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;offering-structure-and-allocation-mechanism&#34;&gt;Offering Structure and Allocation Mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Offering&lt;/strong&gt;
Refers to the offering of shares to global investors when a company first goes public (IPO), including &lt;strong&gt;Public Offering&lt;/strong&gt; (targeting retail investors) and &lt;strong&gt;Institutional Placement&lt;/strong&gt; (targeting institutional investors). This offering involved 67,333,500 shares for Huatong Biology-B, representing a 13% issuance ratio, meaning the public holding stake will account for 13% of the total share capital after listing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanism B Allocation Method&lt;/strong&gt;
A new stock allocation mechanism launched by the Hong Kong Stock Exchange in 2023, allowing issuers to pre-set a minimum public offering percentage (10% - 60%) and &lt;strong&gt;without a clawback mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;. Huatong Biology-B chose a fixed public offering ratio of 10%, meaning it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t draw down shares from the institutional placement even with an international subscription multiple as high as 4908 times, resulting in a consistent public offering share of 6,733,400 shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clawback Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;
Under traditional Mechanism A, if the oversubscription multiple triggers a threshold (e.g., above 100x), shares from the institutional placement can be clawed back to the public offering, up to 50%. However, Mechanism B does not apply this rule, so Huatong Biology-B did not conduct a clawback.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subscription-group-and-subscription-strategy&#34;&gt;Subscription Group and Subscription Strategy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Offering and International Placement&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Offering:&lt;/strong&gt; Accounted for 10% (673.34 million shares) of the global offering, targeting retail investors, with 37.6 thousand applicants, including 19 thousand who only subscribed for one lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;International Placement:&lt;/strong&gt; Accounted for 90% (6060.01 million shares), primarily allocated to institutional investors. One cornerstone investor was introduced in this round, subscribing for HKD 0.77 billion, representing 9.81% of the global offering, with a lock-up period typically lasting 6 months.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group A and Group B&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group A:&lt;/strong&gt; Small to medium investors with subscription amounts ≤ HKD 50 million, allocated 50% of the public offering shares (336.67 million shares).  This group had 19 thousand applicants, including 19 thousand who only subscribed for one lot.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group B:&lt;/strong&gt; High-net-worth investors or institutions with subscription amounts &amp;gt; HKD 50 million, allocated the remaining 50% of the public offering shares (336.67 million shares). This group had 19,516 applicants, with a maximum subscription amount (top hammer) of 2416 shares.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Top Hammer Subscription&lt;/strong&gt;
Refers to Group B investors subscribing for the highest limit of public offering shares, typically allowing them to acquire 50% of the public offering shares. Bamboo Bio-B’s top hammer quantity was 2416 shares, but due to the extremely hot public offering (over-subscribed 4908 times), top hammer investors still needed a draw, with a very low hit rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;subscription-data-and-winning-rules&#34;&gt;Subscription Data and Winning Rules
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subscription Multiple&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Subscription Multiple:&lt;/strong&gt; Total subscription funds offered publicly divided by the offering amount, reflecting retail investor demand heat. Bamboo Bio-B reached 4908.33 times, setting a market record.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Institutional Allocation Multiple:&lt;/strong&gt; Institutional subscription amounts divided by the offering amount. Bamboo Bio-B was 10.15 times, indicating moderate institutional demand.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Hand Winning Rate and All-Round Lottery Draw&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Hand Winning Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The probability of successfully subscribing with one hand (typically the minimum trading unit). Bamboo Bio-B was only 1%, meaning that out of every 100 people, only 1 person would be successful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All-Round Lottery Draw:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to the extremely high oversubscription multiple for the public offering, all subscribers (including Group B and last-hit hammer investors) were required to participate in a lottery draw to allocate shares, without a &amp;ldquo;steady win&amp;rdquo; mechanism.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fractional Share Allocation&lt;/strong&gt;
Publicly offered shares are allocated proportionally after being divided into fractional shares (such as 50 shares), and any remaining fractional shares will be consolidated and distributed from highest to lowest based on subscription amount. In Bamboo Bio-B, the number of successful investors was 13,467 people, and some investors may obtain additional shares through fractional share allocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;special-mechanisms-and-market-impact&#34;&gt;Special Mechanisms and Market Impact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Anchor Investors&lt;/strong&gt;
Strategic investors who sign subscription agreements with the issuer before an IPO, typically well-known institutions or corporations. Xuzhou Biotech-B introduced one anchor investor who subscribed to HK$0.77 billion, representing 9.81% of the global offering, aiming to enhance market confidence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Green Shoe Mechanism (Over-Allotment Option)&lt;/strong&gt;
Underwriters can issue an additional 15% of shares after listing within 30 days to stabilize prices. If the price falls below the IPO price, underwriters must buy back stocks from the secondary market to support the price. Xuzhou Biotech-B did not use a green shoe mechanism, which could lead to significant volatility in its initial stock price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dark Pool Trading&lt;/strong&gt;
Over-the-counter trading of new shares on the day before listing, typically provided by brokers. Dark pool prices reflect the market&amp;rsquo;s preliminary expectations for the new shares. If they are higher than the IPO price (as with Xuzhou Biotech-B’s dark pool price potentially rising), it indicates a good performance on its first trading day; otherwise, it could lead to a break-down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-term-comparison-and-market-background&#34;&gt;Key Term Comparison and Market Background
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mechanism A vs. Mechanism B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Mechanism A allows for a buyback, enabling retail investors to obtain more shares during oversubscription; Mechanism B has a fixed public offering ratio, better suited for IPOs dominated by institutions. Bamboo Bio-B chose Mechanism B, likely because the underwriters wanted to balance the allocation between institutional and retail investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Group A vs. Group B&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Group A had a lower chance of winning but potentially higher returns per share (due to more dispersed allocation), while Group B had a higher chance of winning but incurred higher financing costs. Bamboo Bio-B Group B received 19,516 applications, reflecting high-net-worth investors&amp;rsquo; enthusiasm for pharmaceutical stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cancellation of the Buyback Mechanism’s Impact&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Under Mechanism B, there is no buyback, leading to Bamboo Bio-B’s public offering of only 6.73 million shares, exacerbating the “many crows, few pots” situation for retail investors, resulting in a historical low in the initial subscription rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The IPO case of Xuan Zhu Bio-B vividly illustrates the structural characteristics of the Hong Kong stock market: the application of Mechanism B limited retail investor allocation ratios, base investors stabilized institutional demand, while super-high subscription multiples and a full draw highlighted the market’s speculative fervor for biotech stocks. The absence of dark pool trading and a green shoe mechanism further amplified the uncertainty during the initial listing period. Investors should combine their risk preferences with rational assessments of new stock fundamentals and market sentiment, avoiding blind following.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Black Swan Goose Returns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:10:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, investors focused on financial news. Since Trump’s return, they also needed to pay attention to his Twitter (a private version). The trade war continued to escalate, leading to a sharp decline on April 7th, which was quickly followed by a rebound. This time, though, are people still willing to jump in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-review&#34;&gt;Background Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 7, 2025, following the impact of the U.S. implementation of an “equivalency tariff” policy, global stock markets experienced a “Black Monday.” The A-share market plunged, with the Shanghai Composite Index falling by 7.34% and the Shenzhen Component Index plummeting by 12.5%, with over 4,300 stocks declining by more than 9%. The Hang Seng Index in Hong Kong also fell by 13.22%, along with European and U.S. stock indices exceeding declines of 4%. China subsequently stabilized the market through state-owned enterprise (SOE) purchases and intervention by Huishang Securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 10th, U.S. stocks suffered another significant decline, with Chinese HShares falling by 6%, driven primarily by expectations of escalation in the U.S.-China trade war. Trump signaled a further increase in tariffs on China, and the U.S. would also impose hefty fees on Chinese ships. China announced retaliatory measures and levied special port fees, compounded by a government shutdown, declining consumer confidence, and market panic selling for safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115351840469973590&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Original Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/black-swan-goose-returns/20251011142053.png&#34;
	width=&#34;586&#34;
	height=&#34;766&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;realDonaldTrump&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;76&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;183px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control&#34;&gt;Position Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the state of short selling in A-shares isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete short position; there’s a small portion invested in index funds within Fixed Income Plus, but the bulk is still in the Hong Kong market. Xiaomi has already incurred principal losses, and Meituan remains a shareholder. The position control is somewhat unbalanced. Should we jump in and gamble on Monday? It&amp;rsquo;s a question to consider – currently, we don’t have enough cash flow. If we need to enter, we would rely on old friends like Alipay’s Jiebei for bridging funds. &lt;strong&gt;Greedy snakes swallow elephants&lt;/strong&gt; – the position control is extremely unreasonable, and we should look for opportunities to reduce our holdings later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to April 7th, the current position isn&amp;rsquo;t considered a low-level one; many stocks are at relatively high levels, particularly the technology stocks within the Heng Seng Tech index. If we were to add to positions, it would be more appropriate to use an ETF rather than individual stocks – for example: &lt;strong&gt;Turned around and couldn’t find anything suitable; gains were 20%-30%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the domestic market, long-term trends point towards a period of consolidation and decline, with potential for significant rallies in the short term. To make profits, it&amp;rsquo;s best to execute profit-taking operations within this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;associated-term-definitions&#34;&gt;Associated Term Definitions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-swan&#34;&gt;Black Swan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Black Swan&amp;rdquo; originates from Nassim Nicholas Taleb’s book &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to events that are &lt;strong&gt;extremely unlikely&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt;, but upon occurring, they generate &lt;strong&gt;extreme impact and disruptive consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rarity/Unpredictability:&lt;/strong&gt; These events have no precedent or warning signs before they occur, exceeding all conventional expectations and model predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extreme Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once they happen, they can cause catastrophic effects on markets, economies, and even societies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-hoc Rationalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite being impossible to predict beforehand, people tend to find reasons and explanations after the event occurs, making it appear “understandable.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Legend:&lt;/strong&gt; Before the discovery of Australia, Europeans believed all swans were white until black swans were discovered in Australia, completely overturning thousands of years of knowledge. Therefore, the Black Swan symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;unforeseen and cognitive breakthroughs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;9/11&amp;rdquo; terrorist attack in 2001 (a short-term shock to global markets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The initial impact of &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt; on the global economy and markets (although some argued it had grey rhino characteristics, its sudden outbreak and global spread, as well as the extent of its impact, were largely considered Black Swans).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gray-rhino&#34;&gt;Gray Rhino
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “Gray Rhino” was coined by Michele Wucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to a potential crisis that is &lt;strong&gt;highly probable&lt;/strong&gt;, has a &lt;strong&gt;significant impact&lt;/strong&gt;, and yet is &lt;strong&gt;ignored&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;selectively delayed in addressing&lt;/strong&gt; due to its &lt;strong&gt;obvious warning signs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Probability/Predictability:&lt;/strong&gt; The event has clear indicators and evidence before it occurs, making it a &lt;strong&gt;known&lt;/strong&gt; risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily Ignored:&lt;/strong&gt; Because it’s not sudden but rather long-term or slowly developing, people become numb, exhibit optimism bias, or procrastinate, failing to take timely action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once it erupts, due to the lack of effective responses beforehand, it triggers a chain reaction and causes severe destructive consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Allusion:&lt;/strong&gt; A gray rhino is large in size and has a slow reaction time; people can see it from afar, but often fail to avoid it because of negligence or indifference. Once it charges towards you, it will cause a fatal collision. Therefore, the gray rhino symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;obvious yet ignored&lt;/strong&gt; major threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2008 &lt;strong&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/strong&gt; (many experts had already warned about the high risk of the US subprime mortgage market, but were largely ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sovereign Debt Crises&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;severe asset bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;systemic risks from climate change&lt;/strong&gt; (these are long-accumulated, traceable major risks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Meituan’s Losses to Bond Mismatch</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the turbulent and unpredictable stock market, we often use faith and expectations as our compass, attempting to navigate through the fog and reach the shores of wealth. However, when our voyage deviates from the guidance of the compass, it’s easy to lose direction, even to run aground. This essay is about one such journey, beginning with an unwavering obsession with &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose and fell repeatedly amidst the waves of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clash-of-faith-and-reality-xiaomis-gains-and-losses&#34;&gt;The Clash of Faith and Reality: Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Gains and Losses
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, I bought into Xiaomi with unwavering &lt;strong&gt;faith&lt;/strong&gt; in Lei Jun and a hopeful vision for the company’s electric vehicles. At the time, faith was a powerful force, temporarily blinding me to Lei Jun’s shrewdness as a capitalist and overlooking the risks posed by the High-Level Flash Lightning Distribution Platform. Fortunately, several &lt;strong&gt;wave trading&lt;/strong&gt; operations ended with modest profits, giving me a sweet taste of entering the Hong Kong stock market for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this self-confidence soon followed. After making a small profit on &lt;strong&gt;Jiu Fang&lt;/strong&gt; stocks, I became somewhat &lt;strong&gt;dazed&lt;/strong&gt;, relying solely on the flow of net buying funds from the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect&lt;/strong&gt; indicator instead of rational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituans-waterloo-and-blind-re-positioning&#34;&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waterloo&amp;rdquo; and Blind Re-positioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by the flow of funds, I turned my attention to &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;. However, this time, I didn’t delve into the company’s &lt;strong&gt;financial data&lt;/strong&gt;, its &lt;strong&gt;historical trends&lt;/strong&gt;, or even realize the raging &lt;strong&gt;food delivery war&lt;/strong&gt; that was unfolding. When the stock price began to fall, I failed to cut my losses in time and instead blindly &lt;strong&gt;added to my position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares trading at HK$20,000-30,000, limitations on capital prevented me from managing my positions freely, which undoubtedly exacerbated my losses in Meituan. This lesson deeply made me realize that in the Hong Kong stock market, blind re-positioning is like trying to fill a constantly leaking bathtub with more water – it only accelerates the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-people-are-lucky---an-unexpected-gain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stupid People Are Lucky&amp;rdquo; - An Unexpected Gain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was worrying about Meituan&amp;rsquo;s losses, an unexpected turn of events occurred – I bought &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;. Although I didn’t hold onto it, I quickly sold it and used the profit to offset some of Meituan’s losses. This might be what’s meant by “stupid people are lucky,” allowing me to temporarily escape Meituan&amp;rsquo;s predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finance-more-important-fundamentals-than-investing&#34;&gt;Finance: More Important Fundamentals Than Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience also made me re-examine my &lt;strong&gt;financial management&lt;/strong&gt; approach, aside from the ups and downs of the stock market. At the time, I invested a sum intended for short-term emergency funds into &lt;strong&gt;Chinese bonds&lt;/strong&gt;. This money was meant to be used for payment within two months, but the short-term holding yield on the bonds wasn&amp;rsquo;t high, and it also posed liquidity issues. If I had instead chosen to deposit this money into a &lt;strong&gt;money fund&lt;/strong&gt;, I could have earned more stable returns and readily redeemed it, better meeting my funding needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Stock Exchange Brokerage Fee Liberalization and Market Competition</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-brokerage-fee-liberalization-and-market-competition/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:47:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-brokerage-fee-liberalization-and-market-competition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of “the same contract code, for transactions in the same direction, commission is only charged once” is commonly referred to as &lt;strong&gt;“Commission Aggregation / Combined Commission”&lt;/strong&gt; within the securities industry. This is not a hard-and-fast regulation by the Hong Kong Exchange or regulatory bodies, but rather a business convention formed through market competition and brokers’ efforts to optimize customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding HK stocks, when the same contract code is used for transactions in the same direction, only one commission is charged – does this have any historical business background?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-historical-turning-points-cancellation-of-the-minimum-commission-rule-in-2003&#34;&gt;Key Historical Turning Points: Cancellation of the Minimum Commission Rule in 2003
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most important background to understand this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Reform (Before April 1, 2003):&lt;/strong&gt; The Hong Kong stock market operated under a &lt;strong&gt;Minimum Commission Rule&lt;/strong&gt;. At the time, brokers were required to charge clients a commission of no less than 0.25% of the transaction value. During this period, all brokerage commissions were essentially locked at the same level, and competition primarily focused on research capabilities, client relationships, and service quality; price wars were virtually non-existent. Therefore, there was no incentive to consolidate commissions for clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-Reform (After April 1, 2003):&lt;/strong&gt; The Hong Kong Exchange officially &lt;strong&gt;abolished the Minimum Commission Rule&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing brokers and clients to freely negotiate commission rates. This reform instantly ignited competition in the Hong Kong securities industry, particularly commission price wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-product-of-fierce-market-competition&#34;&gt;A Product of Fierce Market Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the removal of minimum commission fees, securities firms (particularly emerging internet brokers) have adopted various innovative pricing strategies to attract customers. “Consolidated Commission” is one such highly attractive initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attracting Active Traders:&lt;/strong&gt; For high-frequency traders or investors who prefer to buy and sell the same stock in batches (such as to avoid large single orders impacting market prices), per-trade fees can significantly increase transaction costs. The “Consolidated Commission” policy perfectly addresses this pain point, allowing investors to flexibly establish or liquidate positions within a day without worrying about multiple commission charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reducing Customer Transaction Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most direct objective. By consolidating calculations, customer actual commission expenses are reduced, making the broker’s platform more competitive in terms of cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Customer Experience and Loyalty:&lt;/strong&gt; This customer-friendly policy greatly enhances the user experience, making customers feel that the broker is looking out for their interests, thereby strengthening customer loyalty and retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-logic-and-brokerage-interests&#34;&gt;Business Logic and Brokerage Interests
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although superficially, brokerage revenue appears to be declining, from a holistic business logic perspective, it’s a win-win situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Margin, High Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; Reducing the effective cost of each transaction can stimulate customers to trade more frequently, thereby increasing overall trading volume. While brokers “give away” commissions on individual trades, they can compensate by increasing total transaction volume and earning other fees, such as platform usage fees and financing/margin interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Share Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; In a fiercely competitive market, particularly for new internet brokerages, low commission rates and promotional policies are the most effective means of quickly acquiring users and capturing market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points-to-note&#34;&gt;Key Points to Note
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not All Brokers Offer It:&lt;/strong&gt; While “merged commission” has become mainstream, it’s still a broker&amp;rsquo;s business decision and not a mandatory regulation. Some traditional brokers or banks may still charge per trade for their securities services, so investors need to carefully review the broker’s fee schedule when choosing a broker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only Applies to “Commission”:&lt;/strong&gt; Be sure to note that the calculated merged amount only includes the “commission” charged by the broker. Any “fixed fees” collected by the government or exchanges are calculated per trade and cannot be merged. These include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stamp Duty (印花税):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.1% (Paid by both buyer and seller, rounded up to the nearest dollar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFC Transaction Levy (交易征费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0027% (Collected by the Securities and Futures Commission)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HKEX Trading Fee (交易费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.00565% (Collected by the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRC Transaction Levy (会财局交易征费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.00015% (Collected by the Financial Regulatory Authority)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary, the “merged commission” policy of Hong Kong brokers is rooted in the abolition of the Minimum Commission System in 2003. It was a significant business strategy adopted by brokers in an environment of market liberalization and intense competition – to reduce customer costs, enhance service experience, attract and retain customers – representing a microcosm of Hong Kong’s financial market transitioning from traditional to modern, from high barriers to accessibility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>HKSG Flash Crash Sell-Off Case</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:12:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[The company recently raised capital in the Hong Kong market](Nine Fang Zhi Tu.pdf), this fundraising is similar to Xiaomi’s operation, and this article breaks down the details. &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nine-fang-intelligent-investment-and-sales-interpretation&#34;&gt;Nine Fang Intelligent Investment and Sales Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the fees associated with participating in the offering; when can these stocks be sold, what other important information is contained in this document?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This placement activity is a &lt;strong&gt;pre-existing shareholder first, then new&lt;/strong&gt; placement method, targeting new investors (placements), &lt;strong&gt;does not involve retail investor subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are not a placement agent-selected placement recipient (i.e., professional/institutional/individual investors), you do not need to pay any fees.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement-1&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, if you are a placement agent, the fees involved include:
| Placement Price | ✅ Yes | HKD 39.25 per share |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-reselling&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Reselling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Reseller&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resell price &lt;strong&gt;excludes&lt;/strong&gt; commission, transaction fees, stamp duty etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Brokerage Agent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Transaction Fee / Exchange Trading Fee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charged according to Hong Kong Stock Exchange rules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangements&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangements
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Broker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp Duty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp duty of 0.13% is payable for Hong Kong stock purchases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-costs-associated-with-distribution&#34;&gt;✅ Costs Associated with Distribution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-shares-can-be-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Shares Can Be Sold
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the announcement content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The share placement will be undertaken by the placing agents based on their best efforts to place shares with no less than six noteholders… &lt;strong&gt;It is anticipated that none of the noteholders will become a major shareholder of the Company immediately following completion of the share placement.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-can-shares-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Can Shares Sold?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shares sold through the placement can be freely traded once settlement is complete;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no lock-up period;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can be bought and sold freely on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange secondary market;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The placement deadline is &lt;strong&gt;July 17, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, with expected settlement to occur shortly after &lt;strong&gt;July 17th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-important-information-in-announcement&#34;&gt;✅ Important Information in Announcement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-of-funds-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Funds (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine Square Capital will use this money to do four things:
| On-Chain Financial Resource Investment | Undefined | Invest in RWA underlying assets, digital asset exchanges, trust banks, and stablecoin operators |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Services Layout | Undefined | Investment services for digital assets targeting consumers in Hong Kong and the Middle East regions |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Investment Advisory New Model | Unspecified | AI + Research, Combining MCN Operational Experience |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funding-allocation-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supplemental Liquidity Funding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unspecified&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;General corporate use&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;offer-price-discount-is-significant&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer Price Discount is Significant&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;6.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the closing price of 41.75 HKD on July 15th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;17.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 5-day average price of 47.30 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;15.3%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 10-day average price of 46.36 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Share Structure Changes**

- Following the public offering, **total shares outstanding increased from 448 million to 468 million**.
- Existing shareholders’ ownership percentages were **slightly diluted**, but they **continue to maintain a controlling stake**.
- An additional 20,000,000 shares will be held by the underwriters, representing approximately **4.27%** of total outstanding shares.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-disclaimer&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The offering may not be completed, and requires fulfillment of multiple prerequisites (such as market stability, regulatory approval, and the absence of significant adverse events)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is not completed within 14 days, the subscription matter will automatically become invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail investors are excluded from this placement; the placed shares have no lock-up period and can be traded immediately after settlement. Jiu Fang Investment plans to use HK$746 million to invest in digital assets and on-chain finance, potentially transitioning towards Web3 and AI robo-advisor directions in the future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-old-then-new-distribution-method-explained&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Old, Then New&amp;rdquo; Distribution Method Explained
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Existing shareholders first old shares then new&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; is a &lt;strong&gt;common Hong Kong distribution method&lt;/strong&gt;, known in English as &lt;strong&gt;Top-up Placement&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can understand as a two-step operation of “&lt;strong&gt;major shareholders sell old shares first and then subscribe to new shares&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-to-understand-it&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example to understand it
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking the case of &lt;strong&gt;Jiutian Intelligence Investment&lt;/strong&gt; as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Major shareholders sell old shares (First Old)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing shareholders (such as Coreworth Investments) sell their existing holdings of &lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 old shares&lt;/strong&gt; to market investors (the underwriter) at a price of HKD 39.25 per share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder reducing their holding&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;total issued capital remains unchanged&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Company issues new shares to major shareholders (Later New)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company then issues an equal number (&lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 shares&lt;/strong&gt;) of new shares to these major shareholders at a price of HKD 39.25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major shareholder uses the proceeds from selling old shares to buy back new shares, &lt;strong&gt;restoring their holding quantity to its original state&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, the total issued capital increases (from 448 million shares to 468 million shares), &lt;strong&gt;effectively meaning the company has successfully raised capital&lt;/strong&gt;, while the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder&amp;rsquo;s shareholding ratio is slightly diluted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avoid the lengthy process of issuing new shares, instead selling old shares first and then supplementing with new shares to quickly raise capital.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-1&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The majority shareholders will maintain their voting power, and control won&amp;rsquo;t be significantly diluted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-2&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attract New Investors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Through discounted share sales (private placements), attract institutional or high-net-worth investors to enter the market, optimizing the shareholder structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-3&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Not newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Can be immediately traded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;These are existing shares on the market, which can be directly circulated after being sold to new investors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-1&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Shares&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;⚠️ Lock-up Period (typically 180 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shares newly issued by the company, given to original shareholders, and typically require a lock-up period.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-2&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-one-sentence-summary&#34;&gt;✅ One-Sentence Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sell Old, Buy New&amp;rdquo; refers to major shareholders initially selling their existing shares to the market and then purchasing an equal amount of new shares from the company, simultaneously raising capital for the company while maintaining control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-connect-issuance-rules-interpretation&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Connect Issuance Rules Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: Your question is very central: &lt;strong&gt;Why do Hong Kong-listed companies seem to be able to “freely” issue shares? Is the Hong Kong market rulebook particularly relaxed?&lt;/strong&gt;
The answer is: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, HKEX offers significantly more flexibility than the Shanghai A-share market&lt;/strong&gt;, but it’s &lt;strong&gt;not “unlimited,”&lt;/strong&gt; rather there&amp;rsquo;s a system of &lt;strong&gt;“relaxed but limited” rules.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require shareholder meeting approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ The Board of Directors can authorize share issuance not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;20% of the total equity&lt;/strong&gt; annually at the annual general meeting, and no further meetings are required thereafter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Each issuance must be held with a &lt;strong&gt;separate shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt; and pass by a 2/3 majority vote.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require SEC approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ As long as it’s no more than 20% of share capital + offering price is no more than 20%, it can “flash allocation”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Must undergo SEC &lt;strong&gt;case-by-case review&lt;/strong&gt;, which takes longer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Issuance Ratio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Maximum of 20% per issuance, cumulative dilution within 12 months shall not exceed 25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Generally not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-2&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discount Margin Limit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Offering price shall not be lower than 80% of the market price (maximum discount of 20%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Non-public placements shall not be lower than 80% of the market price&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock-up Period&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Typically &lt;strong&gt;30 days or none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;6~36 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-3&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Proceeds Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Disclosure of use only, no substantive review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Must detail use of proceeds, SEC can veto&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-hong-kong-stocks-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ Hong Kong Stocks vs. A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-does-the-hong-kong-stock-exchange-look-casual&#34;&gt;✅ Why Does the Hong Kong Stock Exchange Look “Casual”?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“General Mandate” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
Once a year, shareholders authorize the board to issue up to 20% new shares at their annual general meeting. Afterwards, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meetings are required&lt;/strong&gt;, and the board can selectively issue shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Flash Placement” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
If the issuance does not exceed 20% of the share capital and the discount is no more than 20%, &lt;strong&gt;the issuance can be completed within 24 hours without approval&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No SEC Case-by-Case Approval:
The Hong Kong Stock Exchange only conducts &lt;strong&gt;formative review&lt;/strong&gt;, without substantive intervention in the use of funds or company quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-why-was-jiufang-zhitou-able-to-do-old-and-new-this-time&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: Why was JiuFang ZhiTou able to &amp;ldquo;do old and new&amp;rdquo; this time?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JiuFang ZhiTou obtained a &lt;strong&gt;general authorization&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;2025 June 20th shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for up to a 20% increase in new shares (i.e., up to 89,671,400 shares).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This issuance of 20,000,000 shares represents only &lt;strong&gt;4.46% of the capital&lt;/strong&gt;, far below the 20% limit, and &lt;strong&gt;fully complies with the authorization conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meeting is needed&lt;/strong&gt; nor &lt;strong&gt;is approval from the Securities Regulatory Commission required&lt;/strong&gt;; the board of directors can make the decision to implement it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-1&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong stocks allow “board of directors + annual authorization” rapid issuance under a streamlined process, provided it doesn’t exceed 20% of the share capital and the price cap, enabling “flash placement,” while A-shares require shareholder approval plus SEC review, resulting in a longer, more restrictive procedure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-2&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Jiu Fang Zhi Tu (Nine Fang Intelligent Investment) is not “arbitrary issuance,” but rather &lt;strong&gt;legally and compliantly utilized the relaxed mechanisms of the Hong Kong stock market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
