<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Windows on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/windows/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Windows on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>PowerShell 7 and Persistent Settings Command-Line Prediction View</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 22:19:12 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m used to zsh on Linux, and when writing a blog post the other day, I suddenly discovered that PowerShell 7 also supports persistent settings for command-line prediction views. So I tried it out, and found it quite useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know what operation was performed, but this feature is enabled – it just appeared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s diverse operating system environment, system administrators and developers have been seeking a tool that is cross-platform, efficient, and powerful to meet their needs in system management and automation tasks. PowerShell 7 is precisely such a highly anticipated tool; it not only provides robust scripting capabilities but also enables operation across Windows, Linux, and macOS operating systems, bringing users unprecedented convenience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;powershell-7-a-powerful-cross-platform-tool&#34;&gt;PowerShell 7: A Powerful Cross-Platform Tool
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-features&#34;&gt;Cross-platform features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 breaks platform limitations, allowing users to utilize a single PowerShell 7 tool whether managing enterprise-level servers on Windows systems, performing system maintenance in Linux environments, or tackling everyday development tasks on macOS. This significantly improves work efficiency and reduces the learning curve and operational complexity caused by platform differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;powerful-features&#34;&gt;Powerful features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It possesses powerful scripting capabilities, supporting object-oriented programming, functions, modules, and other advanced programming features. Through PowerShell 7, users can easily operate the file system, creating, deleting, copying, and moving files and folders; access and modify the registry to make in-depth adjustments to the system configuration; and manage processes and services to effectively monitor and control the system&amp;rsquo;s running state. In addition, PowerShell 7 can also interact with various Windows and non-Windows technologies, such as user and permission management in Active Directory, resource allocation and management on the Azure cloud platform, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Open-source ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 is open-source, a feature that allows developers and enthusiasts worldwide to actively participate in its development and improvement. A large number of open-source modules and tools are constantly emerging, enriching the functionality and application scenarios of PowerShell 7. Users can find suitable modules within the open-source community to extend PowerShell 7&amp;rsquo;s capabilities based on their needs, or contribute their own code to promote the development of the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compatibility-and-stability&#34;&gt;Compatibility and Stability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 introduces many new features and improvements while maintaining compatibility with older versions of PowerShell. These enhancements not only improve performance but also enhance stability, allowing users to complete various tasks more smoothly and reducing work interruptions caused by software failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-command-line-prediction-view&#34;&gt;Open command-line prediction view
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among the many useful features of PowerShell 7, the &lt;code&gt;Set-PSReadLineOption -PredictionViewStyle ListView&lt;/code&gt; command is a practical tool that can enhance the user&amp;rsquo;s command-line input experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without enabling commands, inline auto-completion is still possible. However, this only provides completion within the current line. When enabled, it offers predictive suggestions displayed as a list of all potential options. Users can select the desired option using up and down arrow keys, thereby improving the accuracy and efficiency of command input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/20250207222546.png&#34;
	width=&#34;814&#34;
	height=&#34;205&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;powershell7&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;397&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;952px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-commands-persistent&#34;&gt;How to make commands persistent
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To ensure that the &lt;code&gt;Set-PSReadLineOption -PredictionViewStyle ListView&lt;/code&gt; command takes effect every time PowerShell starts, we can add it to PowerShell&amp;rsquo;s profile. A PowerShell profile is a special script that automatically executes its commands when PowerShell starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confirm-configuration-file-path&#34;&gt;Confirm configuration file path
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In PowerShell, we can use the &lt;code&gt;$PROFILE&lt;/code&gt; variable to view the configuration file path. If the file does not exist at that path, users can manually create one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;echo $PROFILE
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-the-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Open the configuration file
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the file corresponding to the configuration file path obtained through the &lt;code&gt;$PROFILE&lt;/code&gt; variable using a text editor, such as the powerful Notepad++ or the lightweight Visual Studio Code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-command&#34;&gt;Add command
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the open configuration file, add the command &lt;code&gt;Set-PSReadLineOption -PredictionViewStyle ListView&lt;/code&gt;. Ensure the command is written accurately to guarantee that the configuration takes effect correctly when executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;save-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Save configuration file
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After completing the command addition, save the configuration file and close the text editor. At this point, the configuration file already contains the commands we want to execute each time PowerShell starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verification-settings&#34;&gt;Verification Settings
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Close the current PowerShell window and restart PowerShell. In the newly started PowerShell, when entering commands, the command-line input prediction view style should be displayed in list view, indicating that our settings have taken effect successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through the above steps, we not only gained a deeper understanding of the powerful features and capabilities of PowerShell 7, but also learned how to enhance the user experience by setting command-line input prediction views, and how to make these settings persistent. We hope this knowledge will help you become more proficient in using PowerShell 7 and efficiently complete various system management and automation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShell/PowerShell/releases&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/PowerShell/PowerShell/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.v2ex.com/t/911909&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.v2ex.com/t/911909&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Desktop upgrade to 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network interconnection</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We previously mentioned the PCIe adapter for solid-state drives, so where did the old SSDs go? They weren&amp;rsquo;t wasted; they were removed and installed in the &lt;code&gt;Mechanical Master Creator Mini-3765H&lt;/code&gt; (purchased a year ago)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new machine still has impressive hardware specs: 2.5G dual network ports, PCIE4.0, and WiFi6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently moved, and the room doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a separate router for networking. The machines are all connected via wireless network. The ASUS motherboard desktop’s wireless card performance isn’t good enough, or it could be due to the router&amp;rsquo;s wireless access; the upload speed between local area networks is poor, which results in slow speeds between the machines. I purchased a 2.5G network card and installed it on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, all of the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s slots are used up: graphics card, wireless network card, 2.5G network card, and a solid-state drive PCIe adapter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two machines still use the original wireless network card for internet access, but they are directly connected with a network cable, and both ends have 2.5G network cards. How to connect the two machines with a network cable doesn&amp;rsquo;t need much explanation; there are many tutorials online. Remember to disable the firewall. You can choose either machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD;
    A[机器1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: - &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS] --&amp;gt;|网线直连（2.5G）| B[机器2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS];
    A --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
    B --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speed-test-of-two-network-segments&#34;&gt;Speed test of two network segments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-local-area-network&#34;&gt;Router local area network
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.3.237
Connecting to host 192.168.3.237, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.3.122 port 1656 connected to 192.168.3.237 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.00   sec  9.17 MBytes  76.7 Mbits/sec
[  4]   1.00-2.00   sec  9.91 MBytes  83.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec  8.74 MBytes  73.3 Mbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec  10.2 MBytes  85.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec  9.23 MBytes  77.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec  8.80 MBytes  73.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.01   sec  8.00 MBytes  66.8 Mbits/sec
[  4]   7.01-8.00   sec  7.69 MBytes  64.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.01   sec  9.72 MBytes  81.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   9.01-10.01  sec  7.63 MBytes  63.6 Mbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan-connection&#34;&gt;Direct LAN connection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.4.1
Connecting to host 192.168.4.1, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.4.2 port 1524 connected to 192.168.4.1 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.01   sec   178 MBytes  1.48 Gbits/sec
[  4]   1.01-2.00   sec   204 MBytes  1.72 Gbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec   214 MBytes  1.80 Gbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec   229 MBytes  1.92 Gbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec   202 MBytes  1.69 Gbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec   213 MBytes  1.79 Gbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.00   sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
[  4]   7.00-8.00   sec   192 MBytes  1.61 Gbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.00   sec   220 MBytes  1.84 Gbits/sec
[  4]   9.00-10.00  sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding Mermaid Support to Hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Occasional disk recognition issues due to too many disks installed on ASUS Z490 motherboards</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the previous discussion, I encountered a problem where the wireless network card was not being recognized. Before rebuilding the partitions, I also searched online for other solutions, such as removing the motherboard battery and disconnecting power for fifteen minutes; or upgrading to the latest BOIS driver, but all of these had issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking there were still things to deal with, I switched to a limited network and ran the ethernet cable from the living room to the room. At this point, another problem arose – the wired network couldn&amp;rsquo;t be recognized either. I tried a drastic measure of reinstalling the system, which resulted in a missing partition error. If these problems consistently occurred, I wouldn’t have bothered troubleshooting for so long. This ASUS disk conflict is intermittent and triggered by unstable system restarts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The desktop computer had a new disk added last week, a 2TB solid-state drive from Yangtze Memory (YMTC), M.2 interface. It hasn&amp;rsquo;t been restarted since then until yesterday when it was shut down once.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disk Family Portrait&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinstall-system&#34;&gt;Reinstall system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been two years since I last reinstalled the system. The C drive is full, and Windows has its usual problems – various software likes to save things on the C drive. So, I decided to reinstall the system. After reinstalling the system, the network card issues were resolved normally. The next day, I restored my development environment and prepared to back up the system. That&amp;rsquo;s when a new problem arose: after restarting the system, the boot partition was lost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the steps in the previous article, I rebuilt the boot partition, but it&amp;rsquo;s not very stable. After restarting, the boot partition might fail to load at any time. I started suspecting issues with the computer case, when I noticed the hard drive cable was loose, but after checking several times, there’s no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-revival&#34;&gt;Memory revival
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, this machine had an SSD installed once. At that time, I bought a PCIe adapter (plugged into the graphics card slot) instead of installing the drive directly on the motherboard. This time, installing it directly on the motherboard might be due to a problem with the motherboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Solid-state transformer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motherboard-manual&#34;&gt;Motherboard Manual
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motherboard manual has an issue: the location of the SATA ports indicated in the manual doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the actual locations. Because I have too many disks, they are all installed on the interfaces. The older SSDs use SATA interfaces. According to the motherboard manual, there is a conflict between these interfaces. After testing, this conflict is triggered unstably. When it triggers, the corresponding disk cannot be loaded. This happens to be the system disk, and the bootloader is also on that disk, so the system fails to boot.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/20250110002401.png&#34;
	width=&#34;807&#34;
	height=&#34;847&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Z490&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;228px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reinstalled the solid-state drive onto the PCIe adapter, and at that point, there was no conflict with the SATA interface on the motherboard anymore, so the system started up normally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unveiling the Secrets of ESP Partitioning, GPT Partition Tables, and the Windows Operating System&#39;s Collaboration</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exploring-esp-gpt-and-windows-cooperation/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 23:58:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exploring-esp-gpt-and-windows-cooperation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday after work, I got home and turned on my desktop as usual. The system booted up normally, but the wireless network card failed to load. I thought the card might have come loose, so I opened the case and reinstalled it. That&amp;rsquo;s when things went wrong – the system wouldn’t boot at all; the bootloader failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I messed with desktop computers, so partitioning is a bit unfamiliar. I used DisGenius to create a new blank partition (usually partitioned towards the front of the disk) and allocated it as an ESP partition (default 300M). Then, I rebuilt the boot in the PE system. You can find relevant information online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create New ESP Partition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can remove MSR partition&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of computer storage, ESP partitions, GPT partition tables, and Windows operating systems are closely linked, each playing a unique and crucial role, jointly supporting the stable operation and efficient management of the system. However, before delving into them, it is necessary to mention the &amp;ldquo;predecessor&amp;rdquo; in the long history of computer partitioning—the MBR partition table format. It reflects the evolution of technology by contrasting with later technologies. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s deeply analyze their inherent connections and subtleties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-mbr-partition-table--the-foundation-of-traditional-disk-partitioning&#34;&gt;I. MBR Partition Table – The &amp;ldquo;Foundation&amp;rdquo; of Traditional Disk Partitioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;MBR, which stands for Master Boot Record, has existed since the early days of personal computers and has dominated the hard drive partitioning field for decades&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-architecture&#34;&gt;Basic architecture
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is located in the first sector of the hard drive, also known as sector 0, and occupies 512 bytes. These 512 bytes are mainly divided into three parts: firstly, the boot program code, which is responsible for loading the operating system&amp;rsquo;s boot loader when the computer starts up, typically occupying 446 bytes; secondly, the disk partition table, occupying 64 bytes, which can define a maximum of 4 primary partition entries, each entry occupying 16 bytes and recording key parameters such as the starting head, sector, cylinder, and type and size of the partition; finally, the last 2 bytes are the MBR termination flag &amp;ldquo;55 AA&amp;rdquo;, used to identify this sector as a valid MBR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;historical-achievements-and-limitations&#34;&gt;Historical achievements and limitations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, the MBR partition table fully met the relatively simple storage needs of personal computers. It allowed operating systems to smoothly recognize hard drive partitions and implement orderly data storage and retrieval. However, as times evolved, its limitations became increasingly apparent. On one hand, limited by the 64-byte space of the partition table, it could only support a maximum of four primary partitions. To create more partitions, complex methods such as extended partitions and logical partitions were required, which brought inconvenience to disk management; on the other hand, it supported a maximum hard drive capacity of only 2TB, which seemed inadequate in the face of high-capacity drives that are now often several TB or even tens of TB, becoming a bottleneck restricting further development of storage technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-esp-partition--the-systems-invisible-boot-key&#34;&gt;II. ESP Partition – The System&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Invisible Boot Key&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESP, which stands for EFI System Partition, is a special partition required by computers based on the UEFI (Unified Extensible Firmware Interface) standard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The boot process: When the computer is powered on, the UEFI firmware first searches for the ESP partition on the hard drive and reads the boot loader stored there (such as Windows Boot Manager), then starts the operating system. It&amp;rsquo;s like a precise key that opens the door to system startup; without it, the system will be lost and confused at startup, not knowing where to go.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The storage drive also stores some drivers essential for the system startup process, ensuring that hardware devices such as hard disk controllers and graphics cards function properly during the early boot phase, laying the foundation for the subsequent smooth takeover by the operating system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-requirements-and-format&#34;&gt;Space requirements and format
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically, the recommended size for the ESP partition is between 100MB and 500MB, and allocating around 200MB is usually sufficient to meet basic needs. Its file system format must be FAT32 because UEFI firmware can only recognize FAT32 when reading boot files, ensuring compatibility and cross-platform support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-gpt-partition-table--the-smart-manager-of-your-hard-drive&#34;&gt;III. GPT Partition Table – The &amp;ldquo;Smart Manager&amp;rdquo; of Your Hard Drive
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPT (GUID Partition Table), also known as a Global Unique Identifier Partition Table, is a new partitioning scheme designed to replace traditional MBR partition tables&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages-revealed&#34;&gt;Advantages revealed
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Capacity Support:&lt;/strong&gt; In today&amp;rsquo;s era of data explosion, high-capacity hard drives are constantly emerging. The GPT partition table breaks through the 2TB capacity limitation of MBR and theoretically supports up to 9.4ZB (Zettabytes, 1 ZB = 1024 EB, 1 EB = 1024 PB, 1 PB = 1024 TB) of extremely large storage space, making it possible to store massive amounts of data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike MBR, which can only have a maximum of four primary partitions, GPT allows for the creation of up to 128 partitions, providing users and system administrators with great flexibility. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s partitioning multiple system partitions, data partitions, or reserving partitions for special purposes, it handles everything smoothly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High reliability: The GPT partition table utilizes a redundant backup mechanism, storing partition information in both the head and tail of the hard drive. When one partition table is damaged, the system can automatically recover from another backup, significantly reducing the risk of data loss due to partition table failures and safeguarding data security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structural-analysis&#34;&gt;Structural Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GPT partition table consists of several parts, including a protective MBR (retained for compatibility with traditional BIOS as a small portion of the MBR structure but not used for actual partitioning management), a GPT header (which stores basic information about the GPT partition table, such as the partition table version, number of partitions, and partition table size), and an array of partition entries (each partition entry details key information such as the starting sector, ending sector, partition type GUID, and unique partition identifier). These structures work together to precisely plan and manage disk space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-windows-operating-system--a-digital-interaction-realm-for-users&#34;&gt;Four, Windows Operating System – A “Digital Interaction Realm” for Users
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows, as a globally widely used operating system, builds a friendly bridge between people and computer hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;integration-with-esp-partitions-and-gpt-partition-tables&#34;&gt;Integration with ESP partitions and GPT partition tables
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Windows installation process on systems booting based on UEFI, the installer automatically creates an ESP (EFI System Partition) and deploys boot files within it. At the same time, the hard drive is initialized with a GPT (GUID Partition Table), partitioning out a system reserved partition (used to store system critical files, similar to the system boot file area in traditional BIOS), a Windows system partition (where the system core files are installed), and other user-defined data partitions. The Windows system relies on the GPT partition table to accurately identify each partition, smoothly booting through the ESP partition, with seamless integration between the three, providing users with a smooth startup and usage experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reliance-on-system-management-and-optimization&#34;&gt;Reliance on system management and optimization
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows leverages the advantages of the GPT partition table for disk management during operation. For example, in the Disk Management tool, GPT partitions can be easily recognized, allowing users to conveniently create, delete, format partitions, and adjust their sizes, meeting data storage needs at different stages. Furthermore, system updates, software installations, and other processes are closely related to the partition layout; a reasonable partitioning scheme helps improve system performance and stability, reducing problems caused by insufficient disk space or partition confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;v-practical-tips-maintenance-and-troubleshooting&#34;&gt;V. Practical Tips: Maintenance and Troubleshooting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding their close relationship makes troubleshooting and maintenance more systematic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disk-space-management&#34;&gt;Disk space management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regularly check the ESP partition space to avoid issues caused by insufficient space due to installing too many startup items or related software, which can affect system boot. For data partitions under GPT partitioning, plan storage reasonably and promptly clean up unnecessary files to prevent a single partition from becoming full and affecting system operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troubleshooting-startup-issues&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting startup issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the system fails to start, first check if the ESP partition is damaged or files are missing. You can use the startup repair tool built into the UEFI firmware, or enter the recovery environment through a Windows installation medium to rebuild the boot files of the ESP partition. If you suspect a GPT partition table failure, use professional disk tools (such as DiskGenius) to check the integrity of the partition table and attempt to repair and restore backup partition information to recover lost partitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESP partitions, GPT partition tables, and the Windows operating system are like a precise team working together, each playing their part to create a stable and efficient computing environment for us. A deep understanding of them not only helps us feel confident during system installation and maintenance but also allows us to understand the underlying logic of computer operation and freely explore the digital world. At the same time, reflecting on the rise and fall of the MBR partition table further reminds us of the power of technological progress, which drives storage technology forward to adapt to the ever-increasing demand for data storage.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Windows&#39; built-in Disk Cleanup tool: Storage</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-disk-cleanup-storage/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:29:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-disk-cleanup-storage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m not entirely sure from what version it started, but in &lt;code&gt;Windows 11&lt;/code&gt;, the Disk Cleanup tool has been significantly improved and is now much smarter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an official tool, so it won’t delete files by mistake, has no ads, no pop-ups, no background processes, and nothing unnecessary&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Windows 11, you can open Disk Cleanup through Settings - System - Storage - Temporary files&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Storage interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinary users can simply select &amp;ldquo;Clean-up Suggestions,&amp;rdquo; and the system will provide recommendations based on your usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I have many temporary files on my disk, so I chose &amp;ldquo;Temporary Files,&amp;rdquo; which contains various temporary files such as those from &lt;code&gt;Visual Studio&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;Windows Update&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Temporary file&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Quickly statistics folder size on Windows platform</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-quick-folder-size-statistics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 19:54:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-quick-folder-size-statistics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Linux platform is very simple; one line of code with &lt;code&gt;du -sh *&lt;/code&gt; gets the job done. What about Windows? With many disks and a desire to clean them up, especially when there are lots of files, the built-in resource manager&amp;rsquo;s folder size statistics are so slow you want to give up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;everything&#34;&gt;Everything
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Developers on the Windows platform should have either used or heard of Everything. Its search speed is much faster than the system&amp;rsquo;s built-in File Explorer. Since the operating system supports fast file indexing, there must be similar tools that can establish a file index and also calculate the size of the files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wiztree&#34;&gt;WizTree
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.diskanalyzer.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.diskanalyzer.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extract and run in standard installation mode or green version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast speed, a variety of data display types, with a tree diagram mode on the left, file types on the right, and of course, graphical displays at the bottom of the software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacesniffer-no-longer-receiving-updates-as-of-2023&#34;&gt;SpaceSniffer (no longer receiving updates as of 2023)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software website: [http://www.uderzo.it/main_products/space_sniffer/]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operation is very simple, select the corresponding disk drive, and the software will display folder sizes in a graphical way. The larger the size, the larger the corresponding matrix in the image. You&amp;rsquo;ll understand the rest with a few clicks. It supports entering conditions to filter files:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File size filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File date filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advanced Usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moe.best/software/spacesniffer.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://moe.best/software/spacesniffer.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Editing Large Files on Windows Platform: EmEditor (Text Editor)</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-editing-large-files-emeditor-text-editor/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 23:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-editing-large-files-emeditor-text-editor/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Guoan database incident has been buzzing around in the black market circles, and it&amp;rsquo;s unclear whether it’s true or not. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we remember it in two years and take another look. Based on past experience, a wave of local social engineering database information was updated, and I saw a huge SQL file: 17.9G. A regular text editor would have trouble even previewing it, let alone opening it. While chatting with netizens, someone mentioned: EmEditor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website: [https://www.emeditor.com/]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried it out during my free time on the weekend, and it&amp;rsquo;s quite convenient. The design supports editing large files, and with sufficient memory, the entire file is loaded into memory, making searching and editing fast. It also supports splitting files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
