<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Windows on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/windows/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Windows on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>PowerShell 7 and Persistent Settings Command-Line Prediction View</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 22:19:12 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having been accustomed to zsh on Linux, I recently discovered that PowerShell 7 also supports persistent settings for command-line prediction views. I tried it out and found it quite useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not sure what action was taken, but this feature is enabled – it just appeared&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s diverse operating system environment, system administrators and developers are seeking a cross-platform, efficient, and powerful tool to meet their needs for system management and automation. PowerShell 7 is such a highly anticipated tool, offering robust scripting capabilities and enabling operation across Windows, Linux, and macOS, bringing unprecedented convenience to users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;powershell-7-a-powerful-cross-platform-tool&#34;&gt;PowerShell 7: A Powerful Cross-Platform Tool
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;cross-platform-features&#34;&gt;Cross-platform features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 removes platform limitations, allowing users to utilize a single tool for enterprise-level server management on Windows, system administration in Linux environments, or everyday development tasks on macOS. This significantly improves work efficiency and reduces learning costs and operational complexity caused by platform differences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;powerful-features&#34;&gt;Powerful features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It features robust scripting capabilities, supporting object-oriented programming, functions, and modules. With PowerShell 7, users can easily manage the file system (creating, deleting, copying, moving files and folders), access and modify the registry for in-depth system configuration, and manage processes and services for effective monitoring and control. Furthermore, PowerShell 7 integrates with various Windows and non-Windows technologies, such as user and permission management in Active Directory and resource provisioning and management on Azure cloud platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-source-ecosystem&#34;&gt;Open-source ecosystem
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 is open-source, enabling global developers and enthusiasts to actively participate in its development and improvement. A wealth of open-source modules and tools are constantly emerging, enriching PowerShell 7&amp;rsquo;s functionality and applications. Users can find suitable modules within the open-source community to extend PowerShell 7’s capabilities or contribute their own code to advance the entire community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;compatibility-and-stability&#34;&gt;Compatibility and Stability
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;PowerShell 7 introduces numerous new features and improvements while maintaining compatibility with older PowerShell versions. These enhancements boost performance, increase stability, and allow users to complete tasks more smoothly, reducing interruptions due to software issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-command-line-prediction-view&#34;&gt;Open command-line prediction view
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Among PowerShell 7&amp;rsquo;s many useful features, the &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; command is a practical tool that enhances the user’s command-line experience&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Without enabling the command, inline auto-completion is available. Enabling it provides predictive suggestions in a list format, allowing users to select options with arrow keys, improving accuracy and efficiency of command input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.ttf248.life/p/powershell-7-persisting-settings-command-line-prediction-view/20250207222546.png&#34;
	width=&#34;814&#34;
	height=&#34;205&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;powershell7&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;397&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;952px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-make-commands-persistent&#34;&gt;How to make commands persistent
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To ensure a command takes effect each time PowerShell starts, you can add it to the PowerShell profile. The PowerShell profile is a special script that automatically executes its commands when PowerShell launches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;confirm-configuration-file-path&#34;&gt;Confirm configuration file path
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In PowerShell, we can use the &lt;code&gt;$_&lt;/code&gt; variable to view the configuration file path. If the file does not exist at that path, the user can create it manually.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;echo $PROFILE
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;open-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Open configuration file
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the file corresponding to the configuration file path obtained through the &lt;code&gt;__INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/code&gt; variable using a text editor, such as the powerful Notepad++ or the lightweight Visual Studio Code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-command&#34;&gt;Add command
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Add the &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; command to the open configuration file. Ensure the command is written accurately to guarantee it takes effect when the configuration file is executed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;save-configuration-file&#34;&gt;Save configuration file
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;After adding the command, save the configuration file and close the text editor. The configuration file now includes the commands we want to execute each time PowerShell starts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;verification-settings&#34;&gt;Verification Settings
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Close the current PowerShell window and restart it. In the newly launched PowerShell, when entering commands, the command-line input prediction view should display in a list format, indicating that our settings have taken effect successfully.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through these steps, we not only gained a deeper understanding of PowerShell 7&amp;rsquo;s powerful features and capabilities but also learned how to enhance the user experience by setting command-line input prediction views and ensuring these settings persist. We hope this knowledge helps you use PowerShell 7 more confidently and efficiently to complete various system management and automation tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/PowerShell/PowerShell/releases&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/PowerShell/PowerShell/releases&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.v2ex.com/t/911909&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.v2ex.com/t/911909&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Upgraded desktop PC to a 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network connections</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The desktop hardware upgrades continue – we mentioned the PCIe adapter for solid-state drives in a previous article. Where did the old SSDs go? They weren&amp;rsquo;t wasted; they were removed and installed in the new computer I bought (a year ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new machine has impressive hardware specs: 2.5G dual network ports, PCIe 4.0, and WiFi 6&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently moved, and the room lacks a dedicated router for networking. Devices connect via wireless network. The ASUS motherboard desktop&amp;rsquo;s wireless card performance is lacking, possibly due to router wireless access or slow upload speeds between local networks, resulting in poor speed between machines. A new 2.5G NIC was purchased and installed in the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network Instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The machines still use the original wireless network cards for internet access, but are directly connected with a network cable. Both ends have 2.5G network cards. How to connect them via Ethernet is widely documented online; remember to disable firewalls and designate one machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-mermaid&#34;&gt;graph TD;
    A[机器1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: - &amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS] --&amp;gt;|网线直连（2.5G）| B[机器2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;IP: 192.168.4.2&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;子网掩码: 255.255.255.0&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;默认网关: 192.168.4.1&amp;lt;br&amp;gt;自动获取DNS];
    A --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
    B --&amp;gt;|无线网卡| Internet;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;speed-test-between-two-networks&#34;&gt;Speed test between two networks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-local-area-network&#34;&gt;Router local area network
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.3.237
Connecting to host 192.168.3.237, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.3.122 port 1656 connected to 192.168.3.237 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.00   sec  9.17 MBytes  76.7 Mbits/sec
[  4]   1.00-2.00   sec  9.91 MBytes  83.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec  8.74 MBytes  73.3 Mbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec  10.2 MBytes  85.2 Mbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec  9.23 MBytes  77.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec  8.80 MBytes  73.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.01   sec  8.00 MBytes  66.8 Mbits/sec
[  4]   7.01-8.00   sec  7.69 MBytes  64.9 Mbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.01   sec  9.72 MBytes  81.1 Mbits/sec
[  4]   9.01-10.01  sec  7.63 MBytes  63.6 Mbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.01  sec  89.0 MBytes  74.6 Mbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan-connection&#34;&gt;Direct LAN connection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;C:\Users\core\Desktop\iperf-3.1.3-win32&amp;gt;iperf3.exe -c 192.168.4.1
Connecting to host 192.168.4.1, port 5201
[  4] local 192.168.4.2 port 1524 connected to 192.168.4.1 port 5201
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-1.01   sec   178 MBytes  1.48 Gbits/sec
[  4]   1.01-2.00   sec   204 MBytes  1.72 Gbits/sec
[  4]   2.00-3.00   sec   214 MBytes  1.80 Gbits/sec
[  4]   3.00-4.00   sec   229 MBytes  1.92 Gbits/sec
[  4]   4.00-5.00   sec   202 MBytes  1.69 Gbits/sec
[  4]   5.00-6.00   sec   213 MBytes  1.79 Gbits/sec
[  4]   6.00-7.00   sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
[  4]   7.00-8.00   sec   192 MBytes  1.61 Gbits/sec
[  4]   8.00-9.00   sec   220 MBytes  1.84 Gbits/sec
[  4]   9.00-10.00  sec   230 MBytes  1.93 Gbits/sec
- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -
[ ID] Interval           Transfer     Bandwidth
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  sender
[  4]   0.00-10.00  sec  2.06 GBytes  1.77 Gbits/sec                  receiver

iperf Done.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Occasional disk recognition issues due to too many disks installed on ASUS Z490 motherboards</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Following on from the previous discussion, I encountered an issue where the wireless network card was not being recognized. Before rebuilding the partitions, I also researched other solutions online, such as removing the motherboard battery and disconnecting power for fifteen minutes; or upgrading to the latest BIOS driver—but all of these proved problematic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking there were still things to deal with, I switched to a limited network and ran the ethernet cable from the living room to the room. Then the problem reappeared – the wired network wasn&amp;rsquo;t recognized either. I tried a drastic measure: reinstalling the system, which resulted in a missing partition error. If this had been happening consistently, I wouldn’t have bothered troubleshooting for so long. This ASUS disk conflict seems intermittent and triggered by unstable system restarts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last week, a new disk was added to the desktop – a 2TB solid-state drive from Yangtze Memory (YMTC), M.2 interface. The machine hasn&amp;rsquo;t been restarted since then until it was shut down yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reinstall-system&#34;&gt;Reinstall system
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been two years since I last reinstalled the system. The C drive is full, and Windows has its usual issues – various software likes to store things on the C drive. So, I decided to reinstall the system. After reinstalling, the network card issue was resolved, and I restored my development environment the next day. Just as I was preparing a system backup, a new problem arose: the boot partition is missing after restarting the system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the steps from the previous article, I rebuilt the boot partition, but it&amp;rsquo;s unstable. It might not load after a reboot. I initially suspected issues with the case, then checked the hard drive cable connections several times, but everything seems fine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;memory-revival&#34;&gt;Memory revival
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many years ago, this machine had an SSD installed using a PCIe adapter (plugged into the graphics card slot) instead of directly connecting it to the motherboard. This time, installing it directly on the motherboard might indicate a motherboard issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;motherboard-manual&#34;&gt;Motherboard manual
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The motherboard manual contains an error: the labeled SATA port locations do not match the actual locations. With multiple disks installed in all available ports (many of which are older SSDs using SATA), and according to the manual, there&amp;rsquo;s a conflict between these ports. Testing revealed this conflict is triggered intermittently, causing the affected disk to fail to load. This is problematic as it’s the system disk with the boot files, resulting in boot failures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://blog.ttf248.life/p/asus-motherboard-z490-too-many-disks-intermittent-disk-recognition/20250110002401.png&#34;
	width=&#34;807&#34;
	height=&#34;847&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Z490&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;95&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;228px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reinstalling the solid-state drive on the PCIe adapter resolves conflicts with the motherboard&amp;rsquo;s SATA ports, allowing the system to boot normally&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Unveiling the Secrets of ESP Partition, GPT Partition Table, and the Windows Operating Systems Collaboration</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/exploring-esp-gpt-and-windows-cooperation/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 23:58:20 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/exploring-esp-gpt-and-windows-cooperation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, after work, I got home and turned on my desktop. The system booted normally, but the wireless network card failed to load. Thinking the card might be loose, I opened the case and reinstalled it. This made things much worse; now the system won&amp;rsquo;t boot at all, and the bootloader has failed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I worked with desktop computers, so partitioning feels a bit unfamiliar. I used DisGenius to create a new blank partition (usually at the beginning of the disk) and allocated it as an ESP partition (defaulting to 300M). Then, I rebuilt the boot from within the PE system. Relevant information can be found online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the world of computer storage, ESP partitions, GPT partition tables, and Windows operating systems are closely linked, each playing a unique and crucial role in supporting stable system operation and efficient management. Before delving into them, however, it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to mention the &amp;ldquo;pioneer&amp;rdquo; in the history of computer partitioning – the MBR partition table format. It reflects the evolution of technology by contrasting with later innovations. Today, let’s explore their intrinsic connections and intricacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mbr-partition-table--the-foundation-of-traditional-disk-partitioning&#34;&gt;MBR Partition Table – The &amp;ldquo;Foundation&amp;rdquo; of Traditional Disk Partitioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;MBR, short for Master Boot Record, has existed since the early days of personal computers and dominated the hard drive partitioning field for decades&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;basic-architecture&#34;&gt;Basic architecture
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;It is located in the first sector of the hard drive, also known as sector 0, and occupies 512 bytes. These 512 bytes are primarily divided into three parts: firstly, the boot program code, responsible for loading the operating system&amp;rsquo;s boot loader during computer startup, typically 446 bytes; secondly, the disk partition table, occupying 64 bytes, which can define up to 4 primary partition entries, each entry using 16 bytes to record parameters such as starting head, sector, cylinder, and partition type and size; finally, the last 2 bytes are the MBR termination flag &amp;ldquo;55 AA&amp;rdquo;, used to identify this sector as a valid MBR.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;historical-achievements-and-limitations&#34;&gt;Historical achievements and limitations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, the MBR partition table adequately met the relatively simple storage needs of personal computers. It allowed operating systems to smoothly recognize hard drive partitions for orderly data storage and retrieval. However, as technology evolved, its limitations became increasingly apparent. On one hand, constrained by a 64-byte partition table space, it could only support a maximum of four primary partitions; creating more required the use of extended and logical partitions, adding complexity to disk management. On the other hand, with a maximum capacity of only 2TB, it struggled to keep pace with today&amp;rsquo;s high-capacity drives—often several terabytes or even dozens—becoming a bottleneck for further storage technology development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;esp-partition--the-systems-invisible-boot-key&#34;&gt;ESP Partition – The System&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Invisible Boot Key&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;ESP, short for EFI System Partition, is a special partition required on computers using the UEFI (Unified Extensible Firmware Interface) standard&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When a computer powers on, the UEFI firmware first locates the ESP partition on the hard drive and reads the boot loader stored there (such as Windows Boot Manager), thereby initiating the operating system. It&amp;rsquo;s like a precise key that unlocks the gateway to system startup; without it, the system would be lost and confused at boot time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ESP partition also stores essential drivers needed during system startup, ensuring that hardware devices (such as disk controllers and graphics cards) function correctly in the early boot phase, laying the foundation for the subsequent operating system to take over smoothly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;space-requirements-and-format&#34;&gt;Space requirements and format
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Typically, the ESP partition is recommended to be between 100MB and 500MB; allocating around 200MB usually suffices for basic needs. Its file system format must be FAT32 because UEFI firmware can only recognize this format for reading boot files, ensuring compatibility and cross-platform support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gpt-partition-table--the-smart-manager-of-your-hard-drive&#34;&gt;GPT Partition Table – The &amp;ldquo;Smart Manager&amp;rdquo; of Your Hard Drive
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;GPT (GUID Partition Table), or Global Unique Identifier Partition Table, is a new partitioning scheme designed to replace traditional MBR partition tables&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;advantages-revealed&#34;&gt;Advantages revealed
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s era of data explosion, high-capacity hard drives are constantly emerging. The GPT partition table overcomes the 2TB capacity limitation of MBR and theoretically supports up to 9.4 ZB (Zettabytes) – an extremely large storage space enabling massive data storage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlike MBR, which limits partitioning to a maximum of four primary partitions, GPT allows for up to 128 partitions, providing users and system administrators with great flexibility—whether it&amp;rsquo;s dividing multiple system or data partitions, or reserving partitions for specific purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The GPT partition table utilizes a redundant backup mechanism, storing partition information in both the hard drive header and tail. This allows the system to automatically recover from another backup if one partition table is damaged, significantly reducing the risk of data loss due to partition table failure and ensuring data security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;structural-analysis&#34;&gt;Structural Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The GPT partition table consists of several parts, including a protective MBR (retained for BIOS compatibility but not used for actual partitioning), a GPT header (storing basic information about the partition table, such as version, number of partitions, and table size), and an array of partition entries (each entry detailing key information like start/end sectors, GUID type, and unique identifier). These structures work together to precisely plan and manage disk space.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;windows-operating-system--a-digital-interaction-space-for-users&#34;&gt;Windows Operating System – A &amp;ldquo;Digital Interaction Space&amp;rdquo; for Users
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows, a widely used operating system worldwide, builds a user-friendly bridge between people and computer hardware&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;integration-with-esp-partitions-and-gpt-partition-tables&#34;&gt;Integration with ESP partitions and GPT partition tables
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;During the Windows installation process on UEFI-based systems, the installer automatically creates an EFI System Partition (ESP) and deploys boot files to it. The hard drive is initialized with a GPT partition table, creating a system reserved partition (similar to the system boot file area in traditional BIOS), a Windows system partition (where core system files are installed), and other user-defined data partitions. Windows relies on the GPT partition table to accurately identify each partition, enabling smooth startup through the ESP, ensuring seamless integration for a fluid user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system-management-and-optimization-foundation&#34;&gt;System management and optimization foundation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Windows leverages the advantages of GPT partition tables for disk management during operation. For example, the Disk Management tool can easily identify GPT partitions, allowing users to conveniently create, delete, format, and resize them – meeting diverse data storage needs at different stages. System updates, software installations, and other processes are also closely related to the partition layout; a well-planned partitioning scheme helps improve system performance and stability, reducing issues caused by insufficient disk space or partition confusion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;practical-tips-maintenance-and-troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Practical Tips: Maintenance and Troubleshooting
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Understanding their close relationship makes daily maintenance and troubleshooting much more systematic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;disk-space-management&#34;&gt;Disk space management
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regularly check the ESP partition space to avoid issues caused by insufficient space due to excessive startup items or software installations, which can affect system boot. For data partitions under GPT, plan storage effectively and promptly clear unnecessary files to prevent full partitions from impacting system operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;troubleshoot-startup-issues&#34;&gt;Troubleshoot startup issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the system fails to boot, first check the ESP partition for corruption or missing files. You can use the UEFI firmware&amp;rsquo;s built-in startup repair tool or enter a Windows recovery environment using the installation media to rebuild the ESP partition’s boot files. If you suspect a GPT partition table failure, use professional disk tools (such as DiskGenius) to check the integrity of the partition table and attempt to repair/restore backup partition information to recover lost partitions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ESP partitions, GPT partition tables, and the Windows operating system work like a precise team, each playing their part to create a stable and efficient computing environment. Understanding them not only helps us confidently install and maintain systems but also allows us to grasp the underlying logic of computers and navigate the digital world with ease. Reflecting on the rise and fall of the MBR partition table further highlights the power of technological progress, which drives storage technology forward to meet ever-increasing data storage demands.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Disk Cleanup tool (built into Windows): Storage</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-disk-cleanup-storage/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 19:29:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-disk-cleanup-storage/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Starting from which version I am not sure, but in &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;, the Disk Cleanup tool has been significantly improved and become more intelligent&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s an official tool, so it won’t delete files by mistake, display ads, pop-ups, background processes, or any unnecessary elements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To open the Disk Cleanup tool&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ordinary users can choose &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;; the system will provide suggestions based on your usage&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a developer, I have many temporary files on my disk, so I chose to delete those temporary files&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Quickly calculate folder size on Windows platform</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-quick-folder-size-statistics/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 19:54:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-quick-folder-size-statistics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What to do? With many disks and files, the system&amp;rsquo;s built-in File Explorer is too slow when trying to calculate folder sizes, making you want to give up&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;everything&#34;&gt;Everything
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You should also have heard of it from friends. Its search speed far surpasses the system&amp;rsquo;s built-in File Explorer. Since the system supports fast file indexing, there must be similar tools available that can establish a file index and simultaneously calculate file sizes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wiztree&#34;&gt;WizTree
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.diskanalyzer.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.diskanalyzer.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Extract and run the standard installation or green version&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fast speed, diverse data display types – a tree diagram on the left, file types on the right, and graphical visualizations in the software&amp;rsquo;s bottom bar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;spacesniffer-no-longer-maintained-as-of-update-2023&#34;&gt;SpaceSniffer (no longer maintained as of update 2023)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Software website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.uderzo.it/main_products/space_sniffer/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;http://www.uderzo.it/main_products/space_sniffer/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The operation is simple: select the corresponding disk, and the software will graphically display folder sizes. Larger volumes correspond to larger matrices in the image. Other operations are self-explanatory with a few clicks. It supports filtering files by input conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File size filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;File date filtering&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://moe.best/software/spacesniffer.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://moe.best/software/spacesniffer.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Editing Large Files on Windows: EmEditor (Text Editor)</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-editing-large-files-emeditor-text-editor/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 31 Jul 2022 23:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/windows-platform-editing-large-files-emeditor-text-editor/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai National Security database incident has been buzzing around the hacker circles, though it&amp;rsquo;s unclear if it’s true or not. Let&amp;rsquo;s see if we remember it in a couple of years and revisit then. Based on past experience, after updating local social engineering (SOC) databases, I saw a massive SQL file: 17.9GB. Even previewing it is problematic with standard text editors, let alone opening it. Chatting online with some users, someone mentioned EmEditor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Website: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.emeditor.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.emeditor.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried it out during my weekend free time – it&amp;rsquo;s quite convenient. The design supports editing large files, and with sufficient memory, the entire file loads into memory, making searching and editing fast. It also supports splitting files.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
