<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stock-Market on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-market/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stock-Market on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:59:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Black Swan Goose Returns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:10:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, investors focused on financial news. Since Trump’s return, they also needed to pay attention to his Twitter (a private version). The trade war continued to escalate, leading to a sharp decline on April 7th, which was quickly followed by a rebound. This time, though, are people still willing to jump in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-review&#34;&gt;Background Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 7, 2025, following the impact of the U.S. implementation of an “equivalency tariff” policy, global stock markets experienced a “Black Monday.” The A-share market plunged, with the Shanghai Composite Index falling by 7.34% and the Shenzhen Component Index plummeting by 12.5%, with over 4,300 stocks declining by more than 9%. The Hang Seng Index in Hong Kong also fell by 13.22%, along with European and U.S. stock indices exceeding declines of 4%. China subsequently stabilized the market through state-owned enterprise (SOE) purchases and intervention by Huishang Securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 10th, U.S. stocks suffered another significant decline, with Chinese HShares falling by 6%, driven primarily by expectations of escalation in the U.S.-China trade war. Trump signaled a further increase in tariffs on China, and the U.S. would also impose hefty fees on Chinese ships. China announced retaliatory measures and levied special port fees, compounded by a government shutdown, declining consumer confidence, and market panic selling for safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115351840469973590&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Original Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/black-swan-goose-returns/20251011142053.png&#34;
	width=&#34;586&#34;
	height=&#34;766&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;realDonaldTrump&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;76&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;183px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control&#34;&gt;Position Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the state of short selling in A-shares isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete short position; there’s a small portion invested in index funds within Fixed Income Plus, but the bulk is still in the Hong Kong market. Xiaomi has already incurred principal losses, and Meituan remains a shareholder. The position control is somewhat unbalanced. Should we jump in and gamble on Monday? It&amp;rsquo;s a question to consider – currently, we don’t have enough cash flow. If we need to enter, we would rely on old friends like Alipay’s Jiebei for bridging funds. &lt;strong&gt;Greedy snakes swallow elephants&lt;/strong&gt; – the position control is extremely unreasonable, and we should look for opportunities to reduce our holdings later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to April 7th, the current position isn&amp;rsquo;t considered a low-level one; many stocks are at relatively high levels, particularly the technology stocks within the Heng Seng Tech index. If we were to add to positions, it would be more appropriate to use an ETF rather than individual stocks – for example: &lt;strong&gt;Turned around and couldn’t find anything suitable; gains were 20%-30%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the domestic market, long-term trends point towards a period of consolidation and decline, with potential for significant rallies in the short term. To make profits, it&amp;rsquo;s best to execute profit-taking operations within this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;associated-term-definitions&#34;&gt;Associated Term Definitions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-swan&#34;&gt;Black Swan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Black Swan&amp;rdquo; originates from Nassim Nicholas Taleb’s book &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to events that are &lt;strong&gt;extremely unlikely&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt;, but upon occurring, they generate &lt;strong&gt;extreme impact and disruptive consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rarity/Unpredictability:&lt;/strong&gt; These events have no precedent or warning signs before they occur, exceeding all conventional expectations and model predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extreme Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once they happen, they can cause catastrophic effects on markets, economies, and even societies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-hoc Rationalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite being impossible to predict beforehand, people tend to find reasons and explanations after the event occurs, making it appear “understandable.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Legend:&lt;/strong&gt; Before the discovery of Australia, Europeans believed all swans were white until black swans were discovered in Australia, completely overturning thousands of years of knowledge. Therefore, the Black Swan symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;unforeseen and cognitive breakthroughs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;9/11&amp;rdquo; terrorist attack in 2001 (a short-term shock to global markets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The initial impact of &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt; on the global economy and markets (although some argued it had grey rhino characteristics, its sudden outbreak and global spread, as well as the extent of its impact, were largely considered Black Swans).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gray-rhino&#34;&gt;Gray Rhino
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “Gray Rhino” was coined by Michele Wucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to a potential crisis that is &lt;strong&gt;highly probable&lt;/strong&gt;, has a &lt;strong&gt;significant impact&lt;/strong&gt;, and yet is &lt;strong&gt;ignored&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;selectively delayed in addressing&lt;/strong&gt; due to its &lt;strong&gt;obvious warning signs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Probability/Predictability:&lt;/strong&gt; The event has clear indicators and evidence before it occurs, making it a &lt;strong&gt;known&lt;/strong&gt; risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily Ignored:&lt;/strong&gt; Because it’s not sudden but rather long-term or slowly developing, people become numb, exhibit optimism bias, or procrastinate, failing to take timely action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once it erupts, due to the lack of effective responses beforehand, it triggers a chain reaction and causes severe destructive consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Allusion:&lt;/strong&gt; A gray rhino is large in size and has a slow reaction time; people can see it from afar, but often fail to avoid it because of negligence or indifference. Once it charges towards you, it will cause a fatal collision. Therefore, the gray rhino symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;obvious yet ignored&lt;/strong&gt; major threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2008 &lt;strong&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/strong&gt; (many experts had already warned about the high risk of the US subprime mortgage market, but were largely ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sovereign Debt Crises&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;severe asset bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;systemic risks from climate change&lt;/strong&gt; (these are long-accumulated, traceable major risks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Long time no see bull market in stocks</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/long-time-no-see-bull-market-in-stocks/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:42:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/long-time-no-see-bull-market-in-stocks/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;On the eve of the 2024 National Day holiday, China’s stock market experienced a remarkable surge, attracting considerable attention. However, following the holiday, the market unexpectedly turned to a dramatic plunge. This “polarization” of the stock market – a rollercoaster ride between soaring highs and plummeting lows – not only subjected investors to a thrilling yet nerve-wracking experience, but also prompted deep reflection within the market regarding policy, economic conditions, and fundamental market rules.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;pre-national-day-stock-market-surge-a-policy-driven-frenzy&#34;&gt;Pre-National Day Stock Market Surge: A Policy-Driven Frenzy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over the five trading days leading up to National Day, China’s stock market surged from a slump into “boiling mode.” On September 30th, the A-share market saw a full-scale rally with all indices hitting historic highs. The Shanghai Composite Index rose by 8.06%, the Shenzhen Component Index increased by 10.67%, and the Innovation Board China Advanced Index soared by 15.36%, while the STAR 50 Index achieved its largest single-day rise in history, jumping 22.84%. Market sentiment was extremely exuberant, with daily trading volumes across the Shanghai, Shenzhen, and Northern Exchanges reaching RMB 2611.5 billion, a significant increase of RMB 11559 billion compared to the previous trading day. More than 5300 stocks on the main board rallied collectively, creating a “sea of red.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The core driver behind this rally was the concentrated release of a series of unexpectedly positive policies by the government and the resulting changes in market expectations. On September 24th, the People’s Bank of China announced a cut in the reserve requirement ratio and interest rates, reducing existing mortgage loan interest rates and standardizing the minimum down payment ratios. The Politburo Standing Committee’s meeting on September 26th emphasized the need to intensify counter-cyclical fiscal and monetary policy adjustments to boost capital markets and actively guide medium and long-term funds into the market. On September 30th, a series of real estate support policies were released. These measures conveyed the government&amp;rsquo;s determination to stabilize the market and promote growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-national-day-stock-market-plunge-calm-and-adjustment-after-the-frenzy&#34;&gt;Post-National Day Stock Market Plunge: Calm and Adjustment After the Frenzy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, market sentiment plummeted sharply after the National Day holiday. On October 8th, the A-share market opened strongly with nearly a limit-up rise, but following a significant high opening, the market experienced violent fluctuations before closing down. Since then, the market’s center of gravity has continuously shifted downwards, and as of October 16th, the Shanghai Composite Index rose and fell by more than 15%, cumulatively falling by over 470 points. From October 8th to 10th, core A-share indices all declined, with the Shenzhen Component Index down 6.21%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reasons for this plunge are multifaceted. On one hand, it was a digestion of risks accumulated from the rapid rise in the previous period; on the other hand, it was also related to adjustments in market expectations regarding policy. Some investors believed that the short-term effects of policies were already evident, but the long-term effects still needed to be observed. Furthermore, volatility in global markets also impacted A-shares. On October 9th, the Hang Seng Index fell by 9.41%, and A50 futures fell by 10.4%, further exacerbating market declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection-and-outlook-on-the-market&#34;&gt;Reflection and Outlook on the Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The dramatic volatility in the stock market around National Day highlighted a deep reflection among investors regarding policy, economics, and market fundamentals. On one hand, the short-term stimulus effects of policies were significant, but their long-term impact remains to be observed. On the other hand, the rapid rise and fall of the market served as a reminder for investors to maintain rationality and avoid emotional investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking ahead, whether A-shares can usher in a genuine “long bull” trend depends on whether policy can effectively transmit to the real economy and ultimately drive substantive improvements in economic fundamentals. Investors should closely monitor the specific implementation of policies and changes in economic data to rationally adjust their investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The sharp rises and falls in the stock market around National Day were a game between policy and the market, and also a test of investors’ mentality. In this “two-pronged” market environment, we saw the power of the market and the influence of policy. How the market will unfold in the future remains to be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
