<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ETF on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/etf/</link>
        <description>Recent content in ETF on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/etf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Fees have been reduced, fees have been reduced – several large domestic ETFs have lowered their fees</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 03:08:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Huatai Pioneer has lowered the all-in fee rate for its CSI 300 ETF and similar products to the lowest tier among comparable ETFs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To better meet the investment and financial management needs of investors, Huatai-Perrin Fund announced adjustments to the management fees and custody fees for its Huatai-Perrin CSI 300 ETF and related funds, revising relevant content in the fund contracts accordingly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading ETFs including ChinaAMC Huaxia Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, ChinaAMC CSI 50 ETF, NanShan Zhongxin 500 ETF, JIA SHI Huaxia Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, and Yifangda Growth Enterprise ETF have simultaneously announced reductions in management and custody fees, bringing rates down to 0.15% and 0.05%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unlike most previous ETF fee reductions, this one was driven by proactive moves from large-scale products, and will likely have a significant impact on the industry. Exchange data shows that as of November 18th, the ChinaAMC Huatai 300 ETF has exceeded 370 billion yuan, making it the largest ETF currently available.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The largest group of super ETFs has begun reducing fees, demonstrating a willingness to benefit investors and allowing them to invest in popular, liquid funds with higher value for money&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry experts believe that fee reductions for ETFs with economies of scale will help mutual funds fulfill their function of serving inclusive finance, benefiting a wider range of investors by reducing holding costs, increasing potential returns, and enhancing investment satisfaction&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Low fees also help enhance the product&amp;rsquo;s competitiveness. With liquidity attraction and cost advantages, it is expected to attract more long-term incremental capital, fostering a healthy &amp;ldquo;long money, long investment&amp;rdquo; ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, broad-based ETFs have become a primary channel for investors seeking entry with modest capital and long-term investment, thanks to their advantages such as flexible trading, high transparency, strong liquidity, and low investment thresholds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fee reduction could act as a catalyst, facilitating greater participation from long-term investors in A-shares&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My fixed-investment Tianhong fund hasn&amp;rsquo;t released an announcement yet, but it should follow suit. If there’s no update, I’ll need to consider switching funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original management fee was 0.5%, and the custody fee was 0.1%. The new fees are 0.15% for management, and 0.05% for custody. This is still a significant reduction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
