<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>ETF on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/etf/</link>
        <description>Recent content in ETF on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/etf/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>“Fee reduction, fee reduction! Domestic mega-ETFs are experiencing a large-scale fee reduction.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 03:08:48 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reduced-fees-large-domestic-etf/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ping An Blockchain ETF et al. announced a reduction in the overall fee rate to the lowest level among peers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 19th, China Merchants Bank Fund announced that, to better meet the investment and financial needs of investors, starting from November 22nd, it will reduce the management fees and custodian fees of Huatai Baorong Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its affiliated funds, and revise relevant content in the fund contracts.
&lt;strong&gt;After the adjustment, the annual management fee for Huatai Baorong Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF and its affiliated funds is reduced to 0.15%, the annual custodian fee is reduced to 0.05%, all set to the lowest fee level among index funds.&lt;/strong&gt;
Almost simultaneously, leading in size in the industry, China Merchants HuRun Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, China Merchants Shanghai Stock 50 ETF, Nanfang Zhongce 500 ETF, Guangxi Shanghai-Shenzhen 300 ETF, Yifada Entrepreneurial Board ETF et al. also announced a reduction in management and custodian fees, with all rates reduced to 0.15% and 0.05%. Unlike most ETFs experiencing fee cuts, this time the reduction was spearheaded by market-leading actively-traded products with significant scale advantages. This is expected to have a substantial impact on the industry going forward. Exchange data shows that as of November 18th, the size of Greater China Fund’s CSI 300 ETF exceeded 370 billion yuan, making it currently the largest ETF in terms of assets under management. The largest batch of super ETFs initiated fee cuts, demonstrating their willingness to offer value to investors and allowing investors to invest in popular and liquid funds at a higher cost-effectiveness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Industry experts believe that the reduction in expense ratios for large-scale ETFs will, on one hand, facilitate the public fund industry’s role in providing inclusive financial services, enabling investors to reduce holding costs and enhance their potential returns and investment satisfaction on a larger scale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other hand, low fee rates will also further improve the competitiveness of the products themselves. With the added benefits of liquidity diversion and cost operation advantages, these products are expected to attract more medium-to-long-term incremental capital into the market, helping to build a healthy ecosystem for “long money, long investment.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In recent years, broad-based ETFs have become the primary channel for funds entering at low levels and engaging in “long money, long investment” due to their unique advantages such as flexible trading, high transparency, strong liquidity, and low investment barriers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This fee reduction may serve as an &amp;ldquo;accelerator,&amp;rdquo; making it easier for long-term capital to enter the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the Tianhong Fund that I invested in hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet released an announcement, it should be followed up on. If no update is provided, I will consider switching funds.
Original Management Fee: 0.5%, Custody Fee: 0.1%. New Management Fee: 0.15%, Custody Fee: 0.05%. This reduction is quite significant.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
