<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Local-Area-Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/local-area-network/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Local-Area-Network on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/local-area-network/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Upgrading from a desktop to a 2.5G network card, accelerating local area network connectivity.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:37:52 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/desktop-upgrade-to-25g-network-card-accelerate-lan-interconnection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Desktop hardware three-in-one, in the previous text we mentioned PCIe adapter for solid state drives, where did the old SSDs go? Of course they weren&amp;rsquo;t wasted – if they were damaged, they were disassembled and installed on the newly purchased ‘MechMaker Mini-3765H’ (bought a year ago).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This new machine has powerful hardware specifications: 2.5G dual network interfaces, PCIe4.0, WiFi6.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I moved house and my room doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a dedicated router for networking, so the machines are connected via wireless networks. The ASUS motherboard desktop’s wireless card performance wasn’t great, or perhaps it was the router’s wireless access, which resulted in slow upload speeds between local networks, leading to poor network speeds between the machines. I purchased a 2.5G NIC and installed it on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, all the slots on the motherboard are full: graphics card, wireless card, 2.5G NIC, PCIe adapter for solid state drives.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;network-instructions&#34;&gt;Network Instructions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both machines connect to the internet using their original wireless network cards, but are directly connected via Ethernet cables between the two ends, with both sides equipped with 2.5G network cards.  The specifics of how to connect the Ethernet cables between the two machines aren&amp;rsquo;t detailed here – there are many tutorials available online; just remember to disable your firewall. You can select either machine as the gateway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;two-subnet-speed-testing&#34;&gt;Two Subnet Speed Testing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;router-lan&#34;&gt;Router LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;direct-lan&#34;&gt;Direct LAN
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wutongsuimeng.github.io/post/%E7%BB%99hugo%E6%B7%BB%E5%8A%A0mermaid%E6%94%AF%E6%8C%81/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Adding Mermaid Support to Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
