<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Speech-Talk on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/speech-talk/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Speech-Talk on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/speech-talk/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Chinas good future will be one with kind elders</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-good-china-with-elderly/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-good-china-with-elderly/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that in twenty years, I&amp;rsquo;ll be a lovely old man, accompanied by a lovely old woman. Not seeking great wealth or status, just good health and the ability to travel around.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search; no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to work hard to become a lovable old man. The China of the future will be one with good old men and women. Even if I’m 60 years old in 10 years, I’ll still be among the youngest in this world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, people find it quite impressive that a 50-year-old Chinese man can have this physique. But behind this body is the principle I believe in: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! After the rain stopped, I wanted to go running, and I&amp;rsquo;ll play soccer tomorrow afternoon. At 50, I can still compete at a high level – I’m not kidding, often playing with professionals. But what&amp;rsquo;s behind it? Discipline. I spend my remaining days running, and some find it monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I am free to run, never listening to music; I believe listening to my own breath is the most beautiful music for running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I rarely use the treadmill. Despite Beijing&amp;rsquo;s severe smog, I run five days a week—two already reserved for the smog. Unlike others, I never skip a day. Each month, I mark a running day in my journal, always at least 18 days. Runs fly by; I don’t wear glasses while running. More importantly, I also play soccer weekly. My last class with my graduate students will be at my home, focusing on the theme of fun—I believe fun is crucial. I never interact with people lacking joy and hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To treat them with respect and keep a distance – such people are truly frightening. If you don&amp;rsquo;t find joy, what joy do you have? I really don’t have much either. What kind of work do you like? This year at the beginning of the year, one of my graduate students was assigned to China News Weekly. We had a special topic. Every year when my graduate students graduated, their last assignment was to write an article about 10 years from now, which I would keep. Then, 10 years later, I would unfold them one by one. I also wrote about turning 50 and writing to 60 – something I never thought would be so distant, beyond the map, but suddenly it&amp;rsquo;s my next stop. Writing from 20 to 30 for my students is like a love letter from spring to summer. But writing from 50 to 60 is just a murmur from late summer to autumn. Now, I’m writing to 10 years from now – slowly writing about myself, about a bed, a meal, and the people around my family. That&amp;rsquo;s perfectly normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what kind of person should one be at 60? My goal is clear. As stated in the preface, this article is lengthy. I want to strive to become a lovable old man in 10 years. China&amp;rsquo;s lovability depends not only on having more young people who will become responsible citizens – no longer just ordinary folks, but energetic and rule-abiding youth – but also on having good old men and women. Currently, over 230 million Chinese are already over 60; in 10 years, that number will certainly exceed 300 million. In terms of the population aged 60 and above alone, China would be a top 5 country globally, possibly even third – just imagine how daunting that is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t think so. I don’t know if everyone has seen the table online showing the average life expectancy in various Chinese provinces and municipalities; Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years old, counting both men and women. The average lifespan certainly favors men over women. That means even when I’m 60 in ten years, I&amp;rsquo;ll be among the youngest in this third stage of life. Women retire at 55 to an average age of 80, leaving them with 25 years; men retire at 60 to an average age of 80, leaving them with 20 years! You can’t just do square dancing all the time. And I can say that today&amp;rsquo;s older sisters and brothers doing square dancing have been given this cultural habit and entertainment by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In another 20 years, there will likely still be square dancing, but on a much smaller scale. Younger generations are not as enthusiastic about group activities; just as older people prefer organized tours, young people increasingly opt for independent and self-guided travel. Square dancing will continue to exist, but its scope will diminish—this isn&amp;rsquo;t inherently good or bad, it’s simply the times changing. When I was 60, the youngest member of a team, I should be asking myself: what kind of person should I become? Chinese painting says that at 60, your ears are attuned – but I certainly wouldn’t listen to everything happily; I&amp;rsquo;d still hear what shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be said, and even happiness can turn sour. More importantly, what can I do for the younger generation?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What can you do to contribute to good things? Don&amp;rsquo;t be lazy, don&amp;rsquo;t compromise easily, oppose what needs opposing. Can you stand in front of a young person when they might harm someone’s interests? I often find myself looking at this mirror now. A good friend of mine has passed away. Tao Wei used to gather with us frequently at our home and once told me a true story. We all felt the pain together. The older generation, like Chen Lao, hoarded everything in their homes – you break open a box and find over 30 items hidden under the bed. You tell them this shirt cost over 500 yuan, now it’s being worshipped with incense daily. Therefore, our generation grew accustomed to battling wits with our parents. What&amp;rsquo;s the value of something bought for 700 yuan?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s easy to run into trouble with these things. Once, Tao Wei spent over 400 yuan on a T-shirt for his father. It was a really nice shirt; how much did it cost? 99. I wore that style and the next day, disaster struck. When he came back in the evening, he demanded 400 yuan from Tao Wei to buy four more for me. After wearing mine out today, Uncle Li and others all praised it. They said this kind of behavior carries a significant risk. Don&amp;rsquo;t do such things when you’re older. I won&amp;rsquo;t mention specifics about who is in the hospital orthopedic ward – an elderly person fractured their bone, and the crucial reason was the shoes bought from a street vendor. Of course, this only addresses the material aspect. Even as we age, we need spiritual life, curiosity, and a willingness to shield younger generations from hardship. Live each day happily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m curious and excited about turning 60, feeling it will be a wonderful beginning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18th birthday might be different from yours</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a very common thing—since graduating high school and abandoning the time spent reading novels, it’s been a long while since I’ve seriously and quietly read a book. Sometimes looking back, after working for so long, do I even remember what I did each year? Often, by mid-year, I&amp;rsquo;ve already forgotten much of what happened in the first half. Blogging is a good habit; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter if much of what I write isn’t public—it’s originally meant for myself anyway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal reader is myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search; no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Everyone&amp;rsquo;s 18th birthday is like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. Each person occasionally asks themselves: Are you the person you wanted to be back then? I fear that nowadays, everyone has countless online friends but no real connections, chats endlessly but lacks genuine conversations, gains endless knowledge but remains far from wisdom. Everyone should ask themself, using their 18th birthday as a reminder: deceiving others is easy; deceiving yourself is difficult!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think everyone&amp;rsquo;s 18th birthday is like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. You can deceive others, but you can’t deceive your own 18-year-old self. Are you the way your 18-year-old self wanted to be? I think that&amp;rsquo;s alright. Today, there are so many more things than I thought about at 18 – material possessions, fame, etc., all obtained. But on the other hand, I’m still on the journey. When I was 18, I studied journalism at the broadcasting academy and wanted to become a great journalist like Farahachi. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path. That&amp;rsquo;s why people often ask me, &amp;ldquo;Bai Shi, why are you still at CCTV?&amp;rdquo; Because I want to be a good journalist. The news continues. It’s the gaze of my 18-year-old self. So I think everyone should occasionally ask their 18-year-old self: Are you living the way you wanted to?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is something that truly can&amp;rsquo;t be faked. This is what I looked like when I was 18. Thirty-two years have passed in the blink of an eye. Everyone who came to Beijing to study would have a photo like this. Back then, we wore wrinkled suits on Tiananmen Square and proudly pinned our school badges to our chests because there were so few college students. My hair was long back then, but I still really liked how I looked at 18. After many years, I suddenly realized that I&amp;rsquo;m grateful for what I faced at 18, because it quietly shaped me. On May 8th, 1986, I bought a collection of Misty Poetry at the Wangfujing Bookstore. That year, I heard Cui Jian’s “Nothing to My Name” at the Workers’ Stadium. And today, I suddenly realized that my writing style—and even my personality—was most influenced by Misty Poetry, rock music, and Gu Long&amp;rsquo;s martial arts novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you experience at 18? What baggage might you carry as a result? I&amp;rsquo;m particularly curious about what 18-year-olds are facing today – is it like being carved with knives and axes? But what tools are doing the shaping? What kind of person have they molded you into? I worry that now everyone has countless social media connections, but lacks true friends; they chat constantly, yet no one truly confides in anyone. Knowledge is limitless, yet wisdom feels distant. They know everything, yet understand nothing. It seems like everyone&amp;rsquo;s talking about individuality. But as an observer, I see that today’s young people are remarkably similar. What should you let him experience at 18? I really love 1986; it was the best way to resolve the issues of 1966.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cultural Revolution ended with the downfall of the Gang of Four in 1976, a result partly due to chance. True progress requires enlightenment and a resurgence of humanity, alongside individual growth. We still need this awakening, and a thorough understanding of human nature. Regardless of economic advancements, if we fail to genuinely understand and guide human nature – addressing its darker aspects while activating its inherent goodness – concerns will persist. My 18th year mirrors the era&amp;rsquo;s; having strayed too far, we must remember our initial purpose, now distilled into the four characters: &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t abandon your original intention.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of how far you go, everyone should ask themselves the question they asked at 18. It&amp;rsquo;s good to have a photo from that time and look at it often to check in with yourself. What others say is irrelevant; it’s easy to deceive them. Deceiving yourself is difficult. I said earlier when I was 18, I would tell someone who is now 20: always let your 18-year-old self be a pair of eyes watching you. And as for those in their twenties, as I mentioned before, try opening many doors – you don’t know which one suits you best. It&amp;rsquo;s surprising in China today to see people in their twenties acting like elders, and many young people who are 70+.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalists does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The text discusses the author&amp;rsquo;s perspective on journalism, emphasizing the need for social conscience, knowledge, and perseverance. The author also shares reflections from their 50s, including maintaining curiosity, balancing material and spiritual needs, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search; no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best journalists first possess a social conscience, then knowledge, and finally perseverance. It’s not enough to just run a short distance; it requires endurance. Combining these three qualities, people expect that potential safety concerns regarding vaccines will be completely resolved – like the milk powder incident, where progress is consistently made through cycles of problem emergence and resolution, ultimately leading to complete solutions. Otherwise, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of journalists?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe the best journalists first possess a sense of social responsibility, second, a foundation of knowledge, and third, perseverance – it’s not enough to just run 100 meters; you have to keep running. Combining these three qualities, I turned 50 this year, and you&amp;rsquo;ll understand that I seem well-suited for journalism. I am naturally closely linked to China’s 40 years of reform. When I turned 30, I stood on the bank of the Songhua River; when I turned 40, my birthday was spent entering and exiting the Olympic broadcasts in 2008. Turning 50 this year coincides with nationwide commemorations of the 40th anniversary of China’s reform and opening-up. So, if we consider a person&amp;rsquo;s 40th year and China’s 40 years of reform – are they a time of clarity or confusion?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After 40 years, China has provided ample material wealth for both its people and the nation. Yet, anxiety and confusion have increased instead of diminished. We thought that strength and prosperity would solve everything, but we&amp;rsquo;ve discovered that material comfort is just a foundation – escaping poverty materially is easy, but achieving spiritual richness and becoming a true global power is incredibly difficult. The U.S. is already targeting our high-tech sector; we need to focus on agricultural products. There’s always a difficulty in being the “number two.” How many number twos has America replaced? Therefore, we inevitably face a long journey to transform this &amp;ldquo;second&amp;rdquo; status into something beyond ourselves – I can&amp;rsquo;t expect to have it all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to start in television at 25, initially doing interviews. I came into contact with hundreds or even thousands of people surrounded by various auras. When young, we thought these auras must bring happiness, but upon getting closer, it turned out not to be the case; the aura and their happiness often had an inverse relationship. Just finished reading about Guo Moruo’s last 29 years—despite holding high positions like Vice Premier of the State Council and various leadership roles in political advisory bodies, both his sons died, one by suicide and another possibly thrown from a building. Could he have been happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? For a former vice premier, having two sons leave her within a few years in their sixties and seventies could bring her happiness. Many famous calligraphy works can bring happiness. Having safely lived through many years can bring happiness. What more is needed? So I think observing people&amp;rsquo;s reading habits is the best mirror. To put it slightly emphatically, I feel that many people’s anxiety now stems from thinking too much and reading too little. This is a reply from Mrs. Yang Jiang to a young person. People expect instant gratification without reading, hoping to find a quick fix with just a phone. How could that be possible? I learned to be clever through the clumsy process of reading books; subtraction comes from reading more and more.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I don&amp;rsquo;t expect everyone to change, but I hope the proportion increases – that more and more Chinese people can find a better version of themselves through education. That’s what matters most. No one sits on the ground staring at the stars and figures everything out; I can’t do that. But I can look in the mirror. A few years ago, a BBC news anchor—they claimed he was their best—came to Beijing. Someone organized a dialogue between him and Chinese anchors at the International Hotel, and we had a conversation. During the discussion, he asked me what the BBC should learn from CCTV. I joked, “Of course, first you need to learn Chinese.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, I joked that the BBC should learn from CCTV about its curiosity towards the world. We&amp;rsquo;ve rapidly expanded our presence globally in recent years, establishing over 70 foreign bureaus. Our reporters feel a great sense of curiosity when encountering new things abroad, observing the world with immense eagerness. The BBC, however, seems to have settled for Britain as their entire world—they’ve lost that curiosity. My friend slapped the table and said, &amp;ldquo;You&amp;rsquo;re absolutely right; that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we lack.&amp;rdquo; In 2007, a Japanese writer told me something similar during an interview: “This country has everything except hope.” I understood then how profound those words were. Looking at it from another angle, a decade ago, I felt China lacked almost everything except for hope—everyone believed there was potential ahead.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But I worry about a day when we too become a wealthy nation with everything but hope. To be honest, I fear that China will reach a point where it feels truly poor despite having everything. I dread becoming someone who has all their material needs met but is ultimately very impoverished at 50. We see many highly educated yet uncultured people and countless individuals with overflowing bank accounts who are still poor in spirit. This is the problem of our time. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t frightening; it holds potential and hope for the future. That’s why I believe there&amp;rsquo;s a moral deficit and a loss of humanity – scientists invent things not out of some grand mission, but from curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting to see what I can produce. So, starting around 50, I began pushing myself to be even more curious, which makes me happy. One frustrating thing now is persistence. You mentioned you’re still persistent, and I said, &amp;ldquo;Don&amp;rsquo;t,&amp;rdquo; because once persistence becomes a matter of life or death, it&amp;rsquo;s close to the end. We used to say that perseverance equals victory. In Chinese football, we&amp;rsquo;d grit our teeth and persevere through those black three minutes – no fun, no method, just perseverance. Perseverance can be important sometimes, but often this statement has two sides. I worry that when I’m persevering in something, like finishing this conversation even though my time is up, I wonder what it will turn out like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Give yourself a small focus, but engage in conversation with everyone. I believe that as long as you can maintain a strong sense of curiosity at 50, it’s fine. I like all fun things, though not necessarily the current trends—today&amp;rsquo;s fashions can disappear quickly. Do you remember any past buzzwords? Can today&amp;rsquo;s internet media possibly evolve into what traditional media once was? Fun always has an inherent appeal. I respect everyone&amp;rsquo;s preferences; there&amp;rsquo;s a reason behind them. But in the long run, people still prefer playing mahjong. When you enjoy fast food, the restaurants serving elaborate meals will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things can&amp;rsquo;t just be dismissed with a passing thought. How much fragmented reading do you do on your phone each day? How much longer-form content do you actually read? But this is also a process; the phone is becoming our shackle. I don’t worry about “content is king,” because seeing more and more short-form content will gradually lead to nearsightedness, but it&amp;rsquo;s a process nonetheless. People will indulge in entertainment until they reach 40, just like seeing teenagers drinking soda – you advise them to drink less, but you know they won’t listen. However, I remain optimistic; at 40, he will return to the world of tea. That is the essence of a Chinese life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s normal, but I hope the next change comes quicker. We’re just lamenting how few investigative journalists there are now; you don’t seem to be doing investigations anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you all&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will Chinese football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;These supplementary reflections were mostly written spontaneously in 2021, during the early days of the pandemic when Bai Yansong&amp;rsquo;s speech was transcribed. The world always changes beyond expectation—not just after twenty years, but even a year or two later. Now, domestic COVID-19 is nearing its end, while overseas outbreaks continue. Regarding football, the national team has been playing well in recent years, and the coach dares to play offensively. Compared to the clueless days of old, it&amp;rsquo;s somewhat enjoyable watching with my grandfather. What an experience it is – a national team match that makes even an elderly person want to change the channel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can use Youku search; no further links will be provided&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Very curious, what could it have fallen to? You find there are many reasons why Chinese football doesn&amp;rsquo;t play well, and one of them is that no one wants to risk losing the ball themselves – they don’t pass it to others; there’s just no such approach&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one small reason. Twenty years of football—after 20 years, Chinese football feels so distant. The first expansion brought the number to 48. China might go, but it still might not. The optimal age for a national team is 26-30; that&amp;rsquo;s today’s 6-10 year olds. Twenty years will make you feel optimistic—certainly possible after 20 years. But when I mention today’s 6-10 year olds, your expression immediately turns serious. So, cause and effect are intertwined: what are we planting today? We almost planted soybeans to have the national team play in a league – what will grow from this? Whoever initiates this action needs to prepare for dismissal; it violates the rules. That’s why I haven&amp;rsquo;t thought about it too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But we really should think about today&amp;rsquo;s 6-10 year olds – are they playing soccer? You’ll know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Moral deficit, human natures loss</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When doing things, the most important thing is to act with a clear conscience. This ensures peaceful sleep and helps you discern right from wrong. If mistakes are made, do your best to rectify them; don&amp;rsquo;t hide or try to forget. Humans are easily forgetful, yet also possess good memories. Inner peace is the ultimate destination – being able to answer yourself honestly leads to a more relaxed life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there is any copyright infringement, please contact me for deletion. This article is only a translated transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;script&#34;&gt;Script
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight characters that carry significant weight: I feel we currently have a deficit of morality, a loss of humanity. History progresses through a cycle of problems arising and being solved, repeatedly solving them thoroughly. You need patience to wait for the reshuffling. For a country like China, many things are a slow process of reshuffling, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic during change and reshuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These past few days, China has been battling two typhoons – one invisible, the other visible. The invisible typhoon is the vaccine, which challenges our sense of security. The visible typhoon rarely lands in Shanghai and impacts Beijing and Tianjin; it&amp;rsquo;s unprecedented for three major cities to face such a storm together in decades. That’s aside from the point. What you need to consider now is whether you can thrive on your own. You’ve changed greatly, possessing many answers. But if the environment remains unchanged, will you be happy? I have eight words that carry significant weight: we currently have a deficit of morality and a loss of humanity – this is the greatest deficit and the biggest loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People expect the safety concerns surrounding the vaccine to be resolved completely, just like the milk powder scandal. It&amp;rsquo;s important to learn from history and understand how the establishment of the US FDA and its comprehensive legal framework are closely linked to past incidents involving unsafe milk and dairy products. The Sanlu milk powder incident forced significant changes in China’s dairy industry. While I can’t guarantee a continuous series of events, I hope this one brings things to a halt. Progress occurs through cycles of problems arising, being solved, and then thoroughly resolved – otherwise, what&amp;rsquo;s the point of journalists? What&amp;rsquo;s the point of citizens?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think the only thing each of us can do is to pay attention. But the problem is that Chinese people tend to forget easily. As I mentioned earlier, after hitting someone&amp;rsquo;s car, we just abandon it on the side of the road and run off, with no one stopping us. A large proportion of our neighbors and colleagues are like this. So change needs to be gradual. And as ordinary citizens, what we can do is pay attention and not forget. It’s not a lack of process; when people aren&amp;rsquo;t able to eat or dress properly, talking about ideals lacks persuasiveness. But once they have enough food and warm clothes, and become the world’s leading diabetes nation, the leading high blood pressure nation, and so on – many “number one” nations – you see Chinese people start running, Chinese people start dieting. Ask the ladies here, how many of you haven&amp;rsquo;t experienced the harsh reality that you don’t have the energy to diet unless you eat a good meal? That&amp;rsquo;s a small shift.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the same with the spiritual realm. When you’re well-fed and clothed, and start exercising or dieting, your spiritual needs gradually increase. For example, I used to smoke, but after starting to run, I suddenly realized I hadn’t had a cigarette in over 20 days – and haven’t since. Of course, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t say I completely quit; that feels too formal. There might be two or three cigarettes a year. When your lifestyle changes, many things shift along with it. For Chinese people, you need patience to wait for this reshuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more people feel unhappy, yet are unwilling to indulge in that unhappiness. While depression is on the rise, isn&amp;rsquo;t it also true that increasingly more people are seeking positive ways to live? This leads to a growth in spiritual matters. So don’t be pessimistic; it all depends on your perspective. I often see drivers cutting in line and feel frustrated. But then I quickly become optimistic because the queue on the other side is much longer now. It&amp;rsquo;s just like that – a process. Look at everyone here, willing to come to this place on a rainy evening to chat about such trivial things; isn’t that wonderful?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Isn&amp;rsquo;t this also a transformation? It means many things require a shift in thinking. I believe there will be much more to come, for example, you mentioned entrepreneurship – isn’t everyone an entrepreneur throughout their life? We attribute too much of a modern feel to the term &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurship,&amp;rdquo; but it has always existed. Su Shi was an entrepreneur; Li Bai was an entrepreneur. Throughout their lives, they created, and most didn&amp;rsquo;t succeed in creating a brand, which is fine. As long as you live with flavor and believe it’s worthwhile. What China particularly lacks now is a value system that recognizes good failure as another form of success. Chinese culture only accepts successful outcomes; it doesn&amp;rsquo;t accept a &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think that&amp;rsquo;s very difficult. There are many reasons why Chinese football doesn’t play well, and one of them is the fear of losing possession – no one wants to pass the ball to someone else, even if it means keeping it themselves. This is just a small reason though. I feel that after reaching my 30s, I wrote about patience and joy, but now at 50, there’s a bit of urgency because time passes so quickly, and many things you expect haven&amp;rsquo;t become reality. However, I also understand that for a country like China, many things are a slow process of change. You see your parents – some were oblivious to traffic lights, but occasionally you see a child pulling their father along. Things are changing, shuffling around, so you need to have patience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>It takes reading many books to find an answer about time</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country is becoming better and stronger. If people could curb their vanity, things would be even better. Looking back from the 1990s to now, the lives of families I&amp;rsquo;ve interacted with have improved significantly. There are also more wealthy individuals. In the development of a market economy, widening income inequality is unavoidable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The issues of social stratification and blocked upward mobility are common problems in today&amp;rsquo;s world. Our party’s contributions to the basic welfare and social security of the people should be recognized. Life will continue to improve; if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to buy a house, you can rent. Educational resource allocation is unequal, sometimes requiring choices. Decide what matters most – better job opportunities/environment or more time with family – and don’t impose your own preferences on others, including your children and family. Sit down and talk it over; life will generally get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-footage&#34;&gt;Video footage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If there is any copyright infringement, please contact me for deletion. This article is only a translated transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve turned 50 this year. I never thought about it before, but now I realize I really am an old guy. This is what I looked like at 30. Didn’t feel particularly young or handsome then, but looking back at 30 now, not bad! What was the biggest life lesson at 30? Looking back. I think it&amp;rsquo;s subtraction – the keyword is subtraction. In a way, experiencing and writing about things while feeling both pain and joy is also a form of subtraction, leaving those experiences behind to start fresh on a new blank page, like running. But for me, doing subtraction—whether for myself or as a reminder to others—was truly important at 30.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently guiding students at Peking University, and I often tell them to focus on building their skills and experiences—the &amp;ldquo;additions&amp;rdquo;—before 30. You don’t know your potential or what opportunities life may offer. It’s not about knowing &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to do something, but rather doing it. Some people work tirelessly on accumulating experiences in their twenties, forgetting the need for “subtraction”—knowing when to let go. I believe around 30 is a crucial time—after building and exploring, you must learn to subtract. Otherwise, it’s too late. Why subtract? Not everything suits you, and not everything &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; suit you. You should try everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eight lines bind you – how far can you run? They may restrain each other&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the time I was 30, I had been promoted exceptionally – in academia, that would be a professor; in journalism, a senior reporter. I received this exceptional promotion at 29. Such things are rare now, but it&amp;rsquo;s when I first felt a profound sense of confusion. When I worked on the Sydney Olympics in 2000 and received much applause, I suddenly felt something was amiss. I started asking myself: what do I really want to do? What needs to be discarded? That year, I made a very important subtraction – I stopped my program for a year, without appearing abroad. Someone advised me that in this industry, if you’re out of sight for just a month, it&amp;rsquo;s manageable; six months and people will forget you. I replied that my face must be pretty cheap.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, we started developing new programs. After a period of challenges and triumphs, I took a full year off in 2001. Everything I&amp;rsquo;m doing today stems from the lessons learned during that time – learning to simplify. I could have pursued many avenues: sports, entertainment (E), producing, etc. But I realized I could only do news, and it was where I should be. I resigned from being the producer of three programs overnight, which led me to who I am today. It brought a sense of clarity. Just recently, talking with colleagues, I mentioned that a crucial decision I made in my late 20s wasn&amp;rsquo;t about having many options; it was about focusing on news – this deep well. There were opportunities for promotion, even to deputy director, but I declined and returned to being an ordinary person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Up until now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been a senior-level cadre at CCTV, and even then, not everyone was an absolute bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree graduate. You understand our system, but I rejected it. I wanted to see how far a bachelor’s degree could go—why can’t a bachelor’s degree continuously learn and lead graduate students? Yes, now I supervise graduate students, 11 every year – all a result of backtracking. It&amp;rsquo;s certainly a reflection on the past. Also, when young, it’s especially easy to feel entitled while constantly striving; any shortcoming or anything missed leaves me deeply uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn to subtract as well. When you&amp;rsquo;re approaching 30, around 28 years old, watching the Olympics in 1996, I came up with a saying… In Zeng Guofan’s lengthy novel, there&amp;rsquo;s an important sentence: what is the best state of life? Zeng Guofan wanted to name his study &amp;ldquo;Hall of Seeking Deficiency.&amp;rdquo; The best time is when flowers aren&amp;rsquo;t fully open, when the moon isn&amp;rsquo;t yet full. But for ordinary people, they see this as a flaw, not perfect enough, not reaching its peak. The best way to ruin someone is to make them pursue perfection and ultimate achievement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The world isn&amp;rsquo;t like that. A flower is at its best when it’s not fully bloomed; once it reaches full bloom, falling petals are near. Similarly, a full moon quickly fades to crescent. That&amp;rsquo;s the important push and revelation for my 30th birthday. It&amp;rsquo;s not about looking good at 40, but I feel more relaxed and free. Why question happiness instead of adhering to suits and black-and-white appearances?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a Chinese saying, &amp;ldquo;forty is the age of confusion.&amp;rdquo; It’s said that thirty is about subtraction, and forty is supposed to be a time of clarity. But I think in this era, most people are confused at forty. My midlife crisis came early—I started questioning the value of everything I&amp;rsquo;ve done around thirty-six or seven.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does it even matter? Have I figured out what happiness is? This book was born from that confusion. You&amp;rsquo;ll find, when you turn 30, that many of your goals for happiness are tied to material possessions; the &amp;ldquo;establishing oneself by 30&amp;rdquo; refers to having education and a stable foundation. You need a car and a house, otherwise your future mother-in-law won’t agree to her daughter marrying you – it&amp;rsquo;s very materialistic. But being wise at 40 is difficult. I think ancient people probably had shorter average life expectancies, so they condensed it into 40 and declared wisdom; I&amp;rsquo;m still confused at 40, &lt;strong&gt;物质没有给我带来，我以为会带给我的幸福&lt;/strong&gt;. And that’s why so many people ask me when they turn 40, are you happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is my book titled &amp;ldquo;Waves of Happiness?&amp;rdquo; It&amp;rsquo;s a question mark, representing the confusion in my heart. The birth of a midlife crisis—around 40, you need to answer many questions for yourself. Around 40, talk to yourself more and read widely to find your own answers. I’m grateful that I entered the world of the Tao Te Ching in my late thirties. As I mentioned in &amp;ldquo;White Talk,&amp;rdquo; when you reach 40 and still need to think things through, if the surrounding environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t change—especially the soft environment—you leave home with a pleasant mood, only to encounter chaotic traffic lights everywhere, and everything you buy is fake, even your vaccinations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been saying that China has been battling two typhoons these past few days – one invisible, and one visible. The invisible typhoon is the vaccine, which impacts our sense of security. The other typhoon, rarely hitting mainland China from Shanghai, is beside the point. What you need to consider is this: you’ve improved yourself, gained many answers, but if the surrounding environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;我有八个字说得比较重，我觉得我们现在是道德赤字人性亏损，这才是目前最大的赤字和最大的亏损&lt;/strong&gt; Just recently, not far from here, I witnessed two cars collide; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t a serious collision. The responsible driver pulled over after hitting another car and explained they would move to the side of the road. But the vehicle in front sped off, and no one stopped him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Will he be a responsible father? A responsible son? Let alone a responsible citizen—and potentially your colleague. This is a moral deficit and a loss of humanity, which will inevitably affect you. No matter how important you are, unless you stay completely isolated at home, the problem is that even staying home won&amp;rsquo;t prevent your children from needing vaccinations; if you deliver food, the food itself might be problematic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, how can a Chinese person learn to transform from an ordinary citizen into a responsible member of society – this is a crucial question for me personally and for our society as a whole, one I&amp;rsquo;ve been grappling with around the age of 40&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 30 is about subtraction, and 40 is confusion, I think the word I&amp;rsquo;d give myself for 50 is curiosity. 50 is awkward – neither here nor there, with options to advance or retreat. You can either build on what you’ve achieved or simply drift towards retirement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I read a book that had an interesting passage: it stated that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley are often in their fifties and sixties—a concept quite different from our own. Just as we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t equate volunteering solely with youth, so too should China move beyond the idea that entrepreneurship is exclusively for young people. Last week, I produced a program about recruiting retired elementary and middle school teachers, who would receive an annual subsidy of two or three million yuan to teach in rural areas—and they must be excellent teachers. This marks a pioneering effort in post-retirement employment, more than just charity. However, reaching 50 still feels distant. How can we move forward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty years old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for people around 50, there are two challenges. The first is yourself: Are you still curious about many things? What is your worldview? I think my greatest gain at 50, or how I am living right now,&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think the best thing to watch today is Tsai Chin&amp;rsquo;s concert DVD. She said something really good: &amp;ldquo;Every time I look at photos, I think my younger self was so beautiful,&amp;rdquo; but back then, twenty years ago, I never thought I looked good. That sentence has a certain flavor. I didn’t feel that way when I was 30; I thought I was quite handsome then, and focused on my flaws. But looking back after 20 years…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was once young too, with so much hair. Treat your today well; seeing you again in two years will be wonderful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as Sishi Tong said, when my legs first lost their ability to walk and I was confined to a wheelchair, I spent every day longing for the days when I could run and play basketball. Every day in that remembrance was incredibly painful.
Years later, I developed pressure sores while in my wheelchair, and was incredibly uncomfortable. I constantly longed for the times from a few years prior when I felt no pain and could sit quietly in my chair.
Years later, I developed kidney failure and now require dialysis. At this point, I miss the time when I only had bedsores, even then. If I don&amp;rsquo;t live to be 100, those first 50 years were for nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not that you need to wait until 50 to understand this – people should realize it in their 30s or 40s. Everything can be easily missed. A meal during a trip, if you don’t eat it, even 30 years later, it won&amp;rsquo;t have the same taste. So my first feeling at 50 is to cherish every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second thing is curiosity. I realize that I can stop being curious about many things at any time, because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen and experienced so much. However, I push myself to be curious. So now, when doing a lot of things, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – can the phone be held vertically for filming? Yes, it can. Can you do live reporting? Can you make seemingly grand summits more relaxed, more fun, and leave a lasting impression? Can you use new media to spread it? All possible. I think curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress. Why can&amp;rsquo;t it be the most important driving force for an individual’s progress? A nation declines when it loses its curiosity. On a larger scale, 50 is a significant test. What kind of vested interest do you become in China at forty or fifty years old? I am very worried that many people around us, hoping to achieve their dreams when they were young, once they realize those dreams and become established figures, turn into people who obstruct others from achieving theirs. Am I right? They then treat young people and things using the very methods they used to dislike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, a few years ago, I started recruiting 11 graduate students each year as a volunteer, mentoring them for two years. We&amp;rsquo;ve now had five graduating classes, totaling 55 students. It feels wonderful to be in this position of influence – you gain insights and the ability to guide them. After each day of teaching, we’d have dinner together, which doesn’t cost much. But that&amp;rsquo;s what a good mentor should do. Being a mentor can take two forms: one is like being a stepping stone. I once said, &amp;ldquo;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to say thank you too much to those who helped me,&amp;rdquo; because my way of saying thank you is to treat the new generation with even greater care and dedication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, it&amp;rsquo;s about paving the way for others. I hope that those who have benefited materially, economically, ideologically, and culturally – all sectors – when you achieve success, consider how you should act. Those who derailed the train yesterday become those blocking it today; history of China is full of such examples, and this will continue if things don&amp;rsquo;t change, perhaps even more so. Therefore, I urge all established beneficiaries to return to the mindset they had when they were young – what kind of people did they want to encounter? Perhaps I haven’t done enough, but at least I am thinking, doing, and speaking about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
