<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Trae on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trae/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Trae on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>No coding, design and develop a self-selected stock module.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/design-develop-custom-stock-module-no-code/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 23:20:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/design-develop-custom-stock-module-no-code/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Last month, we experimented with cursor, but due to the limitations of the free quota, we didn&amp;rsquo;t develop overly complex features; we just did some basic testing. We discovered then that Byte also released similar products, both using the same large models – Claude-3.5 – at their core.
Byte’s product is called Trae, initially launched in the Mac version and finally released its Windows version in February of this year. Big companies are good because you can freely “white嫖” (literally translates to &amp;ldquo;free grab&amp;rdquo;), without having to pay, with unlimited use of Claude-3.5. The performance of this model is quite impressive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, we got stuck on the development of candlestick charts. As I don’t understand React at all, I had to give up. To continue developing, I would need to supplement my knowledge of front-end basics, breaking down the task into smaller, more manageable pieces instead of giving a single large task: developing candlestick charts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;issues-found&#34;&gt;Issues Found
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Due to the lack of sufficient training data using foreign AI models, and Vue3 + Element-Plus, we chose React as the frontend framework.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There may be occasional syntax errors requiring manual fixes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solutions for some complex problems require manual guidance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Code structure optimization requires manual instruction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The most time-consuming part was packaging the frontend code into a container – this was due to my zero experience with &lt;code&gt;.env.production&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;tsconfig.json&lt;/code&gt;, completely lacking understanding of these concepts; I sought help from community members along the way to sort out the logic. There are significant differences between the development (dev) mode and build mode in frontend development, and the checks performed on code. Backend database and service container scripts were completed in a total of five minutes.
&lt;strong&gt;Currently, AI primarily focuses on increasing development efficiency; having a foundation is best, not relying on AI to solve all problems.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;repository-address&#34;&gt;Repository Address
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As the title indicates, this time we&amp;rsquo;re going to chat with AI without actually coding and see what we can achieve.  Let’s take a look at the final outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Repository Address: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/trae-demo&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/ttf248/trae-demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For detailed usage instructions, please refer to the README.md file in the repository.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The repository contains numerous submission records, most of which are conversations between me and Trae, as well as my testing of Trae’s functionalities, with notes on whether manual intervention was used to implement each feature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompt&#34;&gt;Prompt
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The project involves developing functionality from scratch, based on the following prompt:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;Based on the project prototype diagram, develop features including: stock selection (portfolio management), which requires support for adding, deleting, modifying, and querying contracts. The stock selection interface needs to display basic market data. Support multiple different market switches.

Frontend: React
Backend: Golang Gin GORM
Database: PostgreSQL

The backend needs to support cross-domain requests, while also considering data validation and error handling. If the backend service is unavailable, the frontend should display an alert message.

The backend needs to log requests and responses; the frontend also prints communication logs for troubleshooting purposes.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ui-and-interaction-optimization&#34;&gt;UI and Interaction Optimization
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The design of the front-end interface relies entirely on Grok. We initially created a prototype within Trae, but it lacked aesthetics. Because the model used has strong coding capabilities but weaker other abilities, we need to use Grok to optimize the front-end UI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By taking screenshots of the current interface and uploading them to Grok, we can receive numerous optimization suggestions at once. We then manually evaluate these suggestions and copy them into Trae to execute and observe the results of the optimizations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;technology-stack&#34;&gt;Technology Stack
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Frontend: React + TypeScript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Backend: Golang + Gin + GORM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Database: PostgreSQL 17&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;system-architecture&#34;&gt;System Architecture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;backend-architecture&#34;&gt;Backend Architecture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The backend utilizes the Gin framework (Go) to implement RESTful APIs, with the following key modules:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Database Module&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilizes GORM as an ORM framework&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports database connection configuration via environment variables&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Automatically performs database schema migrations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routing Module&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RESTful API design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A unified error handling mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built-in request logging&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-Origin Handling&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports cross-origin requests from local development environments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configurable CORS policies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cookie cross-domain support&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;frontend-architecture&#34;&gt;Frontend Architecture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The frontend was built using React + TypeScript, implementing the following features:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stock list display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Watchlist management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Real-time quote data display&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Error handling mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
