<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Fiscal-Policy on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fiscal-policy/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Fiscal-Policy on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fiscal-policy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is Modern Monetary Theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The U.S. stock market’s sustained bull run is largely driven by dollar liquidity rather than America&amp;rsquo;s inherent “hard power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the 2008 financial crisis, the modern monetary system has gradually become an important theoretical cornerstone for many global economies, primarily emphasizing the subjective agency of large governments in intervening in markets. It utilizes government fiscal deficits as its main tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation. &amp;ndash;more&amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the public is more familiar with regarding large government is &lt;strong&gt;Keynesianism&lt;/strong&gt;, which emphasizes the government’s role in smoothing out cyclical fluctuations – for example, suppressing overheating and stimulating contraction when it’s slowing down. It places a strong emphasis on the multiplier effect of government spending, namely how one unit of monetary stimulus can increase consumer multiplier expansion by a certain amount. When government expenditure 1 opens money, businesses and individuals increase income by 1 unit, businesses expand production and employment, and individuals expand consumption to resist economic contraction. Simultaneously, it is relatively conservative regarding fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. The &lt;strong&gt;multiplier effect&lt;/strong&gt; will drive market recovery, thereby increasing the government’s revenue, especially during the suppression of overheated cycles, which can accumulate funds for stimulating the next cycle, such as the potential debt burden and interest rate levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Modern monetary systems are essentially an extension of extreme Keynesianism, but with key differences. The biggest characteristic is the limitation on government debt. Central banks should not have independent autonomy; their primary objectives should be &lt;strong&gt;inflation and full employment&lt;/strong&gt;. Given that inflation is constrained by limited productive resources and technological advancements – meaning the government continuously increases purchasing power into the market through unlimited fiscal deficits as production efficiency rises with technology, ultimately reaching an ideal point of full employment and a production bottleneck – further monetary expansion would trigger inflation. At this point, they choose to cap fiscal deficits, provided there are still idle productive assets available; increasing deficits will not cause inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the Financial Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, reality is far from an ideal world; execution in each stage involves human participation, and Keynesianism is selectively applied. This leads to more economic stimulus than effective suppression, with economic overheating being used for political gains while suppressing excessive growth is lacking. It’s fundamentally difficult to restrain these issues, resulting in numerous economic problems, and even new financial crises that are no less severe than the economic shocks caused by traditional overcapacity. - The 2008 global financial crisis was, in essence, a market self-reinforcement bubble driven by extreme Keynesianism. It resulted in the proliferation of “odd-shaped” structured financial products – such as real estate and financial investments derived from it – and, crucially, a lack of risk awareness across academia, government, and markets. Debt-fueled prosperity was viewed as an achievement, and many profited from it, including massive financial systems that declared losses were the responsibility of others while announcing profits for themselves. The infamous phrase “you don’t get your money back until it’s gone” ultimately led to widespread investment and the assumption of risk by those who had benefited from earlier stages, culminating in a catastrophic outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis-1&#34;&gt;After the Financial Crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It was after the financial crisis that the shadow of the modern monetary system entered, characterized by rapid &lt;strong&gt;monetization of fiscal deficits and central banks’ unlimited quantitative easing&lt;/strong&gt;, as well as so-called emergency central bank lending policies. The central bank acted as the ultimate lender, supplying an endless supply of bullets, allowing governments to continue incurring debt, and coordinating with fiscal policy. The central bank supported government fiscal deficit spending through purchases of bonds, ensuring consistency of policy objectives. This is also why the boundaries between modern monetary and fiscal policies are becoming increasingly blurred – relying heavily on the central bank’s direct participation in purchasing sovereign debt, a “printing money while buying bonds” approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Eurozone and the United States exhibited similar trends; in 2008, the government debt of the European Union was approximately €6. - 7 trillion euros, with a government leverage ratio of approximately 66%, slightly above the generally recognized warning line of 60%. As of 2014 – that is, during the 5-year period of the bailout – the debt scale reached 9.5 trillion euros, and the leverage rose to 93%. The United States was even more exaggerated; in 2008, U.S. government debt was approximately $10 trillion, which by 2014 had risen to around $18 trillion, and recently it again raised its government debt ceiling. Of course, each drama always used the threat of a government shutdown as a gimmick, but each time it broke through the government debt limit. Currently exceeding $36 trillion, compared to $26 trillion growth since the 2008 financial crisis. Considering the GDP growth factor, the government leverage has grown from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as the ultimate lender, played an important role in multiple rescue operations and is one of the main buyers of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;flaws-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;Flaws and Limitations of the Modern Monetary System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led stimulus scheme, though not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the market’s omniscience and all participants’ selfless dedication at every stage? Let&amp;rsquo;s take a simple example: if a government department increases its budget for a particular direction by 1 million, is it going to go to the mayor’s nephew or a more cost-effective market bidding process? Of course, in reality, interests will form in increasingly complex ways, leading to the result that even though the government expands debt and spending, it flows completely out of control. The recent American establishment of an Office of Efficiency is an extension of this type of problem. These issues manifest differently across varying corrupt economies; we’re focusing on discussing the more prevalent problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-inflation-issues&#34;&gt;1. Inflation Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of the modern information network, governments have a much greater grasp on market information than in the past. However, this isn’t omniscience – markets inherently contain variables and are constantly subject to change based on expectations, entering a recursive loop (“the ouroboros”). I anticipate your predictions. Taking actual performance as an example, despite the relatively successful implementation of Modern Monetary Theory between 2008 and 2020—achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stabilization, with even the Eurozone experiencing phase deflation and US inflation largely remaining within the expected 1-3% range—this led people to believe in increasingly extreme tools, much like they once believed in Keynesianism. Looking back, this was primarily due to the continued high growth trend of manufacturing in developing countries after 2008. For example, China, which gradually established itself as a global production powerhouse during this period, along with other emerging economies like Southeast Asia and India, maintained relatively high levels of industrial value added. This effectively offset the largest constraint within the Modern Monetary Theory – resource supply limitations – allowing both Europe and the United States to sustain comparatively stable inflation even amidst de-industrialization and excessive financialization, alongside increased government debt and a surge in monetary supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-inflation-issues-1&#34;&gt;1. Inflation Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the use of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States experienced relatively significant inflation, peaking at around 10%, even today, despite interest rate hikes lasting nearly three years, the U.S. labor market continues to show an abnormal overheating, and financial markets have seen a divergence from economic growth supported by monetary support, with inflation running towards 3% as the base effect disappears. This overheating phenomenon during interest rate hikes is closely related to fiscal deficits. Interest rate hikes are a contractionary monetary policy, while fiscal policy remains expansionary, compounded by the ultra-massive monetary injection of 2020, which has made U.S. inflation remarkably persistent. The biggest limitation of Modern Monetary Theory is high inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-government-debt-issues&#34;&gt;2. Government Debt Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, governments can indefinitely finance debt repayment through borrowing, provided that the central bank becomes a complete puppet – meaning full alignment of monetary and fiscal policy objectives within a modern monetary system. However, the Federal Reserve is unlikely to fully cede control to the government, given the accumulated government debt balance over many years, particularly interest expenses, which are increasingly becoming a significant burden on finances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2023: In fiscal year 2023, U.S. revenue totaled $4.439 trillion, with interest expense on the debt accounting for approximately 15% of that revenue.  In 2024, this high-interest environment continued, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fiscal Year 2024: The U.S. federal government’s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments totaling $882 billion – approximately 18% of U.S. federal revenue, even exceeding Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-government-debt-issues-1&#34;&gt;2. Government Debt Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the issue of fiscal sustainability. If low interest rates and low inflation, combined with high debt (such as Japan’s), are maintained over the long term, it can indeed form an application of modern monetary theory in this way. According to the 72 rule, as long as interest rates are sufficiently low, incremental debt financing will be very slow. If the cost of capital is 1%, debt-funded growth can reach twice the debt level in 72 years. Assuming inflation breaks this delicate balance, interest payments on debt accumulate, leading to compound interest and causing future debt trajectories to spiral out of control. Principal becomes a secondary factor. If the central bank then deviates from the goals of the ruling party, these issues will become even more acute. “The Trump administration’s policy stances sharply contrasted with the Fed’s hawkish stance at the time, which was also a key factor in the escalation of relations between the government and the Fed during his term. The focus for most observers is likely whether the current chairman can successfully complete his term.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;3-financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;3. Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, the government’s expanded spending enters both households and businesses, leading to increased expenditure and a boost in effective demand. However, given that people are all experienced participants in numerous financial bubbles since 2000, individuals tend to exhibit a significant investment appreciation bias in their choices between investing and consuming, particularly when one or more products with extremely high expected returns appear. People will flock to the financial markets seeking higher gains, even willing to compress living standards and take on additional leverage. This is similar to what occurred during periods of high real estate growth in Japan, the United States, and China. Combining policy stimulus with the pursuit of maximum self-interest by practitioners, issues such as subprime loans are prevalent. Many so-called “rescue” policies actually encourage borrowing. Therefore, history has shown a remarkable consistency: when large-scale monetary and fiscal policies are deployed, it often results in &lt;strong&gt;a frenzy of asset bubbles and wealth redistribution&lt;/strong&gt;. Asset bubbles occur first, followed by wealth redistribution, which leads to another problem – extreme Keynesianism or Modern Monetary Theory’s persistent tendency towards economic Ponzi schemes (Minsky Moment). As long as there is hot money, asset prices continue to rise. As long as they continue to rise, it attracts later entrants holding cash, while the CPI, measuring changes in basic living expenses, doesn&amp;rsquo;t change significantly. Money circulates within specific sectors and becomes worthless for later entrants. &lt;strong&gt;After the frenzy comes the collapse&lt;/strong&gt;, which is Minsky Moment’s relentless vindication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, money itself has a supply and demand relationship. When the market supply is excessive, and traditional investment assets cannot accommodate it, or when it has been harvested too many times and cannot attract investment, such as repeatedly collapsing real estate bubbles (Japanese people haven&amp;rsquo;t dared to touch real estate investments for decades), tax policies that increase property holding taxes to reduce speculative demand, will increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation of excessive monetary supply, the market urgently needs investment assets that are &lt;strong&gt;tax-free&lt;/strong&gt;, and various virtual investment products have emerged. Even U.S. President and First Lady have come in to share a cup, one saying is to dig into the dollar wall, but in fact it&amp;rsquo;s the inevitable result of currency abuse and financial emptiness under global monetary issuance and currency credit damage, challenging the modern monetary theory’s reliance on national monopoly rights-based credit money status, even facing challenges. What kind of soil breeds what kind of financial games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Bubbles and Monetary Credit Issues&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, modern monetary theory and Keynesianism are more like progressive and substitutional relationships, placing a greater emphasis on government intervention in markets and adopting a more radical attitude towards fiscal deficits and the independence of central banks. Excessive use of Keynesianism led to stagflation and financial crises. Following this artificial economic overheating, modern monetary theory quietly took over after 2008. Under globalization, continued productivity gains allowed for rapid growth recovery and maintained inflation levels in using countries, but it also accumulated massive government debt and financial bubbles. When inflation rebounded, with inconsistent goals between central banks and governments, high interest rates and high leverage coexisted, significantly increasing the fiscal burden of government monetization. Fiscal sustainability was drastically reduced, and due to excessive government participation, base monetary injections led to financial bubbles. Unending money printing weakened the currency itself, appearing strong but merely a reflection of others. This also created fertile ground for various new types of speculative financial investment tools, even escaping traditional financial investment tax restrictions. This is a microcosm of the global economy. Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) may not be the future, but rather a past tense used from 2008 onwards, layered with reverse economic globalization. The more financial bubbles were inflated, the higher government debt accumulated, the more frantic the financial speculation tools became, and the greater the efficiency in achieving distorted wealth distribution – the greater the risk of a hard landing, including economic and social risks. Whether Keynesianism or MMT, no matter how much monetary supply is increased, it cannot truly solve the wealth structure problem; instead, it exacerbates risks within asset bubbles and financialization. People are constantly falling into the same pit in different postures repeatedly, but they never learn anything from it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
