<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Psychology on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/psychology/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Psychology on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of games: A convergence of psychological development and social entertainment</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, gaming has evolved beyond a simple form of entertainment and become an integral part of daily life. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of people across various age groups and are closely linked to social interaction and recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental state
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in a stage of exploring themselves and establishing their identity, therefore games can allow them to try on different roles and lives, satisfying curiosity and the desire for exploration. As they age, personal interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, gaming has become a social activity, especially for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, which serve as a bridge for socializing. However, as people age, their social circles stabilize and social needs may be met through more mature means, diminishing the role of gaming in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-a-girl-out&#34;&gt;Taking a girl out
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In China, due to a lack of relationship education, children are pressured to focus solely on academics by their parents, then immediately pushed into relationships upon graduation—a very common phenomenon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lacking stable emotional relationships due to busy schedules, work commitments, or a lack of social skills can lead to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, by helping and protecting female players, they experience a sense of being needed and valued, achieving emotional fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the game&amp;rsquo;s clear interaction rules and controllable environment offer certainty and a sense of security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real life, reducing fears about unpredictable social interactions. However, prolonged reliance on virtual gratification within games may negatively impact their ability to form and maintain healthy emotional relationships in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-pressure&#34;&gt;Reality pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games offer a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of reality. This is particularly true for young people facing academic stress, family issues, or relationship difficulties, for whom games may be a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are often designed to provide players with a sense of accomplishment and recognition for completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they offer a feeling of being appreciated and acknowledged, which they may lack in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-getting-older-they-dont-like-playing-anymore&#34;&gt;After getting older, they don&amp;rsquo;t like playing anymore
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing more time and energy for gaming. As they enter the workforce and start families, increased responsibilities make time and energy more valuable, potentially leading to gaming being seen as a time sink rather than a preferred leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests evolve. What might appeal to someone in their youth—fast-paced, visually impressive games—may later give way to a preference for strategic, story-driven, or more complex experiences. If the market fails to meet these changing needs, interest will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Games</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Pay-to-win games are not discussed here. Within the gaming community, they&amp;rsquo;re commonly called &amp;ldquo;money warriors.&amp;rdquo; It doesn&amp;rsquo;t require understanding game mechanics, just a thick wallet. Their enjoyment comes from being surrounded by sycophants and the thrill of dominance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Popular competitive games like League of Legends, Dota 2, Honor of Kings, and PlayerUnknown&amp;rsquo;s Battlegrounds have established complete world-building and thriving esports ecosystems&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In game design, psychology is a crucial field, and social psychology particularly so. Understanding people&amp;rsquo;s behavior, needs, and motivations can help create more engaging game experiences. Regarding the relationship between &amp;ldquo;showing off&amp;rdquo; (装逼) and social psychology, we can consider it from several perspectives:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People often seek a sense of belonging within social groups. In games, if the design allows players to feel exceptional in some way and attract attention from others, it can enhance their social identity. This may manifest as showing off skills or displaying earned rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some games incorporate social competition elements, encouraging players to showcase their achievements on social networks. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate a competitive spirit among players and may lead some to perform exceptionally well for social recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some games allow players to express themselves through customized characters and virtual items. This self-expression is not just about showing off; it can also be a way to communicate individuality and socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some games emphasize teamwork, achieving game objectives through social interaction. In these contexts, showing off is often discouraged, with a focus on collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Game design can incorporate psychological reward systems to encourage players&amp;rsquo; positive social behavior. For example, offering rewards or privileges to incentivize active participation in social interactions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interactions and social experiences. While &amp;ldquo;showing off&amp;rdquo; behavior may exist in certain situations, game designers typically strive to balance it to ensure a positive and engaging experience for all players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Writing as I think of things, without a complete outline—a bit messy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author frequently plays League of Legends, a game that represents the shared memories of our generation. Most parents disapprove of their children playing, often due to a lack of understanding and experience with this type of game – partly attributable to the game&amp;rsquo;s design, which offers a fresh start each match. For many children, it’s a self-directed exploration without excessive thought. Success or failure in this mode largely depends on the child&amp;rsquo;s innate gaming talent. Based on my own observations, a significant portion of players fall into this category.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost isn&amp;rsquo;t money, it&amp;rsquo;s time&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The game also features an entertainment mode to cater to casual players&amp;rsquo; needs&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For me, League of Legends is more about fulfilling a long-held wish and experiencing the joy of comebacks. There are also many &amp;ldquo;armchair gamers&amp;rdquo; who don&amp;rsquo;t play the game anymore but still watch the World Championship every year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is unavoidable to mention &lt;strong&gt;。指的不是单局游戏的时间，而是你上号的时间，周末的下午、每天工作日的晚上七点到晚上十点之间，你会发现和队友大部分情况都能正常沟通，你发出去的信号，队友能理解，能收到回应。换到其他时间，比如说通宵游戏，你碰到的更多就是&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;，顺风的情况，无事发生，逆风的情况下，他们能问候你的全家，隔着屏幕你都能感受到那股子&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in the IT industry, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed to and played a lot of games across various genres. When it comes to competitive gaming, I’ve always relied on strategy rather than raw reflexes; my natural aptitude is there. Compared to professionals or younger players, my reaction time is slower. My preference is to lead teams—taking control and directing the game. I started playing back in school, when we were guided by the older members of our guild.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The gaming environment now is quite restless, lacking the purity of before&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After advancing to a higher grade, playing high-level matches is truly exhausting. It requires constant intense focus, analyzing your opponent&amp;rsquo;s strategies and figuring out how to counter their traps – it’s the kind of experience where you don’t want to play another game afterward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being truly good at gaming isn&amp;rsquo;t impactful for life’s trajectory unless you pursue it professionally. It can serve as a social tool, but won&amp;rsquo;t provide a livelihood or allow you to establish yourself in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player games and online games are two distinct types of games with significant differences in gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the distinctions between them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This game is played locally on your device and doesn&amp;rsquo;t require an internet connection. Players can enjoy the experience without a network connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;These games typically require an internet connection as players interact with each other in real-time. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online socializing and competition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players primarily interact with in-game AI, preset missions, or adversarial elements. The gaming experience is typically more personalized and influenced by the game&amp;rsquo;s design and narrative.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include cooperating on tasks, competing against or alongside each other, and social elements like chat and guild systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game design emphasizes providing a complete, self-contained narrative and game experience. Game content is typically pre-designed, with players exploring, solving puzzles, or engaging in combat.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Game design must consider real-time interaction and competition or collaboration among players. Game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;4&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It typically runs offline and has relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires a strong internet connection and high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;5&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Typically employs a one-time purchase or download commercial model, allowing players to fully play the game on their local device after purchasing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The game may adopt various commercial models such as free play, advertising, in-app purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these distinctions helps players clarify their preferences when choosing a game, and enables game designers to better meet player expectations&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
