<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Memory Frequency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/memory-frequency/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Memory Frequency on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 21:53:43 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/memory-frequency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Memory timing C36, C30, and C28 – what do these mean? Which one is more suitable at a frequency of 6000MHz?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/memory-timing-c36-c30-and-c28-what-do-these-mean-which-one-is-more-suitable-at-a-frequency-of-6000mhz/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 21:48:19 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/memory-timing-c36-c30-and-c28-what-do-these-mean-which-one-is-more-suitable-at-a-frequency-of-6000mhz/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When assembling or upgrading a computer, we often see memory modules labeled with parameters like “DDR5-6000 CL36” and “DDR5-6000 CL30.” The “6000” represents the memory frequency (MHz), while “CL36” and “CL30” are abbreviations for “CAS Latency,” which is commonly referred to as “timings.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, &lt;strong&gt;what’s the difference between C36, C30, and C28? How do they affect performance when frequencies are the same? And how should you choose?&lt;/strong&gt; Let&amp;rsquo;s discuss this topic in detail today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previously written content about memory frequency: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/computer-assembly/&#34; &gt;电脑组装那些事&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-cas-latency-cl&#34;&gt;What is CAS Latency (CL)?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &lt;strong&gt;CAS Latency (CL)&lt;/strong&gt; refers to the number of clock cycles a memory needs to wait between receiving a read command and actually starting to output data. The smaller this value, the faster the memory responds and the lower the latency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDR5-6000 CL36: This indicates that the memory needs to wait 36 clock cycles to respond to a read request at a frequency of 6000MHz.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DDR5-6000 CL30: At the same frequency, only 30 cycles are needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the frequencies are the same, a lower CL value results in smaller actual latency (Latency).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-calculate-actual-latency&#34;&gt;How to Calculate Actual Latency?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many people mistakenly believe that a higher frequency always equates to better performance, but in reality, &lt;strong&gt;actual latency = (CL ÷ Frequency) × 2000&lt;/strong&gt; (units: nanoseconds, ns). Let’s compare:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| DDR5-6000 CL36 | 6000 | 36 | ((36 ÷ 6000) × 2000) ≈ &lt;strong&gt;12.0 ns&lt;/strong&gt; |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-calculate-actual-latency-1&#34;&gt;How to Calculate Actual Latency?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Frequency (MHz)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;CL Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actual Latency (ns)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR5-6000 CL30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;30&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;((30 / 6000) * 2000) ≈ &lt;strong&gt;10.0 ns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-calculate-actual-latency-2&#34;&gt;How to Calculate Actual Latency?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Model&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Frequency (MHz)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;CL Value&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Actual Latency (ns)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;DDR5-6000 CL28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6000&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;28&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;((28 ÷ 6000) × 2000) ≈ &lt;strong&gt;9.33 ns&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-is-actual-latency-calculated&#34;&gt;How is Actual Latency Calculated?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the actual latency of CL28 is approximately 22% lower than that of CL36. In latency-sensitive applications (such as gaming, high-frequency trading, real-time rendering, etc.), this difference may result in a perceptible performance improvement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;is-there-really-a-big-performance-difference&#34;&gt;Is There Really a Big Performance Difference?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In everyday scenarios like office work, web browsing, and video playback, the difference between CL36 and CL28 is almost imperceptible. However, the advantages of low-latency memory become more apparent in the following situations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Frame Time Stability:&lt;/strong&gt; Lower latency helps reduce stuttering, especially in CPU-bound games (such as &lt;em&gt;CS2&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;Nioh&lt;/em&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Content Creation &amp;amp; Compilation:&lt;/strong&gt; Certain workflows that rely on memory bandwidth and latency (like large code compilation, 3D rendering caching) will also benefit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Overclocking Potential:&lt;/strong&gt; Low-latency memory typically uses better dies (such as Hynix A-die, M-die), which are more suitable for further overclocking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it’s important to note that &lt;strong&gt;low latency often means a higher price and stricter requirements for motherboard/BIOS compatibility.&lt;/strong&gt; If your motherboard doesn&amp;rsquo;t support EXPO/XMP 2.0 or your BIOS is older, you may not be able to stably run CL28 at high frequencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-which-one-should-i-choose-at-6000mhz&#34;&gt;So, which one should I choose at 6000MHz?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For most users, especially those pairing it with &lt;strong&gt;AMD Ryzen 7000/8000 Series processors&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;DDR5-6000 CL30 is currently the “sweet spot” configuration&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The official JEDEC specification recommends a frequency of 6000MHz, and CL30 is the stable timing verified by AMD;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It offers high value for money, with moderate pricing and good compatibility;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actual latency is controlled around 10ns, balancing performance and stability.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re an &lt;strong&gt;extreme performance gamer&lt;/strong&gt; or seeking ultra-high frame rates, and your motherboard supports it well (such as high-end B650/X670 models), you can consider models with &lt;strong&gt;CL28 or even CL26&lt;/strong&gt;, but be prepared to potentially need manual tuning and voltage adjustments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for &lt;strong&gt;CL36&lt;/strong&gt;, while it can be used, it’s typically entry-level DDR5 memory with high latency, &lt;strong&gt;unless your budget is extremely tight, we don&amp;rsquo;t recommend it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C36, C30, and C28 refer to the memory’s CAS Latency (Timings)&lt;/strong&gt;; lower numbers indicate smaller latency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Under the same frequency, CL28 is approximately 22% faster than CL36 in actual latency, offering greater performance advantages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DDR5-6000 CL30 is currently the most balanced choice&lt;/strong&gt; and suitable for most users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For extreme performance, choose CL28; if budget is limited, accept CL36, but weigh latency against price.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
