<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>TikTok on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/tiktok/</link>
        <description>Recent content in TikTok on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/tiktok/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Increased scrutiny of third-party investment advisors; reckoning for those behind TikTok stock trading</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sledgehammer is falling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage services, boosted by short videos, are likely entering a fast track&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late September of this year, after a period of strong performance in the A-share market, Douyin stock recommendations received attention from various parties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several financial news anchors, including &amp;ldquo;Da Lan,&amp;rdquo; have gained popularity on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of popular financial news anchors also shouldn&amp;rsquo;t overlook the power behind them – third-party wealth management firms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using traffic allocation to attract users to watch investment education videos and boost their enthusiasm for purchasing related investment advisory products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumors also suggest that a certain third-party investment advisory firm earned 1 billion yuan in revenue this October alone, exceeding its income for the entire first half of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &amp;ldquo;good times&amp;rdquo; are facing more uncertainties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since November, various departments have issued documents requiring securities service institutions to strengthen compliance management of their social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 15th, Tonghua Shun (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission due to live streaming activities involving implied stock recommendations and other behaviors
This could be signaling that regulators are tightening their oversight of the market
The promotion of services by third-party investment advisory firms, including Nine Square Wisdom Investment (9636.HK), may also face increased pressure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;strictly-monitored-and-watched-closely&#34;&gt;Strictly monitored and watched closely
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin has amplified emotional voices and indirectly influenced trading behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from Jiali Digital, during the period of September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volume reached a new high, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, more than doubling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the actions of third-party investment advisory firms that are &amp;ldquo;adding fuel to the fire&amp;rdquo; are attracting the attention of regulatory authorities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage employees recommending individual stocks through live streams is a frequent violation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend the acceptance of new clients from a certain company due to instances such as &amp;ldquo;implying stock recommendations&amp;rdquo; in their live broadcasts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 14th, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued a document titled &amp;ldquo;Inadequate Live Stream Control, Institutions to be Suspended,&amp;rdquo; directly pointing out that some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate control during live stream promotional activities and engaged in recommending individual stocks during broadcasts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live stock recommendations are prohibited. Live streaming falls under public media dissemination, and live streamers, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, are not permitted to recommend individual stocks during broadcasts. This was stated by the Guangdong Securities Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau’s penalty notice also included a case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, an investment consultant at the Shanghai branch of Haisun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd., published misleading video content through WeChat Video Number, which violated professional conduct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau took supervisory management measures of issuing a warning letter to Wang Yong regarding this matter&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to information obtained by Feng (ID: TradeWind01), some investment advisor firms that do not meet the qualifications have been recommending stocks on Douyin through brokerage affiliations and have now been suspended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people in the industry are doing live streams on Douyin, but they’re actually affiliated with brokerages, which gives them investment consultant qualifications. Then they use online live streams to attract customers and sell investment consultant combination products offline.” A wealth manager from South China told Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01), “But later, because they were recommending stocks during the live stream, it was discovered, so they were suspended. Reputable brokerages generally have educational live streams that discuss sector conditions but don’t involve individual stocks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are paying close attention to illegal stock recommendations on social media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that individual institutions or individuals within the industry have been found to be engaging in illegal stock recommendations and other violations through self-media. To further regulate the operation and management of securities investment consulting agencies&amp;rsquo; self-media within its jurisdiction, each agency should strengthen the management of their own self-media operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may bring more challenges to the promotion of various third-party wealth management service providers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;traffic-businesses-are-illegal&#34;&gt;Traffic businesses are illegal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether investors lured into the market by short videos have made money remains to be seen, but as &amp;ldquo;water sellers,&amp;rdquo; third-party investment advisory firms have already seen their value rise in the secondary market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leading player in online investment education, Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s market capitalization has surged from 287.8 million yuan in early September to 1.2464 billion yuan at the close of trading on November 13th, representing an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report shows that in the first half of this year, Jiufang Zhi Tou conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, reaching 488 accounts and 0.46 billion followers by the end of June this year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as the chief investment consultant of Jiufang Zhito, &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; has 2.26 million followers on Douyin&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are deeply engaged in MCN operations, focusing on users and collaboratively driving the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products. Jiufang Zhi投 (Jiufang Investment) pointed out that &amp;ldquo;By deeply integrating new media tools such as live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we can effectively achieve efficient conversion of traffic.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiufang Zhitou&amp;rsquo;s consultant courses cover a range of prices from several thousand yuan to over 130,000 yuan. The most expensive package, Super Investor, is priced at 139,600 yuan/six months and includes exclusive insights and private consultant services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JIAF’s investment consultant products have a refund rate of over 10%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for Jiu Fang Zhi Tou&amp;rsquo;s flagship series and Jiu Fang Zhi Tou’s Qinlong series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Jiufang Zhitu’s business development will be affected remains to be seen amid regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent media reports indicate that accounts under third-party investment advisory firms such as Jiufang Zhi Tou have been affected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, media reported that &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rdquo; had been suspended from streaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th in the afternoon, Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) searched for the account and found that the livestream appointment for November 18th was still available on the &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rdquo; livestreaming interface&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market news also indicates that relevant authorities have inspected Jufang Intelligence Investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But individuals close to Nine Square Intelligence have told TradeWind (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection is a routine check and has concluded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company rumored to be caught up in this round of regulatory storm recently&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports indicate that Tonghua Shun is being investigated for allegedly illegally recommending stocks, and business operations may be suspended
In response, Tonghuashun stated on November 15th that &amp;ldquo;there is no illegal stock recommendation situation and there has been no investigation.&amp;rdquo;
However, that same evening, Tonghua Shun announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tonghuashun Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau with a suspension of acquiring new customers for three months and other penalties due to inadequate compliance management during the promotion of its live streaming business and instances of implying stock recommendations
Behind this, it may also mean that regulatory authorities&amp;rsquo; attention on promotional stock content on social media platforms like Douyin Live is being further upgraded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the short video market is also attracting many brokerages, but they are currently still cautious due to regulatory requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person from a securities firm told Xin Feng (ID: TradeWind01) that the company is exploring short video operations and methods for attracting traffic, and has also organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning. However, due to compliance requirements, it is still in the exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the various compliance requirements of regulation stem from the evident emotional coloring of content on short video platforms, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality; the two are inherently in conflict&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If emotions influence the capital market, it can easily lead to sharp market fluctuations, which is contrary to the long-term healthy development of the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How securities firms should embrace the arrival of the short video era while avoiding regulatory breaches is a difficult question for all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right, you are a person and an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your sense of calm. We don’t discuss those great individuals who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;me-now&#34;&gt;Me now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average wages, or even considering salaries back home, my current income is already far above average – what more could I possibly be unsatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning a million; when you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning ten million. This is human nature, and people must confront their own inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that red-eyed thing, is it a more relaxed way of making money: short videos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see here is a short video, but what you don’t see is the scriptwriting and filming behind it. But everyone has a dream of being a genius, believing they are suited for that industry, that they are naturally gifted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-to-contact&#34;&gt;Begin to contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so many videos. If you analyze the shots a little bit with your own brain, it’s obvious they have professional editing techniques and a very strong cinematic feel. Basically, that means some of them are from film school backgrounds. Of course, there’s logic behind grassroots success stories, but that doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, there are also many videos teaching you how to make videos. It&amp;rsquo;s then that people realize things – if it were truly profitable, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithm&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithm
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, when Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm recommended movie clips and anime clips, I would keep watching them and find them quite interesting. But then, when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began recommending all sorts of tutorial videos non-stop, filling my entire recommendation feed. And I’m in the IT industry myself. At this point, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if those guys who designed the algorithm had a problem with their heads – are you suggesting that I&amp;rsquo;m stupid or that they&amp;rsquo;re stupid? The key thing is, it keeps finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money using Douyin, trying different angles and types. This article is being written by me at 3 AM, and I didn’t even want to write it. I just wonder how long this business model can last, and for how long can it consume everyone&amp;rsquo;s time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s laughable when you lecture others on how to do things, but can’t control yourself when it comes to your own actions. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically. Here, I just casually rant. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least now, in terms of real-time news dissemination and promotion of national policies, they are actively cooperating. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to when I was studying, it strikes me. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology here. If you can see this line, you’ll notice that the entire draft is very conversational. And honestly, I just kept reading it until it was finished. I used to use Sogou Input Method, for about seven or eight years. But when it comes to voice input, I have to say that iFlytek is still the professional choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? Having a dream that the number of articles this year can exceed one hundred – that’s a dream for me. It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles, just some records. I examine myself three times a day; you’ll surely think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
