<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Politics on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/politics/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Politics on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Analysis of Political Elements in 2025 Spring Festival Film Releases</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:49:42 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/political-elements-in-chinese-new-year-films-2025/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I went to the Spring Festival movie release to join in the crowds, and this time I watched two films that felt quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article explores the new changes in the 2025 Spring Festival movie releases, focusing on &lt;em&gt;Dwelling in the Fuchun Pavilion&lt;/em&gt; (Tangrenjie Tanjian 1900) and &lt;em&gt;Nezha: The Devil&amp;rsquo;s Child&lt;/em&gt;. The former utilizes the backdrop of San Francisco’s Chinatown in 1900 to depict the discrimination and oppression faced by Chinese people, reflecting social and political conditions. As an animated film, the latter employs rich metaphorical elements to subtly critique the current international political landscape – such as the Jade Palace resembling the Pentagon mirroring the American political system, the dollar symbol on the Heavenly Mandate Throne symbolizing U.S. dollar hegemony, the jade amulet similar to American green cards representing status levels, and the Soul-Devouring Elixir like a biochemical weapon reflecting malicious actions. Both films offer a new viewing experience and prompt reflection on the relationship between cinematic art and political expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;innovation-in-the-style-of-chinese-new-year-film-releases&#34;&gt;Innovation in the Style of Chinese New Year Film Releases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, films released during the Spring Festival often featured lighthearted entertainment and family-friendly themes, aiming to allow audiences to relax and unwind during the holiday season, rarely addressing sensitive political topics. However, in 2025, the Spring Festival release broke with convention; &lt;em&gt;The Mystery Down South 1900&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Nezha: Part One&lt;/em&gt; incorporated rich political elements, sparking widespread discussion among viewers and bringing a new atmosphere to the Spring Festival film slate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shanghai-noon-1900-a-vivid-depiction-of-era-politics&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shanghai Noon 1900&amp;rdquo;: A Vivid Depiction of Era Politics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Shanghai Noon 1900&amp;rdquo; is set in San Francisco&amp;rsquo;s Chinatown in 1900, a time when Chinese immigrants faced severe racial discrimination and oppression overseas. The protagonists not only have to solve the mystery of the case but also confront discrimination and unfair treatment from all sides of society. The film’s portrayal of racism and power struggles accurately reflects the social and political environment of that tumultuous era, allowing us to see the difficult struggle of Chinese immigrants for survival and dignity, and the underlying political issues worth deep consideration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such historical context inevitably reminds us of the challenges currently faced by overseas Chinese in the business sector, such as the TikTok and Zhou Zaikang incident. As of December 6, 2024, the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia in Washington, D.C., rejected TikTok’s request, ruling that the congressional law passed under national security grounds requiring a forced sale stood up to constitutional scrutiny. TikTok CEO Zhou Shouheng wrote in a memo to employees that the next step would be “seeking an injunction and awaiting review by the U.S. Supreme Court.” The issue stems from the U.S.’s “Protecting Americans from Foreign Adversary Control of Critical Technology” Act, which mandates that ByteDance must divest its TikTok business within 270 days after passage of the law, with a final deadline of January 19, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-cop-next-door-1900-a-vivid-depiction-of-political-times&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Cop Next Door 1900&amp;rdquo;: A Vivid Depiction of Political Times
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to various hearings, Zhou Haosheng also faced numerous difficulties. On January 31, 2024, the U.S. Senate Judiciary Committee held a hearing on “Big Tech and the Crisis of Online Child Sexual Exploitation,” featuring well-known anti-China lawmaker Tom Cotton. Facing Zhou Haosheng, Cotton fired off eight questions regarding his nationality, including asking if he was Chinese, whether he had applied for Chinese or American citizenship, and even probing into the nationalities of his wife and children. Despite the hearing’s theme being “Online Child Sexual Exploitation,” the legislator shifted the focus to the fact that TikTok, owned by ByteDance (a Chinese company), is a Chinese-owned operation, forcing Zhou Haosheng to answer irrelevant questions. “Just as in &lt;em&gt;The Mystery of Chinatown 1900&lt;/em&gt;, Chinese people abroad faced unwarranted discrimination, Zhou Shengyi also encountered unfair treatment and scrutiny in the business sector due to his background with TikTok. This series of events reflects how overseas Chinese have consistently faced formidable obstacles when pursuing their own development and safeguarding their rights across different eras – whether it’s racial prejudice a century ago or today&amp;rsquo;s political manipulation in commerce – warrants deep reflection.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-deer-and-the-phoenix-born-to-be-wild-political-metaphor-behind-the-myth-unveiled&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Deer and the Phoenix: Born to Be Wild&amp;rdquo;: Political Metaphor Behind the Myth Unveiled
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Deer and the Phoenix: Born to Be Wild&amp;rdquo; appears to be a typical animated film, but many of its settings and plots are laden with political metaphors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mapping of Power Systems&lt;/strong&gt;: The Yuhuang Palace is shaped like the center of supreme power in the celestial realm, with architectural styles similar to the U.S. Pentagon, primarily using white tones symbolizing Western hegemony disguised under the banner of “universal values.” The &amp;ldquo;Monster Hunting Team&amp;rdquo; led by Wuliang Xianzun, with its subordinates Lu Ban and He Feifei, are believed to correspond to the US alliance system of Japan and Korea. The Yuhuang Palace’s “online meeting” scene, where twelve golden immortals gather to discuss the “Battle of Sovereigns,” is like the NATO meetings dominated by the United States, suppressing other countries under the guise of &amp;ldquo;maintaining order.&amp;rdquo; - &lt;strong&gt;Subtext of Economic Hegemony&lt;/strong&gt;: The Yu Huh Palace’s celestial tripod used for alchemy, with dollar signs at the entrance, symbolizes America “refining” other nations&amp;rsquo; resources through economic hegemony.  The Great Immortals Wu Ling Wen used the guise of “upholding heaven and earth” to cast the dragons into the cauldron for refinement, much like some countries exploit “international rules” for their own benefit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Metaphor of Identity and Hierarchy&lt;/strong&gt;: The fairy identity amulet obtained by Nezha, with its color and pattern design resembling an American green card, symbolizes the immortals’ rejection and hierarchical division of “foreign races,” hinting at the differences in identity and unequal treatment between different countries and groups in reality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hidden Allusions to Malicious Actions&lt;/strong&gt;: Great Immortals Wu Ling Wen forced Nezha to take the Soul-Destroying Pill, which resembled a bioweapon, darkly implying that some nations use the guise of “saving the world” to carry out destructive and ruinous actions against other countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-deer-and-the-phoenix-born-to-be-wild-a-political-allegory-hidden-behind-mythology--an-analysis&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The Deer and the Phoenix: Born to Be Wild&amp;rdquo;: A Political Allegory Hidden Behind Mythology – An Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbol of Resources and Development:&lt;/strong&gt; The Seven Colored Lotus, as a key to reshaping Niuwa and Ao Bing’s bodies, symbolizes monopolized energy and technological lifelines dominated by major powers. Its “瓊漿玉液” (琼浆玉液 - Jīngjiāng Yùyuè – literally &amp;ldquo;jade elixir and pearl liquid&amp;rdquo;) requires obtaining through the Yu Huang Palace&amp;rsquo;s “成仙考試” (chéngxiān kǎoshì – “Celestial Transformation Examination”), reflecting developing countries’ reliance on core resources and suffering from “rule-based plunder” within a hegemonic system. The Lotus’ temporary failure and restoration conditions metaphorically represent the survival dilemmas of small nations in an era of energy crises.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;deep-reflections-on-cinematic-art-and-political-expression&#34;&gt;Deep Reflections on Cinematic Art and Political Expression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;These two films, amidst the nationwide viewing craze during the Spring Festival, incorporated political elements, offering audiences a new cinematic experience – one that moved beyond simple entertainment and served as a mirror reflecting political issues within history and reality. This has prompted us to delve into the relationship between cinematic art and political expression. Will directors in future film creations increasingly convey their perspectives on social and political matters through cinema? As a powerful cultural transmission medium, can film simultaneously engage in artistic expression while also taking greater responsibility for observing and contemplating societal realities? These questions are worth exploring as we appreciate films, and we look forward to the film industry bringing more exciting integration of art and real-world expression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter Egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Boabab large model, wasn&amp;rsquo;t performing very well today, froze several times, the article stopped halfway and couldn’t continue, so I had to restart the conversation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The two major political parties in the United States – the Democratic Party and the Republican Party.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-two-major-parties-democrats-republicans/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 23:40:04 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-two-major-parties-democrats-republicans/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Democratic Party and the Republican Party exhibit significant differences in political ideology, policy proposals, and social values.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;political-ideologies-and-policy-positions&#34;&gt;Political Ideologies and Policy Positions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Democratic Party&lt;/strong&gt;: Leans towards liberal/left-wing, advocating for the government to play an active role in economic and social affairs, supporting social welfare, environmental protection, and multiculturalism. In tax policy, the Democratic Party supports tax cuts for low- and middle-income individuals while raising rates for high earners and corporations. On social issues, the Democratic Party supports abortion rights, same-sex marriage, and advocates for strict gun control. In foreign policy, the Democratic Party emphasizes multilateralism and diplomatic means, preferring to address global problems through international cooperation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Republican Party&lt;/strong&gt;: Leans towards conservative, advocating for limited government intervention, emphasizing individual liberty and a free market economy. In tax policy, the Republican Party supports tax cuts, believing they should benefit everyone regardless of income level. On social issues, the Republican Party opposes abortion and same-sex marriage, supports the right to bear arms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-significance-of-trumps-ascendancy&#34;&gt;The Significance of Trump&amp;rsquo;s Ascendancy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Donald Trump was re-elected as President of the United States in 2024, marking a reaffirmation of the Republican Party’s dominance within American politics. Trump’s policy stances included:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Trump advocated for stimulating economic growth through tax cuts and deregulation, particularly supporting the development of traditional manufacturing and energy industries. He also leaned towards protectionist trade policies, renegotiating or withdrawing from existing trade agreements to protect America&amp;rsquo;s economic interests.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immigration Policy:&lt;/strong&gt; Trump planned to strengthen border security, restrict illegal immigration, and implement stricter scrutiny and limitations on legal immigrants. He also supported limiting refugees and asylum seekers to maintain national security. - &lt;strong&gt;Foreign Policy&lt;/strong&gt;: Trump favored a unilateral approach, emphasizing “America First,” reducing reliance on international organizations, reevaluating relationships with allies, and employing tougher diplomatic measures when necessary. He also planned to expand fossil fuel production and usage and loosen restrictions on environmental protection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trump’s potential second term could lead to significant adjustments in U.S. domestic policy and have profound impacts on global politics and economics. His policies were likely to draw attention and reaction from the international community, particularly in areas such as trade, environment, and human rights.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
