<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial-Crisis on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/financial-crisis/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial-Crisis on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/financial-crisis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Is Modern Monetary Theory the future of global economies?</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:16:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/modern-monetary-theory-future-global-economy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The US stock market&amp;rsquo;s ongoing bull run, aside from America’s inherent strength, is largely due to excessive liquidity in the dollar&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system, following the [period indicated by BOLD_0], has gradually become a key theoretical underpinning for many economies worldwide. Its main characteristic is an emphasis on the active role of government intervention in markets, utilizing government fiscal deficits as a primary tool to achieve full employment while stabilizing inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keynesian economics. It emphasizes the government&amp;rsquo;s role in cyclical fluctuations, such as suppressing during overheating and stimulating during contractions, with a strong focus on the multiplier effect of government spending – how much consumption is stimulated by each dollar spent. Government spending of one dollar increases income for businesses and individuals by one dollar, leading to expanded production, job creation, and increased consumer spending to counteract economic contraction. It also maintains relatively conservative fiscal deficit limits and sustainability. Economic recovery will boost government revenue, particularly in suppressing overheating cycles, allowing the accumulation of stimulus resources for future periods, such as government debt potential and interest rate levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The modern monetary system is an extension of extreme Keynesianism, but with a key difference: the limitation on government debt. Central banks should not be independent; their primary goal is to address resource and productivity-constrained inflation—that is, increasing purchasing power in the market through unlimited fiscal deficits as technological advancements boost production efficiency until full employment and production bottlenecks are reached. Further increases in money supply will then lead to inflation, at which point controlling the upper limit of the fiscal deficit becomes necessary. As long as there is idle productive capacity, increased deficits will not cause inflation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-the-financial-crisis&#34;&gt;After the financial crisis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Reality is not an ideal world. The selective application of Keynesianism, with its emphasis on stimulating economic downturns while inadequately curbing overheating, often leads to political gains. This creates a cycle where poor economic performance and overheating are both seen as achievements, making it difficult to implement corrective measures. Consequently, numerous economic problems arise, potentially leading to financial crises not unlike those caused by traditional overcapacity. The 2008 global financial crisis was essentially the result of market self-reinforcement under extreme Keynesian policies, creating a proliferation of shadow banking products—such as real estate and derivatives based on real estate assets. Even before the crisis, there was insufficient risk awareness across academia, government, and the markets, with debt-fueled prosperity being mistaken for achievement and benefiting many, particularly the financial system: they profited from losses while distributing dividends, ultimately leaving participants to bear the gains of previous stages—and often facing bankruptcy—with no possibility of returning funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The shadow of the modern monetary system emerges after the financial crisis, characterized by rapid expansion and so-called emergency lending policies. The central bank acts as a lender of last resort, providing unlimited liquidity, while governments can continuously accumulate debt. Coordinated policy between the central bank and fiscal authorities sees the central bank supporting government deficits through bond purchases, ensuring policy consistency. This blurring of lines between monetary and fiscal policy relies heavily on direct central bank participation in purchasing government bonds – printing money with one hand and spending it with the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both the Eurozone and the United States exhibit similar trends. In 2008, EU government debt was approximately €6.7 trillion, with a leverage ratio of around 66%, slightly above the generally accepted warning line of 60%. By 2014, during the 5-year bailout period, debt reached €9.5 trillion and leverage rose to 93%. The US is even more extreme; in 2008, US government debt was around $10 trillion, reaching approximately $18 trillion by 2014. Recently, the debt ceiling was again raised, typically accompanied by threats of government shutdowns, but each time exceeding the limit. Debt currently surpasses $36 trillion, a $26 trillion increase compared to 2008. Considering GDP growth, government leverage has risen from 60% to over 120%. The Federal Reserve, as lender of last resort, played a crucial role in multiple bailouts and is also a major purchaser of government debt.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;drawbacks-and-limitations-of-the-modern-monetary-system&#34;&gt;Drawbacks and Limitations of the Modern Monetary System
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This government-led economic stimulus plan, though not a planned economy, faces consistent problems. How can you guarantee the omniscience of the market and the selfless dedication of all participants? Take a simple example: if a government department increases its budget by one million, will it go to a leader&amp;rsquo;s nephew or to the more cost-effective bidding process? In reality, interests are channeled in more complex ways, resulting in uncontrollable spending despite the government expanding debt and expenditures. The recent controversy surrounding the establishment of a US government efficiency agency is an extension of this issue. These issues vary in their manifestation across different economies with corruption indices, but we&amp;rsquo;re primarily discussing the underlying universal problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;inflationary-issues&#34;&gt;Inflationary issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the development of modern information networks, governments now possess far greater access to market information than in the past. However, this doesn&amp;rsquo;t equate to omniscience; the market is inherently variable and constantly shifts due to expectations, creating a self-reinforcing structure. I anticipated your anticipation. Consider the actual performance: while Modern Monetary Theory showed promise between 2008 and 2020, achieving short-term economic recovery and inflation stability (even leading to deflation in the Eurozone and keeping US inflation within the expected 1-3% range), it fostered a belief akin to past faith in Keynesianism—a trust in an increasingly extreme tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, the primary reason is that manufacturing in developing countries continued to show high growth after 2008. Countries like China, which solidified its global production position during this period, and emerging economies in Southeast Asia and India, maintained substantial manufacturing value-added, effectively offsetting the limitations of Modern Monetary Theory – specifically resource constraints – and enabling relatively stable inflation even as Western nations faced deindustrialization, financial excess, rising government debt, and increased money supply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after 2020, with the implementation of larger-scale stimulus policies, both the Eurozone and the United States experienced significant inflation, peaking around 10%. Even today, nearly three years into interest rate hikes, the U.S. labor market continues to show excessive heat, and financial markets have seen an unsustainable boom decoupled from economic growth. As base effects fade, U.S. inflation is heading towards 3% again. This overheating during a period of rising rates is closely linked to fiscal deficits. Rate hikes represent monetary policy contraction while fiscal policy remains expansive; the massive money supply in 2020 has made U.S. inflation stubbornly persistent. High inflation is the primary limitation of Modern Monetary Theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;government-debt-issue&#34;&gt;Government debt issue
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In principle, the government can theoretically use debt to repay debt without limits, but this requires a central bank&amp;rsquo;s willingness, that is, a lender of last resort within the modern monetary system. The Federal Reserve clearly isn’t prepared to grant the government such complete freedom; combined with decades of accumulated government debt balances, particularly interest expenses, high interest rates and increasing debt have gradually become a massive fiscal burden.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For fiscal year 2023: U.S. federal revenue was $4.439 trillion, with interest payments on debt accounting for roughly 15% of that revenue. This high-interest trend continued in 2024, according to data released by the U.S. Treasury Department.
For fiscal year 2024, the U.S. federal government&amp;rsquo;s budget deficit reached $1.833 trillion, with net interest payments on debt totaling $882 billion – approximately 18% of U.S. federal revenue, exceeding Social Security expenditures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the sustainability issue of fiscal policy. If low interest rates and low inflation are maintained for a long time, along with high debt (like Japan), it can indeed create an application of modern monetary theory over the long term. According to the Rule of 72, as long as interest rates are sufficiently low, incremental borrowing under a debt-funded system is very slow. With a 1% cost of funds, pure debt financing can double the debt in 72 years. If inflation disrupts this delicate balance, the accumulation of interest payments on the debt through compounding can lead to an uncontrollable trajectory for future debt; the principal becomes secondary. These issues will become even more acute if the central bank&amp;rsquo;s actions are inconsistent with the ruling party’s goals. The political agenda of the Trump administration sharply contrasted with the current hawkish stance of the Federal Reserve, which is a major source of tension in the relationship between the US government and the Fed during this term. What people are most concerned about is whether the current chairman can successfully reach the end of his term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;financial-bubbles-and-monetary-credit-issues&#34;&gt;Financial bubbles and monetary credit issues
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ideally, government spending increases would flow to households and businesses, prompting broader investment and consumption that boosts effective demand. However, having experienced numerous financial bubbles since 2000, people now exhibit a strong preference for investment over consumption, especially when high-growth products emerge. They flock to financial markets seeking appreciation, even at the expense of quality of life and increased leverage—a pattern seen in periods of rapid growth for real estate in Japan, the US, and China. Combined with policy stimulus and practitioners pursuing their own interests, this often leads to subprime lending issues and many so-called &amp;ldquo;rescue&amp;rdquo; policies that essentially encourage debt accumulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;History consistently shows that when monetary and fiscal policies are aggressively implemented, a bubble forms first, followed by wealth redistribution. This leads to the economic Ponzi scheme problem (Minsky moment) inherent in extreme Keynesianism or prolonged Modern Monetary Theory – as long as there&amp;rsquo;s hot money, asset prices continue to rise, attracting new investors; meanwhile, CPI measuring basic living expenses changes little, and capital stagnates in specific sectors. Eventually, newcomers find themselves unable to sustain the flow, leading to a Minsky moment judgment that invariably proves accurate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, currency itself is subject to supply and demand. When market supply exceeds the capacity of traditional investment assets, or when excessive harvesting fails to attract capital—such as repeated collapses in real estate bubbles (something Japanese have avoided for decades)—and tax policies suppress speculation, including increasing taxes on property ownership to reduce speculative demand, these measures increase the cost of financial speculation. In a situation where currency supply is excessive, the market urgently needs &lt;strong&gt;new investment assets&lt;/strong&gt;, leading to the emergence of various virtual investments—even attracting involvement from the U.S. President and First Lady. Some say it&amp;rsquo;s poaching dollars, but in reality, it’s likely an inevitable consequence of global monetary over-issuance and financial churning undermining fiat currency credibility. Even the credit-based status of modern money theory, reliant on state monopoly rights, may be challenged—the type of environment breeds what kind of financial games.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, Modern Monetary Theory (MMT) and Keynesianism share a progressive and substitutional relationship. MMT places greater emphasis on government intervention in the market and adopts a more radical stance towards fiscal deficits and central bank independence. While Keynesian policies led to stagflation and financial crises, MMT quietly took over after 2008, benefiting from continued productivity gains during globalization. It achieved rapid growth and maintained inflation levels in the short term but accumulated substantial government debt and financial bubbles. With rising inflation and conflicting goals between central banks and governments, high interest rates and leverage exacerbated the fiscal burden of servicing debt, significantly weakening fiscal sustainability. Excessive government involvement in monetary supply fueled financial bubbles and eroded the credibility of currency – the strength of the dollar is largely due to the relative weakness of others. This created fertile ground for new financial investment and speculative instruments, some even evading traditional tax limitations. This mirrors the global economy as a whole. MMT may not be the future; it&amp;rsquo;s more like a relic from 2008. Coupled with reverse globalization, the greater the past financial bubbles, government debt accumulation, and reckless speculation, the higher the risk of a hard landing – encompassing economic and social risks. Whether Keynesianism or MMT, regardless of how much money is supplied, it cannot fundamentally address wealth distribution issues; instead, it exacerbates risks within asset bubbles and Ponzi schemes. People repeatedly fall into the same trap in different ways, yet fail to learn from their mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
