<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Random Thoughts and Talks on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/random-thoughts-and-talks/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Random Thoughts and Talks on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 03:15:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/random-thoughts-and-talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Too much AI, a bit of a side effect</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 May 2025 19:39:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-overuse-side-effects/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Since the new &lt;code&gt;AI Inspiration Hub&lt;/code&gt; was established, a lot of trivial things have been tried to be recorded and published using AI. As a result, there&amp;rsquo;s less time for quiet reflection and contemplation. It would be good to slightly control the output of this column in the future and integrate it into a monthly publication format, releasing one article per month.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a kind of aftereffect, or perhaps a side effect – efficiency is improved, but the depth and breadth of thinking have declined&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;efficiency-improvement-undeniable&#34;&gt;Efficiency improvement: undeniable
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Seven Seconds of Fish&amp;rdquo; column hasn&amp;rsquo;t been well-maintained previously. Due to laziness, I didn’t search for information or compile records on some trending events. Now that various AI tools are available, outlining is sufficient; the AI can automatically connect to the internet, search for related event records, and generate articles as needed. A simple formatting adjustment, and it&amp;rsquo;s ready for publication.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s like a godsend for lazy people, it significantly improves efficiency, and you could even say it achieves results with half the effort&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throwing aside the need to write articles, when writing code, the efficiency boost is real. Many coding tasks used to require detailed reading of API interface documentation, but now you can skip them directly – and this skipping is quite necessary. Familiarity with APIs is a &lt;code&gt;physical labor&lt;/code&gt;, not a &lt;code&gt;mental labor&lt;/code&gt;; AI handling this part is just right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;garbage-content&#34;&gt;Garbage content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many of the submissions are low in quality; they aren&amp;rsquo;t entirely without merit, but they lack a sense of life and warmth. It’s a style I used to dislike – dry and lifeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To put it another way, AI-generated content does feel a bit like something produced on an assembly line – lacking soul&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet junk of the new era&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forgetfulness&#34;&gt;Forgetfulness
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This type of article is all AI-generated, and I don’t know the readers&amp;rsquo; situation, but over time, my own impressions will become blurred, or even forgotten&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar issues arise when writing code as well. Without checking the commit history, you have no idea what you were thinking at the time and why you wrote it that way. This is especially true for code generated after repeated communication with yourself and AI – the final version can be very different from the initial idea, even completely different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;search&#34;&gt;Search
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a significant decrease in how often I open Google and Baidu recently. Many questions are now searched for using AI, and the interaction and search results are much better than traditional search engines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s pay our respects to &lt;code&gt;bing ai&lt;/code&gt;, a tool from a major company that was among the first released with internet search capabilities, whether it’s still alive or not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People are using Google less, and visiting &lt;code&gt;stackoverflow&lt;/code&gt; less frequently too. Many questions can now be directly asked to AI, so this website is gradually being phased out by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The blog I’m still maintaining didn&amp;rsquo;t have much traffic to begin with, and now even less so; it’s more of a place for keeping records, writing for myself&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>County-level Brahmin: Big Shots in Small Places</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 23:02:25 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/county-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-towns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Teacher Da Bing has been very popular on Douyin. You often see accounts posting clips from her livestreams. During one livestream, a listener asked, &amp;ldquo;Teacher Da Bing, I want to sell my house in Xi&amp;rsquo;an and return to my hometown to lie flat?&amp;rdquo; Teacher Da Bing replied, &amp;ldquo;At your age, in your thirties, you can’t just lie flat. Your parents are on the road to aging, and your children haven&amp;rsquo;t settled down yet. Returning to your hometown, you&amp;rsquo;ll still need to deal with the &amp;lsquo;brahmin&amp;rsquo; within a small county town.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether the viewpoint is right or wrong, what does the word &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; mean?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;county-level-brahmins-big-shots-in-small-places&#34;&gt;County-Level Brahmins: &amp;ldquo;Big Shots&amp;rdquo; in Small Places
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;In many small county towns, people often talk about &amp;ldquo;county Brahmin&amp;rdquo; – their existence seems to symbolize a local society. They are not necessarily real religious figures or possess impressive titles, but rather seemingly ordinary yet influential individuals. They represent “power, status, and the right to speak” in a small place, symbolizing a certain stratum within that county town.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-a-county-level-brahmin&#34;&gt;What is a &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmin&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;First, we need to understand that &amp;ldquo;Brahmin&amp;rdquo; originally referred to the highest stratum of Indian society, representing wisdom, authority, and spiritual supremacy. However, in Chinese county towns, the term “county town Brahmin” does not have such a complex religious background; it is more of a metaphor for a social phenomenon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put, &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmin&amp;rdquo; can be understood as some “cultural authorities” in the county town, such as teachers, doctors, local well-known merchants, and officials. Although their positions seem ordinary, they possess a relatively high social status in the comparatively closed environment of the county town, or rather, their opinions and actions have an influence that cannot be ignored locally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;who-is-the-county-level-brahmin&#34;&gt;Who is the &amp;ldquo;County-Level Brahmin&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the county town, almost every industry has these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins.&amp;rdquo; They might be:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Educators, especially some teachers with decades of experience in local areas, may not be graduates of prestigious universities, but they deeply understand how to establish credibility through knowledge and are widely respected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local government officials: deputy county-level mayors, section-level cadres, and others. They control certain resources and power; even though their positions may not be high, due to the limited scope of their authority, they can become the &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; of the locality.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Local &amp;ldquo;entrepreneurs&amp;rdquo;: Some of these are bosses in county-level towns, though their scale isn&amp;rsquo;t large, they hold a certain amount of wealth and have local influence. They might run one or two well-known small businesses and wield considerable influence within the town.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These people, though their status may not be prominent compared to the elites or officials in big cities, are practically equivalent to &amp;ldquo;cultural elders&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;power centers&amp;rdquo; within this small society of the county&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-the-status-of-county-level-brahmins-affect-society&#34;&gt;How does the status of &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; affect society?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the meaning of &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins,&amp;rdquo; we must consider the unique environment of a county. In this place, information doesn&amp;rsquo;t flow as quickly as in big cities, and social mobility is relatively fixed. These “Brahmins” often accumulate prestige, knowledge, and networks through long-term cultivation within the locality. They influence various aspects of local politics, economy, and culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cultural influence: In smaller places, especially where the education system may not be so developed and ordinary people have limited choices, local &amp;ldquo;cultural Brahmins&amp;rdquo; quietly shape the cultural atmosphere through knowledge imparted in classrooms, explanations in the media, and even the lessons they teach through their words and deeds in social situations&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concentration of social resources: Due to the limited population and resources in county towns, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often one of the main controllers of local resources. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s social welfare, policy implementation, or project approval, their influence is unavoidable. Their right to speak and make decisions allows them to occupy a place in local society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The network structure of interpersonal relationships: In a relatively closed small society, personal connections are often crucial. These &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; control the flow of information and allocation of resources by establishing strong social networks, allowing them to play a decisive role at critical moments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-metaphor-behind-county-level-brahmin&#34;&gt;The Metaphor Behind &amp;ldquo;County-Level Brahmin&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &amp;ldquo;county-level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; are often respected and revered, this &amp;ldquo;high-and-mighty&amp;rdquo; status is not without its problems. In modern society, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to see that many &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may lack genuine ability and innovative spirit, instead maintaining their position through hereditary relationships and resource monopolies. With the development of informatization, the power of these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; is gradually being broken down, and new social mobility is beginning to impact the appearance of small counties.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, &amp;ldquo;County-Level Brahmins&amp;rdquo; is a fascinating social phenomenon that reflects the power and cultural structures within local societies. Although their “power” may not directly threaten national governance, they are undoubtedly important figures within their localities. In this era of rapid information flow and accelerating social change, these &amp;ldquo;Brahmins&amp;rdquo; in county towns may be facing unprecedented challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h1&gt;&lt;p&gt;It never would have occurred to me to write this piece. I was just curious about what &lt;code&gt;Brahmin&lt;/code&gt; meant, so I tossed it to &lt;code&gt;kimi&lt;/code&gt;, and the result was quite amusing. I could see that the web search had already produced a result, but it instantly changed to display related content unavailable. So I wondered if this word had some special meaning, and then I passed it on to &lt;code&gt;ChatGPT&lt;/code&gt;, which resulted in this article.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Going out for a walk is always good</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had followed my family&amp;rsquo;s plans and diligently studied electrical engineering without venturing into coding, I probably would have been a typical obedient son&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaking off the dust of memories, it all started with a conversation with my roommate near Chinese New Year, and I took the opportunity to reflect on these past years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gaokao results weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly good or bad. I graduated from a 211 university, and according to my dad’s original plan, I should have studied power grids diligently and returned to work at the local power supply bureau in our hometown. As mentioned earlier, I forgot to mention one key aspect of how I ended up on the IT path: my views on money and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still in a rural school in the first year of junior high, my family arranged for me to transfer to a city school by the second year. It felt like Liu姥姥 visiting the Grand View Garden—I had trouble adjusting to the bustle of the city. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone to the cinema many times as a child, and certainly not with my parents; relatives did take me occasionally. Luckily, I made friends with several like-minded guys. Though we don’t keep in touch much now, that time of youth looks back fondly. After weekend tutoring, we would collect plastic bottles from the classroom, expertly crushing them with our feet before packing them into backpacks to bring home for my mom to save. Once we had enough, we&amp;rsquo;d find someone who collected recyclables to take care of them. We played chess, badminton, and Dou Di Zhu (a card game), and the losers would do push-ups as punishment. I was a little grateful then that my dad had been getting me to do various exercises since I was young. From this point on, my view of money became slightly skewed, and I felt a bit insecure. But these small misfortunes were fleeting. My family wasn’t wealthy; we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much pocket money, and sometimes I couldn’t play with the other students, especially on weekends. My parents’ efforts were visible to the naked eye as we moved from the village to the city. The seeds had been planted, waiting to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone not particularly bright, I was generally very happy during my time studying. Just like many people don&amp;rsquo;t realize until after they graduate, studying isn’t that difficult; the conversion between input and output is relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layering memories of the imperial era from childhood, and then encountering a laptop during university was like opening Pandora&amp;rsquo;s Box. I came into contact with games and formed connections with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, purchasing goods upstream and slowly selling them through my own network to make a little money. Gradually, I understood the entire chain’s operational logic. The goods we sold were nothing more than those batch-incubated by upstream programs, their costs approaching zero. At this point, things started going slightly off track. Within my major, there were specialized subfields – on one side was power grids, and on the other, automation (a very diverse field including chip programming and factory electrical automation). I realized that programs could make a lot of money, not just a little, and upstream channels indeed earned a great deal. Coupled with my existing programming background, I started dabbling here and there, making some small sums of money. When choosing a specialization, it naturally led me to automation. I skipped many of the required courses in my junior year, my mind constantly focused on writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article last year mentioned that, driven by a romanticized view of hackers and with the kindness of IT experience outside of formal education, I dabbled in assembly, penetration testing, game hacks, DLL hijacking, and account theft, becoming familiar with various black and gray industries. My parents taught me how to be a good person, and the law still advised me; I didn&amp;rsquo;t go completely astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous link: [That Year We Were Young]({&amp;lt; relref &amp;ldquo;/post/2023/01-09-那时少年&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;}})&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had one relationship during college, but looking back now, it was more about longing for the kind of love seen in TV dramas. At that time, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t mature enough to understand how to truly love someone, let alone build a family and establish myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been fortunate amidst the tide of time. After a period of upheaval during my university years, I naturally couldn’t pursue graduate studies and started working right after graduation. Riding the wave of the IT industry, things have gone smoothly. It’s already been eight years since I started working, and as the hot money in the industry disappears, it&amp;rsquo;s gradually coming to a close. Sometimes I wonder if my initial choices were wrong; perhaps entering the power grid as my father suggested would have been a better option. I might have had those thoughts during the first five years of my career, but they slowly faded away. Joining Hang Seng through campus recruitment, I didn’t change companies for five years. There are definitely shortcomings in terms of technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following arrangements from the Hangzhou headquarters, I went to the Shenzhen branch, where I experienced a workplace struggle (only later did I understand the underlying issues – both sides lost, and the ultimate winner was the board). Driven by my passion for technology, I returned to Hangzhou, carrying a bit of youthful naivete, and then left Hangzhou, moving to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle down, register household registration, and buy a house in Hangzhou. With interest rates at their peak and housing prices at their highest, entering the market would mean being stuck with a mortgage right away. My family savings are limited, so I can’t afford this kind of financial strain. The thought of getting married while carrying that mortgage burden, combined with the downturn in the industry, makes me emotionally unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After so many years, having seen so much, I&amp;rsquo;ve been foolish and reckless myself. Currently, things are going well. Going through some experiences and encountering certain people has gradually matured me. If I had stayed at home all this time, I wonder in what form the flaws in my personality would have erupted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Monetization models based on traffic: Raffles</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Host giving away iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three things mentioned above, which don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have much connection, are actually different monetization models for free traffic, with a bit of a financial game feel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;win-gifts-through-platform-lottery&#34;&gt;Win gifts through platform lottery
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset to obtain platform currency, purchase gifts for their favorite streamers. Each platform also has another gameplay: after users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but can spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery events and obtain limited-edition, high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem has already appeared. Understanding online lotteries simply means the platform is running a casino. With enough participants, it will definitely not lose money. &lt;strong&gt;Commoner&lt;/strong&gt; users are playing with a &amp;ldquo;give it a shot&amp;rdquo; mentality, hoping to win a big prize and then send gifts, showing off and acting like they&amp;rsquo;re in charge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gift-from-streamer-physical-item&#34;&gt;Gift from streamer (physical item)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The platform&amp;rsquo;s lottery mentioned earlier is aimed at users’ writing. Anchors have monthly activity and popularity tasks; enabling the gifting lottery feature, fans who send designated gifts or gifts of a specified amount will have the opportunity to participate in the lottery, which could be high-end phones or cash rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular streamers, this event is quite profitable; it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a temporary free gift campaign. With enough participants, the streamer can still make money. This tests the streamer’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another way to play – with high rewards (cash value). Many outdoor streamers use this approach; it’s a disguised form of online gambling. People don’t care about the content of the live stream; users only care whether they can win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from hosts specializing in fashion shows, ordinary game streamers find it difficult to stimulate player spending through PK mode. Playing games and watching streams are leisure activities; people don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend extra money, especially with &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. Lottery-style promotions can cultivate users’ charging habits and consumption habits, occasionally leading to impulse purchases (with generous rewards, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini-program ranking rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini-program with some pointless processes or offer partial game-related support services. All of this is just a cover—to pass Tencent&amp;rsquo;s review, incorporate a ranking mechanism into the mini-program’s gameplay. Users earn points by browsing incentive ads and completing tasks; the backend sets rankings based on these points, and users with higher rankings receive designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core logic: Advertising revenue &amp;gt; Operating costs + Reward expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini programs can also operate normally, providing reasonable services, and earning income through appropriate advertising. The earnings may not be much, but a trickle of water can still accumulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>That young man, perhaps had some talent, but not much</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been seven years since I started working, and the positive feedback from writing code isn&amp;rsquo;t as much as it used to be. Looking back on how I got on this &amp;ldquo;coding&amp;rdquo; path.
The more choices a person makes, especially when they are young, the more they tend to follow positive feedback, actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city, encountering computer books? Hacker materials? Becoming familiar with the Windows system? These are all later stories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should be transported back to when I was a kid, sneaking around with my cousin using our family&amp;rsquo;s computer to play games; my cousin’s uncle ran a shop in the computer district
We started using computers relatively early on, so we developed a basic understanding of them. Later, in school and during computer classes, I also had quite an interest.
I heard about the computer competitions in junior high school, and thought they were really cool. After transferring schools, that matter was put on hold.
When I was in junior high, I was familiar with basic computer operations and could easily stand out during computer class
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with it, yes, you haven&amp;rsquo;t mistaken yourself, not skilled, but familiar with Microsoft Office software, that would be even more impressive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving&#34;&gt;Moving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the moving situation, once I got into the city, due to my neighbors, I came into contact with the library. Although I read a lot of novels, I also read many magazines.
Computer News, Popular Software
I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in computers, and as a child I had a great admiration for hackers, actively learning related knowledge at school
Understanding the basics of operating systems: Control Panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Computer World&amp;rdquo; magazine&amp;rsquo;s beginner-friendly content is quite suitable; it always uses case studies to explain system operations
《Popular Software》recommends various software, industry news, &lt;strong&gt;and of course, game news; the initial motivation also planted the seeds for games.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-high-school&#34;&gt;Three. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in my second year of high school, &lt;strong&gt;Boge transferred to our class; several senior students had been directly admitted through the computer competition for the previous two years&lt;/strong&gt;, and the school leaders also valued this competition
There&amp;rsquo;s also a foundational hardware aspect; an alumnus of ours donated a building to the school, a new library, a new computer lab – it’s all so coincidental
With Bo’s popular science explanation, he would be considered a computer expert in the class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A top student with computer skills, knowing how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable surveillance software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition, despite its challenges, made it to the finals. I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand everything, and the questions were mostly about basic algorithms, but I did gain some insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still just half a bucket of water, it’s like taking a trip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-college&#34;&gt;Four, College
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it came time to choose a major in college, I listened to my family and chose automation, but what I really wanted was to study high-voltage electricity. After returning home, I entered the power supply bureau, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn much from my coursework.
Self-directed learning ability is practically non-existent in professional courses, but when it comes to computer science courses in large lectures, I find them very easy and natural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping required courses, studying computer science diligently, and spending my days on forums like &amp;ldquo;Jingyi Forum&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;52PoP.&amp;rdquo;
Combining my knowledge of assembly and C++ from my studies, I started earning money by taking on projects from forums. It&amp;rsquo;s been going well, with increasing positive feedback, and it’s gotten to the point where it’s difficult to turn back.
In the end, Xiao Professional chose to write code for chips; my family didn&amp;rsquo;t interfere much and let me choose myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, &lt;strong&gt;the third key figure: Tangge&lt;/strong&gt;, with a high level of education, joined Baidu
My older sister understands me; she knows I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a state of mind to think and research, so she told me to talk it over with my cousin
Figure out the development path for next steps, don&amp;rsquo;t go home for summer vacation, stay with the mentor and work on projects to gain experience
Relied on a still-decent transcript, I got into Hengan Electronic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five, Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a key point, I know I took courses on wall-climbing and elective subjects: Computer Information Retrieval, knowing how to quickly find and locate materials and problems
A helpful person appeared at work, &lt;strong&gt;Shuo&lt;/strong&gt;, who gave me time to learn on my own, troubleshoot and get to the root of problems, and introduced me to the experts at the R&amp;amp;D center
This also laid the groundwork; Shenzhen Branch believes I&amp;rsquo;m very capable, and I successfully took responsibility for the transaction channel team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where the problem lies; I have a lack of foundational knowledge in areas like computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design
It&amp;rsquo;s all based on my own historical experience, not systematic learning
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make mistakes, constantly revising and negating previous code designs, lacking a guiding principle for module design. After seven years, I’m starting to feel burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Night Naming Technique</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 22:10:14 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/night-naming-art/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the vast system of Chinese characters, the character for “fate” or &amp;ldquo;life&amp;rdquo; (命) is unique, without a single homonym. Perhaps this subtly suggests that each person&amp;rsquo;s life is only lived once, irreplaceable and unrepeatable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Flipping through the rankings on Qidian Chinese Network during my leisure time, &amp;ldquo;The Naming of Night&amp;rdquo; has an overwhelming lead in monthly votes, firmly holding the top spot and leaving a huge gap between it and second place – practically unattainable. In the past few years, I&amp;rsquo;ve mostly read works by well-known authors like Tang Jia San Shao and Er Gen, but this time I decided to try out a new author and experience a different reading feel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of early August, &amp;ldquo;Naming Night&amp;rdquo; had reached two million monthly tickets, while the second-place novel only had eighty thousand, a staggering difference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know I&amp;rsquo;m not well-versed enough to evaluate the writing of this book. However, after reading through more than a dozen chapters, the plot is tightly paced and intricately connected, captivating readers. It’s truly deserving of such high monthly votes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s interesting that, just like the character for &amp;ldquo;destiny&amp;rdquo; (命), the character for &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; (死) also has no homophones in Chinese. Does this perhaps imply that the end of life is equally unique and irreplaceable?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right, you are a person and an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your sense of calm. We don’t discuss those great individuals who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;me-now&#34;&gt;Me now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average wages, or even considering salaries back home, my current income is already far above average – what more could I possibly be unsatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning a million; when you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning ten million. This is human nature, and people must confront their own inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that red-eyed thing, is it a more relaxed way of making money: short videos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see here is a short video, but what you don’t see is the scriptwriting and filming behind it. But everyone has a dream of being a genius, believing they are suited for that industry, that they are naturally gifted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-to-contact&#34;&gt;Begin to contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so many videos. If you analyze the shots a little bit with your own brain, it’s obvious they have professional editing techniques and a very strong cinematic feel. Basically, that means some of them are from film school backgrounds. Of course, there’s logic behind grassroots success stories, but that doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, there are also many videos teaching you how to make videos. It&amp;rsquo;s then that people realize things – if it were truly profitable, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithm&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithm
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, when Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm recommended movie clips and anime clips, I would keep watching them and find them quite interesting. But then, when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began recommending all sorts of tutorial videos non-stop, filling my entire recommendation feed. And I’m in the IT industry myself. At this point, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if those guys who designed the algorithm had a problem with their heads – are you suggesting that I&amp;rsquo;m stupid or that they&amp;rsquo;re stupid? The key thing is, it keeps finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money using Douyin, trying different angles and types. This article is being written by me at 3 AM, and I didn’t even want to write it. I just wonder how long this business model can last, and for how long can it consume everyone&amp;rsquo;s time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s laughable when you lecture others on how to do things, but can’t control yourself when it comes to your own actions. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically. Here, I just casually rant. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least now, in terms of real-time news dissemination and promotion of national policies, they are actively cooperating. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to when I was studying, it strikes me. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology here. If you can see this line, you’ll notice that the entire draft is very conversational. And honestly, I just kept reading it until it was finished. I used to use Sogou Input Method, for about seven or eight years. But when it comes to voice input, I have to say that iFlytek is still the professional choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? Having a dream that the number of articles this year can exceed one hundred – that’s a dream for me. It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles, just some records. I examine myself three times a day; you’ll surely think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lost</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at a certain stage in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. In the mundane routine of work, they gradually lose sight of the pursuit of meaning in their profession. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations. Back then, I would have said without hesitation that I longed to write code—code that could amaze and be incredibly impressive. However, since starting work, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed more to business-related matters, much of which is thanks to the benefits brought about by industry development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t included marriage, having children, and establishing a family or career within my sphere of thought. My mind is almost empty, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. Every weekend, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day staying at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something in their life that they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-house&#34;&gt;Buy a house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was still thinking about saving up to buy my own house and carefully calculating every expense towards that goal. However, seeing the prices of houses continue to rise, I went from initial anxiety and resentment to eventually becoming numb. I gradually felt that even if I bought a house, it would just be another heavy burden on me, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was to achieve small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, buying a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. But now, I approach saving money with a more relaxed attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses, eating what I want when I see it, and daring to try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I longed for most in my heart was simply to go home. It didn&amp;rsquo;t require doing anything special, just returning to that familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
