<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you have $1,000 USD and want to sell these dollars to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
1000 \, \text{USD} \times 7.0 \, \text{CNY/USD} = 7000 \, \text{CNY}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7,000 CNY. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling USD to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Exchange, History of Virtual Currency Development</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin once again elected as US President, also bringing virtual currencies back into the public eye. The Hong Kong Exchange has been actively deploying related business, and here’s a brief record of its virtual currency development history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the details of relevant contract listings, we found that the initial introduction wasn&amp;rsquo;t spot contracts but futures – which was reasonable due to their better liquidity and easier attraction of institutional investors. Subsequently introducing spot ETFs was also sensible, as they are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-currency-list&#34;&gt;Virtual Currency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange’s market data does not provide identifiers to distinguish between contracts that are virtual currencies. However, they can be determined by the contract name. The official trading list provides corresponding subcategories &lt;code&gt;virtualasset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-batch-of-crypto-asset-etfs-in-asia&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Batch of Crypto Asset ETFs in Asia
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of the first batch of crypto asset ETFs in Asia, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for investors in Hong Kong and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two new ETFs listed today – Southern East One Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Southern East One Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) – are managed by Southern East One Asset Management Co., Ltd. and track standardized, cash-settled bitcoin futures contracts and ether futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The two crypto asset ETFs listed today add another layer of richness to Hong Kong’s increasingly diverse exchange trading product ecosystem,” said Mr. Yao Jia Ren, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Market Development at HKEX. “These new products will provide investors in Asia for the first time with an opportunity to participate in digital asset investment, reflecting our focus on the digital economy and market demand. We look forward to bringing more thematic ETFs and digital asset products in the coming months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETF is one of the fastest-growing businesses under HKEX, with its product range continuously expanding and becoming increasingly diversified, including the launch of Hong Kong’s first Metaverse ETF, first Carbon Futures ETF, and first Blockchain ETF within the year. It also marked the first time ETFs were included in the滬深港通 (HKSG Connect).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the average daily trading volume of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s buy-and-sell products (ETPs – including ETFs and leveraged and inverse products) for the first eleven months of this year reached HK$118 billion, a 50% increase from last year’s same period of HK$78 billion, reflecting the growing popularity of ETPs among investors. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on HKEX with a market capitalization of HK$3,735 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-batch-of-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Batch of Spot Virtual Asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs, adding to the variety of products in the Hong Kong market and providing investors with more choices, further solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today’s newly listed spot virtual asset ETFs will enrich the diversified and dynamic ETF market ecosystem of the Hong Kong Exchange, offering investors new investment opportunities in asset classes,” said Robert Lin, Head of Securities Product Development at HKEX. “Following the successful launch of the first virtual asset futures ETF a year ago, these first Asian spot virtual asset ETFs will further enhance the product variety and liquidity for the Hong Kong Exchange’s buy-and-sell products. We look forward to continuing to work closely with market stakeholders to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs, which were listed in 2022, have been favored by investors and traded actively. The average daily trading volume of the three spot virtual asset ETFs listed on HKEX increased from HK$890 million in 2023 to HK$5.13 billion in the first quarter of 2024, while attracting HK$5.29 billion in inflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchange-traded products (ETPs), including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products, are one of the fastest-growing markets for HKEX, with the product variety continuously increasing over the past year. The 16 new ETPs launched in 2023 and the first quarter of 2024 include the first Saudi Arabian ETF in the Asia Pacific region, Hong Kong’s first callable option ETFs, and currently there are 179 ETPs listed on HKEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) announced today (Monday) that it will launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series (the “Series”) on November 15, 2024, providing a reliable benchmark price for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong’s development as a leading digital asset hub in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will provide transparent and reliable benchmarks for pricing Bitcoin and Ethereum within the Asian time zone, aiming to offer a unified reference price for virtual assets, addressing price discrepancies between this asset class across global exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKEX Group Chief Executive Officer Chen Yiting stated: “We are pleased to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series to meet the demand for this rapidly growing asset class regionally. By providing transparent and reliable real-time benchmarks, we hope to help investors make informed investment decisions, supporting the healthy development of the virtual assets ecosystem and solidifying Hong Kong’s position as an international financial center.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the index series is part of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring emerging areas, supporting the development of Hong Kong fintech while also providing investors with important benchmarks and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference indices are based on the weighted average spot price of Bitcoin or Ethereum over 24 hours’ trading volume, calculated using aggregated market prices from major virtual asset exchanges, and denominated in US dollars in real-time. The reference exchange rate is designed for financial product settlement and is calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will be the first virtual asset index series developed in Hong Kong that complies with European Union Benchmark Regulation (EUBMR) standards, managed and calculated jointly by a benchmark management company registered in the UK and a virtual assets data and index provider, CCData.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region issued a policy statement on the development of virtual assets, hoping to cultivate a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series will help the public increase their understanding of virtual asset investment trends through providing real-time data and daily reference prices within the Asian time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be announced as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline in the A-share market may be related to the dynamics of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank, the performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors jointly acted on the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to fluctuations in the Renminbi and the decline in the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant volatility. Here’s a detailed breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through:&lt;/strong&gt; At opening, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar-offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and the on-shore RMB rising to a high of 7.22360, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of release by Lianhe Chat, the dollar-offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 mark, with the lowest reported at 7.2639 and the trend remained unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Exchange Rate Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the Renminbi’s midpoint exchange rate against the dollar at 7.1004, a devaluation of 62 basis points, with the adjustment magnitude expanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened low and continued to fall, with declines exceeding 1% overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Foreign Exchange Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment institution stated that the volatility in the foreign exchange market was mainly due to the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank boosting the dollar, coupled with strong U.S. economic data and the potential persistence of inflation delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is the “Super Central Bank Week” for global markets, with the central banks of the United States, Japan, Britain, Australia, and other countries all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss Central Bank unexpectedly announced a cut in interest rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, which broke the market balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecast for Renminbi Trend:&lt;/strong&gt; Zhou Miaohua, researcher at Light Industry Bank’s Financial Market Department, stated that despite some fluctuations in the Renminbi recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the dollar, and short-term volatility will not change the RMB&amp;rsquo;s trend of steady appreciation throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bonded Customs Clearance with Hong Kong Dollar and Renminbi</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing (HKEX) announced on December 13th that it will soon launch the “Hong Kong-Renminbi Dual Counter Model” (hereinafter referred to as “Dual Counter Model”) and dual counter broker mechanisms for its securities markets, further supporting RMB-designated listings, trading, and settlement in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dual-listing-model-and-dual-listing-broker-mechanism&#34;&gt;Dual-Listing Model and Dual-Listing Broker Mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) stated that the registration procedures for these new measures are expected to begin implementation in the first half of 2023, pending regulatory approval and market readiness. Under the dual-listing model, HKEX will optimize related trading and settlement arrangements, allowing investors to swap securities issued by the same issuer on both the Hong Kong Dollar (HKD) and Renminbi (RMB) trading venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance liquidity in the RMB trading venue and narrow the price difference between the two venues, HKEX will introduce a dual-listing broker mechanism. Once relevant legislation is passed by the Legislative Council, market makers engaging in supply activities will be exempt from stamp duty when conducting specific transactions. Simultaneously, these new measures will also prepare for subsequent mainland investors to trade securities priced in RMB through the Hong Kong Connect (HKT) scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The launch of the dual-listing model of Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi and the dual-listing broker mechanism is a key measure for the development of our market. In conjunction with our other market initiatives, this arrangement will help attract more dual-listing securities to be listed in Hong Kong, complementing the existing mainland products at HKEX. HKEX is committed to actively promoting the internationalization of RMB and continuously enhancing Hong Kong’s position as a leading offshore RMB center globally.”  Said Mr. Yao Kai-yan, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Markets at HKEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is noted that the current listing, trading, settlement, and clearing arrangements in the Hong Kong stock market will largely apply to RMB securities under the dual-listing model. HKEX will announce the implementation date of the dual-listing model and the list of eligible dual-listing securities included in the broker mechanism at an appropriate time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-renminbi-trading-booths&#34;&gt;How to Identify Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi Trading Booths
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) documentation indicates that the Hong Kong dollar-Renminbi dual listing arrangement will largely follow the existing stock code allocation plan, meaning Hong Kong dollar booths will have stock codes starting with “0” followed by five digits, while Renminbi booths will have stock codes starting with “8” followed by five digits. The last four digits of both Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi booth stock codes will be identical. Renminbi booth stock abbreviations will be appended with &amp;ldquo;-R&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding trading arrangements, based on the fact that securities in both the Renminbi and Hong Kong dollar booths belong to the same category and can be converted into each other, if one booth (such as the Hong Kong dollar booth) allows for short selling of specified securities, the other booth (such as the Renminbi booth) can also be included as eligible for short selling according to exchange rules. Correspondingly, both booths will be listed in the specified securities lists that are available for short selling on the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the stocks in both booths belong to the same category and can be converted into each other, buying or holding the stock in Renminbi while selling it in Hong Kong dollars will be considered a carry trade (short sale), and vice versa. Settlement times between the two booths are T+2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For specified securities eligible for short selling, such as borrowing stocks in Hong Kong dollars and then selling them on the Renminbi booth, this will be treated as a secured short sale, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that under the dual booth model, since the Renminbi booth is only for trading and settlement, it will not provide physical stock deposits or withdrawals; physical stocks can only be deposited after being held in the Hong Kong dollar booth and then converted to the Renminbi booth. Similarly, the Renminbi booth must be converted to the Hong Kong dollar booth before physical stocks can be withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Hong Kong settlement and clearing fees, excluding dividend collection service fees and interest collection service fees, will be calculated and charged in Hong Kong dollars. Dividend collection service fees and interest collection service fees will be calculated using the currency adopted for the relevant securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism/HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model&lt;/a&gt;
Source: HKEx Pulse / HKEx, Broker China&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Futu Securities Stock Code Special Format Instructions</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Uncommon, it will definitely encounter it over time; related stock code: Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some stock ticker symbols contain periods or other special characters in their names. When submitting these to Interactive Brokers (IB) via &lt;code&gt;Fix&lt;/code&gt;, certain transformations of the stock code name are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;body&#34;&gt;Body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Fidelity Securities case, it’s possible to analyze and implement the conversion rules are fixed through coding. When the rules are not fixed, generally the system needs to store the corresponding mapping relationships, which are updated periodically by business operations personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-links&#34;&gt;Reference Links
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Futures Basic Concepts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets continue to evolve, investors have begun seeking more effective investment tools to enhance their investment returns. To meet investor demand, The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a range of stock futures contracts, all of which represent stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange (HKEX), which boasts high trading volumes and active liquidity. Through investing in stock futures, investors can participate in the performance of individual companies while also benefiting from the short selling and leverage effects offered by the derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the underlying stocks represented by stock futures are typically leading companies within their respective industries, investors can strategically select to invest in those industry-specific futures if they believe a particular sector’s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a specified quantity of financial value (contract size) equivalent to a specified number of shares (the underlying stock) at a predetermined price (the agreed-upon price) on a future, specified date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All stock futures contracts are settled in cash and do not involve the physical delivery of shares upon expiration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expiry&#34;&gt;Contract Expiry
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon contract expiry, the profit or loss amount is calculated as the difference between the agreed-upon price and the final settlement price multiplied by the contract multiplier, which will be deducted from the clearing member’s margin account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price refers to the official closing price of the stock reported by the Shanghai Stock Exchange on the last trading day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a futures investor wishes to close out their position before expiry, a short seller only needs to buy back one futures contract, while a long position holder must sell one futures contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;margin-deposit&#34;&gt;Margin Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In futures trading, both buyers and sellers must initially deposit a basic margin as collateral to fulfill the contract. After each daily settlement, the clearing organization calculates profits or losses for all open contracts based on the closing market price and uses this to deduct from investors’ margin accounts. If unfavorable market conditions result in an investor incurring losses that cause their margin to fall below the specified level, the exchange will require the investor to top up their margin within a designated timeframe to maintain it at the original basic margin level (i.e., to cover).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Transaction Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The fees are low relative to the value of the underlying shares. Each futures contract is equivalent to thousands of shares, and commissions depend on the number of contracts traded, resulting in a very low cost per unit of value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier Short Selling:&lt;/strong&gt; Because investors can easily short stocks through futures contracts, they can profit during market declines by shorting stock futures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Maker System:&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure market liquidity, The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited (HKEX) mandates that market makers provide buy and sell prices within a specified range, maintaining circulation in the stock futures market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; Investors only need to pay a margin representing a small portion of the contract value when buying and selling stock futures contracts, making hedging and trading more cost-effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Foreign Investor Currency Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts provide foreign investors with access to invest in high-quality local stocks because they only pay a margin instead of the full contract value, significantly reducing the currency risk borne by foreign investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic Trading System:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts are traded through The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited’s (HKEX) electronic trading system. All trades are executed according to price and time priority, with immediate display of buy prices, sell prices, and transaction prices, achieving the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing Company Performance Guarantees:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts will be registered, settled, and performance guarantees provided by HKEX’s wholly owned subsidiary, Hong Kong Futures Clearing Limited (the Clearing Company). Because the Clearing Company is the counterparty to all unsettled contracts, participants in the clearing house will not have to bear counterparty risk. However, this guarantee does not include the financial responsibility of the clearing participant for its clients; investors choosing a broker to trade must exercise caution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-making&#34;&gt;Market Making
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants or individual stock futures contracts may register as market makers on the exchange and simultaneously provide both buy and sell prices within the specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should be aware that individual stock futures contracts may not have a market maker registered to provide bid-ask spreads, and their trades will be based on market unit pricing. &lt;strong&gt;Investors should note that stock futures without registered market makers may involve liquidity risk, and caution should be exercised before entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stock-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of Trading Stock Futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock futures involve high risks. Losses arising from trading stock futures may exceed the initial margin paid, potentially requiring you to pay additional margins within a short period. If unable to meet these payments, your position may be liquidated, and you will bear all resulting losses. Therefore, it is crucial to fully understand the risks associated with trading stock futures and assess whether it’s suitable for you. Before engaging in transactions, consult with a broker or financial advisor to determine if futures and options contracts are appropriate based on your financial situation and investment objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjusting-comments&#34;&gt;Adjusting Comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a listed company alters its capital structure through measures such as a cash offer or the issuance of bonus shares, this will lead to changes in share prices at the time of net asset valuation or the effective date, and may also affect uncovered positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If other circumstances remain unchanged, the value of holdings held by shareholders will not be adjusted on the settlement day; however, this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures. Unless the futures contract is appropriately adjusted, changes to the share price will unfairly and unjustly impact the value of a stock futures position. The adjustment ratio determined by the Settlement Corporation is based on maintaining the fair value of the futures contract and only made when there are significant changes. The Hong Kong Exchange will announce the details of the adjustments, and participants in the exchange must inform customers about the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Futures Contracts Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/futures-contracts-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Futures Contracts Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-provider-code&#34;&gt;News Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/news_provider_code.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;News Provider Code&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/products/listed-derivatives/single-stock/stock-futures?sc_lang=zh-cn#list_of_stock_futures&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Exchange - Derivatives / Stocks / Stock Futures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange Interface Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent five years developing financial software, I’ve become most familiar with the interface documentation of various exchanges. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly well-versed in the Hong Kong Exchange’s documents, and recently while handling the ChinaBond business, I also reviewed materials from the Shanghai Stock Exchange (SSE) and Shenzhen Stock Exchange (SZSE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-resources&#34;&gt;Frequently Used Resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Trading-Hour,-Trading-and-Settlement-Calendar?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Hours, Trading and Settlement Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Mechanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/hkex-market/mutual-market/stock-connect/reference-materials/resources/glossary_c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong &amp;amp; China Financial Terminology Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_pdf_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect and Shenzhen Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_csv_c.csv&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect and Shenzhen Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar CSV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;glossary_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong &amp;amp; China Financial Terminology Glossary PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/vcm/vcmtriggersecurity_c.aspx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Circuit Breaker Trigger Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/services/trading/securities/securitieslists/ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Closing-Auction-Session-%28CAS%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Closing Auction Session (CAS) Securities Trading Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Volatility-Control-Mechanism-%28VCM%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Volatility Control Mechanism (VCM) Securities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Designated-Securities-Eligible-for-Short-Selling?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Designated Securities Eligible for Short Selling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34; &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-fortune-中化通&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Fortune (中化通)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Interface Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;
Frequently Asked Questions, Guidance on Development Manuals, Historical Market Data Interface Documents can be obtained by searching for download addresses in the search bar. Search for historical version numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/HKEX-Orion-Market-Data-Platform-Securities-Market-OMD-C?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange Market Data Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Technical-Documents/OMD_CC-Specifications?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;China Fortune Market Data Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-interface-document-h-shares--china-tong&#34;&gt;Trading Interface Document: H Shares + China Tong
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Interface Document Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;H Shares FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;H Shares Dual Pricing Scheme Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Reason_Text_List.xlsx&#34; &gt;HKEX Error Code List XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Tong FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Tong Binary Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sse-shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;SSE (Shanghai Stock Exchange)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.sse.com.cn/services/tradingservice/tradingtech/technical/data/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data and Trading Link Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
Error Interface Documentation can be found in other menus
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;SSE_IS111_ErrorCode_CV3.15.xlsx&#34; &gt;Trading Error Interface Documentation XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.szse.cn/marketServices/technicalservice/interface/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Query Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
The Stock Exchange does not provide separate error message explanations; supplementary information can be found in Chapter 6 of the Market Data Query Interface Documentation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;P020201229686784934466.pdf&#34; &gt;Shenzhen Securities Trading Center Binary Transaction Data Interface Specification (Ver1.18) PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;Nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nyse.com/markets/hours-calendars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Holiday Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/ipos?tab=upcoming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;New Issue Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-price&#34;&gt;Closing Price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://eoddata.com/stocklist/NASDAQ.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Global Market Closing Prices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
