<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 22:13:46 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding spin-offs and splits in the US stock market can be challenging.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-spin-offs-and-splits-in-the-us-stock-market-can-be-challenging/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 22:09:31 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-spin-offs-and-splits-in-the-us-stock-market-can-be-challenging/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Prompt: As a Chinese person, when seeing English financial news and information about actions of US listed companies, why are mergers and acquisitions written like this: NAOV reverse stock split: 1 for 10? Is this a unique English grammar that doesn&amp;rsquo;t conform to Chinese grammatical habits? Based on this, please explain the meaning of the stock split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hello! This is a very good question, and many investors who speak Chinese as their mother tongue will have the same confusion when first encountering English financial news. This is indeed a specific expression habit in English in the field of finance, which differs greatly from the order of Chinese grammar.
I will explain the meaning of the stock split to you in detail.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-a-1-for-10-reverse-stock-split-written-as-1-for-10&#34;&gt;Why is a 1 for 10 Reverse Stock Split Written as “1 for 10”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s break down this expression: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;A for B&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this structure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A&lt;/strong&gt; represents the &lt;strong&gt;new thing you will receive&lt;/strong&gt; (the result).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B&lt;/strong&gt; represents the &lt;strong&gt;old thing you are giving up&lt;/strong&gt; (the cost/exchange).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The word “for” here means &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;in exchange for&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;“1 for 10 reverse stock split”&lt;/strong&gt; translates directly as: &lt;strong&gt;“1 new share for 10 old shares”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In other words, your &lt;strong&gt;every 10 existing shares will be consolidated into 1 new share&lt;/strong&gt;. This is precisely what the Chinese terms “10 combine with 1” or “10 shares merge into 1 share” mean.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;grammatical-habit-comparison&#34;&gt;Grammatical Habit Comparison
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;English Convention (Result for Reason/Cost):&lt;/strong&gt;  Places “the result obtained” at the front and “the cost paid” at the back. For example, &lt;code&gt;You get 1 new share for your 10 old shares.&lt;/code&gt; Headlines are often shortened to &lt;code&gt;1 for 10&lt;/code&gt; for brevity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chinese Convention (Reason/Cost -&amp;gt; Result):&lt;/strong&gt; Tends to follow a chronological or logical order, stating “the original state” first, followed by “the resulting outcome.” For example, “(originally) 10 shares merged into (now) 1 share.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, this isn’t a universal English grammar; it&amp;rsquo;s a very common convention and abbreviation used when expressing &amp;ldquo;exchange ratio&amp;rdquo; in business and finance.
&lt;strong&gt;Illustrative Example (NAOV 1 for 10 Reverse Stock Split):&lt;/strong&gt;
Assume you hold 1000 shares of the NAOV company before a reverse stock split, with a share price of $0.5 per share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Asset Value:&lt;/strong&gt; 1000 shares * $0.5/share = $500 USD
After the reverse split (1 for 10):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Shares Held:&lt;/strong&gt; 1000 shares / 10 = 100 shares&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theoretical Share Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $0.5/share * 10 = $5 per share&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Asset Value:&lt;/strong&gt; 100 shares * $5/share = $500 USD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The primary purpose of the reverse stock split is to increase the price per share, which reduces the number of shares you hold, but (assuming no market fluctuations) your total asset value remains unchanged. Companies typically conduct reverse stock splits to meet exchange minimum price requirements (such as Nasdaq’s requirement for a share price to maintain above $1).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-split-explanation&#34;&gt;Stock Split Explanation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once you understand consolidation, a stock split is easily understood. A stock split is the opposite of consolidation.
English is typically written like this: &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 for 1 stock split&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;3 for 1 stock split&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.
Using the &lt;code&gt;A for B&lt;/code&gt; structure we’ve learned above to interpret it:
&lt;strong&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 for 1 stock split&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; means: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;You will receive 2 new shares in exchange for your 1 old share.&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo;
This is exactly what the Chinese phrase “&lt;strong&gt;1拆2&lt;/strong&gt;” or “&lt;strong&gt;1股拆为2股&lt;/strong&gt;” means.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example (A Company’s 2 for 1 Stock Split):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s assume that before the split, you hold 100 shares of a company with a stock price of $200 per share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Asset Value:&lt;/strong&gt; 100 shares * $200/share = $20,000
After the split (2 for 1):&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Shares Held:&lt;/strong&gt; 100 shares * 2 = 200 shares&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Price Per Share (Theoretically)&lt;/strong&gt;: $200/share / 2 = $100 per share&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Asset Value:&lt;/strong&gt; 200 shares * $100/share = $20,000&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The purpose of a stock split is to lower the price per share, making it more attractive to small investors and increasing liquidity. It will increase your number of shares held, but equally so, your total asset value remains unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English Example&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Impact on Share Holding Quantity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Impact on Stock Price per Share&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse Split&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10合1&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;1 for 10&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exchange 10 old shares for 1 new share&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Decrease&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Increase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-1&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Company Action&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Chinese Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English Example&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;English Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Impact on Shareholding Quantity&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Impact on Stock Price per Share&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Split&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;1拆2&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;code&gt;2 for 1&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Exchange 1 old share for 2 new shares&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Increase&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Decrease&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-2&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this explanation will help you better understand English financial news! It truly is a way of expression that requires a shift in mindset to get used to.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Stock Exchange Brokerage Fee Liberalization and Market Competition</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-brokerage-fee-liberalization-and-market-competition/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 21:47:51 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-brokerage-fee-liberalization-and-market-competition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The practice of “the same contract code, for transactions in the same direction, commission is only charged once” is commonly referred to as &lt;strong&gt;“Commission Aggregation / Combined Commission”&lt;/strong&gt; within the securities industry. This is not a hard-and-fast regulation by the Hong Kong Exchange or regulatory bodies, but rather a business convention formed through market competition and brokers’ efforts to optimize customer experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding HK stocks, when the same contract code is used for transactions in the same direction, only one commission is charged – does this have any historical business background?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-historical-turning-points-cancellation-of-the-minimum-commission-rule-in-2003&#34;&gt;Key Historical Turning Points: Cancellation of the Minimum Commission Rule in 2003
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most important background to understand this issue.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-Reform (Before April 1, 2003):&lt;/strong&gt; The Hong Kong stock market operated under a &lt;strong&gt;Minimum Commission Rule&lt;/strong&gt;. At the time, brokers were required to charge clients a commission of no less than 0.25% of the transaction value. During this period, all brokerage commissions were essentially locked at the same level, and competition primarily focused on research capabilities, client relationships, and service quality; price wars were virtually non-existent. Therefore, there was no incentive to consolidate commissions for clients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-Reform (After April 1, 2003):&lt;/strong&gt; The Hong Kong Exchange officially &lt;strong&gt;abolished the Minimum Commission Rule&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing brokers and clients to freely negotiate commission rates. This reform instantly ignited competition in the Hong Kong securities industry, particularly commission price wars.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;a-product-of-fierce-market-competition&#34;&gt;A Product of Fierce Market Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Following the removal of minimum commission fees, securities firms (particularly emerging internet brokers) have adopted various innovative pricing strategies to attract customers. “Consolidated Commission” is one such highly attractive initiative.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attracting Active Traders:&lt;/strong&gt; For high-frequency traders or investors who prefer to buy and sell the same stock in batches (such as to avoid large single orders impacting market prices), per-trade fees can significantly increase transaction costs. The “Consolidated Commission” policy perfectly addresses this pain point, allowing investors to flexibly establish or liquidate positions within a day without worrying about multiple commission charges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reducing Customer Transaction Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the most direct objective. By consolidating calculations, customer actual commission expenses are reduced, making the broker’s platform more competitive in terms of cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Customer Experience and Loyalty:&lt;/strong&gt; This customer-friendly policy greatly enhances the user experience, making customers feel that the broker is looking out for their interests, thereby strengthening customer loyalty and retention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-logic-and-brokerage-interests&#34;&gt;Business Logic and Brokerage Interests
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although superficially, brokerage revenue appears to be declining, from a holistic business logic perspective, it’s a win-win situation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Margin, High Volume:&lt;/strong&gt; Reducing the effective cost of each transaction can stimulate customers to trade more frequently, thereby increasing overall trading volume. While brokers “give away” commissions on individual trades, they can compensate by increasing total transaction volume and earning other fees, such as platform usage fees and financing/margin interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Share Acquisition:&lt;/strong&gt; In a fiercely competitive market, particularly for new internet brokerages, low commission rates and promotional policies are the most effective means of quickly acquiring users and capturing market share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-points-to-note&#34;&gt;Key Points to Note
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not All Brokers Offer It:&lt;/strong&gt; While “merged commission” has become mainstream, it’s still a broker&amp;rsquo;s business decision and not a mandatory regulation. Some traditional brokers or banks may still charge per trade for their securities services, so investors need to carefully review the broker’s fee schedule when choosing a broker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only Applies to “Commission”:&lt;/strong&gt; Be sure to note that the calculated merged amount only includes the “commission” charged by the broker. Any “fixed fees” collected by the government or exchanges are calculated per trade and cannot be merged. These include:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stamp Duty (印花税):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.1% (Paid by both buyer and seller, rounded up to the nearest dollar)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SFC Transaction Levy (交易征费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.0027% (Collected by the Securities and Futures Commission)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HKEX Trading Fee (交易费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.00565% (Collected by the Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;FRC Transaction Levy (会财局交易征费):&lt;/strong&gt; 0.00015% (Collected by the Financial Regulatory Authority)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary, the “merged commission” policy of Hong Kong brokers is rooted in the abolition of the Minimum Commission System in 2003. It was a significant business strategy adopted by brokers in an environment of market liberalization and intense competition – to reduce customer costs, enhance service experience, attract and retain customers – representing a microcosm of Hong Kong’s financial market transitioning from traditional to modern, from high barriers to accessibility.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>- Significant differences in trading and settlement between stocks and digital currencies</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/significant-differences-in-trading-and-settlement-between-stocks-and-digital-currencies/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 18:28:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/significant-differences-in-trading-and-settlement-between-stocks-and-digital-currencies/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;To truly understand the significant differences between traditional stocks and digital currencies in terms of trading and settlement, we need to deeply grasp the core “components” and “rules” that make up each ecosystem. We can view them as two entirely different games: one a rigorous, multi-party collaborative “professional league,” and the other a code-as-law, open-to-all “open world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the previous two questions, are there any foundational knowledge points we could explore to further expand this understanding? Let’s also compile some resources for you to learn more about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-1-the-foundation-of-traditional-stock-markets--a-chain-of-trust-composed-of-professional-institutions&#34;&gt;Part 1: The Foundation of Traditional Stock Markets – A Chain of Trust Composed of Professional Institutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of traditional financial markets is &lt;strong&gt;“trust”&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;“intermediaries.”&lt;/strong&gt; The entire system is designed as a multi-layered structure, with each stage played by regulated professional institutions to ensure market stability and security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-players&#34;&gt;The Players
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You (Investor):&lt;/strong&gt; The starting and ending point of the transaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Broker:&lt;/strong&gt; The &lt;strong&gt;sole gateway&lt;/strong&gt; for you to enter the market. You cannot directly go to the Shanghai Stock Exchange or New York Stock Exchange to buy stocks; you must use a broker holding a license to execute your trading instructions and hold your funds and securities (as a nominal holder).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Exchange:&lt;/strong&gt; The market’s &lt;strong&gt;“trading floor”&lt;/strong&gt;. Examples include the New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) and NASDAQ. Its primary function is to provide a fair, open venue where buy and sell offers meet (matching), thereby discovering prices. &lt;strong&gt;The exchange only handles order matching; it does not handle subsequent fund and stock transfers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Counterparty Clearing Corporation (CCP):&lt;/strong&gt; The market’s &lt;strong&gt;“risk guarantor”&lt;/strong&gt;. This is at the core of risk management. After a trade is executed, the CCP intervenes between all buyers and sellers, becoming “all buyers to all sellers” and “all sellers to all buyers.”  This way, any party&amp;rsquo;s default risk is borne by the CCP, preventing risks from spreading through the market like dominoes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Securities Depository (CSD):&lt;/strong&gt; The market’s &lt;strong&gt;“ultimate vault” and “master registry”&lt;/strong&gt;. Examples include DTCC in the US and China’s ZSDEC. This is a crucial institution that electronically centralizes and custodians the vast majority of securities in the entire market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-concepts-the-paperless-and-non-moveable-nature-of-securities&#34;&gt;Core Concepts: The “Paperless” and “Non-Moveable” Nature of Securities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dematerialization:&lt;/strong&gt; The stocks you buy today are not physical paper certificates, but a series of electronic records within a CSD (Central Securities Depository) database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Immobilization:&lt;/strong&gt; This is key to understanding settlement. When settlement occurs, there isn&amp;rsquo;t actually an “electronic stock file” being sent from one broker’s server to another. Instead, all the stocks are “fixed” stored in this central vault – the CSD. The settlement process simply involves the CSD making a transfer of shares from the seller broker’s omnibus account to the buyer broker’s omnibus account on its master ledger. Your broker then updates its own internal customer records to reflect that you now hold more shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This multi-tiered, clearly defined structure, while introducing time delays (T+N), has established a robust and mature risk isolation and management mechanism – the cornerstone of modern financial markets&amp;rsquo; stable operation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;part-two-the-foundation-of-the-digital-currency-market--a-trustless-system-built-on-code-and-cryptography&#34;&gt;Part Two: The Foundation of the Digital Currency Market – A “Trustless” System Built on Code and Cryptography
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Digital currencies aim to reduce or eliminate reliance on traditional intermediaries, with its foundation being &lt;strong&gt;“cryptographic proof”&lt;/strong&gt; rather than &lt;strong&gt;“institutional trust.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-technology-the-technology&#34;&gt;Core Technology (The Technology)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blockchain / DLT (Distributed Ledger Technology):&lt;/strong&gt; Think of it as a &lt;strong&gt;distributed, globally maintained ledger that cannot be altered, held by countless individuals.&lt;/strong&gt; Every transaction is publicly recorded and verifiable by anyone, but no single person or institution can control it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public &amp;amp; Private Keys:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the &lt;strong&gt;sole proof of ownership for your assets in the digital currency world.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Public Key:&lt;/strong&gt; Equivalent to your &lt;strong&gt;bank account number&lt;/strong&gt;. You can safely share this with anyone to receive digital currencies. Your wallet address is generated from the public key.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Private Key:&lt;/strong&gt; Equivalent to your &lt;strong&gt;bank password + U盾 + signature combination&lt;/strong&gt;, it’s the only key to access assets associated with that address. &lt;strong&gt;Whoever holds the private key has absolute control over the assets in that address.&lt;/strong&gt; This is also the origin of the encryption world&amp;rsquo;s golden rule: “Not your keys, not your coins” (If you don’t hold the private key, you don’t own the cryptocurrency).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Crypto Wallet:&lt;/strong&gt; It &lt;strong&gt;doesn’t store any “coins”&lt;/strong&gt; (coins always reside on the blockchain). The wallet’s essence is a &lt;strong&gt;tool for managing your private key&lt;/strong&gt; and helping you sign transactions with your private key to interact with the blockchain network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contract:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a piece of code that automatically executes on the blockchain. Its logic is “If…then…” (IF-THEN). For example, a decentralized exchange’s smart contract could be: “If I receive 1 ETH from User A, then automatically send 2000 USDC to User A&amp;rsquo;s address.” The entire process is automatically enforced by code with no human intervention and without requiring trust in anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-rules-consensus-mechanism&#34;&gt;Core Rules: Consensus Mechanism
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;How do thousands of nodes in a network reach agreement on which transactions are valid when there is no central server? That’s the role of a consensus mechanism. The two most common types are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of Work (PoW):&lt;/strong&gt; As exemplified by Bitcoin. It involves “miners” performing massive hash calculations (like solving an extremely difficult math problem) to compete for the right to record transactions. The first miner to solve the puzzle can package the latest transactions into a block and broadcast it to the entire network, which other nodes verify and accept. This method is highly energy-intensive but provides very high security.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of Stake (PoS):&lt;/strong&gt; Adopted by Ethereum after its upgrade. It no longer relies on a competition of computing power; instead, “validators” who hold and “stake” tokens are selected to create and validate blocks. The more tokens staked, the greater the probability of being chosen to record transactions. If they act maliciously, their staked tokens will be forfeited. This method is more energy-efficient and efficient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To better understand, we can use a table to summarize the fundamental differences between them:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Asset Type&lt;/strong&gt; | Electronic Ledger (Dematerialized) in CSD | Native Digital Token on Blockchain |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-1&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Stock Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Digital Currency Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proof of Ownership&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Depository records (beneficial ownership)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Control over private keys (direct ownership)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-2&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Stock Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Digital Currency Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trust Model&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trust in regulated legal and financial institutions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Trust in open-source code and cryptographic proofs (“trustless”)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-3&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Stock Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Digital Currency Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Ledger&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Centralized ledger maintained by a CSD&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Distributed ledger maintained by all network nodes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-4&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Stock Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Digital Currency Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Counterparty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;CCP (Central Counterparty)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The other party in the trade or smart contract&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-5&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Traditional Stock Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Digital Currency Market&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-and-comparison-6&#34;&gt;Summary and Comparison
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through the above additions, you can see that traditional finance relies on establishing a complex “trust chain” to manage risk and complete settlements; while digital currencies attempt to build a system without intermediaries using technological means (cryptography and distributed networks) to achieve self-validation. These two fundamentally different underlying logics determine the stark differences in all aspects of transactions, clearing, and settlement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Why the concept of “settlement” is necessary in traditional stock trading?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/why-the-concept-of-settlement-is-necessary-in-traditional-stock-trading/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:18:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/why-the-concept-of-settlement-is-necessary-in-traditional-stock-trading/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s era of the global digital wave, we&amp;rsquo;ve become accustomed to instant transfers and near-instant payments. Therefore, many people are confused: why, after clicking “sell” on a stock, does my funds not immediately clear in full and become available, but instead takes one or two business days? This is precisely a crucial and historically significant concept within traditional stock trading – &lt;strong&gt;settlement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prompt: Why does traditional stock trading require the concept of settlement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trading” and “Settlement” are two separate steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; This refers to the moment you place a buy or sell order on an exchange that is successfully matched. At this point, you and your counterparty have reached a legally binding contract committing to exchanging stocks and funds at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the process of fulfilling the terms of the agreed-upon contract – namely, the ownership of the stock officially and irrevocably transfers from seller to buyer, while the funds are officially and irrevocably transferred from the buyer’s account to the seller’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need for these two separate steps and a time lag (such as T+1, T+2 systems) stems from historical evolution and rigorous risk management in finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-roots-originating-in-the-paper-era&#34;&gt;Historical Roots: Originating in the “Paper” Era
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the widespread adoption of computer systems, stocks were tangible &lt;strong&gt;paper certificates&lt;/strong&gt;. Following a trade executed orally or through gestures at an exchange, subsequent work was incredibly laborious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical Transportation:&lt;/strong&gt; The seller’s brokerage firm needed to retrieve the corresponding stock certificate from its vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endorsement Transfer:&lt;/strong&gt; Signing and endorsing the back of the certificate to verify ownership transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual Delivery:&lt;/strong&gt; These certificates and associated checks had to be delivered by personnel (couriers) throughout the city to the buyer&amp;rsquo;s brokerage firm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verification &amp;amp; Reconciliation:&lt;/strong&gt; The buyer’s brokerage firm needed to verify the authenticity of the certificates and the accuracy of the transaction details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire process involved a significant amount of manual labor and physical transfer, riddled with delays and uncertainty. Consequently, an settlement cycle of several days (initially as long as T+5) was established to complete these complex processes. In the late 1960s, Wall Street was plunged into a “Paperwork Crisis” due to a surge in trading volume; a large number of trades could not be completed on time, even forcing exchanges to shorten trading hours. This directly spurred the establishment of modern electronic clearing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-core-an-unreplaceable-risk-management&#34;&gt;Modern Core: An Unreplaceable Risk Management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite all transactions being electronic today, the T+N settlement system remains in place because its core function has evolved from “waiting for logistics” to &lt;strong&gt;managing the massive risks of the financial system&lt;/strong&gt;. This process is primarily carried out by a key player – &lt;strong&gt;Central Counterparty (CCP) Clearinghouses&lt;/strong&gt;, such as the Depository Trust &amp;amp; Clearing Corporation (DTCC) and the China Securities Depository and Clearing Corporation (CSDC) in the United States and China, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement system is mainly designed to mitigate the following core risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;counterparty-risk&#34;&gt;Counterparty Risk
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most fundamental risk. If you sell shares, how can you be 100% certain that the buyer will pay on time? Conversely, how can the buyer be 100% certain that the seller will deliver genuine shares? If either party defaults, it could trigger a chain reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; The intervention of a Central Counterparty (CCP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a trade occurs, the CCP steps in between the buyer and seller, &lt;strong&gt;acting as both the seller’s “buyer” and the buyer’s “seller.”&lt;/strong&gt; Through this legal arrangement called “novation,” the original buyer-seller relationship is no longer direct; instead, each party is responsible to the CCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Seller:&lt;/strong&gt; As long as shares are delivered to the CCP, they will definitely receive money from the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Buyer:&lt;/strong&gt; As long as money is delivered to the CCP, they will definitely receive shares from the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the default risk of a single participant is absorbed by the highly creditworthy central institution – the CCP – and does not spread throughout the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clearing--netting&#34;&gt;Clearing &amp;amp; Netting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A large brokerage firm handles millions of transactions in a single day, involving both buying and selling. If each transaction were processed individually, the system would be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; “Clearing” is performed before settlement date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the trading day (T-day), clearing agencies consolidate all buy and sell transactions for each broker, known as &lt;strong&gt;“netting” or “clearing &amp;amp; netting.”&lt;/strong&gt; For example, a brokerage firm might have bought $10 billion worth of stock and sold $9.8 billion on a given day. On settlement day, it only needs to pay a net difference of $20 million in cash, rather than engaging in a $19.8 billion exchange. Similarly, securities settlements are also processed on a net basis. This significantly improves the efficiency of the entire market and reduces liquidity requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-complete-lifecycle-of-a-stock-transaction&#34;&gt;The Complete Lifecycle of a Stock Transaction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a simple example to see the entire process from trade to settlement (using a T+2 model):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T Day (Trading Day):&lt;/strong&gt; You click “Buy” 100 shares of a company&amp;rsquo;s stock in the morning and it immediately executes. At this point, you reach an agreement with the seller, but &lt;strong&gt;ownership of the stock and funds has not yet transferred.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T Day Aftermarket ~ T+1 Day (Clearing Period):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exchange sends your trade data to the Central Clearing Corporation (CCP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP confirms the transaction information is accurate and performs a “contract swap,” becoming your counterparty for the trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP calculates the net amount of all your trades on that day through your brokerage firm, and notifies your broker how much money and securities you need to deliver by T+2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T+2 Day (Settlement Day):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the morning, your broker transfers the net settlement funds to the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP confirms receipt of the funds and instructs the Securities Custody Agency to transfer 100 shares of stock from the seller’s brokerage account to your brokerage account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your broker updates your account information internally, showing that you now hold these 100 shares of stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, settlement is complete, and you officially become the legal owner of these 100 shares of stock, with the right to receive dividends, participate in voting, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, the traditional concept of “settlement” in stock trading is a product of historical practice combined with modern risk control theory. It evolved from a mechanism to solve the problem of paper-based certificate circulation into a core system that uses a central counterparty and net settlement to ensure the stability and efficiency of the entire financial market. This seemingly &amp;ldquo;delayed&amp;rdquo; design is actually the key firewall protecting every investor from counterparty default risks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Over-the-Counter (OTC) Clearing and Settlement of Digital Currencies: Unveiling the Mechanisms Behind 7x24 Continuous Trading</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:03:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/over-the-counter-otc-clearing-and-settlement-of-digital-currencies-unveiling-the-mechanisms-behind-7x24-continuous-trading/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional stock markets with defined opening and closing times, the digital currency market has attracted the attention of global investors due to its 7x24-hour continuous trading feature. This characteristic has also raised a core question: how are digital currencies cleared and settled in a world without a “market close” concept? Does it completely overturn these concepts in traditional finance? The answer is that digital currencies not only have clearing and settlement, but the way they are implemented and their system design are key to supporting all-day trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-difference-from-t2-to-real-time-settlement&#34;&gt;Core Difference: From T+2 to Real-Time Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional stock trading follows a “T+N” settlement system (e.g., T+1 in China, T+2 in the US), meaning that the actual transfer of funds and securities after a trade is executed (on day T) takes one or more business days to complete. During this period, clearing agencies conduct offsetting, calculate the receivables and payables of each party, and settle differences.
Digital currencies have completely changed this model. Its core settlement and delivery can be summarized as &lt;strong&gt;“Trade-to-Clear, Clear-to-Deliver,”&lt;/strong&gt; primarily due to its underlying blockchain technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockchain-a-natural-real-time-full-settlement-system&#34;&gt;Blockchain: A Natural Real-Time Full Settlement System
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blockchain itself can be considered a decentralized, immutable public ledger. Each transaction is recorded in a “block” and linked to the previous block through cryptographic methods, forming an irreversible “chain.” This process has the following key characteristics:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Real-Time:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a transaction is validated by nodes on the network and packaged into a block, the transfer of assets is completed. Although confirmation times vary depending on the congestion and block generation speed of different blockchain networks (such as Bitcoin and Ethereum), ranging from seconds to several minutes, this is a qualitative leap compared to traditional finance’s “T+N.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Full Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; Unlike net settlement in traditional clearing systems, each transaction on the blockchain is independent and fully executed. When A transfers a bitcoin to B, it is clearly recorded in the ledger as A&amp;rsquo;s address decreasing by one and B&amp;rsquo;s address increasing by one, without any netting of multiple transactions before transfer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Finality:&lt;/strong&gt; Once a block has been confirmed by enough subsequent blocks, this transaction is considered “final” and irreversible. This means that once settled, no one can undo or modify it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, fundamentally, &lt;strong&gt;asset settlement occurs on the blockchain, automatically completed through network consensus, without the need for traditional central clearing counterparties (CCPs) or custodians.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centralized-vs-decentralized-exchanges-different-clearing-and-settlement-pathways&#34;&gt;Centralized vs. Decentralized Exchanges: Different Clearing and Settlement Pathways
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although the underlying technology is decentralized, the primary venues where users conduct digital currency transactions – exchanges – are divided into two types: centralized (CEX) and decentralized (DEX), which have different clearing and settlement mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;centralized-exchanges-cex-internal-clearing--on-chain-settlement&#34;&gt;Centralized Exchanges (CEX): Internal Clearing + On-Chain Settlement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When users trade on centralized exchanges like Binance and Coinbase, they are actually operating within the exchange’s internal centralized ledger, rather than directly on the blockchain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Clearing (Ledgering):&lt;/strong&gt; When users deposit digital currencies or fiat currency into an exchange, the exchange records corresponding balances in its database for the user&amp;rsquo;s account. All buy and sell actions a user takes on the platform, such as buying BTC with USDT, essentially just represents increases and decreases in numbers within different accounts in the exchange’s database. This process is completed quickly by the exchange’s &lt;strong&gt;“matching engine,”&lt;/strong&gt; which can be considered a real-time internal clearing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Settlement (Withdrawal/Deposit):&lt;/strong&gt; The actual settlement that occurs on the blockchain only happens when users &lt;strong&gt;“deposit”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer from an external wallet into the exchange) and &lt;strong&gt;“withdraw”&lt;/strong&gt; (transfer out of the exchange to an external wallet). At this point, the exchange initiates a chain transaction to truly transfer asset ownership.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High-Performance Matching Engine:&lt;/strong&gt; Ensures rapid order matching under high concurrency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cold &amp;amp; Hot Wallet Separation:&lt;/strong&gt; Most user assets are stored in offline “cold wallets” to ensure security, while a small amount of assets is kept in online “hot wallets” to meet users’ daily withdrawal needs. This is the core design for ensuring 7x24 hours of asset safety operation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Internal Ledger Database:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizes a high-performance distributed database to ensure the accuracy and immediacy of internal transaction records.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;decentralized-exchanges-dexs-on-chain-atomic-swaps&#34;&gt;Decentralized Exchanges (DEXs): On-Chain Atomic Swaps
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In decentralized exchanges like Uniswap and SushiSwap, the trading process is radically different. Users always maintain control over their own wallet private keys, and transactions are executed directly on-chain through “smart contracts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Atomic Swap:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the core of how DEXs clear and settle trades. A smart contract is a program that automatically executes on a blockchain, ensuring that the exchange of assets is &amp;ldquo;atomic&amp;rdquo;—either both parties successfully exchange their assets, or neither does—preventing one party from sending assets without receiving confirmation from the other.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing and Settlement Synchronized:&lt;/strong&gt; Users authorize interactions with smart contracts through their wallets. Once a transaction is triggered and confirmed on the blockchain, clearing and settlement are instantly completed in a single step. The entire process requires no trust in any centralized intermediaries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Key Points:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Smart Contracts:&lt;/strong&gt; The core logic of the exchange, including trading pairs, liquidity pools, and pricing algorithms (such as Automated Market Makers - AMMs) are all hardcoded into the smart contract, making them public and transparent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;On-Chain Oracles:&lt;/strong&gt; Used to securely feed external market price information onto the blockchain, providing price references for certain types of DEXs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frontend:&lt;/strong&gt; Provides a web or app interface that allows users to connect their wallets and interact with the backend smart contracts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary-the-new-paradigm-for-digital-currency-clearing-and-settlement&#34;&gt;Summary: The New Paradigm for Digital Currency Clearing and Settlement
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In essence, digital currencies are not without the concepts of clearing and settlement; rather, they have transformed from a multi-party, time-consuming back-office process into an efficient, transparent, and even real-time automated one through blockchain technology and innovative system designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing Concepts Remain:&lt;/strong&gt; This is evident in CEXs as real-time matching and ledger accounting, and in DEXs, smart contracts incorporate clearing rules.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement is the Core Transformation:&lt;/strong&gt; Finality of settlement is guaranteed by blockchain consensus, enabling near real-time asset transfers – a cornerstone supporting 7x24 uninterrupted trading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;System Design Serves Uninterrupted Operation:&lt;/strong&gt; Whether it’s CEX cold and hot wallet architectures or DEX automated smart contracts, the primary design objective is to achieve a transaction environment without manual intervention and never closed, while ensuring security.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This disruptive clearing and settlement mechanism is not only a significant distinguishing feature of digital currency markets compared to traditional finance but also provides important insights into the future evolution of financial infrastructure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>RWA (Real World Assets) and Web3: A New Bottle of Old Wine?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/rwa-real-world-assets-and-web3-a-new-bottle-of-old-wine/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:48:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/rwa-real-world-assets-and-web3-a-new-bottle-of-old-wine/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Driven by the tide of technological innovation, RWA (Real World Assets) and Web3 have become hot topics in the financial industry. Traditional financial institutions – once regarded as conservative and stable giants – are now actively embracing these emerging concepts, vigorously promoting the development of RWA and DeFi (Decentralized Finance). However, behind this technology-driven transformation lies a core question worth pondering: Are these dazzling new concepts truly disruptive innovation, or simply giving traditional financial businesses a “new look”?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rwa-and-web3-decoding-core-concepts&#34;&gt;RWA and Web3: Decoding Core Concepts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RWA (Real World Assets), referring to real-world assets,&lt;/strong&gt; are tangible or intangible assets from the physical world that are issued and traded as digital assets on a blockchain through “tokenization” technology. These assets can encompass real estate, bonds, private credit, artwork, carbon credits, and more. Its core value lies in:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Liquidity:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividing illiquid assets (such as real estate) into smaller shares, reducing investment barriers, and enabling them to be traded easily on secondary markets like stocks.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Improving Transparency and Efficiency:&lt;/strong&gt; Utilizing blockchain’s immutability and traceability to simplify asset issuance, trading, and settlement processes, reduce intermediaries and human error, ultimately lowering costs and improving efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expanding Financing Channels:&lt;/strong&gt; Providing asset owners with a globalized, more efficient financing platform, breaking down geographical and traditional financial intermediary restrictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Web3, often referred to as “the next generation internet,”&lt;/strong&gt; has core principles of building a decentralized, user-owned and controlled internet ecosystem. Unlike the Web2 era dominated by a few tech giants, Web3 is based on blockchain technology, aiming to return data ownership and control to users. Its key features include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decentralization:&lt;/strong&gt; Information and applications are no longer stored on single company servers but distributed across numerous nodes in the network, reducing the risk of single points of failure and censorship.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;User Sovereignty:&lt;/strong&gt; Users have greater control over their personal data, choosing with whom to share it and how it is used.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Permissionless and Censorship-Resistant:&lt;/strong&gt; Anyone can participate in the network, publish applications or use services without needing approval from centralized authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-are-traditional-financial-institutions-embracing-rwa-and-defi&#34;&gt;Why Are Traditional Financial Institutions Embracing RWA and DeFi?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Traditional financial institutions are actively pushing for RWA and DeFi primarily due to the following strategic considerations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency Gains &amp;amp; Cost Reduction:&lt;/strong&gt; The traditional financial system is characterized by significant manual auditing, complex clearing and settlement processes, and burdensome compliance steps, leading to inefficiency and high costs. Through smart contracts and blockchain technology, DeFi and RWA can automate many of these processes, significantly reducing operational costs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Creating New Revenue Streams &amp;amp; Markets:&lt;/strong&gt; The emergence of RWA has opened up new asset classes and business models for financial institutions. For example, providing tokenized services for real estate or private credit projects, underwriting, and trading can generate new fees and consulting revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Responding to Competition &amp;amp; Maintaining Leadership:&lt;/strong&gt; Competition from fintech companies and crypto native enterprises is intensifying. By proactively positioning themselves in RWA and DeFi, traditional financial institutions can demonstrate their innovative capabilities, attract a new generation of clients, and secure a favorable position in the future financial landscape.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enhancing Transparency &amp;amp; Risk Management:&lt;/strong&gt; The transparency offered by blockchain helps improve the visibility of underlying asset information, allowing investors to better assess risks.  Furthermore, standardized token protocols and automated compliance checks can also enhance risk management efficiency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;business-essence-new-wine-in-an-old-bottle&#34;&gt;Business Essence: New Wine in an Old Bottle?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite RWA and DeFi bringing innovation in technology and models, from a core business logic perspective, the current RWA-related businesses undertaken by traditional financial institutions are largely extensions and digital upgrades of their &lt;strong&gt;traditional businesses&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Taking &lt;strong&gt;RWA&lt;/strong&gt; as an example, its core is to tokenize traditional assets. This process bears a striking resemblance to traditional &lt;strong&gt;Asset Securitization (ABS)&lt;/strong&gt;. ABS involves transforming illiquid assets with predictable cash flows into tradable securities in financial markets through packaging and layering. RWA simply shifts the carrier of securitization from traditional electronic certificates to blockchain-based tokens. Its essence remains &lt;strong&gt;credit intermediation and asset management&lt;/strong&gt; – selecting high-quality assets, structuring them, and selling them to investors. For example, packaging the future rental income rights of a commercial property into tokens is no different than issuing Real Estate Investment Trusts (REITs) in terms of its core financial nature.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similarly, in the &lt;strong&gt;DeFi&lt;/strong&gt; sector, although its “decentralized” concept aims to disrupt traditional financial intermediaries, the way current institutions are participating is primarily to &lt;strong&gt;utilize their technological advantages to optimize existing businesses&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, using smart contracts to simplify loan approval and disbursement processes or conducting more efficient cross-border payments and settlements through decentralized exchanges. Its core business of &lt;strong&gt;lending, trading, and payment&lt;/strong&gt; remains the cornerstone of the financial system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It can be said that traditional financial institutions driving RWA and DeFi is more like a “self-revolution,” namely, without changing its core financial functions, using new technologies to improve efficiency, reduce costs, and expand markets.&lt;/strong&gt; They are not trying to completely overthrow themselves but rather hope to consolidate and expand their industry position through technological innovation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In conclusion, RWA and Web3 have undoubtedly brought profound changes to the financial industry. They have solved many pain points in traditional finance through technology. However, for traditional financial institutions at this stage, embracing these technologies is more like a cautious and pragmatic strategic choice. Its core business logic has not fundamentally changed, still revolving around assets, credit, and transactions – these ancient financial themes.  As technology matures and regulation improves, we may see more disruptive financial innovations; however, given the current situation, “new wine in an old bottle” is perhaps the most accurate description.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Digital Currency Fundamentals</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/digital-currency-fundamentals/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:30:00 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/digital-currency-fundamentals/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We use an easy-to-understand analogy to explain the relationship between digital currency “mining” and “accounting,” as well as why Bitcoin and Ethereum have different supply caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let’s use an easy-to-understand analogy to explain the relationship between digital currency “mining” and “accounting,” as well as why Bitcoin and Ethereum have different supply caps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mining-and-accounting-a-public-participation-ledger-competition&#34;&gt;Mining and Accounting: A Public Participation Ledger Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine the entire Bitcoin network as a massive, public, and transparent electronic ledger. Every Bitcoin transaction (such as Zhang San sending a Bitcoin to Li Si) that occurs anywhere in the world needs to be recorded onto this large ledger for the transaction to be considered successful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But who records these transactions? If anyone could just write them down arbitrarily, it would become chaotic!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To solve this problem, the Bitcoin system has designed an ongoing “accounting competition.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accounting (Bookkeeping)&lt;/strong&gt;: This involves bundling all transactions that have occurred in the past approximately 10 minutes into a &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo; (which can be understood as a page of the ledger). This block not only includes transaction records but also contains a link to the previous &amp;ldquo;block&amp;rdquo; (the previous page of the ledger), linking one page after another to form an immutable chain, which is called “blockchain.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mining&lt;/strong&gt;: The core issue is: who has the right to record this page? The answer is: whoever first solves an extremely complex mathematical problem gets the accounting rights for that time. This solving process is形象地称为“mining”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why is it called &amp;ldquo;Mining&amp;rdquo;?&lt;/strong&gt; Because this process requires a large amount of computing resources (mining machines) and energy (power), just like real-world mining requires equipment and labor.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What is the purpose of solving the problem?&lt;/strong&gt; This mathematical problem itself has no practical meaning; its sole purpose is to increase the difficulty of accounting, ensuring that an average person (or a mining pool) can solve it approximately every 10 minutes. This guarantees stable ledger update speed and ensures system security. Anyone who wants to tamper with the ledger must have twice the computing power of the entire network, which is practically impossible economically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Therefore, the relationship between mining and accounting can be summarized as:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Mining” is the process of competing for “accounting rights,” while “Accounting” is the reward and responsibility after successfully “mining.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mining-and-accounting-a-public-participation-ledger-competition-1&#34;&gt;Mining and Accounting: A Public Participation Ledger Competition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Successful “miners” who successfully mine a block will perform two tasks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Package the latest transactions into a new block and connect it to the blockchain (completing the accounting).&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Receive rewards granted by the system.&lt;/strong&gt; This reward consists of two parts:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Block Reward:&lt;/strong&gt; The system automatically generates a batch of newly created Bitcoins as a reward. This is the only way that new Bitcoin is created.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Transaction Fees:&lt;/strong&gt; The fees paid by the payers of all transactions within the block.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-does-bitcoin-have-a-cap-while-ethereum-doesnt&#34;&gt;Why Does Bitcoin Have a Cap, While Ethereum Doesn&amp;rsquo;t?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This involves fundamental differences in the design philosophy and objectives of these two cryptocurrencies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitcoin-digital-gold-limited-supply&#34;&gt;Bitcoin: Digital Gold, Limited Supply
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bitcoin was designed from the outset to be a &lt;strong&gt;value storage&lt;/strong&gt; tool like gold. Gold is valuable for one key reason: its scarcity – the amount on Earth is finite.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To mimic this scarcity, Satoshi Nakamoto, the creator of Bitcoin, established two immutable rules during design:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Limited Supply:&lt;/strong&gt; The total supply of Bitcoin is permanently limited to &lt;strong&gt;21 million coins&lt;/strong&gt;. Not a fraction more, not a fraction less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Halving Production:&lt;/strong&gt; Approximately every four years (or with every 210,000 blocks mined), the block reward earned by miners will be reduced in half.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2009 began at 50 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2012 halving to 25 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2016 halving to 12.5 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2020 halving to 6.25 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2024 halving to 3.125 BTC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;…and so on, until approximately 2140, when the new reward will approach zero indefinitely.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This design gives Bitcoin &lt;strong&gt;deflationary&lt;/strong&gt; characteristics. Over time, the output of new coins decreases, and if demand remains constant or increases, its value theoretically rises. This reinforces its positioning as “digital gold.” Once all bitcoins have been mined, miners’ income will depend entirely on transaction fees.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ethereum-decentralized-application-platform-more-flexible-supply-strategy&#34;&gt;Ethereum: Decentralized Application Platform, More Flexible Supply Strategy
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ethereum’s goals differ from Bitcoin. It&amp;rsquo;s not just a digital currency; it’s a &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;world computer,&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; a platform designed to run smart contracts and decentralized applications (DApps).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can imagine Ethereum as a decentralized “app store” and “operating system.” Within this system, you need to pay “gas fees” to run your programs or make transactions, and this gas is Ether (ETH).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To maintain this vast and complex system, Ethereum continuously incentivizes miners (now validators) to protect the network’s security. If a hard cap were set like Bitcoin’s, with no new coins being mined after it&amp;rsquo;s finished, whether transaction fees alone would be sufficient to guarantee the network’s long-term security is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Ethereum chose a &lt;strong&gt;no-hard-cap&lt;/strong&gt; strategy. However, this doesn’t mean it will experience unlimited inflation. Ethereum’s monetary policy has undergone several significant adjustments:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early (Proof-of-Work PoW)&lt;/strong&gt;: Similar to Bitcoin, new coins were generated through mining, but there was no fixed total limit or set halving cycle. This resulted in a relatively high inflation rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;London Upgrade (EIP-1559)&lt;/strong&gt;: Introduced an “burn fee” mechanism. A portion of the base fees paid by users for transactions would be directly “burned” (permanently removed from circulation) instead of going to miners. This meant that when the network was active with transactions, the amount of ETH burned could exceed the newly issued amount, leading to &lt;strong&gt;deflation&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Merge (The Merge)&lt;/strong&gt;: Ethereum transitioned from “mining” (Proof-of-Work PoW) to “staking” (Proof-of-Stake PoS). No longer do miners expend electricity solving problems; instead, “validators” earn accounting rights and rewards by staking their own ETH. This shift &lt;strong&gt;significantly reduced the issuance rate of new ETH&lt;/strong&gt; (over 90%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In summary, here are Ethereum’s key characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No Hard Cap&lt;/strong&gt;: Provides flexibility for the network&amp;rsquo;s long-term security and development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Supply&lt;/strong&gt;: Through “burn mechanisms” and “staking rewards,” its total supply can be mildly inflationary or experience deflation during periods of high transaction activity. Its goal isn’t absolute scarcity, but rather to &lt;strong&gt;maintain sufficient security while ensuring ETH remains available as “fuel.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Digital Gold, Value Storage&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;World Computer, Decentralized Application Platform&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-1&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Supply Limit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Yes&lt;/strong&gt;, 21 Million coins&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;No&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-2&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin (BTC)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum (ETH)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monetary Policy&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Deflationary (Fixed supply, halving production)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Dynamic Supply (Minting + Burning, potentially inflationary or deflationary)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-3&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Bitcoin&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Ethereum&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Issuance Purpose&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Reward miners until the block is mined&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Long-term, continuous security and operation of the network&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;key-differences-overview-4&#34;&gt;Key Differences Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hopefully, this straightforward explanation will help you understand their relationship and differences!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>HKSG Flash Crash Sell-Off Case</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2025 19:12:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hksg-flash-crash-sell-off-case/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;[The company recently raised capital in the Hong Kong market](Nine Fang Zhi Tu.pdf), this fundraising is similar to Xiaomi’s operation, and this article breaks down the details. &amp;ndash;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nine-fang-intelligent-investment-and-sales-interpretation&#34;&gt;Nine Fang Intelligent Investment and Sales Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What are the fees associated with participating in the offering; when can these stocks be sold, what other important information is contained in this document?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This placement activity is a &lt;strong&gt;pre-existing shareholder first, then new&lt;/strong&gt; placement method, targeting new investors (placements), &lt;strong&gt;does not involve retail investor subscriptions&lt;/strong&gt;, therefore:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you are not a placement agent-selected placement recipient (i.e., professional/institutional/individual investors), you do not need to pay any fees.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-placement-1&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Placement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, if you are a placement agent, the fees involved include:
| Placement Price | ✅ Yes | HKD 39.25 per share |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-reselling&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Reselling
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Reseller&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Commission&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Resell price &lt;strong&gt;excludes&lt;/strong&gt; commission, transaction fees, stamp duty etc.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangement&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Brokerage Agent&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Transaction Fee / Exchange Trading Fee&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Charged according to Hong Kong Stock Exchange rules&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-fees-associated-with-brokerage-arrangements&#34;&gt;✅ Fees Associated with Brokerage Arrangements
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Fee Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Borne by Broker&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Notes&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp Duty&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Stamp duty of 0.13% is payable for Hong Kong stock purchases&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-costs-associated-with-distribution&#34;&gt;✅ Costs Associated with Distribution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-shares-can-be-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Shares Can Be Sold
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the announcement content:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The share placement will be undertaken by the placing agents based on their best efforts to place shares with no less than six noteholders… &lt;strong&gt;It is anticipated that none of the noteholders will become a major shareholder of the Company immediately following completion of the share placement.&lt;/strong&gt;”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-when-can-shares-sold&#34;&gt;✅ When Can Shares Sold?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This means:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shares sold through the placement can be freely traded once settlement is complete;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is no lock-up period;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;They can be bought and sold freely on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange secondary market;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The placement deadline is &lt;strong&gt;July 17, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;, with expected settlement to occur shortly after &lt;strong&gt;July 17th&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-important-information-in-announcement&#34;&gt;✅ Important Information in Announcement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h4 id=&#34;use-of-funds-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Funds (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine Square Capital will use this money to do four things:
| On-Chain Financial Resource Investment | Undefined | Invest in RWA underlying assets, digital asset exchanges, trust banks, and stablecoin operators |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Services Layout | Undefined | Investment services for digital assets targeting consumers in Hong Kong and the Middle East regions |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)**
| Purpose | Percentage | Description |
|---|---|---|
| Digital Asset Investment Advisory New Model | Unspecified | AI + Research, Combining MCN Operational Experience |
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;funding-allocation-hk74622-billion-net&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Funding Allocation (HK$7.4622 Billion Net)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Percentage&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Supplemental Liquidity Funding&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Unspecified&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;General corporate use&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;offer-price-discount-is-significant&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Offer Price Discount is Significant&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;6.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the closing price of 41.75 HKD on July 15th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;17.0%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 5-day average price of 47.30 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discounted by &lt;strong&gt;15.3%&lt;/strong&gt; compared to the past 10-day average price of 46.36 HKD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;#### **Share Structure Changes**

- Following the public offering, **total shares outstanding increased from 448 million to 468 million**.
- Existing shareholders’ ownership percentages were **slightly diluted**, but they **continue to maintain a controlling stake**.
- An additional 20,000,000 shares will be held by the underwriters, representing approximately **4.27%** of total outstanding shares.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-disclaimer&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk Disclaimer&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h4&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The offering may not be completed, and requires fulfillment of multiple prerequisites (such as market stability, regulatory approval, and the absence of significant adverse events)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If it is not completed within 14 days, the subscription matter will automatically become invalid.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Retail investors are excluded from this placement; the placed shares have no lock-up period and can be traded immediately after settlement. Jiu Fang Investment plans to use HK$746 million to invest in digital assets and on-chain finance, potentially transitioning towards Web3 and AI robo-advisor directions in the future.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;first-old-then-new-distribution-method-explained&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;First Old, Then New&amp;rdquo; Distribution Method Explained
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Existing shareholders first old shares then new&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; is a &lt;strong&gt;common Hong Kong distribution method&lt;/strong&gt;, known in English as &lt;strong&gt;Top-up Placement&lt;/strong&gt;, which you can understand as a two-step operation of “&lt;strong&gt;major shareholders sell old shares first and then subscribe to new shares&lt;/strong&gt;”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-to-understand-it&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example to understand it
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Taking the case of &lt;strong&gt;Jiutian Intelligence Investment&lt;/strong&gt; as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 1: Major shareholders sell old shares (First Old)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Existing shareholders (such as Coreworth Investments) sell their existing holdings of &lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 old shares&lt;/strong&gt; to market investors (the underwriter) at a price of HKD 39.25 per share.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This results in the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder reducing their holding&lt;/strong&gt;, and the &lt;strong&gt;total issued capital remains unchanged&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Step 2: Company issues new shares to major shareholders (Later New)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The company then issues an equal number (&lt;strong&gt;20,000,000 shares&lt;/strong&gt;) of new shares to these major shareholders at a price of HKD 39.25.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The major shareholder uses the proceeds from selling old shares to buy back new shares, &lt;strong&gt;restoring their holding quantity to its original state&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, the total issued capital increases (from 448 million shares to 468 million shares), &lt;strong&gt;effectively meaning the company has successfully raised capital&lt;/strong&gt;, while the &lt;strong&gt;major shareholder&amp;rsquo;s shareholding ratio is slightly diluted&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Quick Fundraising&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Avoid the lengthy process of issuing new shares, instead selling old shares first and then supplementing with new shares to quickly raise capital.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-1&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain Control&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The majority shareholders will maintain their voting power, and control won&amp;rsquo;t be significantly diluted.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-2&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Purpose&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attract New Investors&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Through discounted share sales (private placements), attract institutional or high-net-worth investors to enter the market, optimizing the shareholder structure.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-are-we-doing-this-3&#34;&gt;✅ Why are we doing this?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Old Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Not newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Can be immediately traded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;These are existing shares on the market, which can be directly circulated after being sold to new investors.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-1&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Type&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Newly Issued Shares&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Immediately Tradeable&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Description&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;New Shares&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Newly issued&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;⚠️ Lock-up Period (typically 180 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Shares newly issued by the company, given to original shareholders, and typically require a lock-up period.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-key-differences-old-stocks-vs-new-stocks-2&#34;&gt;✅ Key Differences: Old Stocks vs. New Stocks
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;-one-sentence-summary&#34;&gt;✅ One-Sentence Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;Sell Old, Buy New&amp;rdquo; refers to major shareholders initially selling their existing shares to the market and then purchasing an equal amount of new shares from the company, simultaneously raising capital for the company while maintaining control.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-connect-issuance-rules-interpretation&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Connect Issuance Rules Interpretation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Kimi: Your question is very central: &lt;strong&gt;Why do Hong Kong-listed companies seem to be able to “freely” issue shares? Is the Hong Kong market rulebook particularly relaxed?&lt;/strong&gt;
The answer is: &lt;strong&gt;Yes, HKEX offers significantly more flexibility than the Shanghai A-share market&lt;/strong&gt;, but it’s &lt;strong&gt;not “unlimited,”&lt;/strong&gt; rather there&amp;rsquo;s a system of &lt;strong&gt;“relaxed but limited” rules.”&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require shareholder meeting approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ The Board of Directors can authorize share issuance not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;20% of the total equity&lt;/strong&gt; annually at the annual general meeting, and no further meetings are required thereafter.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ Each issuance must be held with a &lt;strong&gt;separate shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt; and pass by a 2/3 majority vote.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Does it require SEC approval?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;❌ As long as it’s no more than 20% of share capital + offering price is no more than 20%, it can “flash allocation”&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Must undergo SEC &lt;strong&gt;case-by-case review&lt;/strong&gt;, which takes longer&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Issuance Ratio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Maximum of 20% per issuance, cumulative dilution within 12 months shall not exceed 25%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Generally not exceeding &lt;strong&gt;30%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-2&#34;&gt;✅ H-Shares vs A-Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discount Margin Limit&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Offering price shall not be lower than 80% of the market price (maximum discount of 20%)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Non-public placements shall not be lower than 80% of the market price&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-ipo-rules-comparison-key-differences-1&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: IPO Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lock-up Period&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ Typically &lt;strong&gt;30 days or none&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;6~36 months&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-h-shares-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences-3&#34;&gt;✅ H Shares vs A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Project&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;H Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Rules&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Use of Proceeds Restrictions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Disclosure of use only, no substantive review&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;✅ &lt;strong&gt;Must detail use of proceeds, SEC can veto&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-hong-kong-stocks-vs-a-shares-issuance-rules-comparison-key-differences&#34;&gt;✅ Hong Kong Stocks vs. A Shares: Issuance Rules Comparison (Key Differences)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-why-does-the-hong-kong-stock-exchange-look-casual&#34;&gt;✅ Why Does the Hong Kong Stock Exchange Look “Casual”?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“General Mandate” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
Once a year, shareholders authorize the board to issue up to 20% new shares at their annual general meeting. Afterwards, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meetings are required&lt;/strong&gt;, and the board can selectively issue shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Flash Placement” Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt;
If the issuance does not exceed 20% of the share capital and the discount is no more than 20%, &lt;strong&gt;the issuance can be completed within 24 hours without approval&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No SEC Case-by-Case Approval:
The Hong Kong Stock Exchange only conducts &lt;strong&gt;formative review&lt;/strong&gt;, without substantive intervention in the use of funds or company quality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-lets-take-an-example-why-was-jiufang-zhitou-able-to-do-old-and-new-this-time&#34;&gt;✅ Let&amp;rsquo;s take an example: Why was JiuFang ZhiTou able to &amp;ldquo;do old and new&amp;rdquo; this time?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JiuFang ZhiTou obtained a &lt;strong&gt;general authorization&lt;/strong&gt; at the &lt;strong&gt;2025 June 20th shareholder meeting&lt;/strong&gt;, allowing for up to a 20% increase in new shares (i.e., up to 89,671,400 shares).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This issuance of 20,000,000 shares represents only &lt;strong&gt;4.46% of the capital&lt;/strong&gt;, far below the 20% limit, and &lt;strong&gt;fully complies with the authorization conditions&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, &lt;strong&gt;no further shareholder meeting is needed&lt;/strong&gt; nor &lt;strong&gt;is approval from the Securities Regulatory Commission required&lt;/strong&gt;; the board of directors can make the decision to implement it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-1&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong stocks allow “board of directors + annual authorization” rapid issuance under a streamlined process, provided it doesn’t exceed 20% of the share capital and the price cap, enabling “flash placement,” while A-shares require shareholder approval plus SEC review, resulting in a longer, more restrictive procedure.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-summary-in-one-sentence-2&#34;&gt;✅ Summary in one sentence
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, Jiu Fang Zhi Tu (Nine Fang Intelligent Investment) is not “arbitrary issuance,” but rather &lt;strong&gt;legally and compliantly utilized the relaxed mechanisms of the Hong Kong stock market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Comprehensive Analysis: Capital Gains Tax, CRS, and Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp; US Stocks Investment Tax Guide</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:12:40 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/comprehensive-analysis-capital-gains-tax-crs-and-inland-residents-hong-kong-us-stock-investment-tax-guide/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks, understanding relevant tax regulations is crucial. This article will comprehensively analyze what capital gains tax is, why it applies to investments in Hong Kong and US stocks, and explain the workings of CRS (Common Reporting Standard). Furthermore, this article will also provide detailed answers regarding the tax responsibilities and specific tax rates for mainland residents investing in Hong Kong and US stocks through various channels (Hong Kong brokers, Hong Kong-Shanghai Link, and Shenzhen-Hong Kong Link).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-concept-breakdown&#34;&gt;Core Concept Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-capital-gains-tax-cgt&#34;&gt;What is Capital Gains Tax (CGT)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Capital Gains Tax (CGT), often abbreviated as CGT, is a tax levied on the &lt;strong&gt;profits realized from selling assets&lt;/strong&gt;. These assets can include stocks, bonds, real estate, precious metals, and more. When you sell an asset for a price higher than your purchase price, the resulting gains (known as capital gains) may be subject to Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that not all countries or regions levy Capital Gains Tax. For example, Hong Kong currently does not impose Capital Gains Tax.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;why-are-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-subject-to-capital-gains-tax&#34;&gt;Why are Hong Kong and US Stocks Subject to Capital Gains Tax?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States is a country that levies capital gains tax. For non-U.S. taxpayers (such as most mainland investors), while selling US stocks typically qualifies for exemption from capital gains tax, certain conditions must be met (e.g., residency in the U.S. for no more than 183 days within a year). However, dividends received from US stocks are subject to withholding income tax at a rate of usually 30%, but according to the China-U.S. Tax Agreement, mainland Chinese residents can apply to reduce this rate to 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks:&lt;/strong&gt; As stated above, Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax. Therefore, regardless of the channel through which you trade Hong Kong stocks, no tax is payable on the difference between purchase and sale prices. This doesn’t mean that mainland residents don&amp;rsquo;t need to declare this income to the Chinese mainland tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-crs-reporting-common-reporting-standard&#34;&gt;What is CRS Reporting (Common Reporting Standard)?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CRS, or the “Common Reporting Standard,” is a global standard for the automatic exchange of financial account information. Its primary purpose is to combat tax evasion involving offshore accounts and cross-border tax avoidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How it Works:&lt;/strong&gt; In simple terms, financial institutions (such as banks and brokers) that have signed up to CRS need to identify the non-resident taxpayers’ accounts and report their account information (including names, addresses, taxpayer status, account balances, and annual total income) to their local tax authorities. These tax authorities then exchange this information with the relevant tax authorities of the countries/territories where the account holders are residents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Mainland Investors:&lt;/strong&gt; For mainland residents who open accounts with Hong Kong brokers, due to their tax residency being China, Hong Kong financial institutions will exchange their account information through the Hong Kong Customs and Excise Department to the Chinese State Taxation Administration. This means that the inland tax authorities can gain access to information about its residents’ overseas financial assets and income, providing a basis for collecting global income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inland-resident-hong-kong--us-stock-trading-tax-breakdown&#34;&gt;Inland Resident Hong Kong &amp;amp; US Stock Trading Tax Breakdown
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, Chinese tax residents are required to pay personal income tax on their &lt;strong&gt;income sourced globally&lt;/strong&gt;. This means that even if investment gains occur abroad and may be exempt in the local jurisdiction, there is still an obligation to declare and pay taxes to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Chinese tax department has intensified its enforcement of taxation regarding individual overseas income.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-and-us-stocks-via-hong-kong-brokers&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong and US Stocks via Hong Kong Brokers
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you are a mainland resident, trading Hong Kong and US stocks through Hong Kong brokers (such as Futu Securities, Tiger Brokerage, etc.), your tax responsibilities are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; The profits you receive from the difference between buying and selling US stocks belong to “transfer pricing income.” According to China’s Personal Income Tax Law, it should be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities. Although the United States typically exempts non-residents from capital gains taxes, Chinese tax residents still need to pay taxes on this global income.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from US stocks will usually have 10% withheld by the broker as estimated income tax (enjoying preferential tax agreements between China and the US). This tax paid abroad can be offset when declaring it in China, but the offset amount cannot exceed the taxable amount calculated according to Chinese tax laws.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stock Trading:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; Although Hong Kong does not levy capital gains tax, profits from Hong Kong stock trading (price differences) are also considered “transfer pricing income” and must be declared and paid at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; to the Chinese tax authorities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividends:&lt;/strong&gt; Dividends received from H shares (companies registered in mainland China and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 20% personal income tax withheld by the company. Dividends received from non-H shares (companies registered in Hong Kong or overseas and listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange) will have 10% dividend tax withheld in Hong Kong. This tax paid abroad can also be offset when declaring it in China.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-hong-kong-stocks-via-the-hksar-mainland-china-bond-connect-hk--sh&#34;&gt;Trading Hong Kong Stocks via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To promote capital market connectivity between Mainland China and Hong Kong, the government has introduced targeted tax incentives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Gains:&lt;/strong&gt; According to announcements from the Ministry of Finance, the State Taxation Administration, and the Securities and Futures Commission, personal income tax is currently &lt;strong&gt;exempted&lt;/strong&gt; on any &lt;strong&gt;capital gains&lt;/strong&gt; realized by mainland individual investors through the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH) when buying and selling listed stocks on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. This incentive policy has been explicitly &lt;strong&gt;extended to December 31, 2027&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dividend Income:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), the H Share company will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For dividend income received from investing in &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Non-H Shares&lt;/strong&gt; via the HKSAR-Mainland China Bond Connect (HK &amp;amp; SH), China Merchants Service Bureau will withhold personal income tax at a rate of &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt;. Any pre-paid personal income tax paid in Hong Kong can be claimed for tax refund by submitting a valid withholding certificate to the relevant tax authority of China Merchants Service Bureau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Brokerage Firms&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, 20% Rate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US Withholding 10%, Can be Deducible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-1&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reported to Mainland, Rate 20%&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Withheld 20%; Non-H Shares: Hong Kong Advance 10%, Deductible in Mainland&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-2&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Channel&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Investment Target&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Capital Gains Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Dividend/Bonus Tax&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect (沪港通)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Stocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exempted (until end of 2027)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;H Shares: Deduction of 20%; Non-H Shares: Listing Deduction of 20%, Hong Kong Tax Already Paid Can Be Refunded&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tax-highlights-summary-3&#34;&gt;Tax Highlights Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Important Note:&lt;/strong&gt; The information above is based on current policies. Tax regulations may change, and investors are advised to consult with a professional tax advisor or monitor the latest information released by the tax authorities before making investment decisions and filing tax returns to ensure compliance. The typical time frame for reporting foreign income is from March 1st to June 30th of the following year.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>SPDR S&amp;P 500 ETF Trust Code Analysis: SST1G182500500.U Why is the underlying stock code SST 1 instead of SST?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spdr-sp-500-etf-trust-options-code-analysis-sst1g182500500u-why-is-the-underlying-stock-code-sst-1-instead-of-sst/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 14:49:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/spdr-sp-500-etf-trust-options-code-analysis-sst1g182500500u-why-is-the-underlying-stock-code-sst-1-instead-of-sst/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This report aims to deeply analyze the U.S. equity options code “SST1G182500500.U,” particularly why its underlying stock code portion is displayed as “SST 1” instead of the original “SST” when sent to Interactive Brokers (IB). By analyzing the standardization structure of option symbols, related company behavior, and broker’s internal processing mechanisms, this report will elucidate the reasons behind this phenomenon and its impact on options traders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;us-equity-options-symbol-standardization-osi&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Equity Options Symbol Standardization (OSI)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To ensure the efficient operation and transparency of the options market, the U.S. Option Clearing Corporation (OCC) has established a standardized options symbol system known as the Options Symbol Initiative (OSI). This system employs a unified alphanumeric format to clearly encode key information about the option contract &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Since February 12, 2010, the 21-character OSI standard has been fully implemented in the United States and Canada, replacing the previous chaotic five-character code format &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A standard OSI options symbol typically contains the following four core components:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underlying Asset Code (Root Symbol)&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the code for the underlying stock or ETF that the option is based on.  This field can contain up to six characters, and is usually the same as the trading code for the underlying stock. For example, the root symbol for Nike options is “NKE” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If the root symbol is less than six characters, it must be padded with spaces to reach a length of six characters &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Expiration Date&lt;/strong&gt;: This portion consists of six digits representing the expiration date in “year year-month month-day day (yymmdd)” format. For example, &amp;ldquo;220624&amp;rdquo; represents an option that expires on June 24, 2022 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Call/Put Indicator&lt;/strong&gt;: This is a single-character field indicating the type of option. ‘C’ represents a call option (Call Option), which grants the holder the right to purchase the underlying stock at a specified price; ‘P’ represents a put option (Put Option), which grants the holder the right to sell the underlying stock at a specified price &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strike Price&lt;/strong&gt;: This is the preset price at which the option can be exercised to buy (call) or sell (put) the underlying stock. In the OSI format, the strike price is represented by eight digits, with the last three digits representing the decimal place (“mills,” hundredths of a dollar). To read the actual strike price, you must divide these eight digits by 1,000, or move the decimal point three places to the left. For example, “00099000” represents a strike price of $99.00 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Options, as derivatives, derive their value from the underlying asset. Most U.S. options are traded on exchanges such as the Chicago Board Options Exchange (CBOE) and cleared through the OCC. As the world’s largest equity derivative clearing organization, the OCC operates under the supervision of the SEC and CFTC to ensure the stability and integrity of the options market &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;parsing-option-code-sst1g182500500u&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parsing Option Code SST1G182500500.U&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The option code “SST1G182500500.U” includes some elements of the OSI format, but also contains non-standard representations. This is often due to company-specific adjustments or broker internal display conventions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;sst1-adjusted-underlying-code&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SST1: Adjusted Underlying Code&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;“SST1” is the most important part of this option code, directly answering users’ core question about why the underlying code is “SST 1” rather than “SST.” The “1” suffix indicates that this option contract has undergone adjustments due to company actions (such as stock splits or mergers).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to OCC’s official memorandum #56689, dated June 11, 2025, which clearly states: “Option symbol: SST changed to SST1,” effective date is June 12, 2025 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This memo provides a clear explanation as to why the underlying symbol is “SST1.” Brokers like Robinhood have also confirmed this convention, stating that “if held option contracts on shares experience a reverse split…the stock code will be appended with a number. For example, if holding ABC options contracts, after a reverse split they will display as ABC1” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This industry standard further confirms the validity and purpose of the “SST1” suffix.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;g1825-expiration-date-non-standard-format&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;G1825: Expiration Date (Non-Standard Format)&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “G1825” portion differs significantly from the OSI standard’s “Year-Month-Day (yymmdd)” format (e.g., 2025 July 18 should be “250718”) &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref5:2&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.
Prior to OSI implementation, option symbols were typically represented by single-letter codes for the month of expiration &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. In this older convention, the letter “G” represented the call option for July &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:5&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. If following this logic, “18” would represent the date, and “25” would represent the year. Therefore, “G1825” most likely represents &lt;strong&gt;July 18, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the OSI standard’s explicit deprecation of this letter-code expiration date representation &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, “SST1” (a common OSI adjustment convention) persists alongside “G1825,” indicating that Interactive Brokers or its data sources may employ a hybrid or internal representation. This could be a legacy format for adjusting options, or a proprietary display convention used by the broker combining elements of the old symbol system with new adjustment indicators. The inconsistency in option symbols – the core OSI adjustment root symbol coexisting with a non-standard expiration date format – reflects the challenges in financial data standardization at the “last mile.” While central institutions strive for uniformity, brokers may introduce subtle variations or additional identifiers due to compatibility concerns, internal data management considerations, or platform functionality. This results in potential discrepancies between the “official” OSI symbol and the symbols a user might see or need to input on a specific trading platform. Therefore, options traders not only need to understand the general OSI standard but also must be aware of and adapt to any subtle differences in symbol representation employed by individual brokers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;00500-strike-price&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;00500: Strike Price&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “00500” provided by the user represents a five-digit number, which does not align with the eight-digit strike price field in the OSI standard [1]. If following OSI rules, dividing the eight digits by 1,000 would yield a strike price of $0.50 (as “00000500” equates to $0.50).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Considering that SST stock underwent a reverse split of 10 shares for every 1 share [9], strike prices are typically adjusted according to the split ratio (e.g., a $5.00 strike price would become $0.50 after a 1:10 split), making a very low strike price like $0.50 entirely reasonable for the adjusted options. The five digits “00500” likely represent the value 500, and when converted to “mills” (one-thousandth of a dollar), it equates to $0.50. The discrepancy in digit count may indicate that IB’s internal representation truncates leading zeros for very small strike prices before converting to the full 8-digit OSI format, or utilizes a different internal encoding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;u-broker-specific-suffix&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;.U: Broker-Specific Suffix&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;.U&amp;rdquo; suffix is not part of the standardized OCC/OSI 21 character format ¹. It is highly likely to be an internal identifier or marker used by Interactive Brokers (IB) or its specific market data vendors. Such suffixes are common in proprietary systems, used to convey additional information about contracts, such as their listed exchange, specific trading characteristics, or a unique identifier within their database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-focus-sst1-root-symbol&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Focus: SST1 Root Symbol&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite potential minor deviations from the strict OSI specification for other option symbols, the “SST1” root symbol is undoubtedly the most critical element. It directly addresses the user’s core question and points to the company behavior that led to the symbol changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;company-behaviors-impact-system1-inc-ssts-reverse-split&#34;&gt;Company Behavior&amp;rsquo;s Impact: System1, Inc. (SST)&amp;rsquo;s Reverse Split
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;corporate-actions-universal-impact-on-option-contracts-adjustment&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate Actions&amp;rsquo; Universal Impact on Option Contracts Adjustment&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Options are financial derivatives whose value is directly derived from the underlying asset, such as stock [1]. Therefore, any significant event affecting the underlying security (typically referred to as corporate actions) must be reflected in the terms of open option contracts. This ensures that the economic value and integrity of the derivative remain intact [^13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corporate actions encompass a wide range of events, including stock splits (both forward and reverse), mergers, acquisitions, special dividends, and spin-offs [^13]. Each type of action can have a unique impact on option contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clearing Corporations (CCs) play a crucial role as the central clearinghouses for options in the United States. They are legally responsible for determining and implementing necessary adjustments to open option contracts in response to these corporate actions [^13]. These adjustments are formally communicated to market participants through detailed OCC Information Notices &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The method of adjustment varies depending on the corporate action, but may include changes to the option’s strike price, the number of shares (or other asset, referred to as the deliverable) represented by each contract, or even the option symbol itself. The overall objective of these adjustments is to preserve the total intrinsic value of the option contracts for option holders [^13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;reverse-stock-splits-and-their-typical-impact-on-option-terms&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverse Stock Splits and Their Typical Impact on Option Terms&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A reverse stock split is a corporate action designed to reduce the number of outstanding shares while proportionally increasing the price per share&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For example, a 1-for-10 reverse split means that shareholders previously holding ten shares now own one share, but the value of the new share is theoretically ten times that of the old share&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For options contracts, reverse splits typically require adjustments to contract terms. The OCC (Options Clearing Corporation) is responsible for determining the specific adjustment methods, which may involve changing the number of underlying shares represented by each option contract (e.g., in a 1:10 split, reducing from 100 shares to 10 shares) and/or proportionally increasing the strike price[^13]. The goal is to ensure that the total value represented by the contracts remains consistent with the value before the split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Common results of reverse stock splits are changes in option symbols, typically adding a numerical suffix to the original stock code (e.g., “1”). This helps distinguish these adjusted contracts from newly issued standard options after the split&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. A significant side effect is that these adjusted options often experience a substantial decline in liquidity[^13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;system1-inc-sst-1-for-10-reverse-stock-split-details&#34;&gt;System1, Inc. (SST) 1-for-10 Reverse Stock Split Details
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;System1, Inc. (NYSE: SST) is a full-channel customer acquisition marketing platform that announced a 1-for-10 reverse stock split. This corporate action became effective prior to the market open on June 12, 2025 &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary motivation for this reverse split was to increase the per-share trading price of its Class A common stock, allowing the company to regain compliance with New York Stock Exchange (NYSE) listing requirements &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:6&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a direct result of this split, each 10 shares of common stock (including restricted and outstanding shares) automatically converted into 1 new share &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This significantly reduced the total number of issued and outstanding Class A common shares from approximately 79.8 million to 7.98 million &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite the reverse split, the company’s Class A common stock continued to trade on the New York Stock Exchange using its existing trading code “SST”, but the CUSIP number was updated &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occs-role-in-determining-and-implementing-adjustments-the-symbolic-change-from-sst-to-sst1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC’s Role in Determining and Implementing Adjustments: The Symbolic Change from SST to SST1&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To address System1, Inc.’s reverse stock split, OCC issued memorandum #56689 on June 11, 2025, detailing the specific adjustments for options contracts &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The memo explicitly stated that, effective June 12, 2025, “Option Symbol: SST changed to SST1” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This official instruction from OCC was the direct cause of the “SST1” root symbol appearing in user option codes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The memo further clarified the adjustment terms: “Contract Multiplier: 1. Strike Price Divider: 1. New Multiplier: 100 (e.g., for any dollar extension to premium or strike price, 1.00 would equal $100)” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref5:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This indicated that while the nominal contract multiplier remained at 100, the underlying asset referenced by the “SST1” symbol had been adjusted to reflect a split of 10 shares for every 1 reverse stock split, effectively maintaining the total contract value. The memo explicitly stated, “The price of SST1 will be determined as follows: SST1 = 0.10 (SST)” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref6:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This meant that each “SST1” option contract now represented 100 units, but each unit corresponded to 0.1 shares of the original SST stock, thereby preserving the total contract value after the split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustments-to-sst-option-underlyings&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustments to SST Option Underlyings&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;For a 1-for-10 reverse stock split, OCC’s adjustments to existing SST options contracts aim to maintain the total economic value of the contracts. OCC did not change the number of shares per contract from 100 to 10 (which could occur in some split scenarios), but instead chose to adjust the &lt;strong&gt;underlying symbol itself to “SST1”&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This “SST1” symbol indicates that the option contract continues to represent 100 units, but each unit now corresponds to 0.1 shares of the original SST stock &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref7:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Therefore, an “SST1” option contract effectively represents 100 * 0.1 = 10 shares after the 10-for-1 split. The strike price remains nominal in the symbol, but is now applied to this revalued underlying. This approach ensures that the total exercisable value of the contract remains consistent with its pre-split value. For example, if an option was exercised at a strike price of $50 before a 1:10 split, the exercise value would be $5,000 (100 shares * $50). After the split, the new issued post-split SST option strike price will be $500. However, the adjusted “SST1” option maintains its original strike price (e.g., $50) and applies it to a value of 1/10 of the underlying, effectively preserving the $5,000 total value [^13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Table 1: Impact of SST Reverse Split on Option Contract Characteristics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;| &lt;strong&gt;Underlying Stock Symbol&lt;/strong&gt; | SST | SST (Applicable to New Shares and New Options) |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustment-to-the-deliverable-of-sst-options-contracts&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustment to the Deliverable of SST Options Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Before 1-for-10 Reverse Split &amp;amp; 10-for-1 Split (Prior to June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;After 1-for-10 Reverse Split &amp;amp; 10-for-1 Split (Post June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Adjusted Option Symbol&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SST (Root symbol of the standard option)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SST1 (Root symbol of the existing, post-split option)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustment-to-the-deliverable-of-sst-options-contracts-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustment to the Deliverable of SST Options Contracts&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Before 1:10 Reverse Split (Prior to June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;After 1:10 Reverse Split (Post June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number of Shares Covered per Contract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;100 shares SST&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;10 shares SST split (through 100 units of SST1)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustment-to-sst-option-deliverable&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustment to SST Option Deliverable&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Before Split-Reverse Split (Prior to June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;After Split-Reverse Split (Post June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustment-to-sst-option-deliverable-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustment to SST Option Deliverable&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Before 1-for-10 Reverse Split (Prior to June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;After 1-for-10 Reverse Split (Post June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Underlying CUSIP&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Original CUSIP&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;New CUSIP (87200P208) 10&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustment-to-sst-option-deliverable-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustment to SST Option Deliverable&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Feature&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Before 1-for-10 Split and Reverse Split (Prior to June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;After 1-for-10 Split and Reverse Split (Post June 12, 2025)&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Liquidity of Adjusted Options&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Normal&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Decreasing 13&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;occ-adjustments-to-sst-option-deliverable-characteristics&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;OCC Adjustments to SST Option Deliverable Characteristics&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Company actions, particularly reverse stock splits, while crucial for a company’s finances, often have “unforeseen” impacts on the derivatives market, introducing significant inefficiencies. The creation of unique “post-split options” – characterized by low liquidity, complex pricing and trading – fragments this security&amp;rsquo;s option market. This fragmentation reduces overall market efficiency and can lead to wider bid-ask spreads and difficulty in price discovery. This situation reflects a trade-off between corporate governance needs (such as stock splits to meet listing requirements) and the expectation of a fully liquid and simple derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Options Clearing Corporation (OCC) plays a critical role in this process. Company actions fundamentally alter the nature of the underlying security. Without intervention, this would create material discrepancies and potentially unfair outcomes within derivative contracts. The OCC utilizes its regulatory authority and clearing corporation functions to adjust option terms. This ensures that the economic value of the options is preserved and that the market remains orderly and fair. This ongoing adjustment mechanism is crucial for maintaining overall market integrity and ensuring continuity of value for option holders as the underlying company evolves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-interactive-brokers-requires-sst-1&#34;&gt;Why Interactive Brokers Requires “SST 1”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;brokerage-handling-of-adjustment-post-expiration-option-symbols&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brokerage Handling of Adjustment Post-Expiration Option Symbols&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interactive Brokers (IB) as a leading brokerage firm, adheres explicitly to industry standards for option symbols. Their documentation confirms that IB “utilizes the 21-character ‘Options Symbol Initiative’ (OSI) format” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This commitment signifies their adherence to conventions established by Options Clearing Corporations (OCC) regarding the consolidation and processing of option symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IB also provides clients with mechanisms to understand and view potential impacts on their holdings stemming from company actions. Their Trader Workstation (TWS) and Messaging Center offer tools for monitoring company behavior and its impact on positions [^15].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of appending numerical suffixes (e.g., “1”) to original stock symbols to denote adjustment post-expiration is a common convention within the industry. This practice is often directly enforced by OCC to differentiate these contracts from newly issued, unadjusted underlying options related to company actions &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref8:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other brokerages also follow similar practices. For example, Robinhood explicitly states “If your holding of stock options experiences a reverse split,…the stock code will be appended with a number. For example, if you hold ABC options, after a reverse split, it will display as ABC1” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Similarly, Merrill Edge notes that an “A” (representing “Adjusted”) will appear alongside the symbol and that the symbol itself “will include an additional digit – representing the adjustment” [^13]. Questrade also mentions “A” icons or other special indicators [^14].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-suffix-as-an-industry-convention-for-distinguishing-contracts-after-adjustments&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“1” suffix as an industry convention for distinguishing contracts after adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The symbol “SST1” is most directly and primarily due to official changes made by OCC. As detailed in OCC Information Memorandum #56689, following the 1-for-10 reverse stock split conducted by System1, Inc., the memorandum explicitly stated: “Option Symbol: SST changed to SST1” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref9:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This is not an internal naming convention of IB, but rather a standardized industry protocol for identifying options contracts post-adjustment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This convention is crucial because new, &lt;strong&gt;unadjusted&lt;/strong&gt; option series will be listed and begin trading on the underlying stock after reverse stock splits like those undertaken by companies. These new options will continue to use their original symbols (e.g., “SST”). To prevent confusion between these new standard contracts and older, adjusted contracts (where the underlying asset or effective exercise value relative to the post-split stock has been changed), adjusted contracts are assigned a modified symbol, such as “SST1” [^13].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the “SST1” symbol is a clear identifier indicating that the terms of the option contract have been amended by OCC to reflect System1, Inc.’s 1-for-10 reverse stock split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-does-this-convention-maintain-clarity-in-trading-systems-and-prevent-confusion&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How does this convention maintain clarity in trading systems and prevent confusion?&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without this unique symbol system, traders might inadvertently trade a “SST” option, mistakenly believing it represents the standard contract for 100 shares post-split. In reality, it would be an older, adjusted contract, potentially representing a different number of shares (e.g., effectively representing 10 shares post-split SST) or having a revalued strike price.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using adjusted symbols like “SST1” ensures that trading systems, clearinghouses, and all market participants can accurately identify, price, process, and settle these contracts. This precision is crucial in preventing errors in order routing, pricing, exercise, and assignment, which could otherwise lead to significant financial discrepancies and disputes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, this convention facilitates the simultaneous listing and trading of adjusted (legacy) options contracts and newly issued standard contracts on the same underlying security, with each contract identifiable by its unique symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-brokers-integrate-these-adjusted-symbols-into-their-platforms&#34;&gt;How Brokers Integrate These Adjusted Symbols into Their Platforms
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Interactive Brokers, along with other brokers like Interactive Brokers, seamlessly integrates these OCC-mandated symbol changes into their trading platforms, including Trader Workstation (TWS). When corporate actions occur and the OCC publishes adjustments, IB updates the symbols for options contracts affected in client portfolios and option chains &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref1:8&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While the underlying stock itself continues to use its original symbol (“SST”) for trading, existing adjusted option positions will be displayed with their new symbol (“SST1”).  For any order entry or queries related to these specific adjusted contracts, traders must use the “SST1” root symbol, which explains why users need to send “SST 1” to IB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a key observation: The underlying stock, System1, Inc., continues to use its original symbol “SST” for trading &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref3:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. However, for &lt;strong&gt;existing, adjusted option contracts&lt;/strong&gt;, the underlying root symbol within the option contract is “SST1” &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref10:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This creates a subtle situation where when trading &lt;strong&gt;new&lt;/strong&gt; options (these options will be based on the split-adjusted “SST” stock going public), the underlying is “SST”; but when trading &lt;strong&gt;existing, adjusted&lt;/strong&gt; options, the underlying in the option symbol is “SST1”.  This is a nuanced yet crucial distinction that can easily confuse traders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This phenomenon highlights a significant operational complexity within option trading, extending beyond simply understanding OSI formats. It underscores the need for continuous vigilance and a deep understanding of how corporate actions fragment the options market. Simply knowing the current stock code isn’t enough; traders must differentiate between the standard option on the underlying asset and its adjusted counterpart with a changed symbol. This further emphasizes the importance of carefully reviewing option chain details, company action notifications, and broker-specific guidance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The implementation of adjusted option symbols (such as “SST1”) is clearly an &amp;ldquo;operational necessity&amp;rdquo; for exchanges and brokers. It’s a powerful mechanism to manage the complexity of corporate actions, maintain market integrity, and ensure accurate clearing and settlement &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. However, from the end-user perspective, this change can be a significant source of confusion, as evidenced by direct user queries. While brokers attempt to mitigate this confusion through visual indicators like an “A” icon 13 or automatic adjustments within client portfolios &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref4:7&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, potential complexities remain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This reveals the ongoing tension and trade-off between robust financial market infrastructure technical requirements and user-friendly interface demands.  While the “SST1” convention is efficient and necessary from a systems perspective, it places an additional burden on individual traders to understand its implications. This highlights the enduring value of expert analysis and detailed educational reports in bridging this knowledge gap, ensuring that market participants can effectively and confidently navigate these complexities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;impact-on-traders--best-practices&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Traders &amp;amp; Best Practices&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-to-identify-adjusted-options&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;How to Identify Adjusted Options&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Symbol Suffixes:&lt;/strong&gt; The most direct and immediate indicator of adjusted options is the numerical suffix appended to the option root symbol (e.g., “1”, “7” for mini options, or other numbers) &lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:9&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. For example, seeing “SST1” instead of “SST” in an option held within System1, Inc. is a clear signal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Visual Indicators on Trading Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt; Many well-known trading platforms, including Merrill Edge and Questrade, include specific visual cues. Traders should look for prominent “A” icons (representing “Adjusted”) or other special indicators alongside the option symbol in the option chain, quote window, or portfolio view [^13]. Interactive Brokers also uses icons (e.g., “C” representing company behavior) within its tax optimizer and messaging center to highlight affected positions [^15].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Liquidity:&lt;/strong&gt; A strong practical signal of an adjusted option is a significant decrease in trading volume and open interest compared to other options in the same series or newly issued, unlevered standard options based on the underlying asset [^13]. This activity reduction can lead to wider bid-ask spreads.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discrepant Strike Prices:&lt;/strong&gt; Adjusted options may appear “out of whack” or inconsistent with other parts of the underlying stock option chain in terms of their strike prices [^13]. Furthermore, the presence of multiple put or call options with the same expiration date and strike price can indicate that an adjusted option is coexisting with newly issued standard options [^13].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pricing Anomalies:&lt;/strong&gt; If an option’s price appears unusually low or “priced incorrectly” (or vice versa – “too good to be true”), investigation is warranted, as an adjustment may have altered its intrinsic value or the deliverable asset [^13].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-importance-of-reviewing-occ-information-memorandums-and-broker-notices&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Importance of Reviewing OCC Information Memorandums and Broker Notices&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Options Clearing Corporation (OCC) is the final authority for determining and implementing adjustments to U.S. option contracts[^13]. Their “Information Memorandums” are the official and authoritative source for understanding the precise terms of any corporate action adjustment&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref11:3&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. These memorandums provide key details regarding the deliverable (such as the number of shares per contract), strike prices, and changes in new option symbols.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokers such as Interactive Brokers have a legal obligation and operational capability to notify their clients of upcoming corporate actions that may impact their positions. These notices are typically available through client messaging centers, corporate action tools, or platform alerts[^15]. They provide information on how the broker will process adjustments within its systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relying solely on visual cues or general understanding of corporate actions may be insufficient and can lead to costly misunderstandings. To ensure accurate position management and trading decisions, it is essential to review these official and broker-specific sources to determine the precise adjustment terms (such as cash in lieu of fractional shares, specific deliverable changes).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;post-adjustment-option-considerations&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-Adjustment Option Considerations&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Reduction in Liquidity:&lt;/strong&gt; The most significant impact of post-adjustment options is a severe reduction in liquidity[^13]. This typically leads to wider bid-ask spreads, making it more difficult and costly to enter or exit positions at fair market prices. Traders may find it challenging to locate counterparties willing to transact at the desired order size.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Increased Pricing Complexity:&lt;/strong&gt; Due to changes in the deliverable asset, valuing post-adjustment options becomes more complex. Standard option pricing models (such as the Black-Scholes model) may not directly apply unless carefully manual adjustments are made to account for the new number of shares or effective exercise prices. This complexity can lead to inefficient pricing and increase trader risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Restricted Trading Capacity:&lt;/strong&gt; Certain brokerage platforms, such as Robinhood, may impose restrictions on trading post-adjustment options, typically limiting them to “only sell” positions&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref2:4&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. This means traders can sell existing adjusted contracts but are prohibited from opening new positions, significantly restricting strategy flexibility.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ambiguity Regarding Exercise/Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; Understanding the exact deliverable asset at exercise or settlement is crucial. According to OCC’s specific adjustment terms, post-adjustment options may deliver a combination of shares, stock and cash, or even solely cash[^13]. Misunderstanding these terms can lead to unforeseen financial outcomes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommendations-for-options-traders&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations for Options Traders&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Proactively Collect Information:&lt;/strong&gt; Develop a habit of regularly monitoring financial news media and your broker’s corporate actions section to understand any announcements regarding the underlying stocks held in your options positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Review Official Documentation:&lt;/strong&gt; Immediately upon learning of company action, consult relevant OCC information memorandums (available on the OCC website or through your broker&amp;rsquo;s resources) as well as your broker’s specific notices. These are the authoritative sources for understanding precise adjustment terms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reassess Your Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Carefully evaluate how the adjustments affect the intrinsic value, breakeven points, and their role within your overall trading strategy for your specific option contracts. Determine if the adjusted contracts still align with your original investment thesis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Consider Position Management:&lt;/strong&gt; Given the inherent complexity and typical liquidity constraints, it’s generally advisable to consider exiting positions if the adjustments render your options positions no longer aligned with your trading objectives or if liquidity issues become unmanageable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor New Contracts:&lt;/strong&gt; As a best practice, avoid establishing new positions in adjusted option contracts. Instead, focus on newly issued standard option series on the underlying stock following company action, as these options typically offer better liquidity and more direct pricing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Company actions have an impact on derivative markets, which is an inherent part of corporate finance; however, they often introduce significant inefficiencies. The creation of adjustments to options, with their lower liquidity and more complex pricing and trading dynamics (such as liquidity and pricing behavior), fragment the option market for a particular security. This fragmentation reduces overall market efficiency and can lead to wider bid-ask spreads and difficulty in price discovery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;User queries perfectly illustrate that simply recognizing standard OSI format option symbols is insufficient when dealing with company actions. The seemingly minor “1” suffix (making it “SST1”) within the “SST” symbol – does not merely represent a superficial change; it foreshadows a series of fundamental changes to the contract terms, underlying asset, and market dynamics (such as liquidity, pricing behavior). This requires traders to go beyond simple symbol recognition and delve into the reasons behind these changes. This proactive research is an indispensable part of effective risk management and trading execution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Option code “SST1G182500500.U” clearly indicates a tailored post-split option contract for System1, Inc. (SST). The key “SST1” root symbol was not arbitrarily assigned but is the direct result of an official adjustment enforced by the Options Clearing Corporation (OCC). This adjustment was necessary due to System1, Inc.’s 2025 June 12 effective one-for-ten reverse stock split.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This corporate action fundamentally altered the underlying deliverable of existing option contracts. While the nominal contract multiplier remains at 100, the “SST1” reference symbol now represents that each contract effectively corresponds to 10 shares of the post-split SST stock, thereby preserving the original economic value.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactive Brokers, like other major brokers, follows these OCC-enforced symbol conventions. By requiring the “SST1” (or “SST 1”) reference code, IB ensures accurate identification, processing, and display of these adjusted contracts within its trading systems, preventing potential errors and maintaining market integrity. The “G1825” and “.U” elements in user symbols may represent specific broker-defined or legacy expiration dates and internal identifiers, but they do not alter the fundamental reason for the “SST1” root symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For any serious options trader, a thorough understanding of option symbols, particularly within this complex corporate context, is not just beneficial – it’s absolutely critical. Corporate actions can fundamentally change the terms, deliverable, and liquidity characteristics of outstanding option contracts, transforming them into “post-split option contracts” with unique symbols and trading behavior. Therefore, proactively monitoring company announcements, diligently reviewing official OCC information memoranda, and being acutely aware of broker-specific symbol conventions are essential best practices. These measures are crucial for accurately interpreting option contract terms, effectively managing risk exposures, and making informed strategic trading decisions in a dynamic market environment. Ignoring these key adjustments could lead to unforeseen financial consequences, operational complexities, and potentially significant losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-1&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-2&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;footnotes&#34; role=&#34;doc-endnotes&#34;&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:1&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option Symbology Initiative – IBKR Guides, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ibkrguides.com/kb/en-us/article-972.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.ibkrguides.com/kb/en-us/article-972.htm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:2&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How to Read the Ticker Symbols for Stock Options – Investopedia, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/05/052505.asp&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.investopedia.com/ask/answers/05/052505.asp&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref5:2&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:3&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System1, Inc. – Reverse Split Option Symbol: SST New Symbol: SST1 Date: 06/12/2025 – Options Clearing Corporation, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://infomemo.theocc.com/infomemos?number=56689&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://infomemo.theocc.com/infomemos?number=56689&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref5:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref6:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref7:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref8:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref9:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref10:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref11:3&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:4&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How corporate actions affect your options | Robinhood, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://robinhood.com/us/en/support/articles/how-corporate-actions-affect-your-options/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://robinhood.com/us/en/support/articles/how-corporate-actions-affect-your-options/&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:4&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:5&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option naming convention – Wikipedia, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_naming_convention&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_naming_convention&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:5&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:6&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System1 Class A Common Stock to Begin Trading on a Split-Adjusted Basis on June 12, 2025 – Business Wire, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250611797981/en/System1-Class-A-Common-Stock-to-Begin-Trading-on-a-Split-Adjusted-Basis-on-June-12-2025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.businesswire.com/news/home/20250611797981/en/System1-Class-A-Common-Stock-to-Begin-Trading-on-a-Split-Adjusted-Basis-on-June-12-2025&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:6&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:7&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System1 Class A Common Stock to Begin Trading on a Split-Adjusted Basis on June 12, 2025, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.streetinsider.com/news.php?id=24925768&amp;amp;classic=1&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.streetinsider.com/news.php?id=24925768&amp;amp;classic=1&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref2:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref3:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref4:7&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:8&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prime Trade File Upload Instructions – IBKR Guides, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.ibkrguides.com/traderworkstation/prime-trade-file-upload-instructions.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.ibkrguides.com/traderworkstation/prime-trade-file-upload-instructions.htm&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref1:8&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&#34;fn:9&#34;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Option symbol – Wikipedia, accessed June 24, 2025, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_symbol&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Option_symbol&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#160;&lt;a href=&#34;#fnref:9&#34; class=&#34;footnote-backref&#34; role=&#34;doc-backlink&#34;&gt;&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you have $1,000 USD and want to sell these dollars to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
1000 \, \text{USD} \times 7.0 \, \text{CNY/USD} = 7000 \, \text{CNY}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7,000 CNY. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling USD to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Exchange, History of Virtual Currency Development</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin once again elected as US President, also bringing virtual currencies back into the public eye. The Hong Kong Exchange has been actively deploying related business, and here’s a brief record of its virtual currency development history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the details of relevant contract listings, we found that the initial introduction wasn&amp;rsquo;t spot contracts but futures – which was reasonable due to their better liquidity and easier attraction of institutional investors. Subsequently introducing spot ETFs was also sensible, as they are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-currency-list&#34;&gt;Virtual Currency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange’s market data does not provide identifiers to distinguish between contracts that are virtual currencies. However, they can be determined by the contract name. The official trading list provides corresponding subcategories &lt;code&gt;virtualasset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-batch-of-crypto-asset-etfs-in-asia&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Batch of Crypto Asset ETFs in Asia
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of the first batch of crypto asset ETFs in Asia, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for investors in Hong Kong and internationally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two new ETFs listed today – Southern East One Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Southern East One Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) – are managed by Southern East One Asset Management Co., Ltd. and track standardized, cash-settled bitcoin futures contracts and ether futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The two crypto asset ETFs listed today add another layer of richness to Hong Kong’s increasingly diverse exchange trading product ecosystem,” said Mr. Yao Jia Ren, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Market Development at HKEX. “These new products will provide investors in Asia for the first time with an opportunity to participate in digital asset investment, reflecting our focus on the digital economy and market demand. We look forward to bringing more thematic ETFs and digital asset products in the coming months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETF is one of the fastest-growing businesses under HKEX, with its product range continuously expanding and becoming increasingly diversified, including the launch of Hong Kong’s first Metaverse ETF, first Carbon Futures ETF, and first Blockchain ETF within the year. It also marked the first time ETFs were included in the滬深港通 (HKSG Connect).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the average daily trading volume of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s buy-and-sell products (ETPs – including ETFs and leveraged and inverse products) for the first eleven months of this year reached HK$118 billion, a 50% increase from last year’s same period of HK$78 billion, reflecting the growing popularity of ETPs among investors. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on HKEX with a market capitalization of HK$3,735 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-batch-of-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Batch of Spot Virtual Asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs, adding to the variety of products in the Hong Kong market and providing investors with more choices, further solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Today’s newly listed spot virtual asset ETFs will enrich the diversified and dynamic ETF market ecosystem of the Hong Kong Exchange, offering investors new investment opportunities in asset classes,” said Robert Lin, Head of Securities Product Development at HKEX. “Following the successful launch of the first virtual asset futures ETF a year ago, these first Asian spot virtual asset ETFs will further enhance the product variety and liquidity for the Hong Kong Exchange’s buy-and-sell products. We look forward to continuing to work closely with market stakeholders to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs, which were listed in 2022, have been favored by investors and traded actively. The average daily trading volume of the three spot virtual asset ETFs listed on HKEX increased from HK$890 million in 2023 to HK$5.13 billion in the first quarter of 2024, while attracting HK$5.29 billion in inflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchange-traded products (ETPs), including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products, are one of the fastest-growing markets for HKEX, with the product variety continuously increasing over the past year. The 16 new ETPs launched in 2023 and the first quarter of 2024 include the first Saudi Arabian ETF in the Asia Pacific region, Hong Kong’s first callable option ETFs, and currently there are 179 ETPs listed on HKEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) announced today (Monday) that it will launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series (the “Series”) on November 15, 2024, providing a reliable benchmark price for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong’s development as a leading digital asset hub in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will provide transparent and reliable benchmarks for pricing Bitcoin and Ethereum within the Asian time zone, aiming to offer a unified reference price for virtual assets, addressing price discrepancies between this asset class across global exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKEX Group Chief Executive Officer Chen Yiting stated: “We are pleased to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series to meet the demand for this rapidly growing asset class regionally. By providing transparent and reliable real-time benchmarks, we hope to help investors make informed investment decisions, supporting the healthy development of the virtual assets ecosystem and solidifying Hong Kong’s position as an international financial center.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of the index series is part of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring emerging areas, supporting the development of Hong Kong fintech while also providing investors with important benchmarks and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference indices are based on the weighted average spot price of Bitcoin or Ethereum over 24 hours’ trading volume, calculated using aggregated market prices from major virtual asset exchanges, and denominated in US dollars in real-time. The reference exchange rate is designed for financial product settlement and is calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will be the first virtual asset index series developed in Hong Kong that complies with European Union Benchmark Regulation (EUBMR) standards, managed and calculated jointly by a benchmark management company registered in the UK and a virtual assets data and index provider, CCData.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region issued a policy statement on the development of virtual assets, hoping to cultivate a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Indices Series will help the public increase their understanding of virtual asset investment trends through providing real-time data and daily reference prices within the Asian time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be announced as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline in the A-share market may be related to the dynamics of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank, the performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors jointly acted on the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to fluctuations in the Renminbi and the decline in the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant volatility. Here’s a detailed breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through:&lt;/strong&gt; At opening, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar-offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and the on-shore RMB rising to a high of 7.22360, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of release by Lianhe Chat, the dollar-offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 mark, with the lowest reported at 7.2639 and the trend remained unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Exchange Rate Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the Renminbi’s midpoint exchange rate against the dollar at 7.1004, a devaluation of 62 basis points, with the adjustment magnitude expanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened low and continued to fall, with declines exceeding 1% overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Foreign Exchange Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment institution stated that the volatility in the foreign exchange market was mainly due to the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank boosting the dollar, coupled with strong U.S. economic data and the potential persistence of inflation delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is the “Super Central Bank Week” for global markets, with the central banks of the United States, Japan, Britain, Australia, and other countries all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss Central Bank unexpectedly announced a cut in interest rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, which broke the market balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecast for Renminbi Trend:&lt;/strong&gt; Zhou Miaohua, researcher at Light Industry Bank’s Financial Market Department, stated that despite some fluctuations in the Renminbi recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the dollar, and short-term volatility will not change the RMB&amp;rsquo;s trend of steady appreciation throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bonded Customs Clearance with Hong Kong Dollar and Renminbi</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing (HKEX) announced on December 13th that it will soon launch the “Hong Kong-Renminbi Dual Counter Model” (hereinafter referred to as “Dual Counter Model”) and dual counter broker mechanisms for its securities markets, further supporting RMB-designated listings, trading, and settlement in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dual-listing-model-and-dual-listing-broker-mechanism&#34;&gt;Dual-Listing Model and Dual-Listing Broker Mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) stated that the registration procedures for these new measures are expected to begin implementation in the first half of 2023, pending regulatory approval and market readiness. Under the dual-listing model, HKEX will optimize related trading and settlement arrangements, allowing investors to swap securities issued by the same issuer on both the Hong Kong Dollar (HKD) and Renminbi (RMB) trading venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance liquidity in the RMB trading venue and narrow the price difference between the two venues, HKEX will introduce a dual-listing broker mechanism. Once relevant legislation is passed by the Legislative Council, market makers engaging in supply activities will be exempt from stamp duty when conducting specific transactions. Simultaneously, these new measures will also prepare for subsequent mainland investors to trade securities priced in RMB through the Hong Kong Connect (HKT) scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The launch of the dual-listing model of Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi and the dual-listing broker mechanism is a key measure for the development of our market. In conjunction with our other market initiatives, this arrangement will help attract more dual-listing securities to be listed in Hong Kong, complementing the existing mainland products at HKEX. HKEX is committed to actively promoting the internationalization of RMB and continuously enhancing Hong Kong’s position as a leading offshore RMB center globally.”  Said Mr. Yao Kai-yan, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Markets at HKEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is noted that the current listing, trading, settlement, and clearing arrangements in the Hong Kong stock market will largely apply to RMB securities under the dual-listing model. HKEX will announce the implementation date of the dual-listing model and the list of eligible dual-listing securities included in the broker mechanism at an appropriate time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-renminbi-trading-booths&#34;&gt;How to Identify Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi Trading Booths
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) documentation indicates that the Hong Kong dollar-Renminbi dual listing arrangement will largely follow the existing stock code allocation plan, meaning Hong Kong dollar booths will have stock codes starting with “0” followed by five digits, while Renminbi booths will have stock codes starting with “8” followed by five digits. The last four digits of both Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi booth stock codes will be identical. Renminbi booth stock abbreviations will be appended with &amp;ldquo;-R&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding trading arrangements, based on the fact that securities in both the Renminbi and Hong Kong dollar booths belong to the same category and can be converted into each other, if one booth (such as the Hong Kong dollar booth) allows for short selling of specified securities, the other booth (such as the Renminbi booth) can also be included as eligible for short selling according to exchange rules. Correspondingly, both booths will be listed in the specified securities lists that are available for short selling on the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the stocks in both booths belong to the same category and can be converted into each other, buying or holding the stock in Renminbi while selling it in Hong Kong dollars will be considered a carry trade (short sale), and vice versa. Settlement times between the two booths are T+2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For specified securities eligible for short selling, such as borrowing stocks in Hong Kong dollars and then selling them on the Renminbi booth, this will be treated as a secured short sale, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that under the dual booth model, since the Renminbi booth is only for trading and settlement, it will not provide physical stock deposits or withdrawals; physical stocks can only be deposited after being held in the Hong Kong dollar booth and then converted to the Renminbi booth. Similarly, the Renminbi booth must be converted to the Hong Kong dollar booth before physical stocks can be withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Hong Kong settlement and clearing fees, excluding dividend collection service fees and interest collection service fees, will be calculated and charged in Hong Kong dollars. Dividend collection service fees and interest collection service fees will be calculated using the currency adopted for the relevant securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism/HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model&lt;/a&gt;
Source: HKEx Pulse / HKEx, Broker China&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Futu Securities Stock Code Special Format Instructions</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Uncommon, it will definitely encounter it over time; related stock code: Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some stock ticker symbols contain periods or other special characters in their names. When submitting these to Interactive Brokers (IB) via &lt;code&gt;Fix&lt;/code&gt;, certain transformations of the stock code name are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;body&#34;&gt;Body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Fidelity Securities case, it’s possible to analyze and implement the conversion rules are fixed through coding. When the rules are not fixed, generally the system needs to store the corresponding mapping relationships, which are updated periodically by business operations personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-links&#34;&gt;Reference Links
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Futures Basic Concepts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets continue to evolve, investors have begun seeking more effective investment tools to enhance their investment returns. To meet investor demand, The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a range of stock futures contracts, all of which represent stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange (HKEX), which boasts high trading volumes and active liquidity. Through investing in stock futures, investors can participate in the performance of individual companies while also benefiting from the short selling and leverage effects offered by the derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the underlying stocks represented by stock futures are typically leading companies within their respective industries, investors can strategically select to invest in those industry-specific futures if they believe a particular sector’s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a specified quantity of financial value (contract size) equivalent to a specified number of shares (the underlying stock) at a predetermined price (the agreed-upon price) on a future, specified date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All stock futures contracts are settled in cash and do not involve the physical delivery of shares upon expiration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expiry&#34;&gt;Contract Expiry
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon contract expiry, the profit or loss amount is calculated as the difference between the agreed-upon price and the final settlement price multiplied by the contract multiplier, which will be deducted from the clearing member’s margin account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price refers to the official closing price of the stock reported by the Shanghai Stock Exchange on the last trading day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a futures investor wishes to close out their position before expiry, a short seller only needs to buy back one futures contract, while a long position holder must sell one futures contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;margin-deposit&#34;&gt;Margin Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In futures trading, both buyers and sellers must initially deposit a basic margin as collateral to fulfill the contract. After each daily settlement, the clearing organization calculates profits or losses for all open contracts based on the closing market price and uses this to deduct from investors’ margin accounts. If unfavorable market conditions result in an investor incurring losses that cause their margin to fall below the specified level, the exchange will require the investor to top up their margin within a designated timeframe to maintain it at the original basic margin level (i.e., to cover).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low Transaction Costs:&lt;/strong&gt; The fees are low relative to the value of the underlying shares. Each futures contract is equivalent to thousands of shares, and commissions depend on the number of contracts traded, resulting in a very low cost per unit of value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easier Short Selling:&lt;/strong&gt; Because investors can easily short stocks through futures contracts, they can profit during market declines by shorting stock futures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Maker System:&lt;/strong&gt; To ensure market liquidity, The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited (HKEX) mandates that market makers provide buy and sell prices within a specified range, maintaining circulation in the stock futures market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Leverage Effect:&lt;/strong&gt; Investors only need to pay a margin representing a small portion of the contract value when buying and selling stock futures contracts, making hedging and trading more cost-effective.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduced Foreign Investor Currency Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts provide foreign investors with access to invest in high-quality local stocks because they only pay a margin instead of the full contract value, significantly reducing the currency risk borne by foreign investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Electronic Trading System:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts are traded through The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited’s (HKEX) electronic trading system. All trades are executed according to price and time priority, with immediate display of buy prices, sell prices, and transaction prices, achieving the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clearing Company Performance Guarantees:&lt;/strong&gt; Stock futures contracts will be registered, settled, and performance guarantees provided by HKEX’s wholly owned subsidiary, Hong Kong Futures Clearing Limited (the Clearing Company). Because the Clearing Company is the counterparty to all unsettled contracts, participants in the clearing house will not have to bear counterparty risk. However, this guarantee does not include the financial responsibility of the clearing participant for its clients; investors choosing a broker to trade must exercise caution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-making&#34;&gt;Market Making
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants or individual stock futures contracts may register as market makers on the exchange and simultaneously provide both buy and sell prices within the specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should be aware that individual stock futures contracts may not have a market maker registered to provide bid-ask spreads, and their trades will be based on market unit pricing. &lt;strong&gt;Investors should note that stock futures without registered market makers may involve liquidity risk, and caution should be exercised before entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stock-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of Trading Stock Futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock futures involve high risks. Losses arising from trading stock futures may exceed the initial margin paid, potentially requiring you to pay additional margins within a short period. If unable to meet these payments, your position may be liquidated, and you will bear all resulting losses. Therefore, it is crucial to fully understand the risks associated with trading stock futures and assess whether it’s suitable for you. Before engaging in transactions, consult with a broker or financial advisor to determine if futures and options contracts are appropriate based on your financial situation and investment objectives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjusting-comments&#34;&gt;Adjusting Comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a listed company alters its capital structure through measures such as a cash offer or the issuance of bonus shares, this will lead to changes in share prices at the time of net asset valuation or the effective date, and may also affect uncovered positions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If other circumstances remain unchanged, the value of holdings held by shareholders will not be adjusted on the settlement day; however, this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures. Unless the futures contract is appropriately adjusted, changes to the share price will unfairly and unjustly impact the value of a stock futures position. The adjustment ratio determined by the Settlement Corporation is based on maintaining the fair value of the futures contract and only made when there are significant changes. The Hong Kong Exchange will announce the details of the adjustments, and participants in the exchange must inform customers about the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Futures Contracts Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/futures-contracts-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Futures Contracts Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-provider-code&#34;&gt;News Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/news_provider_code.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;News Provider Code&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/products/listed-derivatives/single-stock/stock-futures?sc_lang=zh-cn#list_of_stock_futures&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Exchange - Derivatives / Stocks / Stock Futures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange Interface Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent five years developing financial software, I’ve become most familiar with the interface documentation of various exchanges. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly well-versed in the Hong Kong Exchange’s documents, and recently while handling the ChinaBond business, I also reviewed materials from the Shanghai Stock Exchange (SSE) and Shenzhen Stock Exchange (SZSE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-resources&#34;&gt;Frequently Used Resources
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Trading-Hour,-Trading-and-Settlement-Calendar?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Hours, Trading and Settlement Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Mechanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/hkex-market/mutual-market/stock-connect/reference-materials/resources/glossary_c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong &amp;amp; China Financial Terminology Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_pdf_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect and Shenzhen Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_csv_c.csv&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect and Shenzhen Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar CSV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;glossary_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong &amp;amp; China Financial Terminology Glossary PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/vcm/vcmtriggersecurity_c.aspx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Circuit Breaker Trigger Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/services/trading/securities/securitieslists/ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Closing-Auction-Session-%28CAS%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Closing Auction Session (CAS) Securities Trading Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Volatility-Control-Mechanism-%28VCM%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Volatility Control Mechanism (VCM) Securities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Designated-Securities-Eligible-for-Short-Selling?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Designated Securities Eligible for Short Selling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34; &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-fortune-中化通&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Fortune (中化通)
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Interface Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;
Frequently Asked Questions, Guidance on Development Manuals, Historical Market Data Interface Documents can be obtained by searching for download addresses in the search bar. Search for historical version numbers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/HKEX-Orion-Market-Data-Platform-Securities-Market-OMD-C?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange Market Data Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Technical-Documents/OMD_CC-Specifications?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;China Fortune Market Data Interface&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-interface-document-h-shares--china-tong&#34;&gt;Trading Interface Document: H Shares + China Tong
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Interface Document Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;H Shares FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;H Shares Dual Pricing Scheme Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Reason_Text_List.xlsx&#34; &gt;HKEX Error Code List XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Tong FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;China Tong Binary Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sse-shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;SSE (Shanghai Stock Exchange)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.sse.com.cn/services/tradingservice/tradingtech/technical/data/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data and Trading Link Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
Error Interface Documentation can be found in other menus
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;SSE_IS111_ErrorCode_CV3.15.xlsx&#34; &gt;Trading Error Interface Documentation XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.szse.cn/marketServices/technicalservice/interface/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Query Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
The Stock Exchange does not provide separate error message explanations; supplementary information can be found in Chapter 6 of the Market Data Query Interface Documentation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;P020201229686784934466.pdf&#34; &gt;Shenzhen Securities Trading Center Binary Transaction Data Interface Specification (Ver1.18) PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;Nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nyse.com/markets/hours-calendars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Holiday Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/ipos?tab=upcoming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;New Issue Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-price&#34;&gt;Closing Price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://eoddata.com/stocklist/NASDAQ.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Global Market Closing Prices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
