<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have $1000 and want to sell it to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1000 \times 7.0 \, \text{Renminbi/USD} = 7000 \, \text{Renminbi}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7000 RMB. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling US dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing USD from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange transactions. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Exchange, History of Virtual Currency Development</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bitcoin once again elected as US President, also bringing virtual currencies back into the public eye. The Hong Kong Exchange has been actively deploying related business initiatives, and here’s a brief record of its virtual currency development history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the details of relevant contract listings, we found that the initial introduction wasn&amp;rsquo;t spot contracts but futures – which was reasonable due to their better liquidity and easier access for institutional investors. The subsequent introduction of spot ETFs was also logical, as ETFs are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;virtual-currency-list&#34;&gt;Virtual Currency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange’s market data does not provide identifiers to distinguish between contracts that are virtual currencies. However, they can be determined by the contract name. The official trading list provides corresponding subcategories &lt;code&gt;virtualasset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-exchange-and-clearing-limited-hkex-welcomed-the-listing-of-asias-first-batch-of-cryptocurrency-etfs-today-friday-further-expanding-its-product-ecosystem-and-providing-more-choices-for-hong-kong-and-international-investors&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing Limited (HKEX) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first batch of cryptocurrency ETFs today (Friday), further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for Hong Kong and international investors.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The two new ETFs listed today – Southern East One Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Southern East One Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) – are managed by Southern East One Asset Management Co., Ltd., and track standardized, cash-settled bitcoin futures contracts and ether futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;HKEX’s Chief Operating Officer and Head of Market Development, Yao Jia Ren, said: “The two cryptocurrency ETFs listed today add another layer of richness to Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s diversified exchange trading product ecosystem.” These new products will provide investors with the opportunity to participate in digital asset investments for the first time in Asia, and reflect our focus on the digital economy and market demand. “We look forward to bringing more thematic ETFs and new digital assets products in the coming months.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETF is one of Hong Kong Exchange’s fastest-growing business areas, with product varieties expanding and diversifying continuously in 2022, including the launch of the first metaverse ETF, the first carbon futures ETF, and the first blockchain ETF, as well as the first time incorporating ETFs into the HKSB Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-exchange-and-clearing-hkex-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-batch-of-crypto-asset-etfs-in-asia-furthermore-hkexs-exchange-traded-products-etps-including-etfs-and-leveraged-and-inverse-products-saw-an-average-daily-trading-volume-of-hk118-billion-in-the-first-ten-months-of-this-year-a-50-increase-from-last-years-corresponding-period-of-hk78-billion-reflecting-the-growing-popularity-of-etps-among-investors-as-of-november-2022-there-were-168-etps-listed-on-hkex-with-a-total-market-capitalization-of-hk3735-billion&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing (HKEX) welcomes the listing of the first batch of crypto asset ETFs in Asia. Furthermore, HKEX’s exchange-traded products (ETPs), including ETFs and leveraged and inverse products, saw an average daily trading volume of HK$118 billion in the first ten months of this year, a 50% increase from last year&amp;rsquo;s corresponding period of HK$78 billion, reflecting the growing popularity of ETPs among investors. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on HKEX with a total market capitalization of HK$3,735 billion.
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-batch-of-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes the Listing of the First Batch of Spot Virtual Asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (Hong Kong Exchange) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs, adding to the variety of products in the Hong Kong market and providing investors with more choices, further solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Robert Lin, Head of Securities Product Development at the Hong Kong Exchange, “The newly listed spot virtual asset ETFs will enrich the diversified and dynamic ETF market ecosystem of the Hong Kong Exchange, offering investors new investment opportunities in asset classes. Following the successful launch of virtual asset futures ETFs a year ago, Asia’s first batch of spot virtual asset ETFs will further enhance the product variety and liquidity traded by the Hong Kong Exchange. We look forward to continuing to work closely with stakeholders in the market to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.” “ The first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs listed in 2022 were highly favored by investors and enjoyed thriving trading volumes. The average daily trading volume of the three virtual asset futures ETFs listed on the Hong Kong Exchange increased from HK$890 million in 2023 to HK$5,130 million in the first quarter of 2024, while attracting HK$5.29 billion in inflows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Exchange-traded products (including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products) are one of the fastest-growing markets at the Hong Kong Exchange, with the number of product types continuously increasing over the past year. The 16 new ETF products launched in 2023 and the first quarter of 2024 include the first Saudi Arabian ETF in the Asia-Pacific region, the first batch of callable warrants ETFs in Hong Kong, and currently there are 179 ETFs listed on the Hong Kong Exchange.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (Hong Kong Exchange) announced today (Monday) that it will launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series (the Index Series) on November 15, 2024, providing a reliable benchmark price for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong’s development as a leading digital asset hub in Asia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will provide transparent and reliable benchmarks for the pricing of Bitcoin and Ethereum within the Asian time zone, aiming to offer a unified reference price for virtual assets and address price discrepancies between this asset class across global exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Group Chairman Chen Yiting said: “We are delighted to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series to meet the demand for this rapidly growing asset class in the region.” “By providing transparent and reliable real-time benchmarks, we aim to help investors make informed investment decisions, thereby supporting the healthy development of the virtual asset ecosystem and consolidating Hong Kong’s position as an international financial center.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this index series is part of the Hong Kong Exchange’s commitment to exploring emerging areas. It supports the development of Hong Kong Fintech while also providing investors with important benchmarks and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment.
The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-to-launch-virtual-asset-index-series-1&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange to Launch Virtual Asset Index Series
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The benchmark index will be based on the 24-hour weighted average spot prices of Bitcoin and Ethereum, calculated according to the aggregated market prices from major virtual asset exchanges. The index will be denominated in US dollars in real time. The reference rate is designed for financial product settlement and is calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong Time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will be the first compliant virtual asset index series in Hong Kong that meets European Union Benchmark Regulation (EUBMR) standards, managed and calculated jointly by a benchmark management company registered in the UK and virtual asset data and index provider CCData.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region issued a policy statement on the development of virtual assets, aiming to cultivate a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Assets Index Series will provide public access to real-time data and daily reference prices in Asian time zones, helping to increase understanding of trends in virtual asset investment. More details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be released as appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the exchange rate of the Renminbi and a decline in the Shanghai Composite Index may be related to developments at global central banks, an unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss National Bank, performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors interact together in the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to volatility in the Renminbi and a decline in A-shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant fluctuations. Here&amp;rsquo;s the detailed information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through&lt;/strong&gt;: At the opening of trading, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar to offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and 7.22360 respectively during intraday trading, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of reporter release by Lianhe Finance, the dollar to offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 level, with a lowest reported price of 7.2639, and the trend remained strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Price Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the RMB/USD midpoint quotation at 7.1004, a depreciation of 62 basis points, expanding the adjustment magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened lower and continued to decline, with declines exceeding 1%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Forex Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment firm stated that volatility in the forex market was primarily due to the Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cutting interest rates, which boosted the dollar, coupled with strong US economic growth and the potential for inflationary persistence delaying rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;: This week is a “super central bank week” for global markets, with the U.S., Japan, UK, Australia, and other countries’ central banks all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cut rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, breaking market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RMB Trend Forecast&lt;/strong&gt;: Guotai Securities Financial Markets Department Researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent fluctuations in the RMB, the overall amplitude is significantly smaller than that of the U.S. dollar and other major currencies. Short-term volatility will not change the RMB’s steady uptrend this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Bonded Customs Clearance with Hong Kong Dollar and Renminbi</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Exchange and Clearing (HKEX) announced on December 13th that its securities markets are about to launch the “Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi Dual-Counter Mode” (hereinafter referred to as “Dual-Counter Mode”) and dual-counter broker mechanisms, further supporting RMB-designated listings, trading, and settlement in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dual-listing-model-and-dual-listing-dealer-mechanism&#34;&gt;Dual-Listing Model and Dual-Listing Dealer Mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) stated that the registration process for these new measures is expected to commence in the first half of 2023, pending regulatory approval and market readiness. Under the dual-listing model, HKEX will optimize related trading and settlement arrangements, allowing investors to swap securities issued by the same issuer in both Hong Kong Dollar (HKD) and Renminbi (RMB) trading venues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance liquidity of the RMB trading venue and narrow the price gap between the two venues, HKEX will introduce a dual-listing dealer mechanism. Once relevant legislation is passed by the Legislative Council, market dealers engaged in providing quoted volume activity will be exempt from stamp duty when conducting specific transactions. Simultaneously, these new measures will also prepare for subsequent mainland investors to trade securities priced in RMB through the Hong Kong Connect trading scheme. “The launch of the Hong Kong-Renminbi (RMB) dual currency clearing arrangement and the dual currency dealing mechanism for institutional investors is a key measure to support market development. In conjunction with our other market initiatives, this arrangement will help attract more dual currency securities listed in Hong Kong and leverage synergies with existing Mainland products on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange. ‘The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) is committed to actively promoting the internationalization of RMB and continuously enhancing Hong Kong’s position as a leading offshore RMB center globally,’ said Mr. Yao Kai-yan, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Market Liaison. It is noted that the current listing, trading, settlement and clearing arrangements in the Hong Kong stock market will largely apply to RMB clearing securities under the dual currency clearing arrangement. HKEX will announce the implementation date of the dual currency clearing model and the list of eligible dual currency clearing securities included in the institutional investor mechanism at an appropriate time.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-renminbi-trading-booths&#34;&gt;How to Identify Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi Trading Booths
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchange documents show that the Hong Kong dollar-Renminbi dual listing arrangements will largely follow the existing stock code allocation plan, namely that stocks on the Hong Kong dollar booth will have 5-digit stock codes starting with “0,” while stocks on the Renminbi booth will have 5-digit stock codes starting with “8.” The last four digits of stock codes for both the Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi booths will be identical. Stock abbreviations for the Renminbi booth will be appended with &amp;ldquo;-R.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding trading arrangements, based on securities that are the same category and can be converted between the Renminbi and Hong Kong dollar booths, if one booth (such as the Hong Kong dollar booth) is a designated security that can be shorted, the other booth (such as the Renminbi booth) can also be included as a designated security that can be shorted in accordance with exchange rules. Correspondingly, both booths will be listed on the exchange’s list of securities that can be shorted. Given that the stocks on two trading desks belong to the same category and can be mutually converted, buying or holding them in Hong Kong dollars and selling them in Renminbi will be treated as shorting the position, and vice versa. The settlement time between the two desks is T+2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For designated stocks eligible for short selling, such as borrowing shares in Hong Kong dollars and then selling them on the Renminbi desk, this will be considered secured short selling, and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s worth noting that under the dual-desk model, since the Renminbi desk is only for trading and settlement, it will not provide physical stock deposits or withdrawals; physical stocks can only be deposited after being converted to the Renminbi desk, and similarly, the Renminbi desk must be converted to the Hong Kong dollar desk before physical stocks can be withdrawn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-renminbi-trading-service-desks&#34;&gt;How to Identify Hong Kong Dollar-Renminbi Trading Service Desks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fees associated with related settlement and clearing of transactions, all Hong Kong settlement fees (excluding dividend collection service fee and interest collection service fee), are calculated and charged in Hong Kong Dollars. Dividend collection service fee and interest collection service fee are calculated in the eligible currency used by the relevant securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism/HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model&lt;/a&gt;
Source: HKEx Pulse / HKEx, Broker China&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Futu Securities Stock Code Special Format Instructions</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Uncommon, it will definitely encounter it over time; related stock code: Berkshire Hathaway&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;text&#34;&gt;Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some stock ticker symbols contain periods or other special characters in their names. When reporting these to Interactive Brokers (IB) via &lt;code&gt;Fix&lt;/code&gt;, certain transformations of the stock code name are required.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;body&#34;&gt;Body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the Fidelity Securities case, it’s possible to analyze and implement the conversion rules are fixed through coding. When the rules are not fixed, generally the system needs to store the corresponding mapping relationships, which are updated periodically by business operations personnel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-links&#34;&gt;Reference Links
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Futures Basic Concepts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets continue to evolve, investors have begun seeking more effective investment tools to enhance their investment returns. To meet investor demand, The Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a range of stock futures contracts, all of which represent stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, the Hong Kong Stock Exchange (HKEX), which boasts high trading volumes and active liquidity. Through investing in stock futures, investors can participate in the performance of individual companies while also benefiting from the short selling and leverage effects offered by the derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the underlying stocks represented by stock futures are typically leading companies within their respective industries, investors can select to invest in those industry-specific futures if they believe a particular sector’s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a specified quantity of financial value (contract size) equivalent to a specified number of shares (the underlying stock) at a predetermined price (the agreed-upon price) on a future, specified date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All stock futures contracts are settled in cash; there is no physical delivery of the underlying stock at expiration.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expiry&#34;&gt;Contract Expiry
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Upon contract expiry, the profit or loss amount is calculated as the difference between the agreed-upon price and the final settlement price multiplied by the contract multiplier, which will be deducted from the clearing member’s margin account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price refers to the official closing price of the stock reported by the Shanghai Stock Exchange on the last trading day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If a futures investor wishes to close out their position before expiry, a short seller only needs to buy back one futures contract, while a long position holder must sell one futures contract.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;margin-deposit&#34;&gt;Margin Deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In futures trading, both buyers and sellers are required to initially deposit a basic margin as collateral to fulfill the contract. After each daily settlement, the clearing organization calculates profits or losses for all open contracts based on the closing market price and uses this to deduct from the investor’s margin account. If unfavorable market conditions result in an investor incurring losses that cause their margin to fall below the specified level, the exchange will require the investor to top up their margin within a designated timeframe to maintain it at the original basic margin level (i.e., to cover).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low Transaction Fees: Each stock futures contract is equivalent to thousands of shares, but brokerage commissions are determined by the number of contracts, making transaction costs relatively low in terms of value.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier Short Selling: Because investors can easily short stocks through futures contracts, they can profit during market declines by shorting stock futures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market Maker System: To ensure market liquidity, The Hong Kong Exchange &amp;amp; Clearing Limited (HKEX) requires market makers to simultaneously provide buy and sell prices within a specified range, maintaining circulation in the stock futures market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage Effect: Investors only need to pay a margin representing a small portion of the contract value when buying or selling stock futures contracts, making hedging and trading more cost-effective. - Reduce foreign investor’s currency risk: Stock futures contracts provide a way for overseas investors to invest in high-quality local stocks because buying and selling stock futures only requires paying a margin, rather than the full value of the contract, thereby significantly reducing the currency risk borne by overseas investors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading through electronic trading systems: Stock futures contracts are traded using the Taiwan Futures Exchange’s electronic trading system. All orders are executed in the order of price and time, and immediate display of buy prices, sell prices, and transaction prices ensures the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages-1&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clearing companies provide performance guarantees: Stock futures contracts will be registered, settled, and guaranteed by HKFE Clearing Ltd (the clearing company), a wholly owned subsidiary of the Hong Kong Futures Exchange.  Due to the clearing company being the counterparty for all open positions, there is no need for participants in the exchange to bear counterparty risk between themselves. However, the scope of this guarantee does not include the financial responsibility of the exchange participants towards their clients; investors should exercise caution and diligence when selecting a broker for buying and selling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-making&#34;&gt;Market Making
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants or individual stock futures contracts may register as market makers on the exchange and simultaneously provide both buy and sell prices within the specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should note that individual stock futures contracts may not have a market maker registered to provide buy-sell spreads, and their trades will be based on market trading units. &lt;strong&gt;Investors should be aware that buying and selling stock futures without a registered market maker may involve liquidity risk, and caution should be exercised before entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stock-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of Trading Stock Futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock futures involve high risks. Losses arising from trading stock futures may exceed the initial margin paid at opening, potentially requiring you to pay additional margins within a short period. If unable to meet these payments, your position may be liquidated, and you will bear all resulting losses. Therefore, it is crucial to fully understand the risks involved in trading stock futures and assess whether it aligns with your financial situation and investment objectives. Before engaging in transactions, consult with a broker or financial advisor to determine if futures and options contracts are suitable for your circumstances.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjusting-comments&#34;&gt;Adjusting Comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When a listed company changes its capital structure through methods such as offering shares or issuing bonus shares, this will lead to changes in the stock price at the time of net asset valuation or the effective date, and may also affect uncovered contracts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If other circumstances remain unchanged, the value held by shareholders’ portfolios will not change on the settlement day, but this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures. Unless the futures contract is appropriately adjusted. If the initial pricing remains unchanged and the contract multiplier remains constant, the adjustment of the stock price will unfairly and unjustly affect the value of the stock futures holding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the clearing organization determines the adjustment ratio, it does so based on maintaining the fair value of the futures contracts and only makes adjustments when there are significant changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Futures Contracts Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/futures-contracts-overview.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Futures Contracts Overview&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;news-provider-code&#34;&gt;News Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/news_provider_code.png&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;News Provider Code&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/products/listed-derivatives/single-stock/stock-futures?sc_lang=zh-cn#list_of_stock_futures&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong Exchange - Derivatives / Stocks / Stock Futures&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange Interface Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having spent five years developing financial software, I’ve become most familiar with the interface documentation of various exchanges. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly well-versed in the Hong Kong Exchange’s documents, and recently while handling the China Bond Connect business, I also reviewed materials from the Shanghai Stock Exchange (SSE) and Shenzhen Stock Exchange (SZSE).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Official Website&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Trading-Hour,-Trading-and-Settlement-Calendar?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Hours, Trading and Settlement Calendar&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Mechanism&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/hkex-market/mutual-market/stock-connect/reference-materials/resources/glossary_c&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Hong Kong-Mainland China Financial Terminology Glossary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_pdf_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;2021-Calendar_csv_c.csv&#34; &gt;Shanghai Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar CSV&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-1&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;glossary_c.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Financial Terminology Glossary PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/vcm/vcmtriggersecurity_c.aspx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Broker Inquiry Mechanism Cooling-off Period Trigger Record&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/chi/services/trading/securities/securitieslists/ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;List of Securities: Basic Information, Security Classification&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Closing-Auction-Session-%28CAS%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Closing Auction Session (CAS) Securities Trading Hours&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;frequently-used-2&#34;&gt;Frequently Used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Volatility-Control-Mechanism-%28VCM%29-Securities?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Volatility Control Mechanism (VCM) Securities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sc.hkex.com.hk/TuniS/www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Securities-Lists/Designated-Securities-Eligible-for-Short-Selling?sc_lang=zh-CN&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Designated Securities Eligible for Short Selling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;ListOfSecurities_c.xlsx&#34; &gt;Securities List: Basic Information, Securities Classification XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;###行情 Interface Documentation: H Shares + China Fortune Securities
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Interface Documentation Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;
Frequently Asked Questions, Guidance on Development Manuals, Historical Interface Documentation can be obtained by downloading through the search bar by searching for historical version numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Market-Data-Services/Infrastructure/HKEX-Orion-Market-Data-Platform-Securities-Market-OMD-C?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;H Shares Securities Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Mutual-Market/Stock-Connect/Reference-Materials/Technical-Documents/OMD_CC-Specifications?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;China Fortune Securities Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-fortune-securities&#34;&gt;Trading Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Fortune Securities
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-conchoneship&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Conchoneship
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://example.com/OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Replace with actual URL if available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://example.com/OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt; (Replace with actual URL if available)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-interface-document-hong-kong-stocks--zhonghua-tong&#34;&gt;Trading Interface Document: Hong Kong Stocks + Zhonghua Tong
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Infrastructure/Overview?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trading Interface Document Summary Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v2_2-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Secondary Market Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;Reason_Text_List.xlsx&#34; &gt;Hong Kong Exchange Error Code List XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_FIX_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Zhonghua Tong FIX Protocol Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEx_CCCG_Binary_Trading_Interface_Specifications_v1_3-%28clean%29.pdf&#34; &gt;Zhonghua Tong Binary Interface Document PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sse-shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;SSE (Shanghai Stock Exchange)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.sse.com.cn/services/tradingservice/tradingtech/technical/data/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data and Trading Link Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
Error Interface Documentation can be found in other menus
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;SSE_IS111_ErrorCode_CV3.15.xlsx&#34; &gt;Trading Error Interface Documentation XLSX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Shanghai Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://www.szse.cn/marketServices/technicalservice/interface/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Market Data Query Interface Documentation&lt;/a&gt;
The Shanghai Stock Exchange does not provide separate error message explanations; supplementary information can be found in Chapter 6 of the Market Data Query Interface Documentation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;P020201229686784934466.pdf&#34; &gt;Shenzhen Securities Trading Center Binary Transaction Data Interface Specification (Ver1.18) PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;Nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nyse.com/markets/hours-calendars&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Holiday Schedule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.nasdaq.com/market-activity/ipos?tab=upcoming&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;New Issue Information&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;closing-price&#34;&gt;Closing Price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://eoddata.com/stocklist/NASDAQ.htm&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Global Market Closing Prices&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
