<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding buy rate and sell rate in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate.&amp;rdquo; Many people may not be clear on these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, we will use a simple example to help everyone understand the meaning and function of these rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;What are &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to buy foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you sell foreign currency (like US dollars) to a bank, the bank will pay you in RMB according to the buying rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to sell foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell it to you at the selling rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exchange rate at which the bank buys foreign currency from you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The price the bank offers you for foreign currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that banks&amp;rsquo; buying and selling exchange rates are typically different, with the selling rate generally higher than the buying rate. This difference is how banks make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-study-analysis&#34;&gt;Case Study Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let&amp;rsquo;s take a specific example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you go to a bank to exchange for US dollars, and the bank&amp;rsquo;s exchange rate is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.0 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.2 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You sell US dollars to a bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have $1,000 and want to sell it to a bank, the bank will calculate using its buy rate&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1,000 USD x 7.0 CNY/USD = 7,000 CNY
\]
&lt;p&gt;That means the bank will give you 7,000 RMB. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;买入汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are selling dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-2-you-buy-us-dollars-with-rmb&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: You buy US dollars with RMB
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars, the bank will calculate using the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$972.22 USD
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, 7000 RMB can be exchanged for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;卖出汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are purchasing dollars from a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-buy-rate-different-from-the-sell-rate&#34;&gt;Why is the buy rate different from the sell rate?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the bank&amp;rsquo;s selling exchange rate (7.2 RMB/USD) is higher than its buying exchange rate (7.0 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from foreign exchange transactions by exploiting this difference. In other words, banks make a profit by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
Selling exchange rate (7.2) - Buying exchange rate (7.0) = 0.2 RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference is the bank&amp;rsquo;s source of profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank buys foreign currency from you at this exchange rate (the rate when you sell foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank sells foreign currency to you at this exchange rate (the rate when you buy foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between the buying and selling exchange rates is the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these exchange rate concepts allows us to better know how much foreign currency we will receive or how much Chinese Yuan is needed to purchase it when exchanging currencies. Hopefully, this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Stock Exchange, History of Cryptocurrency Development</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election as US President, virtual currency has once again entered the public consciousness. Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) has also been actively developing related businesses; here’s a brief overview of HKEX&amp;rsquo;s virtual currency development history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the contract details, it&amp;rsquo;s clear that futures were initially introduced, which is reasonable given their better liquidity and ease of attracting institutional investors. The subsequent introduction of spot ETFs was also logical, as ETFs are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptocurrency-list&#34;&gt;Cryptocurrency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Stock Exchange&amp;rsquo;s market data doesn&amp;rsquo;t provide a tag to distinguish whether a contract is for virtual currency, but it can be determined by the contract name. The official transaction list does provide corresponding subcategories &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-first-asia-based-crypto-etfs-listing&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes First Asia-Based Crypto ETFs Listing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first cryptocurrency ETFs, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for Hong Kong and international investors&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Two new ETFs launched today — China Southern East Funds Management’s Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) — are managed by China Southern East Asset Management Co., Ltd. They track standardized, cash-settled Bitcoin futures contracts and Ethereum futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Chief Operating Officer and Co-Head of Markets, Nicole Yau, stated: &amp;ldquo;The two newly listed cryptocurrency ETFs add to Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s increasingly rich and diverse ecosystem of exchange-traded products. These new products will provide investors in Asia with their first opportunity to participate in digital asset investments, reflecting our focus on the digital economy and market demand. We look forward to welcoming more thematic ETFs and digital asset products in the coming months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETFs are one of the fastest-growing businesses under Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a constantly expanding and increasingly diverse range of products. In 2022, this included the launch of its first Metaverse ETF, first carbon futures ETF, and first blockchain ETF, as well as the inclusion of ETFs in the Shanghai–Hong Kong Stock Connect scheme for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average daily turnover of Exchange Traded Products (ETPs), including ETFs and leveraged/inverse products, on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange for the first eleven months of this year was HK$11.8 billion, a 50% increase from HK$7.8 billion in the same period last year, reflecting growing investor demand. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange with a total market capitalization of HK$373.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-spot-virtual-asset-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange welcomes the listing of the first spot virtual asset ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first spot virtual asset ETFs, expanding Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s product range and providing investors with greater choice, solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Head of Securities Product Development Robert Lo said, &amp;ldquo;The newly launched virtual asset spot ETF will enrich Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s diverse and vibrant ETF market ecosystem, providing investors with investment opportunities in a new asset class. Following the successful launch of virtual asset futures ETFs a year ago, Asia’s first virtual asset spot ETFs will further enhance the variety and liquidity of products traded on Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing. We look forward to continuing to work closely with market participants to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investor demand for the first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs launched in 2022 has been strong, with robust trading volume. The daily turnover of Hong Kong-listed virtual asset futures ETFs increased from HK$8.9 million in 2023 to HK$51.3 million in Q1 2024, accompanied by net inflows of HK$529 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exchange trading of products (including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products) is one of the fastest-growing markets on Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a continuously expanding range of product types. Sixteen new ETF products were added in 2023 and Q1 2024, including Asia’s first Saudi Arabia ETF and Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s first exchange-traded options ETFs. There are currently 179 ETFs listed in Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchanges-and-clearing-is-launching-a-series-of-virtual-asset-indices&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing is launching a series of virtual asset indices
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Monday) announced the launch of the HKEX Virtual Asset Index Series on November 15, 2024. This index series will provide a reliable benchmark for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s development as Asia’s leading digital asset hub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will provide a transparent and reliable benchmark for the pricing of Bitcoin and Ethereum in Asian time zones, aiming to establish a unified reference price for virtual assets and resolve price discrepancies across global exchanges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing CEO Nicolas Aguzin said, &amp;ldquo;We are pleased to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series to meet regional demand for this rapidly growing asset class. By providing a transparent and reliable real-time benchmark, we aim to help investors make informed decisions, support the healthy development of the virtual asset ecosystem, and solidify Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as an international financial center.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this index series is part of Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring emerging areas, supporting the development of Hong Kong’s financial technology while also providing investors with important benchmark tools and solutions in a constantly evolving market environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference rate is calculated based on a weighted average of 24-hour trading volumes in Bitcoin or Ethereum, aggregated from major cryptocurrency exchanges and priced in USD. It&amp;rsquo;s designed for the settlement of financial products and calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will be the first in Hong Kong to comply with EU Benchmark Regulation (BMR), co-managed and calculated by a UK-registered benchmark administrator and virtual asset data and index provider, CCData&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Special Administrative Region government issued a policy statement in 2022 aiming to foster a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange’s Virtual Asset Index series will help increase public understanding of virtual asset investment trends by providing real-time data and daily reference prices in the Asian time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Further details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be released as appropriate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has seen significant volatility, breaking through 7.26</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the broader market decline are likely linked to global central bank policies, the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise interest rate cut, US economic data performance, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors collectively impacted the foreign exchange and stock markets, leading to Renminbi volatility and A-share declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the link provided, the Renminbi exchange rate experienced a significant fluctuation on March 22, 2024. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yuan weakened at opening, with the dollar exceeding 7.24 against the offshore RMB to 7.24926 and surpassing 7.22 against the onshore RMB to 7.22360, both breaking highs seen since November 17, 2023. At the time of this report, the dollar has broken past 7.26, reaching a low of 7.2639, and the trend continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 22, the central bank set the midpoint of the yuan against the dollar at 7.1004, a decrease of 62 basis points, with an expanded adjustment range&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affected by multiple factors, China&amp;rsquo;s three major A-share indices opened and closed lower, with declines exceeding 1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior currency trader at a Hong Kong investment firm stated that foreign exchange market volatility is primarily due to the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s unexpected rate cut boosting the dollar, combined with a strong US economy and persistent inflation potentially delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the dollar index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is a &amp;ldquo;super central bank week&amp;rdquo; for global markets, with interest rate decisions to be announced by central banks in the US, Japan, UK, Australia, and more. The Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise rate cut marks the first such action among G10 central banks since the pandemic began, disrupting market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangda Bank financial market researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent RMB fluctuations, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies like the US dollar, and short-term volatility will not alter the year&amp;rsquo;s upward trend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi dual counter service</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter-mode/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter-mode/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing announced on December 13th that its securities market will launch a &amp;ldquo;dual currency trading model&amp;rdquo; (hereinafter referred to as the “dual counter model”) and a dual counter designated participant mechanism, further supporting Renminbi counter listings, trading, and settlement in Hong Kong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dual-counter-model-and-dual-counter-bookmaker-mechanism&#34;&gt;Dual counter model and dual counter bookmaker mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) stated that, pending regulatory approval and market readiness, the registration process for new measures is expected to begin in the first half of 2023. Under the dual-counter model, HKEX will optimize trading and settlement arrangements to allow investors to switch between Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi counter securities issued by the same entity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance liquidity and narrow the spread in its Renminbi trading counters, Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing will introduce a dual counter dealing mechanism. Following legislative approval, market makers engaging in volume supply activities may be exempt from stamp duty on specific transactions. These measures also aim to prepare for future Mainland investors pricing securities via Stock Connect with RMB.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of a Hong Kong dollar-RMB dual counter model and dual counter market maker mechanism is an important step in our market development. Coupled with other market initiatives, this arrangement will help attract more dual-counter securities to list in Hong Kong and create good synergy with existing mainland products offered by the Exchange. &amp;ldquo;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing is committed to actively promoting the internationalization of RMB and continuously enhancing Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading offshore Renminbi center,&amp;rdquo; said Head of Equities and Market Supervision, Calmer Yao.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s existing listing, trading, clearing and settlement arrangements will generally apply to RMB counter securities under the dual-counter model. The Hong Kong Stock Exchange will announce the implementation date and a list of eligible dual-counter securities for inclusion in the designated participant mechanism in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-rmb-exchange-counters&#34;&gt;How to identify Hong Kong dollar-RMB exchange counters
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to Hong Kong Exchange documents, the dual currency (Hong Kong dollar-Renminbi) trading arrangement will largely follow the existing stock code allocation plan: stocks on the Hong Kong dollar counter will begin with &amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo; followed by a five-digit number, while those on the Renminbi counter will begin with &amp;ldquo;8.&amp;rdquo; The last four digits of the stock codes for both counters will be identical. Stock short names on the Renminbi counter will have &amp;ldquo;-R&amp;rdquo; appended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding trading arrangements, securities with the same category and convertible between Renminbi and Hong Kong dollar counters can be designated for short selling. If one counter (e.g., Hong Kong dollar) is designated, the other (e.g., Renminbi) may also be included according to exchange rules, and both will appear on the exchange&amp;rsquo;s list of securities approved for short sale.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stocks listed on both counters belong to the same category and are interchangeable. Buying with Hong Kong dollars and selling in Renminbi, or vice versa, will be considered &amp;ldquo;round-trip trading.&amp;rdquo; Settlement time between the two counters is T+2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short selling of specified stocks, such as borrowing Hong Kong dollars to sell them on the RMB counter, and vice versa, will be considered secured short selling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s worth noting that under the dual-currency counter model, physical stock deposits and withdrawals are not available at the RMB counters as they are solely for trading and settlement. Physical stocks must first be deposited at the HKD counters before being converted to the RMB counters. Similarly, physical stocks can only be withdrawn after conversion from the RMB counters to the HKD counters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Transaction settlement and delivery fees, including all Hong Kong clearing fees, are calculated and charged in Hong Kong dollars, except for dividend collection fees and interest collection fees, which are calculated based on the currency of the relevant securities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism/HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model&lt;/a&gt;
Source: Hong Kong Stock Exchange Pulse, Securities Times China&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Special Format Instructions for Interactive Brokers Stock Codes</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Rare, but eventually you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter it given enough time. Associated stock code: Berkshire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When submitting stock codes with names containing certain formatting, adjustments to the code name are required for Interactive Brokers (IB)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding Interactive Brokers, it can be analyzed to determine that the conversion rules are fixed and can be implemented through coding. When the rules are not fixed, the system generally needs to store corresponding mappings, which business operation personnel update periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong stock futures basics</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets evolve, investors are seeking more effective investment tools to enhance returns. To meet this demand, Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a series of stock futures contracts representing stocks listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, Hong Kong Joint Stock Exchange Limited (Joint Stock). These contracts offer high liquidity and active trading, allowing investors to participate in the performance of individual companies while benefiting from features like short selling and leverage available in derivative markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investors can choose to invest in stock futures representing specific industries if they believe that industry&amp;rsquo;s performance will outperform or underperform the overall stock market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a financial instrument equivalent to a specified quantity of stock at a predetermined price on a future date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expires&#34;&gt;Contract expires
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The profit or loss amount, calculated as the difference between the initial agreement price and the final settlement price, multiplied by the contract multiplier, will be deducted from the account of the contract holder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price is the official closing price reported on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange on the last trading day for the relevant stock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If stock futures investors wish to close their positions before expiration, short sellers only need to buy back a futures contract, while long position holders sell a futures contract&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-deposit&#34;&gt;Security deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When trading futures, both buyers and sellers must first pay an initial margin as a guarantee of fulfilling the contract. The clearing house calculates daily profits and losses on all open contracts at the closing market price, which serves as the basis for debiting or crediting investor accounts. If adverse market conditions result in losses that reduce the margin below the required level, the exchange will require investors to replenish their funds within a specified timeframe to maintain the initial margin level (i.e., topping up).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Low transaction fees: Each stock futures contract represents the value of thousands of shares, and commissions for buying or selling contracts depend on the number of contracts traded, resulting in very low costs relative to the contract&amp;rsquo;s value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short selling stocks is now easier: Investors can profit in a downturn by short selling stock futures, as this process is readily available&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market makers are required by Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing to simultaneously provide bid and ask prices within a specified range to ensure market liquidity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage allows investors to buy or sell stock futures contracts by paying only a small portion of the contract&amp;rsquo;s face value, making hedging and trading more cost-effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing foreign exchange risk for overseas investors: Stock futures contracts provide a way for foreign investors to invest in high-quality local stocks, as trading them requires margin rather than the full contract value, significantly reducing their exposure to foreign exchange risk&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading is conducted through an electronic trading system: stock futures contracts are bought and sold using the exchange&amp;rsquo;s electronic system. Orders are executed based on price and time priority, with real-time display of bid prices, ask prices, and transaction prices, achieving the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The clearing house provides performance guarantees: stock futures contracts will be registered, cleared, and guaranteed by Hong Kong Futures Clearing Company Limited (the Clearing House), a wholly-owned subsidiary of the exchange. As the Clearing House acts as counterparty to all open positions, participants are relieved from counterparty risk. However, this guarantee does not cover clearing members&amp;rsquo; financial obligations to their clients; investors should carefully select their brokers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealer-system&#34;&gt;Dealer system
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants may register as market makers for individual stock futures, providing both bid and ask prices within a specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should note that individual stock futures may not have market maker registrations offering bid-ask spreads, and trading will be based on market order units.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;risks-of-trading-stocks-and-futures&#34;&gt;Risks of trading stocks and futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Trading stock futures involves high risk. Losses can exceed the initial margin deposit, potentially requiring you to pay additional funds in a short period. Failure to do so may result in forced liquidation of your positions, with all losses borne by you. Therefore, it is essential that you understand the risks of trading stock futures and assess whether they are suitable for you. Before trading, consult a broker or financial advisor based on your financial situation and investment goals to determine if trading futures and options contracts is appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjust-comments&#34;&gt;Adjust comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Changes to a company&amp;rsquo;s equity structure through share offerings or bonus shares can affect the stock price at net asset value or effective date, potentially impacting open positions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all other factors remain the same, the value of a shareholder&amp;rsquo;s holdings will not change on the net asset value date. However, this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures unless appropriate adjustments are made to the futures contract. Without adjusting the settlement price and if the multiplier of the stock futures contract remains unchanged, an adjustment in the underlying stock price would create unreasonable and unfair effects on the value of the stock futures position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clearing house adjusts rates to maintain fair value for futures contracts, making changes only when significant alterations occur. The Hong Kong Exchange will announce the details of these adjustments, and exchange participants must inform their clients about them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Stock futures contracts overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-provider-code&#34;&gt;Information Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Trading Interrupted</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:51:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A trade disruption refers to when a trade has been executed and IB has received execution information from the exchange. Then, the exchange realizes that an error has occurred (such as pricing, electronic processing issues, obvious errors, etc.) and decides to disrupt (cancel) the trade. This process is entirely determined and controlled by the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A busted traderefers to a situation where an execution occurs and IB receives the execution messagefrom the exchange. The exchange then realizes some type of error (Pricing,electronic, obvious error, etc) and rules to bust (cancel) the trade. Theexchange makes these rulings entirely on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a trading perspective, it is equivalent to trade cancellation and trade correction on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange API Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my fifth year of financial software development, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with various exchange interface documents – particularly familiar with the Hong Kong Stock Exchange’s documentation. Recently, while handling ChinaConnect business, I reviewed materials from the Shenzhen and Shanghai stock exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hkex&#34;&gt;hkex
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonly-used&#34;&gt;Commonly used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-connect&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Connect
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download addresses for frequently asked questions, development manual guidance, and historical market data interface documentation can be found by searching; search for historical version numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotation-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-connect&#34;&gt;Quotation Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Connect
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(LINK_0).pdf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(LINK_0).pdf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(LINK_0).pdf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(LINK_0).pdf&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;shanghai-stock-exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Error reporting interface documentation is available in other menus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shenzhen-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;shenzhen-stock-exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shenzhen Stock Exchange did not provide specific error messages; see Chapter 6 of the order interface documentation for additional information&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;market-price&#34;&gt;Market price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
