<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Financial Knowledge Base on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 03:15:22 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/financial-knowledge-base/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding buy rate and sell rate in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, especially at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate.&amp;rdquo; Many people may not be clear about these two concepts, or even confused. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s use a simple example to help everyone understand the meaning and function of these two rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-buy-exchange-rate-and-sell-exchange-rate&#34;&gt;What are &amp;ldquo;buy exchange rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell exchange rate&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The buy rate is the exchange rate at which a bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currency; that is, when you sell foreign currency (such as US dollars) to a bank, the bank will pay you in RMB according to the buy rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The selling exchange rate is the rate at which a bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currency; that is, when you buy foreign currency with Chinese Yuan, the bank will sell it to you at the selling exchange rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The buy exchange rate is the price at which a bank buys foreign currency from you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: The price the bank offers you for foreign currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that banks&amp;rsquo; buying and selling exchange rates are usually different, with the selling rate generally higher than the buying rate. This difference is the bank’s source of profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-study-analysis&#34;&gt;Case Study Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these two exchange rates, let&amp;rsquo;s take a specific example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you go to the bank to exchange for US dollars, and the exchange rate offered by the bank is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy exchange rate: 1 US dollar = 7.0 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: 1 US dollar = 7.2 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-the-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You sell US dollars to the bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have $1,000 and want to sell it to a bank; the bank will calculate based on its buying exchange rate&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1000 x 7.0 yuan/dollar = 7000 yuan
\]
&lt;p&gt;That means the bank will give you 7,000 RMB. The exchange rate here is a &lt;strong&gt;buy rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are selling dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-2-you-buy-us-dollars-with-rmb&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: You buy US dollars with RMB
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Suppose you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate based on the selling exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$7,000 yuan ÷ 7.2 yuan/dollar = $972.22
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7000 Chinese Yuan for approximately 972.22 US dollars. The exchange rate here is a &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are buying US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-buying-exchange-rate-different-from-the-selling-exchange-rate&#34;&gt;Why is the buying exchange rate different from the selling exchange rate?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the bank&amp;rsquo;s buying exchange rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling exchange rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from foreign exchange transactions by using this difference in rates. In other words, banks make a profit by charging a higher selling exchange rate and paying a lower buying exchange rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
Selling exchange rate (7.2) - Buying exchange rate (7.0) = 0.2 RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference is the bank&amp;rsquo;s source of profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Buy exchange rate: The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the rate at which you sell foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Selling exchange rate: This is the exchange rate at which the bank sells foreign currency to you (the exchange rate when you buy foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between the buying and selling exchange rates is the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you understand these exchange rate concepts, you can more clearly know how much foreign currency you will receive when exchanging currencies, or how much Chinese Yuan (RMB) you need to spend to buy foreign currency. I hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong Stock Exchange, History of Cryptocurrency Development</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:00:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-stock-exchange-virtual-currency-history/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With Donald Trump&amp;rsquo;s re-election as US President, virtual currency has once again entered the public consciousness. Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing (HKEX) has also been actively deploying related businesses; here is a brief record of HKEX’s development history regarding virtual currency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reviewing the details of the relevant contract list, I discovered that what was initially introduced wasn&amp;rsquo;t spot trading but futures. This is reasonable because the liquidity in the futures market is better and it’s easier to attract institutional investors. The subsequent introduction of spot ETFs was also reasonable, as ETFs are a more readily accepted investment tool.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cryptocurrency-list&#34;&gt;Cryptocurrency List
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Stock Exchange&amp;rsquo;s market data does not provide an identifier to distinguish whether a contract is a virtual currency, but it can be determined by the contract name. The official transaction list, however, provides the corresponding subcategory &lt;code&gt;virtualasset&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Market-Data/Securities-Prices/Exchange-Traded-Products?sc_lang=en&amp;amp;asset=virtualasset&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;december-16-2022&#34;&gt;December 16, 2022
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchange-welcomes-listing-of-asias-first-cryptocurrency-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchange Welcomes Listing of Asia’s First Cryptocurrency ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Markets Limited (HKEX) today (Friday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first cryptocurrency ETFs, further expanding its product ecosystem and providing more choices for investors in Hong Kong and internationally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two newly listed ETFs today — Southern East Investment Bitcoin Futures ETF (stock code: 3066) and Southern East Investment Ethereum Futures ETF (stock code: 3068) — are managed by Southern East Asset Management Co., Ltd. They track standardized, cash-settled bitcoin futures contracts and ethereum futures contracts traded on the Chicago Mercantile Exchange (CME).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Chief Operating Officer and Co-Head of Markets, Nicole Yau, said: &amp;ldquo;The two cryptocurrency ETFs listed today add another layer to Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s increasingly rich and diverse ecosystem of exchange-traded products. These new products will provide investors in Asia with their first opportunity to participate in digital asset investments, and reflect our focus on the digital economy and market demand. We look forward to welcoming more thematic ETFs and new digital asset products in the coming months.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ETFs are one of the fastest-growing businesses under Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a constantly expanding and increasingly diversified range of products. In 2022, they launched their first Metaverse ETF, their first carbon futures ETF, and their first blockchain ETF, and for the first time included ETFs in the Shanghai–Hong Kong Stock Connect scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The average daily turnover of products listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange (ETPs, including ETFs and leveraged and inverse products) for the first ten months of this year was HK$11.8 billion, a 50% increase from HK$7.8 billion in the same period last year, reflecting the growing popularity of ETPs among investors. As of November 2022, there were 168 ETPs listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange with a total market capitalization of HK$373.5 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;april-30-2024&#34;&gt;April 30, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchanges-and-clearing-welcomes-the-listing-of-the-first-virtual-asset-spot-etfs&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing welcomes the listing of the first virtual asset spot ETFs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Markets Limited (HKEX) today (Tuesday) welcomed the listing of Asia’s first virtual asset spot ETFs, expanding the range of products in the Hong Kong market and providing investors with a wider selection, solidifying Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading ETF market in Asia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Head of Securities Product Development Robert Lo said: &amp;ldquo;The newly launched virtual asset spot ETF will enrich Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing&amp;rsquo;s diverse and vibrant ETF market ecosystem, providing investors with investment opportunities in a new asset class. Following the successful launch of virtual asset futures ETFs one year ago, Asia’s first batch of virtual asset spot ETFs will further enhance the variety and liquidity of tradable products on Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing. We look forward to continuing to work closely with market participants to introduce more new products into our internationalized market.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first batch of virtual asset futures ETFs listed in 2022 have been highly favored by investors and enjoyed brisk trading. The average daily turnover of the three virtual asset futures ETFs listed in Hong Kong increased from HK$8.9 million in 2023 to HK$51.3 million in the first quarter of 2024, while also attracting net inflows of HK$529 million.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The exchange trading of products (including ETFs, leveraged and inverse products) is one of the fastest-growing markets in Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing, with a continuously increasing variety of product types. The 16 newly launched ETF products in 2023 and Q1 2024 include Asia’s first Saudi Arabia ETF and Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s first exchange-traded fund linked to options, bringing the total number of ETFs listed in Hong Kong to 179.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;october-28-2024&#34;&gt;October 28, 2024
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;hong-kong-exchanges-and-clearing-will-launch-a-series-of-virtual-asset-indices&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing will launch a series of virtual asset indices
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) today (Monday) announced that it will launch the HKEX Virtual Asset Index Series (the Index Series) on November 15, 2024, to provide a reliable benchmark price for the rapidly growing asset class of virtual assets, supporting Hong Kong’s development as Asia&amp;rsquo;s leading digital asset hub&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will provide a transparent and reliable benchmark for the pricing of Bitcoin and Ethereum in Asian time zones, committed to providing a unified reference price for virtual assets and resolving price discrepancies between global exchanges&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Chief Executive Officer Nicolas Aguzin said: &amp;ldquo;We are pleased to launch the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series to meet the demand in the region for this rapidly growing asset class. By providing a transparent and reliable real-time benchmark, we hope to help investors make informed investment decisions, thereby supporting the healthy development of the virtual asset ecosystem and consolidating Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as an international financial center.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of this index series is part of Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing&amp;rsquo;s commitment to exploring emerging areas, supporting the development of financial technology in Hong Kong while also providing investors with important benchmark tools and solutions in a constantly changing market environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The index series will include reference indices for Bitcoin and Ethereum, as well as reference exchange rates&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reference index is based on a benchmark spot price, weighted by the 24-hour trading volume of Bitcoin or Ethereum, and calculated according to aggregated market prices from multiple major virtual asset exchanges, quoted in US dollars. The reference rate is designed for financial product settlement and is calculated daily at 4:00 PM Hong Kong time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This index series will be the first in Hong Kong to comply with European Union Benchmark Regulation (BMR), and will be jointly managed and calculated by a benchmark management agency registered in the UK and virtual asset data and index provider CCData&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Government of the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region released a policy statement on virtual assets in 2022, aiming to foster a vibrant virtual asset industry and ecosystem in Hong Kong. The launch of the Hong Kong Exchange Virtual Asset Index Series will help the public increase their understanding of virtual asset investment trends by providing real-time data and daily reference prices in the Asian time zone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More details regarding the design and calculation methods of the index series will be released in due course&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/news/news-release/2022/221216news?sc_lang=zh-hk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/240430news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.hkex.com.hk/News/News-Release/2024/241028news?sc_lang=zh-HK&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant volatility, breaking through 7.26</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline of the broader market may be related to the actions of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss National Bank, the performance of US economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors collectively impacted the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to volatility in the Renminbi exchange rate and a decline in A-share markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the content of the link you provided, on March 22, 2024, the exchange rate of the Renminbi experienced a significant fluctuation. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US dollar exchange rate against the offshore renminbi broke through: The yuan weakened at the opening of the day, with the dollar versus the offshore renminbi rising above 7.24 to 7.24926 and rising above 7.22 to 7.22360 against the onshore renminbi during intraday trading, both breaking through highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time this reporter from Caiyun Society reported, the dollar versus the offshore renminbi broke through the 7.26 level, falling to a low of 7.2639, and the trend has not stopped.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;PBOC Midpoint Adjustment: On March 22, the central bank announced that the RMB exchange rate against the US dollar was set at 7.1004, down 62 basis points, with a larger adjustment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The A-share market reacted with a decline, influenced by various factors; all three major indices opened and closed lower, with falls exceeding 1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reasons for Forex Market Volatility: A senior currency trader from an investment firm in Hong Kong stated that forex market volatility is primarily due to the US dollar being boosted by the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s unexpected interest rate cut, combined with a strong US economy and persistent inflation which may delay interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the US Dollar Index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Updates:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is a &amp;ldquo;super central bank week&amp;rdquo; for global markets, as central banks in the United States, Japan, the UK, Australia, and many other countries will announce interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss National Bank unexpectedly announced an interest rate cut, becoming the first G10 central bank to do so since the outbreak of the pandemic, which disrupted market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangda Bank&amp;rsquo;s Financial Markets Research Department researcher Zhou Maohua stated that, although the renminbi has experienced some fluctuations recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the US dollar. Short-term volatility will not change the year’s trend of a steady and upward trajectory for the renminbi.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi dual counter model</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter-mode/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 20:25:47 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hk-rmb-dual-counter-mode/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing announced on December 13 that its securities market will soon launch a “dual currency trading model” (hereinafter referred to as the &amp;ldquo;dual counter model&amp;rdquo;) and a dual counter designated participant mechanism, further supporting the listing, trading, and settlement of Renminbi counters in Hong Kong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dual-counter-model-and-dual-counter-bookmaker-mechanism&#34;&gt;Dual counter model and dual counter bookmaker mechanism
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hong Kong Stock Exchange says that after regulatory approval and market readiness, the registration process for various new measures is expected to begin in the first half of 2023. Under the dual-counter model, the exchange will optimize related trading and settlement arrangements so that investors can switch between Hong Kong dollar counter and Renminbi counter securities issued by the same issuer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To enhance the liquidity of the Renminbi counter and narrow the spread between the two counters, Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing will introduce a dual-counter market maker mechanism. After relevant legislation is passed by the Legislative Council, market makers engaged in providing liquidity can be exempted from stamp duty when conducting specific transactions. At the same time, these new measures will also prepare for subsequent mainland investors trading securities priced in Renminbi through Stock Connect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The launch of a Hong Kong dollar-RMB dual counter model and dual counter market maker mechanism is an important measure for our market development. Coupled with our other market initiatives, this arrangement will help attract more dual-counter securities to list in Hong Kong and create good synergy with the Exchange’s existing mainland products. “Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing is committed to actively promoting the internationalization of RMB and continuously enhancing Hong Kong&amp;rsquo;s position as a leading global offshore RMB center,” said Calvyn Yao, Chief Operating Officer and Head of Markets at HKEX.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is understood that the existing listing, trading, clearing and settlement arrangements for Hong Kong stocks will also generally apply to Renminbi counter securities under the dual-counter model. The Hong Kong Stock Exchange will announce the implementation date of the dual-counter model and the list of eligible dual-counter securities that meet the requirements for inclusion in the designated participant mechanism in due course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-identify-hong-kong-dollar-rmb-exchange-counters&#34;&gt;How to identify Hong Kong dollar-RMB exchange counters
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to documents from the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, the arrangement for dual currency (Hong Kong dollar-Renminbi) trading will generally follow the existing stock code allocation plan. Stocks on the Hong Kong dollar counter will have 5-digit codes starting with &amp;ldquo;0&amp;rdquo;, while stocks on the Renminbi counter will have 5-digit codes starting with &amp;ldquo;8&amp;rdquo;. The last four digits of the stock codes for both Hong Kong dollar and Renminbi counters will be the same. Stock short names on the Renminbi counter will be suffixed with &amp;ldquo;-R&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding trading arrangements, based on the premise that securities in Renminbi and Hong Kong dollar counters are of the same category and can be converted to each other, if one counter (e.g., Hong Kong dollar counter) is designated for short selling, the other counter (e.g., Renminbi counter) can also be included as designated for short selling according to exchange rules; accordingly, both counters will appear on the list of designated securities for short selling published by the exchange&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given that the stocks of the two counters belong to the same category and are convertible, both buying or holding in Hong Kong dollars and selling in Renminbi, or vice versa, will be regarded as a round-trip transaction. The settlement time between the two counters is T+2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Short selling of specified stocks, such as borrowing shares in Hong Kong currency and then selling them on the RMB counter, will be considered a guaranteed short sale, and vice versa&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is worth noting that under the dual currency counter model, physical stock deposits and withdrawals are not available for RMB counters as they are solely used for trading and settlement. Physical stocks can only be deposited at Hong Kong dollar counters before being converted to RMB counters. Similarly, physical stocks can only be withdrawn after conversion from RMB counters to Hong Kong dollar counters.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fees for related transactions, settlement and delivery, as well as all Hong Kong clearing fees, are calculated and charged in Hong Kong dollars, except for dividend collection service fees and interest collection service fees, which are calculated based on the qualified currency adopted by the relevant securities&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/Services/Trading/Securities/Overview/Trading-Mechanism/HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model?sc_lang=en&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKD-RMB-Dual-Counter-Model&lt;/a&gt;
Source: Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Market Pulse, Securities Times China&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Special Format for Interactive Brokers Stock Codes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Aug 2021 17:35:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-stock-code-format-explanation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not common, but you&amp;rsquo;re bound to encounter it eventually; associated stock code: Berkshire&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-body&#34;&gt;Main body
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some stock codes contain &amp;ldquo;.&amp;rdquo; or other special characters, and when submitted to Interactive Brokers (IB) via the &amp;ldquo;Fix&amp;rdquo; report, certain conversions of the stock code names are required&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;BRK/B -&amp;gt; BRK B&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding Interactive Brokers, it can be analyzed to determine that the conversion rules are fixed and can be implemented through coding. When the rules are not fixed, the system generally needs to store corresponding mapping relationships, which business operation personnel update periodically.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-link&#34;&gt;Reference link
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ibkr.info/article/462&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;How do I enter the symbol for Berkshire Hathaway Class B shares onto TWS?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hong Kong stock futures basic concepts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Aug 2021 10:54:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hong-kong-futures-basics/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As financial markets continue to evolve, investors have begun seeking more effective investment tools to increase their returns. To meet investor demand, Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) has launched a series of stock futures contracts, the underlying stocks for which are listed on its wholly-owned subsidiary, Hong Kong Joint Stock Exchange Limited (Joint Stock Exchange). These contracts feature high liquidity and active trading volume. Investing in stock futures allows investors to participate in the performance of individual listed companies while also enjoying benefits such as short selling and leverage offered by the derivatives market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since stock futures represent leading companies within their respective industries, investors who believe that the performance of a particular industry will outperform or underperform the overall stock market can choose to invest in the stock futures of that industry accordingly&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;basic-definition&#34;&gt;Basic Definition
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A stock futures contract is an agreement to buy or sell a financial instrument equivalent to a specified quantity (contract size) of a specific stock at a predetermined price (the initial margin price) on a future, fixed date&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All stock futures contracts are cash-settled, and there is no physical delivery of shares when the contract expires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;contract-expires&#34;&gt;Contract expires
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The profit or loss amount, calculated as the difference between the initial agreement price and the final settlement price multiplied by the contract multiplier, will be debited from the account of the contract holder&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final settlement price is the official closing price reported on The Stock Exchange of Hong Kong on the last trading day for the relevant stock&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If investors in stock futures wish to close their positions before the contract expires, those who initially sold short only need to buy back a futures contract, while those who bought contracts need to sell one&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;security-deposit&#34;&gt;Security deposit
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When trading futures, both buyers and sellers must first pay a margin as security for fulfilling the contract. The clearing house will calculate profits and losses on all open contracts at the market price after each day&amp;rsquo;s closing, which serves as the basis for debiting or crediting investor accounts. If unfavorable market conditions result in an investor incurring losses and their margin falls below the stipulated level, the exchange will require the investor to top up their account within a specified timeframe to maintain the original margin level (i.e., cover the shortfall).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advantages&#34;&gt;Advantages
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transaction fees are low: Each stock futures contract is equivalent to the value of thousands of shares of stock, and the commission for buying or selling contracts depends on the number of contracts, so transaction costs are very low relative to the contract value&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Short selling stocks is now easier: Investors can profit in a declining market by short selling stock futures, as they can do so conveniently&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Market makers are required by Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing to simultaneously provide bid and ask prices within a specified spread to ensure market liquidity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Leverage allows investors to buy or sell stock futures contracts by paying only a small portion of the contract&amp;rsquo;s face value, making hedging and trading more cost-effective&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reducing Foreign Exchange Risk for Overseas Investors: Stock futures contracts provide a way for overseas investors to invest in high-quality local stocks, as buying and selling stock futures requires only margin deposits rather than the full contract value, significantly reducing the foreign exchange risk faced by overseas investors&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading is conducted through an electronic trading system: stock futures contracts are bought and sold using the exchange&amp;rsquo;s electronic trading system. All orders are executed on a price and time priority basis, and buy prices, sell prices, and transaction prices are displayed in real-time, achieving the highest level of market transparency.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The clearing house provides performance guarantees: stock futures contracts will be registered, cleared, and have performance guarantees provided by Hong Kong Futures Clearing Company Limited (the Clearing House), which is wholly owned by the exchange. Since the Clearing House acts as the counterparty for all open positions, participants in the exchange will not need to bear counterparty risk. However, the scope of the guarantee does not include the financial obligations of exchange participants to their clients; investors must exercise caution when selecting a broker.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;dealer-system&#34;&gt;Dealer system
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Market participants may register as market makers for individual stock futures, providing both bid and ask prices within a specified maximum spread. Exchange participants and their clients should note that individual stock futures may not have market maker registrations offering bid-ask spreads, and trading will be based on market order units. &lt;strong&gt;Investors should be aware that trading in stock futures without market maker registration may involve liquidity risk and should carefully consider before entering the market.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-risks-of-trading-stocks-and-futures&#34;&gt;The risks of trading stocks and futures
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock futures involve high risk, and losses from buying or selling stock futures may exceed the margin deposited at opening a position, potentially requiring you to pay additional deposits in a short period. If these payments are not made, your positions may be closed out, and any resulting losses will be borne by you alone. Therefore, you must clearly understand the risks of trading stock futures and assess whether they are suitable for you. Before conducting transactions, you should consult with a broker or financial advisor based on your own financial situation and investment goals to determine if buying and selling futures and options contracts is appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;adjust-comments&#34;&gt;Adjust comments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If a company changes its equity structure through share offerings or bonus shares, it may lead to changes in the stock price at net asset value or on the effective date, and this may affect open positions&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If all other factors remain the same, the value of a shareholder&amp;rsquo;s portfolio will not change on the net asset value date, but this is different for buyers or holders of stock futures unless appropriate adjustments are made to the futures contract. Without adjusting the par value and if the multiplier of the stock futures contract remains unchanged, an adjustment in the stock price will have unreasonable and unfair effects on the value of the stock futures position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The clearing house decides to adjust the ratio based on the principle of maintaining the fair value of futures contracts, and will only make adjustments when there are significant changes. Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing will announce the details of the adjustment, and exchange participants must inform their clients about the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-futures-contracts-overview&#34;&gt;Stock futures contracts overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stock Futures Contract Overview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;information-provider-code&#34;&gt;Information Provider Code
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Information Supplier Code&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing - Derivatives / Individual Stocks / Stock Futures
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.hkex.com.hk/-/media/HKEX-Market/Products/Listed-Derivatives/Single-Stock/Stock-Futures/Stock-Futures-Information-Sheets/HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;HKEX_Stock_Futures_SC.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Trading Interrupted</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 10:51:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/interactive-brokers-trading-interruption/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A trade disruption refers to when a trade has been executed and IB has received execution information from the exchange. Then, the exchange realizes that an error has occurred (such as pricing, electronic processing issues, obvious errors, etc.) and decides to disrupt (cancel) the trade. This process is entirely determined and controlled by the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A busted traderefers to a situation where an execution occurs and IB receives the execution messagefrom the exchange. The exchange then realizes some type of error (Pricing,electronic, obvious error, etc) and rules to bust (cancel) the trade. Theexchange makes these rulings entirely on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From a trading perspective, it is equivalent to trade cancellation and trade correction on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Exchange API Documentation Summary</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:35:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/exchange-interface-documentation-summary/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my fifth year of financial software development, I&amp;rsquo;ve been dealing with various exchange interface documents the most. I’m also familiar with the Hong Kong Stock Exchange documentation. Recently, while handling China UnionPay business, I consulted some materials from the Shenzhen and Shanghai stock exchanges.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;[Official website link]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;commonly-used&#34;&gt;Commonly used
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading Hours, Trading and Settlement Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trading Mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glossary of Financial Terms Relating to Mainland and Hong Kong&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Stock Connect Trading Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong and Mainland Trading Calendar (CSV)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Glossary of Financial Terms for Hong Kong and Mainland China&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cooling-off period triggered under price fluctuation mechanism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of Securities: Basic Information, Security Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Securities in the Closing Auction Session (CAS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Volatile Stock Market Mechanism (VSM) Securities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Securities Eligible for Short Selling&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List of Securities: Basic Information, Security Classification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;market-data-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-connect&#34;&gt;Market Data Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Connect
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Summary of Quotation Interface Documentation Links&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Download addresses for frequently asked questions, development manual guides, and historical market data interface documentation can be obtained through the search bar; search for historical version numbers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Equities Market Data Feed Specification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Connect Trading Interface Specifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Binary_Interface_Specifications_v_1,-d-,32c.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&#34; &gt;HKEX_OMDC_Developers_Guide_1_11.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-_Index_datafeed_%28v2_2%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMDC_Connectivity_Guide_Securities_Market-&lt;em&gt;Index_datafeed&lt;/em&gt;(v2_2).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-%28v1-3%29.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Interface_Specification_China_Connect_Securities-(v1-3).pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Connectivity_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&#34; &gt;OMD_Developers_Guide_China_Connect_Securities.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;quotation-interface-documentation-hong-kong-stocks--china-connect&#34;&gt;Quotation Interface Documentation: Hong Kong Stocks + China Connect
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quotation Interface Document Compilation Link&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange FIX Protocol Interface Document&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange Order Connectivity Gateway Binary Trading Interface Specifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Stock Exchange Error Code List&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) CCCG FIX Trading Interface Specifications v1.3 (Cleaned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hong Kong Exchanges and Clearing Limited (HKEX) - China Connect Binary Trading Interface Specifications v1.3 (Cleaned)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shanghai-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Shanghai Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quotation Interface Documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The error interface documentation can be accessed in other menus&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Report Error Interface Document XLSX&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;shenzhen-stock-exchange&#34;&gt;Shenzhen Stock Exchange
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Quotation Interface Documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shenzhen Stock Exchange did not provide separate error messages, but there are additional notes in Chapter 6 of the quotation interface documentation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shenzhen Stock Exchange Binary Trading Data Interface Specification (Ver1.18) PDF&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;nasdaq&#34;&gt;Nasdaq
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Holiday Schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Upcoming IPO Information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;market-price&#34;&gt;Market price
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Global market closing prices&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
