<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Father&#39;s Love on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fathers-love/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Father&#39;s Love on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/fathers-love/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Alternative fantasies and emotional attachments weathered by time</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 22:12:57 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/years-of-settling-alternative-fantasy-and-emotional-attachment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the earliest online literature readers enter middle age, the types of stories they enjoy have also changed. Protagonists now frequently appear as fathers, mentors, or elderly individuals, catering to middle-aged readers&amp;rsquo; different needs regarding life and emotions. These works no longer solely focus on leveling up and defying the odds; instead, they emphasize emotional resonance and reflections on life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;target-audience-the-evolving-readership-over-time&#34;&gt;Target audience: The evolving readership over time
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Once avid online literature readers, most have now entered middle age. They&amp;rsquo;ve experienced the trials of life and their mindset and values have changed. The passionate narratives and adventurous themes they once cherished are no longer their sole pursuit. Instead, they seek emotional resonance that aligns with their current lives, as well as memories of past years and expectations for the future. Middle-aged &amp;ldquo;refreshing&amp;rdquo; novels emerged from this psychological need, attracting readers within this specific demographic through storylines more relatable to middle-aged life and mindset.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;character-transformation-from-youthful-hero-to-middle-aged-responsibility&#34;&gt;Character transformation: from youthful hero to middle-aged responsibility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;My Apprentice Are All Big Villains: After becoming a master, the protagonist Lu Zhou faces a group of apprentices with diverse personalities and powerful abilities. They waver between good and evil, and Lu Zhou needs to guide them towards righteousness. This novel depicts the challenges and perplexities faced by a middle-aged person when teaching the next generation through interactions between the protagonist and his apprentices. At the same time, the growth and transformation of the apprentices allows readers to see hope and the future, as if seeing their own expectations for their children or the younger generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;emotional-resonance-reflections-on-life-and-family-responsibility&#34;&gt;Emotional Resonance: Reflections on Life and Family Responsibility
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A protagonist gains a system on their sixtieth birthday, embarking on a new life journey. This premise allows middle-aged readers to feel a sense of &amp;ldquo;it&amp;rsquo;s not too late&amp;rdquo; hope and inspiration. Even though the protagonist is already in their later years, they can still realize their value and dreams through the system. This storyline reminds readers of opportunities missed and unfulfilled dreams in their own lives, while also conveying a positive attitude towards life and encouraging them to never give up on pursuing their goals at any age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;plot-design-reflecting-the-rhythm-and-fun-of-middle-aged-life&#34;&gt;Plot design: Reflecting the rhythm and fun of middle-aged life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plots in mid-life &amp;ldquo;refreshing&amp;rdquo; novels often pay more attention to the details of life and the nuanced expression of emotions. They no longer pursue the fast-paced leveling up and adventure characteristic of younger refreshing stories, but instead focus on relationships and emotional entanglements between characters. For example, in “The Strongest Master,” the friendship between the protagonist and his apprentice, as well as the brotherhood among fellow disciples, are all depicted with care. This type of plot design allows mid-life readers to feel a sense of warmth and familiarity, as if seeing their own family, friendships, and love reflected in their lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
