<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Centos Stream on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/centos-stream/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Centos Stream on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/centos-stream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>CentOS 8 Stream EOL</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 23:24:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;An upstream open-source development platform prior to release
First noticed the open-source operating system lifecycle&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s expired, what&amp;rsquo;s the problem? Besides security issues, DNF isn&amp;rsquo;t working. I noticed it failed when I recently installed a tool, and checking the mirror source revealed that it has expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-centos-stream&#34;&gt;Introduction to CentOS Stream
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-and-role&#34;&gt;Positioning and Role
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream sits between Fedora Linux (upstream development) and RHEL (downstream development), acting as a bridge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be seen as a version for experiencing the latest Red Hat Enterprise Linux features, suitable for early adopters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;birth-and-background&#34;&gt;Birth and Background
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As time passed, Red Hat began seeking more effective ways to develop its enterprise-level Linux platform and launched CentOS Stream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After CentOS 8 reached its end-of-life in late 2021, CentOS Stream continued to receive updates as its successor and has become the future direction of the CentOS project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features-and-advantages&#34;&gt;Features and Advantages
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is a rolling-release Linux distribution offering faster updates. It provides greater transparency and opportunities for community, partner, and customer involvement, allowing users to contribute to Red Hat Enterprise Linux more quickly and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of CentOS Stream is software that Red Hat intends to include in a future stable version of RHEL, providing a stable ABI/API for community members for development and testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases--target-users&#34;&gt;Use Cases &amp;amp; Target Users
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is suitable for CentOS users who want to continue receiving the latest Linux feature updates, as well as developers and partners who wish to participate in Red Hat Enterprise Linux development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also aims to help community members, Red Hat partners, and others fully leverage innovative open-source programs within a more stable and predictable Linux ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;please-provide-the-chinese-text-you-want-me-to-translate-i-am-ready-when-you-are-just-paste-the-text-here&#34;&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Active Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Security Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 years ago (15 Sep 2021)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 years ago (24 Sep 2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Opted for a long-term support (LTS) version to avoid the hassle of upgrades&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
