<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Centos Stream on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/centos-stream/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Centos Stream on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/centos-stream/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>CentOS 8 Stream EOL</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 23:24:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is an upstream open-source development platform prior to Red Hat Enterprise Linux releases
First noticed the open source operating system lifecycle [Red Hat and CentOS lifecycle]({relref &amp;ldquo;/post/2020/07-redhat and centos life cycle&amp;rdquo;})&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s expired, what&amp;rsquo;s the problem? Besides security issues, DNF is no longer working. I noticed it failed when I installed a tool recently, and checking the mirror source revealed that &lt;code&gt;CentOS 8 Stream&lt;/code&gt; has expired.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction-to-centos-stream&#34;&gt;Introduction to CentOS Stream
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-and-role&#34;&gt;Positioning and Role
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream sits between Fedora Linux (upstream development) and RHEL (Red Hat Enterprise Linux, downstream development), acting as a bridge&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be seen as a version for experiencing the latest Red Hat Enterprise Linux features, suitable for early adopters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;birth-and-background&#34;&gt;Birth and Background
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;As time went on, Red Hat began seeking more effective ways to develop its enterprise-level Linux platform and launched CentOS Stream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After CentOS 8 ended maintenance at the end of 2021, CentOS Stream continued to be updated as its successor and has become the future direction of the CentOS project&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features-and-advantages&#34;&gt;Features and Advantages
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is a rolling-release Linux distribution that provides faster updates. It offers greater transparency and more opportunities for community, partner, and customer involvement, allowing users to contribute to Red Hat Enterprise Linux more quickly and directly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The content of CentOS Stream is software that Red Hat intends to include in a subsequent stable version of RHEL, so it can provide community members with a stable ABI/API for development and testing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases-and-target-users&#34;&gt;Use Cases and Target Users
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is suitable for CentOS users who want to continue receiving the latest Linux feature updates, as well as developers and partners who wish to participate in Red Hat Enterprise Linux development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also aims to assist community members, Red Hat partners, and others in fully leveraging innovative open-source programs within a more stable and predictable Linux ecosystem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;expiration-date&#34;&gt;Expiration Date
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Active Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Security Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 years ago (15 Sep 2021)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 years ago (24 Sep 2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solution&#34;&gt;Solution
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;rsquo;t bother troubleshooting upgrade issues, so I chose the long-term support version of Ubuntu 24.04&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
