<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Code-Area on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/code-area/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Code-Area on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/code-area/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>AI Programming and Task Decomposition</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-programming-and-task-decomposition/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 08:44:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ai-programming-and-task-decomposition/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I added a copy function to the site, which took me half a day of tinkering. Ultimately, the rendering effect wasn&amp;rsquo;t quite satisfactory, and as a somewhat mediocre frontend developer, I didn’t plan on improving it – if it worked, it was good enough. This year, I used &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; to develop a mini-program, which has made me more familiar with frontend development. I refactored it (the &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; redesigned it).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Realization: Breaking down tasks really helps; many small tasks are quite natural for the &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; to develop. For the closed mini-program, 75% of the code was provided by &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt;, broken down into multiple tasks delivered, and manually assembled the project code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;previous-context&#34;&gt;Previous Context
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.github.io/post/2022/001/%E4%BB%A5%E4%B8%BA%E5%BE%88%E7%AE%80%E5%8D%95%E7%9A%84%E4%BA%8B%E6%83%85%E5%A2%9E%E5%8A%A0%E4%B8%80%E4%B8%AA%E4%BB%A3%E7%A0%81%E5%A4%8D%E5%88%B6%E6%8C%89%E9%92%AE/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Making simple things easier: Adding a code copy button&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-text&#34;&gt;Main Text
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;promot&lt;/strong&gt;: Design CSS and JavaScript code to locate webpage elements with the class &amp;ldquo;highlight&amp;rdquo;, and add a copy button within its container, enabling copy-to-clipboard functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first draft of the code was immediately problematic; I regenerated it, making it largely usable, but the copied content was incorrect, containing redundant text. Further guidance led to optimizing the core color design and specifying desired effects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having learned your specific requirements for button size and color, we redesigned the button styles to accommodate these demands.  Below is an adjusted CSS style that incorporates your provided color scheme and optimizes the button&amp;rsquo;s dimensions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within this style, I reduced the button’s size and font size to create a more refined look. “Simultaneously, the button’s default state is semi-transparent. When hovering over the button, it becomes opaque and the background color slightly brightens to provide visual feedback. This design meets your color requirements while maintaining a modern and user-friendly aesthetic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A simpler &lt;code&gt;JavaScript&lt;/code&gt; implementation has also been provided:”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I had hoped to see a copy button added to the top-right corner of the code area, due to my lack of familiarity with front-end development and an inability to accurately describe the functionality based on keywords and “AI,” I spent several rounds chasing after it without achieving the desired outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It remains to be seen what impact “AI” will have on software development as time goes on.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
