<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Gift-Ideas on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift-ideas/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Gift-Ideas on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift-ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Revenue Generation Business Model: Raffle/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-model-raffle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Live streamers sending iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three seemingly unrelated items are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic – a bit like a financial game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-lottery-for-gifts&#34;&gt;Platform Lottery for Gifts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset their acquisition of platform currency and purchase gifts to send to the host, &amp;ldquo;Xin Yi&amp;rdquo; (Hearty), with each platform having another gameplay mechanic. After users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but instead spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery activities, obtaining limited high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the online lottery is simply understood as the platform opening a casino. With enough participants, it’s guaranteed not to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;屌丝&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (literally &amp;ldquo;loser,&amp;rdquo; often used colloquially to describe lower-income individuals) users, fueled by a desire to try their luck and win big, hoping to hit a jackpot and then send gifts – gaining face and acting as a “big brother”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-stream-gifts-physical-items&#34;&gt;Live Stream Gifts (Physical Items)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lottery mentioned previously targets users’ own writing. Each month, the hosts have water flow tasks and popularity tasks. The gameplay of opening gift giveaways allows fans to send specific gifts or gifts of a specified amount, giving them the opportunity to participate in the lottery. The prizes could be high-end phones or cash red envelopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular hosts, this activity is very profitable, essentially equivalent to temporary zero-cost purchases. If enough people participate, the host also makes money. This tests the host’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another gameplay where the rewards are very high (cash value), and many outdoor anchors operate in this way, effectively turning it into an online gambling. Users only care about whether they can win, not the content of the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from show-type hosts, through PK mode, they induce fans to consume and recharge, and ordinary game anchors cannot drive players’ consumption sentiment. Playing games and watching live streams are both ways to pass the time and don&amp;rsquo;t want to incur additional expenses, especially &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. The lottery method can cultivate users’ recharging habits, consumption habits, and occasionally even impulsive spending (sending a lot, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini Program Ranking Rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini program with some useless workflows or provide partial game-related auxiliary services. The above are all cover stories, designed to pass Tencent’s audit – the mini program’s gameplay incorporates a ranking mechanism. Users earn points by browsing promotional ads and completing tasks, and the backend sets rankings based on these points, with higher-ranked users receiving designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Logic: Advertising Revenue &amp;gt; Operating Costs + Reward Expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mini program can also operate normally by providing reasonable services and earning revenue through appropriate advertising – this may not generate much income, but it’s a steady trickle and is acceptable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
