<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Gift-Ideas on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift-ideas/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Gift-Ideas on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift-ideas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Revenue Generation Business Model: Raffle/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Live streamers sending iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These three seemingly unrelated items are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic – a bit like a financial game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;platform-lottery-for-gifts&#34;&gt;Platform Lottery for Gifts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset their acquisition of platform currency and purchase gifts to send to the host, &amp;ldquo;Xin Yi&amp;rdquo; (Hearty), with each platform having another gameplay mechanic. After users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but instead spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery activities, obtaining limited high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this point, the online lottery is simply understood as the platform opening a casino. With enough participants, it’s guaranteed not to lose money. &lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;屌丝&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt; (literally &amp;ldquo;loser,&amp;rdquo; often used colloquially to describe someone from a lower socioeconomic background) users, fueled by a desire to gamble and win big, hoping to hit a jackpot and then send gifts – gaining face and becoming a “big brother”!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;live-stream-gifts-physical-items&#34;&gt;Live Stream Gifts (Physical Items)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The lottery mentioned in the preceding text targets users’ own writing. Each month, the hosts have water flow tasks and popularity tasks. The gameplay of enabling gift giveaways allows fans to send specific gifts or gifts of a specified amount, giving them the opportunity to participate in the lottery. The prizes may include high-end phones or cash red envelopes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular live streamers, this activity is very profitable, essentially equivalent to a temporary zero-cost purchase. If enough people participate, the streamer also makes money. This tests the streamer’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also a gameplay where the rewards are very high (cash value), and many outdoor streamers engage in this type of scheme, which is essentially online gambling. The content of the livestream doesn’t matter; users only care about whether they can win. Excluding live streaming hosts of stage performance types, through PK (peer-versus-peer) modes, inducing fans to consume and recharge, ordinary game streamers are difficult to drive player spending sentiment. Playing games and watching live streams are primarily for entertainment and don’t necessarily lead to additional financial expenditure, especially &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. Lottery-style mechanisms can cultivate users&amp;rsquo; charging habits, consumption habits, and occasionally even impulsive purchases (giving away a lot, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini Program Ranking Rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini program that incorporates some useless workflows or provides partial game-related auxiliary services. The preceding items are all cover stories, designed to pass Tencent’s review by adding a ranking mechanism to the mini program&amp;rsquo;s gameplay – incorporating elements like bringing in some pointless processes or offering part-game related assistance. Users earn points by browsing promotional ads and completing tasks, with a leaderboard established in the background based on these points, rewarding users with designated rewards based on their rank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core Logic: Advertising Revenue &amp;gt; Operational Costs + Reward Expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mini program can also operate normally by providing reasonable services and earning revenue through appropriate advertising – this may not yield much profit, but it’s like a trickle, and that&amp;rsquo;s acceptable too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
