<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Valuation on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/valuation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Valuation on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/valuation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Broad-based index investing: Broker ETF, Hang Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to do this – buy a good blue-chip stock and just leave it alone. But I waited for it to fall, didn&amp;rsquo;t add to my position, and sold when it rose. As a result, I never managed to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s more trouble than it&amp;rsquo;s worth to find suitable blue-chip stocks; instead, just pick a broad market index and buy an ETF. The current plan is: securities ETF, Hang Seng Tech Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trading strategy has a professional term: left-side dip buying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, the plan is to choose a broad-based index for thorough practice; it just needs to outperform the returns of fixed deposits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brokerage-etfs&#34;&gt;Brokerage ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Securities ETF refers to exchange-traded funds (ETFs) with China&amp;rsquo;s securities companies as their primary investment target, primarily investing in listed securities company stocks in the Chinese stock market. Securities ETFs typically track a specific securities company index, such as the Zhongxin Securities Company Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought it before, but I chased after the high price at that time and ended up losing money, so I just cleared out the position. In China&amp;rsquo;s market, every bull market sees securities firms rise; how much they rise depends on the sentiment of investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-technology-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Technology Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is a stock index launched by the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology sector in the Hong Kong market. The index includes major tech companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering multiple fields such as the internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituents and their respective weightings in the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) are as follows (data compiled from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Xiaomi Group-W (01810.HK): Approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tencent Holdings (00700.HK): Approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Alibaba Group - W (09988.HK): Approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;JD Group-SW (09618.HK): Approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meituan-W (03690.HK): Approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kuaishou-W (01024.HK): Approximately 6.10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Li Auto (02015.HK): Approximately 6.09%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SMIC (00981.HK): Approximately 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NetEase-S (09999.HK): Approximately 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ctrip Group-S (09961.HK): Approximately 4.48%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 66.6% (Some sources indicate a combined share of the top ten between 68%-69%, with differences due to varying statistical time points)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;important-notes&#34;&gt;Important Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The weighting cap mechanism: The Hang Seng Technology Index sets an 8% upper limit on the weight of individual stocks. For example, SMIC&amp;rsquo;s weighting once exceeded 8% before its March 2025 adjustment, but was subsequently passively reduced to a compliant range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Constituent Stock Adjustment: On May 16, 2025, Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD (01211.HK) will be included in the index and Century Golden Resource (00772.HK) will be removed. The adjustment will take effect on June 6. Therefore, as of today (May 20), the constituent stock list remains the pre-adjustment list, and BYD has not yet been included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Among the top ten constituents, internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, and Meituan) are dominant, with significant weighting in new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Li Auto) and semiconductors (SMIC), reflecting the index&amp;rsquo;s coverage of technology and the new economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data timeliness: Differences in data from different sources are mainly due to varying statistical time points. For example, data from March 2025 shows that the top ten combined accounted for approximately 69.4%, while data from May 14th showed 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-back-to-cover-losses-on-the-left-side&#34;&gt;Buy back to cover losses on the left side
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;left-side falling price replenishment&amp;rdquo; strategy is an investment approach where, during a period of continuous stock price decline, investors anticipate the price nearing a bottoming zone and proactively purchase in batches to reduce holding costs, awaiting future price rebounds for profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method falls under the category of &amp;ldquo;left-side trading,&amp;rdquo; which means taking a contrarian position before the market has clearly bottomed out. In practice, investors typically employ a “pyramid” accumulation strategy, gradually increasing their purchase quantity as the price declines to reduce their average holding cost. For example, initially buying a certain number of shares; if the price continues to fall, then increasing the buy volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reduce holding costs: By buying in batches during a downturn, average stock cost is diluted, creating conditions for future profits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Positioning in advance: Establishing a position before the market reverses; if the judgment is correct, greater returns can be achieved when the market recovers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High risk: Continued decline in stock price may lead to greater losses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Funding requirements: Requires sufficient funds to support continuous replenishment, and may face a situation where funds are locked up for an extended period&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, &amp;ldquo;right-side trading&amp;rdquo; involves entering buy positions after the market trend is clear and there are obvious signs of price recovery, which carries relatively low risk but may miss some of the gains from the early stages of a rebound. Therefore, investors should choose a suitable trading strategy based on their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance, designed to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies and provide a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and formulate corresponding investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Main valuation methods:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discounted Cash Flow (DCF): This method is based on the expected future cash flows generated by an asset, which are then discounted to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes the intrinsic value of an asset and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable profitability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relative Valuation: This method assesses a company&amp;rsquo;s relative value by comparing its valuation metrics with those of other companies in the same industry, such as price-to-earnings ratio (P/E), price-to-book ratio (P/B), and price-to-sales ratio (P/S). Relative valuation is easy to operate and widely used for quick assessments and comparisons within an industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The asset-based approach determines a company&amp;rsquo;s value by assessing its net asset value, which is the difference between total assets and liabilities. This method is suitable for asset-dominant companies such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Application of Valuation Theory&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment decisions: Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and formulate buy-or-sell strategies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mergers and Acquisitions: In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influencing the success or failure of the deal&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Financial Report: The company needs to assess its assets and liabilities at fair value to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that valuation results are affected by various factors, including market conditions, company operating status, and macroeconomic indicators. Therefore, when conducting a valuation, it is necessary to comprehensively consider all factors and combine qualitative and quantitative analysis to obtain more accurate assessment results.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
