<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Valuation on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/valuation/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Valuation on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/valuation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Wide Base Exponential Fixed Investment (also known as “Buy and Hold”): Brokerage ETF, Heng Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to do things, like buying a suitable blue-chip stock and just letting it sit, waiting for it to drop so I could assess the situation before adding more, and selling when it rose. The result was that I never managed to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding an appropriate blue-chip stock is troublesome; it’s better to choose a broad market index ETF. Currently, my plan is to invest in a brokerage ETF and the Hong Kong Technology Index ETF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kind of trading strategy described above has a professional name: bottom fishing (buying back during a leftward decline).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the next step, I plan to select a broad market index to thoroughly practice it – achieving an annualized return that outperforms the regular savings account interest rate is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brokerage-etfs&#34;&gt;Brokerage ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A brokerage ETF is an exchange-traded fund (ETF) primarily invested in Chinese securities companies as the main investment target. It mainly invests in the listed stocks of Chinese securities companies in the stock market. Brokerage ETFs typically track a specific brokerage company index, such as the China Securities Brokerage Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously bought it once, but at that time I was chasing highs and ultimately suffered losses, so I liquidated the position. The Chinese market – whenever there’s a bull run, brokerage companies are bound to rise, and how much they will rise depends on investors&amp;rsquo; emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-tech-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is an equity index launched by the Hong Kong Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology industry in Hong Kong markets. The index includes major technology companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering areas such as internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituent stocks of the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) and their weightings are listed below (data sourced from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tencent Holdings&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00700.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00700.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09988.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09988.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JD Group-SW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09618.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09618.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kuaishou-W&lt;/strong&gt; ([01024.HK](http://01024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-tech-index-1&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASML Holding&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00981.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00981.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetEase-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09999.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09999.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ctrip Group-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09961.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09961.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 4.48%
&lt;strong&gt;Total Percentage:&lt;/strong&gt; Approx. 66.6% (Note: Some sources show the top ten combined percentage between 68%-69%, due to differences in statistical timing points.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-notes&#34;&gt;Key Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Cap Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hang Seng Tech Index sets an 8% weight limit for individual stocks. For example, before the adjustment on March 2025, SMIC’s weighting exceeded 8%, but was subsequently passively reduced to comply with the limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constituent Stock Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;: On May 16, 2025, the Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01211.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01211.HK&lt;/a&gt; ) will be included in the index and Guolian Group (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00772.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00772.HK&lt;/a&gt;) will be excluded. The adjustment will take effect on June 6th. Therefore, as of today (May 20th), the constituent stocks are still based on the pre-adjustment list, and BYD has not yet been included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Among the top ten constituent stocks, internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, Meituan) dominate, with significant weights in new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Ideal) and semiconductors (SMIC), reflecting the index’s coverage of technology and the new economy. &lt;strong&gt;Data Timeliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The primary differences in data from various sources stem from differing statistical time points. For example, data from March 2025 showed a combined top ten share of approximately 69.4%, while data from May 14th indicated 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on the weighting distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-put-cover&#34;&gt;Short Put Cover
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “Short Put Cover” strategy is an investment approach where investors, anticipating a stock price nearing its bottom as it continues to decline, actively buy in batches to reduce their average cost basis, waiting for future price recovery and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method falls under the category of “Short Trading,” which involves counter-trend operations before the market has clearly established a bottom. Specifically, investors typically employ a “pyramid” or stepped-up buying strategy, gradually increasing the quantity purchased as the stock price declines to dilute the average cost basis. For example, initially purchasing a certain number of shares, if the price continues to fall, the investor increases the purchase volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; By buying in batches during the decline, the average cost basis is diluted, creating conditions for future profits. - &lt;strong&gt;Pre-positioning:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing positions before the market reverses, aiming to secure larger profits when the market rebounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; If stock prices continue to fall, it could lead to greater losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Tie-up:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires sufficient funds to continuously add to positions and may face the risk of capital being long-term trapped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, “right-side trading” involves buying after market trends become clear and there are definite signs of a price rebound, which carries lower risk but could miss out on initial gains during a rally. Therefore, investors should choose a suitable trading strategy based on their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation Theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance that aims to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies, providing a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and develop appropriate investment strategies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Valuation Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method is based on the cash flows expected to be generated by an asset over its future period and discounts these cash flows to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes intrinsic value and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relative Valuation Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method assesses a company&amp;rsquo;s relative value by comparing valuation metrics such as Price-to-Earnings (P/E) ratio, Price-to-Book (P/B) ratio, and Price-to-Sales (P/S) ratio with those of other companies in the same industry. - Relative Valuation Method is straightforward to operate, widely used for rapid assessment and comparison within the same industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Basis Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method determines a company’s value by evaluating its net assets – total assets minus liabilities. The Asset Basis Method is suitable for asset-driven companies such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.
&lt;strong&gt;Application of Valuation Theories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Decisions:&lt;/strong&gt; Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and develop buy or sell strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions:&lt;/strong&gt; In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influences the success or failure of the deal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory-1&#34;&gt;Valuation Theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies need to assess the fair value of their assets and liabilities to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial statements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that valuation results are influenced by various factors, including market conditions, company operations, macroeconomic indicators, etc. Therefore, when conducting a valuation, it is necessary to consider all factors comprehensively and combine qualitative and quantitative analysis to obtain a more accurate assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
