<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Bai-Yansong on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bai-yansong/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Bai-Yansong on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bai-yansong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The future of China will undoubtedly be a China of good elders and good old people.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that twenty years from now, I’ll be a cute old man, spending time with a cute old woman. I don&amp;rsquo;t seek great wealth or status; just to be healthy and strong enough to travel and explore wherever we go.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I said that in 10 years, I’d be a charming old man, and I would work hard to become a charming old man. The future of China will definitely need good old men and women. Even if I&amp;rsquo;m 60 in 10 years, I’ll be the youngest in the world’s third-rate society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be honest, if everyone sees 50-year-old Chinese men with this physique, it would be pretty impressive. But behind this physique is a saying I believe: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! When the rain stops, I want to go for a run; tomorrow afternoon I’ll play soccer. At 50 years old, I can still play big games – it&amp;rsquo;s not a joke, and I often play with professionals. But what’s behind all of this? “Behind it is autonomy. The remaining days I spend running, and people might find that very monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I can run freely, never listening to music – because I feel my own breath is the most beautiful music while running.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Additionally, I rarely run on the treadmill. Also, many people in Beijing experience smog as severe as that, so I run five days a week, with two days dedicated to the smog. And unlike others, I jokingly say it’s probably because I never stop. Each month, I record my runs in my journal – drawing one day for every day of mileage accumulated during my experiences, at least 18 days per month. When running, they just flash by; I don&amp;rsquo;t even wear glasses while running, but more importantly, I still kick a ball every week. My graduate students’ last lecture was always held at our home – on the topic of “Fun,” which I believe is incredibly important. I never engage with people who lack any joy or hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I first started teaching a few years ago, one of my graduate students was featured in &lt;em&gt;China News Weekly&lt;/em&gt;. We had a special issue called “Zhi” (致 – meaning “letter to”), and ten years later, when my student graduated each year, the final assignment he would complete was writing an article for me ten years down the line. I’d keep it, and then I’d gradually develop it with them as they progressed, including writing one myself at 50 for those turning 60 – something I never imagined possible, a distant land beyond the map. But suddenly, it became my next stop: writing to 20-year-olds for 30-year-olds, like spring letters to summer love. However, when I wrote at 50 for 60, it was more like summer’s fading whispers to autumn’s quiet contemplation. Now, as I write ten years later, it&amp;rsquo;s a gradual unfolding from all over the world – a bed, a meal, being in the presence of my family. This is perfectly normal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But what kind of person will I be at 60 years old? My topic is very clear: in a pleasant introduction, this article is long. I say that in 10 years, I will be a lovable old man, and I want to work hard to become a lovable old man. China wanting to be lovable isn&amp;rsquo;t just about having more like-minded citizens who become citizens, not just ordinary young people, energetic young people who understand the rules, young people who will make a good China in the future. Currently, over 60 million people in China have already exceeded 2.3 billion, and it will definitely exceed three billion within 10 years – that is, if you consider only the population over 60, China could be among the top five or even third countries in the world. Think about how terrifying that is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t feel that way myself. - I don’t know if everyone has seen the online table today listing the average lifespans of all provinces and municipalities in China. Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years, including an average for both men and women. Naturally, men still have a significant disadvantage in terms of lifespan. That means that even if I&amp;rsquo;m 60 years old in ten years, I’d be one of the youngest in this world. Looking ahead… If women retire at 55 and live another 25 years until an average age of 80, and men retire at 60 and live another 20 years until an average age of 80! You need to do something other than just dancing square dances. Moreover, I can say that the grandmothers and uncles who are now dancing square dances represent the cultural habits and entertainment styles brought to them by this era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Even in 20 years, the next generation may still have many people dancing square dances, but they will be significantly reduced. This is because the next generation are no longer active participants in collective activities, just like older generations who enjoy traveling in tour groups – now young people are increasingly choosing independent and self-guided travel. Square dancing will continue to exist in the future, but its scope will undoubtedly shrink, which isn’t necessarily good or bad; it&amp;rsquo;s simply a process of societal restructuring and constant change. When I was 60, I was one of the youngest members of the team. What kind of person should I be? The Chinese saying goes that 60 is when your ears become attuned – I believe I wouldn’t have been happy then, still excited about everything, but also disappointed by things I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have heard. More importantly, what should I do for young people! What should we do to promote good things? - Not lazy, not easily compromising; it’s important to oppose when you should, young people could harm his interests – can you stand in front of them? I&amp;rsquo;ve been constantly looking at this mirror lately. My good friend, Tao Wei, used to often gather with us, including at our home, and he once told me a genuine story. We collectively mourned together, while the older generation, like Chen Lao Dai, kept everything stored within their homes, saying things out of the blue – you hide 30+ items under the bed for what purpose? You need to tell him that this garment cost over 500 yuan, and then we started supporting his family. We’ve grown accustomed to battling our parents intellectually and strategically – how much did a garment costing over 700 yuan cost?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-4&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;220&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it’s easy to get into trouble. Tao Wei once bought a T-shirt for his father for over 400 yuan. That T-shirt was really good, how much did it cost? “99,” I wore it. The next day, disaster struck. When he came back in the evening, he praised Tao Wei for taking a picture and giving him 400 yuan, asking him to buy four more for me. Afterwards, everyone who saw me wearing it, including Zhang and Li Daxi, thought it was great, and then said that the risk of lying like this was very large. In the future, you shouldn’t do this. I don&amp;rsquo;t specifically mention which person in the orthopedic department of the hospital broke a bone; the most important reason was that he bought shoes from a street stall. Of course, I’m only talking about this on a material level – even when old, one still needs mental stimulation, curiosity, and a willingness to shield young people from the wind and rain, living each day happily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious and excitedly waiting for my 60th birthday to arrive, because I think that&amp;rsquo;s the beginning of a beautiful time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18 years old is probably different from yours.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very common phrase &lt;strong&gt;information fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – since graduating from high school, aside from the time I spent reading novels, I haven’t really taken the time to sit down and read a book quietly and attentively for a long time. Sometimes, looking back, after so many years working, I still remember what I did each year? Often, by the middle of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten a lot of things from the first half. Writing a blog is a good habit, even though much of what I write isn’t appropriate and doesn’t matter – it was originally written for myself to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal readers are myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of one’s 18 years is like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. Each person occasionally takes their own 18th birthday to ask themselves, “Are you the way you wanted to live back then?” I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that nowadays everyone has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, nobody to have a heart-to-heart conversation, knowledge acquisition is endless, but far from wisdom. Everyone should use your 18th year to ask yourself, it’s too easy to deceive others, but deceiving oneself is so difficult!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think each of one’s 18 years is like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. You can deceive others, but you cannot deceive your own 18-year-old self. Is today you the way you were going to be at 18? I think it&amp;rsquo;s okay. - Today, material fame and countless other things are valued far more than what I, at 18, could have imagined. However, on the other hand, we’re always moving forward. When I was 18, I was studying journalism at the Broadcasting Academy, and I wanted to become like Farquhar – the best journalist. And today, I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path. That’s why many people say, “How can White still be on CCTV?” because I want to be a good journalist. The pursuit of news continues. This is my 18-year-old perspective, so I think everyone should occasionally ask themselves: Are you the person you originally wanted to be?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is something you can’t fool anyone with. This is what I looked like at 18, and it&amp;rsquo;s just gone in an instant – 32 years have passed. Every student who came to Beijing to study at that time would have this same photo. Back then, the crumpled suits on Tianmen Square, the school badge pinned to your chest – because there were so few university students back then, no badges, you felt really proud. We had long hair back then, but we still liked our 18-year-old selves. Looking back after all these years, I suddenly realize that I’m grateful for the things I faced at 18, because they shaped me silently. It was May 8th, 1986, and I bought a selection of Misty Poems at Wangfujing Bookstore that year. And today I suddenly realized that my writing style has been most influenced by Cui Jian’s “One Evening,” which I heard at the Workers&amp;rsquo; Stadium. It’s had the biggest impact on me, including my personality being shaped by Misty Poetry, rock music, and Lu Guofu’s martial arts novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you go through at 18? Here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You might carry what essentials you need for the road. I&amp;rsquo;m particularly interested in what 18-year-olds are experiencing today? Are they being carved away like with an axe, relentlessly shaping themselves? But what tools did he use? What kind of image did it create? I’m afraid that everyone now has countless social media circles, yet no one to talk to, endless knowledge acquisition, but still far from wisdom – knowing everything and nothing at all, seemingly everyone is proclaiming their individuality. However, as an observer, I find that young people today are remarkably similar. What should I put them through at 18? I really like 1986 because it’s the best way to resolve 1966.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In 1966, the Cultural Revolution ended after 76 years of defeating the Gang of Four – it was largely accidental. It could only be truly achieved through the enlightenment and awakening of human nature and the growth of every individual. I believe we still need to go through a period of enlightenment and fully understand human nature. Regardless of how much economic progress China makes, if we don’t genuinely fill in this understanding of humanity – then guide it, control its dark side, and activate its good side – there will continue to be many things to worry about in the future. So my 18th year was also representative of that era; it went too far, but we shouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget why we started out. It’s now been condensed into these four words: “Don’t Lose Your Original Intent.” So, I think regardless of how far you go, everyone should ask themselves what their 18-year-old self would think. It’s good to keep a photo from that time and often ask yourself, “What do people say about it? Does it matter?” It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to fool others than to fool yourself. I just said to a 20-year-old today, &amp;ldquo;When you&amp;rsquo;re 18, let your 18-year-old be the eyes that watch you.&amp;rdquo; And as I also mentioned earlier, in your twenties, go try many doors – you don’t know which one is right for you. It’s surprising in China now to often see older people in their twenties and lots of younger people in their seventies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalist does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This excerpt recounts the author’s perspective on the profession of journalism, emphasizing that reporters should possess a social conscience, a broad knowledge base, and perseverance. The author also shares their reflections at age 50, including maintaining curiosity, achieving balance between material and spiritual pursuits, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best journalist is first, having a social conscience; second, possessing knowledge; and third, being able to run long distances. I couldn’t handle running 100 meters – I ran it. I believe these three things combined, people expect the safety concerns surrounding vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the formula milk scandal. We always solve problems after they arise, completely resolving them, and moving forward in this logical cycle. Otherwise, what is there for a journalist to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe the best journalist first has a social conscience, second has knowledge reserves, and third can run long distances – I’ve stopped being intimidated by 100 meters; I’m running. I think these three things combined explain why, at 50 years old, I feel like I fit well in journalism. I&amp;rsquo;m naturally intertwined with China’s 40 years of reform, and on my 30th birthday, standing on the banks of the Songhua River, when I was 40, my birthday coincided with the 2008 Olympics – I went in during the live broadcast and came out during the broadcast. Now at 50, as the nation commemorates 40 years of reform and opening up, it’s certainly a corresponding moment: if the “Great Era” is 40, what is China&amp;rsquo;s 40 years of reform – confusion or enlightenment? “Looking at China after 40 years of development, it’s provided a great deal to people and the nation in terms of material wealth. However, anxiety and confusion have increased rather than decreased. We thought that becoming strong and wealthy meant everything was okay, but we realized that material prosperity is just a foundation. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to escape poverty materially, but truly becoming prosperous spiritually and emerging as a major power is incredibly difficult. The United States is now targeting our high-tech industries – we need to target agricultural products instead. There’s always this saying in the world: ‘It’s hard for number two to become number one!’ How many ‘second generation’ iPhones has America fixed? Therefore, we must go through a long period of time transforming ‘number two’ into something that surpasses itself. I can&amp;rsquo;t get everything; it’s impossible.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate to start working in television at 25, initially with celebrity interviews. I came into contact with hundreds or even thousands of figures carrying various accolades. Back then, as a young person, I thought these halos must make them incredibly happy, but when I got closer, I realized no, the halo had little to do with their happiness, and sometimes it was even inversely proportional. Recently, I finished watching Guo Mo’er&amp;rsquo;s last 29 years – Guo Mo’er barely escaped persecution throughout his life, holding positions like Deputy Minister of State Council, Vice Chairman of the CPPCC, and Vice Chairwoman. Would he have been happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? When you are in your sixties or seventies, two of your sons leave you within a few years, and yet you can still be happy as a Deputy Premier. “Having many famous calligraphy and paintings can bring happiness, allowing oneself to spend many years safely – what do you need? I think reading people’s books is the best mirror. To put it briefly, I feel that a lot of our anxiety now comes from thinking too much and not reading enough books. This is how Yang Geng, an elderly woman, responded to a young man: if you don&amp;rsquo;t read books, you just rely on fast food, grab a mobile phone and try to find a quick fix. How can that be possible? I learned to be clever through the slow, clumsy process of reading a book; subtraction is done when there are more and more books – it’s about reducing what you have.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I don’t expect everyone to be able to read the best version of themselves through reading, but I hope the proportion increases – that more and more Chinese people can develop themselves better through reading. No one sits on the ground and looks up at the sky, trying to figure out everything. I can&amp;rsquo;t do that. But I can look in a mirror. A few years ago, a BBC news anchor came to Beijing, claiming to be the BBC’s most outstanding news anchor, and then someone organized a dialogue between him and a Chinese news anchor at the International Hotel. During our conversation, he asked me a question: “Do you think the BBC should learn from CCTV?” I first made a joke and said, &amp;ldquo;Of course, they should first learn Chinese.&amp;rdquo; Then, after making the joke, I said, &amp;ldquo;The BBC should most of all learn the world’s curiosity. We&amp;rsquo;ve gone to the world very quickly in recent years&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; Here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have various bureaus, currently exceeding 70. We feel that whenever a student sees something new from abroad, they are incredibly curious. We observe the world with this immense curiosity, and BBC has already considered Britain itself to be global – you’ve lost that sense of wonder. Older brother is right, what we lack is precisely this. In 2007, when I interviewed a Japanese writer for him, he said about Japan, ‘Besides lacking hope, it has everything else.’ Later, I realized the depth of his words. From another perspective, ten years ago, I felt that China lacked everything except hope – everyone believed there was a future ahead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-4&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;But won’t one day we also become a wealthy nation that only desires everything? To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m very worried that China will end up being a negative one – when you have everything, you realize how truly poor you are. When I’m 50 years old, I fear becoming someone who can satisfy all material conditions but is incredibly impoverished. In our reality, there are many highly educated people with no culture, and there are many poor people with countless numbers on their bank accounts – this is the problem of this era. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t frightening because there’s a forward direction and hope. This is why I say that a lack of morality and human flaws are the root causes. That’s why I think scientists invented so much not because they initially carried great missions, but out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I figure out how to make it? “So I’ve always started to urge myself to be more curious around the age of 50, so I’m very happy. The one thing that’s currently bothering me is persistence. When you were just talking about ‘you’re still persisting,’ I said, ‘Don’t say that – once you persist, you’re close to death.’ We used to say that persistence equals success, and if Chinese football just persisted through the ‘black three minutes’ – if they just kept at it – it was all about perseverance. But without methods or fun, it became a matter of simply persisting. Sometimes persistence is important, but often this saying has two sides. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that when I do something, like talking to people, I’ll persist and finish what I started, even though my time is now up. But I’m curious, and I want to see how my conversations with others will turn out.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-5&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Give yourself a very small keyword, but engage in conversations with people. I think that at 50 years old, as long as you can maintain a great deal of curiosity, there’s no problem, I like all fun things, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily have to be the most popular thing today. Today’s trends might disappear overnight. There are always trending words every year; do you remember some of them? Could some media on the internet 10 years from now become traditional media? So, fun things will always have their own inherent appeal, and I respect everyone&amp;rsquo;s likes – there must be a reason for it. But when you look at it in the long run, you’ll find that Chinese people still like to play mahjong the most. When you also like eating fast food, then restaurants serving large meals will naturally start to close down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things are not just about expressing feelings and moving on. How much fragmented reading do you get from your daily mobile phone use? How much longer-form reading do you have? But this is also a process, and the phone is becoming our handcuffs. So I feel that people will increasingly consume shorter things, which leads to people gradually becoming short-sighted, but this is also a process – I never worry about content being king. It will always return. You’ll entertain yourself to death every day, until you&amp;rsquo;re 40 years old, like when I see teenagers drinking soda, and I try to tell them to drink less, but you know they will still drink it. However, on the other hand, I’m optimistic that at 40, he’ll return to a world of tea. That’s the life of a Chinese person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s perfectly normal, but I hope this transition happens faster. We’re just expressing an observation – investigative journalism is becoming so rare these days, and you don’t even read it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will Chinese football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The supplementary reader responses were largely written on a whim in 2021. The timing of Wang Yi’an’s speeches being transcribed was just as the pandemic was beginning. Don&amp;rsquo;t say twenty years later, or even one year or two later – the world is always beyond people’s expectations. Now that the domestic COVID-19 situation has ended, overseas situations are still causing trouble. Regarding football, Chinese national team played quite well in recent years; the coach dared to take a more attacking approach, which was much better than when they were just starting out. Watching matches with grandpa was interesting – what kind of experience is that?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Curious, very curious, what could be any different? So you find that Chinese football plays badly because many people are afraid to lose the ball in their own area and pass it to others, so they’re done for themselves – there&amp;rsquo;s no such way of playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one of many small reasons. When talking about 20 years of football, 20 years from now China football seems incredibly distant. The first expansion became 48 teams, and it’s possible China might go, but it’s still possible they won&amp;rsquo;t. The best age range for a national team is 26-30, so 20 years from now that would be children aged 6 to 10 – being optimistic about this is certainly something, but 20 years later it will definitely work out. When I talk about children aged 6-10 today, you immediately become serious. So cause and effect: what are we planting today? What kind of beans are we growing if we’re planting them now? We almost planted soybeans for the national team – what would they grow into? Whoever initiates this action, they should prepare to be removed from the game – it’s a violation of the rules, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t dwell on it. But you really should think about today’s children aged 6-10; are they playing soccer? You just know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ethical deficit, erosion of humanity</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To do things properly, first and foremost, you need to have a clear conscience. This allows you to sleep soundly, without minor ailments or major issues. It&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid making mistakes in the first place. If you do make a mistake, it should be to try and rectify it, not to hide it away and hope you’ll forget about it – humans are naturally inclined to forget, but they can also have excellent memories. A clear conscience is your destination; being able to answer your own questions with satisfaction allows you to live more lightly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjQ4NA==.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;. If there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this text; this document is solely for translating the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight words to say that are quite heavy – I feel we’re currently experiencing a moral deficit, a depletion of human nature, and a logical cycle where problems arise and need to be solved, ultimately resolved completely. You need patience to wait for this process of upheaval. For a country like China, many things are a slow process of sorting out. So don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic about change; it’s undergoing a cleansing/reshuffle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, China has been battling two typhoons – one is intangible and the other is tangible. The intangible typhoon is the vaccine, which is impacting our inner security dam. The other typhoon hasn’t frequently landed in Shanghai, and hasn&amp;rsquo;t caused Beijing and Tianjin to suffer as much; it’s a rare event for three directly-administered cities to face a storm together that hasn’t occurred in decades. This is off-topic. What you need to consider next is whether your own self-improvement, the significant changes you’ve undergone, and the many answers you now possess will make you happy if the surrounding environment remains unchanged. I have eight words to express this heavily – I feel that we currently suffer from a moral deficit and a loss of humanity; this is the biggest deficit and greatest shortfall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, people were expecting the safety risks of vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the initial formula scandal. So sometimes you need to look at history and understand that you know about the establishment and formation of a complete legal framework for the US Food and Drug Administration, which is closely related to the initial milk and dairy product insecurity. Therefore, the Sanlu Milk Powder incident forced China to undergo significant changes in the dairy industry. While vaccines aren&amp;rsquo;t going to be one after another, I hope this time it’s a halt. You need to know that times always move forward through a logical cycle of identifying problems and completely solving them, otherwise what do journalists do? What do citizens do?
I think we can all do is care. But the problem is that people in China are too easily forgetful. “As I just said, after crashing someone’s car and then fleeing to the side of the road, a whole vehicle of people didn&amp;rsquo;t stop to intervene. A large proportion of our neighbors and colleagues are like that – people who behave this way. So we need to gradually change that. And as ordinary citizens, the things we can do is pay attention, not forget. I don’t think it’s a lack of something; when you’re hungry and cold, and you spend your days talking about ideals, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t have persuasive power. But once they’ve eaten and are warm, if they let themselves become the world’s number one country for diabetes, hypertension, and so many other ‘number one’ countries, then you’ll see Chinese people starting to run and start dieting. And when I ask all of you ladies here – has anyone not experienced the brutal experience of not being able to lose weight because they couldn&amp;rsquo;t afford a decent meal?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-2&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The spiritual aspect we’ve been discussing is also the same. When you’re well-fed and warm, and start running or dieting, your need for spirit will gradually increase as well. For example, I used to smoke, but one day after starting to run, I suddenly realized I hadn&amp;rsquo;t smoked in 20 days – not at all. I haven’t smoked since. Of course, I wouldn’t deliberately say, “I’ve completely quit!” because I think it lacks a certain sense of ceremony. It doesn’t rule out smoking two or three cigarettes during the year. When your lifestyle changes, many things will change with it. I believe that for Chinese people, you need to be patient and wait for the upheaval. More and more people feel unhappy and unwilling to indulge themselves in unhappiness. “While depression is increasing, on the other hand, isn’t it also seeing more and more people seeking positive ways to live? At this time, things related to the mental aspect will grow, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic; how you look at the same thing matters. I often see people driving aggressively in the street, and I feel frustrated, but then I quickly become optimistic because the queue on the other side is longer than before. This is a process like this – all of you, here tonight after a rainstorm, are willing to chat about so many useless things; isn’t that a good thing?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-3&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is also a transformation, so there are many things that need to be thought about in a different way. Of course, I think there will be much to learn in the future, such as when you talk about starting a business – is everyone an entrepreneur? Everyone’s life is an entrepreneurial one. We’re giving too much of a time-sensitive element to entrepreneurship, but entrepreneurship has always been around. Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Su Shi (Su Dongpo) an entrepreneur? Wasn&amp;rsquo;t Li Bai an entrepreneur? Everyone will have many innovations throughout their lives, and ultimately they created their own brand. It doesn’t matter if most innovations don’t come to fruition, as long as you live a life that is rich in flavor and you believe it’s worth it. I think China particularly lacks good failure as another value of success. People only accept successful outcomes, but a good failure is also a success, and we don&amp;rsquo;t accept that. “I think that’s going to be very difficult, so you see why Chinese football isn&amp;rsquo;t played well has many reasons, and one of those reasons is that everyone is afraid to lose the ball back to themselves and just kick it out. If there wasn’t this kind of play, of course, that’s only a very small part of the reason. So I think as I get to my age, by 30, it&amp;rsquo;s hard to write about ‘Transparent Happiness’ because you can’t rush it, and now at 50, there’s a little urgency because time is passing so quickly, and you expect so many things that haven’t become reality. But on the other hand, I also understand that for a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process. You see older generations – some of them were just blindly following traffic lights, but occasionally you’ll see children pulling their fathers along as they change. They&amp;rsquo;re changing, they&amp;rsquo;re being shuffled around, so I think you need to be patient.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Regarding time, you need to read a lot of books to find the answers.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overall, the country is getting better and stronger economically, becoming wealthier. If people’s vanity didn&amp;rsquo;t exist, this wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the case. Looking back from the 1990s to now, in the families I’ve encountered, everyone’s lives have improved significantly compared to before, and at the same time, the number of wealthy individuals has increased. During the development of market-oriented economic growth, wealth inequality inevitably emerged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often talked about – class solidification and a blocked upward mobility path – are common problems worldwide. The Communist Party&amp;rsquo;s contributions to people’s basic welfare benefits and social security should be recognized. Things will get better and better, you don’t need to buy a house; you can rent one. Children&amp;rsquo;s education also faces issues with unequal resource allocation, sometimes requiring compromises – do you want better job opportunities, a better work environment, or more time to spend with family? Don’t impose your own ideas on others, including your child and family members. Sit down and talk it over; life will inevitably get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;, if there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this article; this text is only for the translation of the transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/30%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;503&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;30 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m now 50 years old this year, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t think about it in the past. I felt like an old man. Now I realize that I really am an old man. This is what I looked like at 30. When you’re 30, you don’t feel very young or beautiful, but when you look back at 50, you think it&amp;rsquo;s pretty good. What was the biggest life lesson at 30 when you look back? I think it’s subtraction – the key word is subtraction. From a certain perspective, “pain and joy” is also a kind of subtraction; you experience and write down many things, then leave them there, on a new blank sheet, or go for a run. But for me, at 30, I really think that whether it’s for myself or for everyone else, doing subtraction is very important. I’m currently a student carrying heavy loads – I often remind them, “Before you turn 30, you need to be relentlessly adding; you need to try things; you don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of possibilities are out there, and you don’t know what opportunities fate will give you.” So it’s not about knowing how you feel, but some people are frantically adding in their twenties, all sorts of additions, but they forget to subtract when it’s time; I think around 30 is a very important time in life – after doing a series of additions and running around everywhere, you need to do an important subtraction. Otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s too late. Why would you subtract? You aren’t suited for everything, and you aren’t suited for what others are suited for; you should try everything.
Eight lines are tying you up – how far can you run? They might hinder each other.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;%e5%bb%89%e4%bb%b7.jpg&#34; &gt;Cheap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At thirty years old, I had been promoted to a full professorship – that’s what they called it academically, while journalists referred to it as a senior journalist. I was promoted to a full professorship at twenty-nine, and such promotions have become rare these days. However, at that time, I began to feel a tremendous sense of confusion. When the Sydney Olympics were held in 2000, I received many accolades, but I suddenly realized that something wasn’t right. I started asking myself, “What exactly do you want to do? What things need to be discarded?” That year, I made a very important subtraction – I stopped my show and didn&amp;rsquo;t appear for a year, without any public appearances. People told me, &amp;ldquo;As a host, you can get by if you don’t appear on screen for a month; if you don’t appear for six months, no one will remember you.” But I said, “My face is quite valuable.” That year, I began to develop new programs. “This was after going through immense pain and joy, and in 2001, I stopped for an entire year. Everything I’m doing today is a reflection of that time – a process of simplification. Back then, I could do so many things: I could play sports, I could get into E (presumably referring to electronic music or entertainment), and countless other fun activities, even producing shows. But I said no, and I realized I could only do journalism. And it was what I was truly meant to do. At the time, I was the producer of three programs, and I quit them all overnight. That’s how I became who I am today. I became simpler. A few days ago, talking to a colleague, I said that at around 30 years old, one of my most important decisions wasn&amp;rsquo;t just about having many options, but the feeling that I was meant to be solely focused on journalism – this deep well, with numerous positions potentially offering you a promotion to deputy director. I rejected it and returned to a common citizen’s level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E7%94%9F.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;502&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Undergraduate Student&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;428px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To date, I’ve been working with provincial-level cadres and even party officials – none of whom were exclusively graduates of undergraduate programs. You understand our system, but I refuse to participate. I wanted to see how far a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree could take someone, and why a bachelor&amp;rsquo;s degree shouldn’t be limited to continuous learning and potentially mentoring graduate students. Yes, I currently mentor 11 graduate students per year – this is a reduction in numbers. It’s certainly a feeling of reflection looking back. Furthermore, when you’re young, it’s easy to feel that everything should be perfect; if something isn&amp;rsquo;t achieved or has a flaw, it causes me great discomfort. Please don’t have everyone seated also learn how to subtract, that is, at that time when you are 28 or 30 years old, watching the 1996 Olympics, I came up with a sentence: “Defects are an important part of perfection; there is no perfect world.” In Zeng Qianfan’s long novel, it actually wrote down a very important sentence: what is the best state of life? Zeng Qianfan wanted to name his study room “Que Hall,” and the flowers hadn&amp;rsquo;t fully bloomed yet was the best. The moon wasn&amp;rsquo;t yet full was the best, but for ordinary people, they would all feel that it was a defect, not perfect enough, not reaching the extreme, the best way to ruin someone is to let them pursue perfection and reach the extreme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/flower_hasnt_fully_bloomed.jpg&#34;
	
	
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Flower hasn’t fully bloomed&#34;
	
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old-3&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This world isn’t like that. Flowers are most beautiful when they aren&amp;rsquo;t fully open; once they do, they’re close to falling. The moon is most beautiful when it’s full and round, but as it slowly fades into a crescent moon, it’s also approaching that point. Therefore, I feel this was a very important boost and revelation for me at 30. Forty isn&amp;rsquo;t as attractive as it was then. But I felt relaxed, freer. Why shouldn’t I start asking about happiness instead of dressing in suits and ties or always looking formal?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/40%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;894&#34;
	height=&#34;499&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;40 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese people have a saying that 40 is not confused; 30 is subtraction, and 40 is confusion. I don’t think the current era sees 40 as the most confused. My midlife crisis came surprisingly early, starting around thirty-six or seventy, when I began to question whether everything I had done was worthwhile?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Did it have meaning? What do I truly want for happiness? This book was born out of this confusion. When you’re 30, you often find that your happiness goals are linked to material possessions. “Thirty and established” refers to having a degree. You need a car, a house, or otherwise your mother-in-law won&amp;rsquo;t consider marrying you off – it’s very materialistic, but &amp;ldquo;40 is not confused&amp;rdquo; is difficult. - I think ancient people likely had a longer average lifespan than we do today, so it was condensed into 40 years, which is why they weren’t confused. I feel that I’m confused at 40, &lt;strong&gt;material things haven&amp;rsquo;t brought me happiness as I thought they would.&lt;/strong&gt; Similarly, when people ask you around 40, “Are you happy?” the title of my book is a question mark – it represents the confusion within me. The emergence of midlife crisis: at 40, you need to answer yourself many questions, talk to yourself more often at around 40, read a lot, and give yourself some answers. I’m very glad that I entered the world of the &lt;em&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/em&gt; when I was thirty-six or seventy. In &lt;em&gt;White Say&lt;/em&gt;, I already discussed it, and if you’re still thinking about things at forty years old, and the surrounding environment doesn&amp;rsquo;t change – especially the soft environment – if you can walk out of the house in a good mood and find yourself randomly running red lights, then anything you buy is fake, and even getting vaccinated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve been saying that China has been battling two typhoons these past few days – one was intangible, and the other was tangible. The intangible typhoon is vaccines; it’s attacking our inner security dam. The other typhoon, China rarely sees typhoons landing in Shanghai – that&amp;rsquo;s a digression. Next, you need to think about whether you’re just focusing on your own well-being, if you’ve undergone significant changes, and if you have many answers. If the surrounding environment doesn’t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;I have eight characters I say are quite heavy – I feel that we currently suffer from a moral deficit and a loss of humanity; this is the biggest deficit and the greatest loss.&lt;/strong&gt; A few days ago, I witnessed a head-on collision not far from here. Thankfully, the damage wasn&amp;rsquo;t severe; it was responsible, because he hit another car. He explained to the other driver that we were planning to pull over to the side of the road, and the other driver slowly began preparing to do so. The vehicle in front took off without stopping him. There wasn’t anyone to restrain him.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Would this be a responsible father? Would this be a responsible son? And what about his responsibility as a citizen – it inevitably impacts you. You might be a big shot, but unless you haven&amp;rsquo;t stepped foot outside your door, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent your child from getting vaccinated. Even delivery services can have issues!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If 30 is subtraction and 40 is confusion, I think 50 should be the word I give myself: curiosity. 50 is awkward; neither village nor town to reach, advanceable; retreat, you can also mix it in, perhaps until retirement. Lying on something you’ve achieved for ten years, blending through to retirement, seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a book, and one of the books within it wrote very interestingly that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley tend to be in their fifties and sixties – which is different from our concept. How can China ever stop treating entrepreneurship as a young endeavor, just like how China shouldn’t treat volunteer work as youth volunteer work. Last week I did a program about China recruiting retired primary and secondary school teachers, with an annual allowance of two or three hundred thousand yuan, and then going to rural areas to teach, and must be excellent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/50%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;899&#34;
	height=&#34;506&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;50 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for a 50-year-old person, there are two challenges: the first is yourself – are you still curious about many things? What is your outlook on life? I feel that my biggest gain at 50, or the way I’m living now, is to treat every today well. Twenty years old tends to live in tomorrow; if you&amp;rsquo;re not careful, a 50-year-old easily lives in yesterday. But I try to restrain myself, neither living in tomorrow nor in yesterday. I treat every today well – a 50-year-old shouldn’t always say “we’ll do it tomorrow” or “it was better back then!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think it&amp;rsquo;s best to watch Cai Qin’s concert discs today. Cai Qin said something quite profound, saying that whenever I look at photos, I feel like I looked good two years ago. But on that particular day two years ago, I never thought I looked good before. That’s a really flavorful sentence. “I didn’t realize it when I was 30, back then I thought I looked pretty good. I felt like I had a lot of flaws, but now that I look back 20 years later, I realize… I was young once too. I had so much hair, so cherish every day you have, and it would be best if you looked at your current state two years from now.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Yu Shi-sheng said, when my legs first couldn’t walk, I sat in a wheelchair, constantly yearning for the time when I could run and play basketball. Every day, filled with longing, it was incredibly painful.
Several years later, I developed bedsores on my wheelchair and felt all over pain. At that time, I constantly yearned for the days when just a few years ago, I didn’t feel any pain, and had peaceful moments sitting in a wheelchair.
After another period of time, I was diagnosed with uremia, and I had to go dialysis. At this point, I would always yearn for the time when I only had bedsores on my wheelchair. If I couldn&amp;rsquo;t live to reach a state where every day was treated well, those 50 years ahead would have been wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-2&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually feel that it’s pointless to wait until 50 to understand this principle – you should grasp it in your 30s or 40s, because all things are easily missed if you wait. Like a meal during a trip; if you don&amp;rsquo;t eat it, you can still have it thirty years later, and it might not even taste the same. That’s why my first feeling at 50 is to be kind to every day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Secondly, I’ve realized that I can stop being curious about many things because I’ve seen so much and had so many experiences. However, I encourage myself to remain curious. So when I do a lot of things now, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – can you hold your phone up to take pictures? Yes, you can. Can you do live reporting, attend seemingly grand and formal conferences, and make the connection easier? It’s more fun, and it leaves a more lasting impression. Can you then use new media to spread the word? Absolutely. “I believe curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress, and why can’t it be the most important driver for individual advancement? A nation that loses its curiosity will inevitably decline. On a broader level, 50 is a crucial test. When you&amp;rsquo;re in your fifties in China, what kind of entrenched interests do you hold? I’m very concerned that many people around me pursue countless dreams when they’re young because of hope, but once they achieve their dreams and become entrenched beneficiaries, they transform into those who block others from realizing their dreams – am I wrong? Looking back, they treat young people and matters in the way they used to dislike.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-3&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Therefore, a few years ago I started recruiting 11 graduate students each year as volunteers, and after they spent two years with me, they had already graduated five classes, totaling 55 pure graduate students who have now completed their studies. I think it’s a very happy thing to be a beneficial figure like this – you gain some insights, and you also have the ability to guide them. After each day of class, I invite them for dinner, which doesn&amp;rsquo;t cost much. However, this is what a good benefactor should do – a benefactor can be two aspects: one is to become a paving stone again. I once said that I don’t want to say thank you too often to those who have helped me, because I want to reciprocate with new young people in double the way. That&amp;rsquo;s how I express my gratitude.
&lt;strong&gt;If you constantly say “thank you” and end up becoming a roadblock.&lt;/strong&gt; The next is to pave the road for others. “I hope that in China, regardless of whether it’s material interests, economic power, ideological dominance, or cultural influence – across all fields – when you find yourself in that position as a vested interest holder, you will consider how you should act. Yesterday’s pusher of the train has become today’s roadblock; looking back at Chinese history, this is everywhere. It won&amp;rsquo;t be like this, and sometimes it can even be amplified. Therefore, I call on all vested interests to return to the mindset of when you were young – to emulate the kind of people you hoped to encounter then. Even if that person I might not be as good, at least I’m thinking, doing, and speaking about it.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
