<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Bai-Yansong on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bai-yansong/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Bai-Yansong on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/bai-yansong/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The future of China will undoubtedly be a China of good elders and good old people.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:28:28 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/future-china-with-good-grandparents/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I hope that twenty years from now, I’ll be a cute old man, spending time with a cute old woman. I don&amp;rsquo;t seek great wealth or status; just to be healthy and strong enough to travel and explore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I said that in 10 years, I’ll be a charming old man, and I will work hard to become a charming old man. The future of China must be one with good old men and good old women. Even if I am 60 years old in 10 years, I will be the youngest person in this world&amp;rsquo;s third kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frankly speaking, if everyone sees the 50-year-old Chinese man with this physique, it’s quite impressive. But behind this physique is a phrase I believe in: the more disciplined you are, the freer you become! When it rains, I want to go for a run; tomorrow afternoon, I will play soccer. At 50 years old, I can still play big games, and it&amp;rsquo;s not a joke. Moreover, I often play with professionals. But what’s behind this? It’s discipline. I spend my remaining days running, and people might find running very monotonous. The more disciplined you are, the freer you become. Because of my discipline, I can run freely, without listening to music – because I think my own breathing is the most beautiful music while running.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I basically don&amp;rsquo;t run on a treadmill. And many people in Beijing experience severe smog; I run 5 days a week, and two days are left for the smog. Then, jokingly, I say it might be because I never stop. Every month, I draw one day of my running experience in my diary – at least 18 days each month, and when I run, they just flash by. When I run, I also take off my glasses, but more importantly, I still play soccer every week. My graduate students’ last lecture is always held at our home on that particular day, with a theme called “Fun.” I think fun is very important. I never deal with people who lack any joy or hobbies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would rather avoid such people – they are too frightening; if you don&amp;rsquo;t have fun, you feel like you have nothing to enjoy. You like what kind of job? In early January this year, one of my graduate students wrote for &lt;em&gt;China Weekly&lt;/em&gt;, and we had a special issue called “Looking Ahead.” Ten years from now, my graduate students will, at the end of each graduation year, write an essay for me – and I keep those essays. Then, ten years later, I’ll continue to develop them, and I&amp;rsquo;ll also write one as a 50-year-old to a 60-year-old; 60 is a distant land that I never thought of before, but it’s just another stop on my way to 20 – writing to my students who are 30. That’s like a love letter from spring to summer. But when I&amp;rsquo;m 50 and write to 60, it’s like autumn whispering to fall. Now, I’m writing to myself ten years from now, from the whole world, about my bed, a meal, and the company of my family – this is normal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what will I be at 60? My title is very clear: in this long article, I said that in 10 years, I’ll be a charming old man, and China wants to be charming not just because there will be more young people like citizens who become citizens, no longer just ordinary people; energetic young people, young people who understand rules. The future of China must be one with good old men and good old women. Currently, over 60-year-olds in China exceed 2.3 billion – and that number will definitely exceed three billion in 10 years, meaning that if you consider only the population over 60, China would be among the top five countries in the world, or even the third. Imagine how frightening that is!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t find it frightening. I wonder if you&amp;rsquo;ve seen online a table of the average life expectancy in various provinces and municipalities of China – Shanghai and Beijing both exceed 80 years, including men and women. Men naturally occupy a larger share of the female population. That means even if I am 60 years old in 10 years, I will be one of the youngest people in this world&amp;rsquo;s third kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking to the future. If women retire at 55 with an average life expectancy of 80 years, and they continue for 25 years after retirement; if men retire at 60 with an average life expectancy of 80, and they continue for 20 years after retirement! You won’t do anything but dance square dances. And I can say that the older ladies and gentlemen who are dancing square dances today are cultural habits and entertainment styles brought to them by the times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Twenty - I was one of the youngest members of the team when I was 60 years old, and I should be what kind of person? Chinese painting says that at 60, your ears become attuned, and I believe I wouldn’t listen to anything then, always happy, still annoyed by things I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mention, and even happiness would turn into unhappiness. More importantly, I need to figure out what to do for the young people!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What should we do for good things? Don’t be lazy, don’t easily compromise, speak up when you need to oppose, because young people might harm their interests, can you stand in front of them and block their way? I often look at myself in the mirror now. My good friend, Tao Wei, passed away – he used to gather with us at our home, and once told me a true story. We collectively mourned together, and back then, the older generation like Chen Lao would hoard things at home, spilling everything out of the box, hiding 30-odd items under the bed. You need to tell him how much that piece of clothing cost – over 500 yuan – and then support it, lighting incense every day. Therefore, this generation of ours is used to fighting with our parents, arguing about knowledge and ideas. How much did we buy back for 700 yuan?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;220&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But it’s risky. Once, Tao Wei bought a T-shirt for his father for over 400 yuan. That shirt was really good – how much did it cost? 99, I wore it. The next day, disaster struck. When he came back from work, he praised Tao Wei and gave him 400 yuan to buy four more shirts for me. After I wore it out, Zhang Shu Li Da Ye all thought it was great, and later said the risk of lying like this is very large. Don’t do such things in the future. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to mention a specific person – in the hospital orthopedic department, an elderly man broke his bone, and the most important reason was that he bought shoes from a street vendor. Of course, I’m only talking about this on a material level. Even when you get old, you still need spiritual life and curiosity, and you should be willing to shield young people from the wind and rain, live one day happily.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m very curious and excitedly waiting for my 60th birthday to arrive. I think it’s the beginning of a beautiful time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thank you all.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>My 18 years old is probably different from yours.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:19:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/my-18th-might-be-different/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The very common phrase &lt;strong&gt;information fragmentation&lt;/strong&gt; – since graduating from high school, aside from the time I spent reading novels, I haven’t really taken the time to sit down and read a book quietly and attentively for a long time. Sometimes, looking back, after so many years of work, I still remember what I did each year? Often, by the middle of the year, I&amp;rsquo;ve forgotten a lot of things from the first half. Writing a blog is a good habit, even though much of what I write isn’t appropriate and doesn’t matter – it was originally written for myself to read.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My most loyal readers are myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each of my own 18 years was like a gaze of anticipation and questioning, and each person occasionally asks themselves, &amp;ldquo;Are you the way you wanted to live back then?&amp;rdquo; I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that everyone now has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, no one to have a heart-to-heart conversation with, unlimited knowledge acquisition, yet far from wisdom. Everyone should use your 18 years to ask yourself, &amp;ldquo;Are you the way you wanted to live back then?&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think each of my own 18 years was like a gaze of anticipation and questioning. You can deceive others, but you cannot deceive your 18-year-old self. Is today you the way you were supposed to be at 18? I feel it&amp;rsquo;s okay. Today, material fame and many other things have been obtained, which is much more than what I thought when I was 18, but on the other hand, we are always on the road. When I was in journalism school at the Broadcasting Academy, I wanted to become a top reporter like Faraway, and today I&amp;rsquo;m still on that path. But this is exactly what many people say about Mr. Bai – &amp;ldquo;How have you stayed on CCTV because you want to be a good journalist?&amp;rdquo; News is still there. This is my 18-year-old gaze, so I think everyone occasionally asks themselves, “Are you the way you wanted to live back then?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is truly impossible to deceive others. This is my appearance at 18, but it’s gone in a blink of an eye. Twenty-eight years have passed. Every person who comes to Beijing to study will have such a photo album. In that era, the wrinkled suit on Tianmen Square, and the school badge pinned to the chest, because at that time there were few college students, no school badges, feeling very proud. Their hair was long back then, but they still liked their 18-year-old appearance. Many years later, I suddenly realized I was grateful for the things I faced at 18, because it silently shaped me. In 1986, on May 8th, I bought a selection of Misty Poems at Wangfujing Bookstore. That year, I listened to Cui Jian’s “One and All” at the Workers&amp;rsquo; Stadium. Today, I suddenly realized that my writing style was most influenced by it, including my personality being influenced by Misty Poetry, Rock Music, and Lu Guhong’s martial arts novels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What did you experience at 18? You can carry that with you. I especially want to know what the 18-year-olds today are experiencing? Are they being carved up like a knife chopping wood? What tools are they using? What kind of appearance are they shaping? I&amp;rsquo;m afraid that everyone now has countless circles, no friends, chatting all day long, no one to have a heart-to-heart conversation with, unlimited knowledge acquisition, yet far from wisdom, knowing nothing and seemingly everyone is talking about individuality. But as an observer, I find that today’s young people are very similar. What should I do? What should I let the 18-year-old experience? I really like 1986 because 1986 was the best way to solve 1966.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;1966 Cultural Revolution was ended by 76 in 1986, which had a degree of chance; it could only be ended by the enlightenment and awakening of human nature and the growth of every individual. This truly allows you to dig up the concerns you have. I think we still need enlightenment, we still need to fully understand human nature. No matter how much economic progress or changes China has made, if we don’t truly fill in the understanding of human nature, and then respond to the good side of human nature and control the bad side, there will still be many things that worry us in the future. So my 18 years were also this era&amp;rsquo;s 18 years, it&amp;rsquo;s gone too far, don’t forget why you started in the first place, now condensed into four big words: “初心”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I think no matter how far you go, everyone should use your 18 years to ask yourself. So taking a photo at 18 is good, and often take it out to ask yourself. What others say doesn’t matter? It&amp;rsquo;s too difficult to deceive yourself. I just said to today’s 20-year-olds, “You should always let your 18-year-old be the eyes that watch you.”  I also mentioned earlier that in my twenties, you should try many doors, because you don’t know which one is most suitable for you&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What kind of journalist does society need?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 11:08:38 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-kind-of-journalists-does-society-need/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This excerpt recounts the author’s perspective on the profession of journalism, emphasizing that reporters should possess a social conscience, a broad knowledge base, and perseverance. The author also shares their reflections at age 50, including maintaining curiosity, achieving balance between material and spiritual pursuits, and contemplating the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The best journalist is first, having a social conscience; second, possessing knowledge; and third, being able to run long distances. I couldn’t handle running 100 meters – I ran it. I believe these three things combined, people expect the safety concerns surrounding vaccines to be completely resolved, just like with the melamine scandal. We always move forward in a logic loop of problems arising, solving problems, and completely resolving them. Otherwise, what is there for a journalist to do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript-1&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I believe the best journalist first has a social conscience, second has knowledge reserves, and third can run long distances – I’ve outrun the 100 meters, so it’s no problem. I think these three things combined, at 50 years old, you’ll understand that I seem to be well-suited for journalism. I&amp;rsquo;m naturally intertwined with China’s 40 years of reform, and on my 30th birthday, standing by the banks of the Songhua River, when I was 40, my birthday coincided with the 2008 Olympics, and I came out of the Olympic broadcast in which I went in. At 50 this year, as China commemorates 40 years of reform and opening up, there’s certainly a corresponding connection – whether the “Great Era” is at forty or China’s reform is at fifty-five?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that after walking through 40 years of road, China has already given people enough in terms of material things, and to the country enough. However, anxiety and confusion have increased, not decreased. We thought we were strong and wealthy, so everything was OK, but we discovered that material wealth is just a foundation; it’s difficult to become spiritually rich and truly a great power. The United States is already attacking your high-tech, we need to attack agricultural products. There&amp;rsquo;s always been a saying in the world: &amp;ldquo;It&amp;rsquo;s hard for second place to be achieved!&amp;rdquo; How many Second Place countries has America fixed? Therefore, we must go through a long period of time to transform “not one” into surpassing ourselves. I can’t get everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was fortunate that I started doing television at 25, first from figure interviews, and I contacted hundreds or thousands of figures with various halos. At that time, young people thought that these halos must make them very happy, but when they got closer, they found no, the halos have little to do with their happiness, and sometimes they are inversely proportional. Recently, I just finished reading about Guo Moruo’s last 29 years – Guo Moruo barely escaped persecution, serving as Deputy Minister of State Council, Vice Chairman of CPPCC, Vice Chairwoman of National People&amp;rsquo;s Congress, etc. But his two sons committed suicide, and the other may have been thrown to death from a building? Would he be happy?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What do you use to measure happiness? When you are in your sixties, two of your sons leave you in a few years; even if you’re a Deputy Minister, can you be happy? Many famous paintings can make people happy, and spending many years safely is enough to make you happy. What do you want? So I think looking at people is the best mirror. To say something more important, I think much of our anxiety now comes from thinking too much and reading too little books. This is Yang Geng’s reply to a young person – if you don&amp;rsquo;t read books, you rely on fast food; you pick up a mobile phone and plan to find a miracle pill. How can that be? I learned cleverness through the slow process of more and more books; subtraction comes from reading more books.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I don’t expect everyone to achieve it, but I hope the proportion increases – more and more Chinese people can read themselves better in books, which is the most important thing. No one sits on the ground and looks up at the stars, trying to figure out everything. I can&amp;rsquo;t do that. But I can look in a mirror. A few years ago, when a BBC news anchor came to Beijing, claiming to be the “most awesome” news anchor in BBC, he had someone organize a dialogue between him and a Chinese news anchor; we talked. That guy asked me during the conversation, &amp;ldquo;What do you think BBC should learn from CCTV?&amp;rdquo; I first made a joke and said, of course, they should first learn Chinese.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next, after making a joke, I said, “I think BBC most needs to learn from CCTV is their curiosity about this world.” We’ve been observing the world with great curiosity these years as we quickly reach out to the world; we have more than 70 correspondents now, and we feel that when a student sees something new in foreign countries, he feels very curious. We carry a huge sense of curiosity and observe the world, while BBC has already considered Britain itself as the world. You don’t need to be curious anymore. The brother slapped the table and said, “What we lack is this thing.” In 2007, when I interviewed a Japanese writer, he told me, &amp;ldquo;Japan&amp;rsquo;s country besides lacking hope, has everything else.&amp;rdquo; Later I realized that this sentence was really deep; from another angle, ten years ago, I thought China Okay, here’s the English translation of the provided text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To be honest, I&amp;rsquo;m very worried that China will one day end up on the downside – feeling truly impoverished even when everything is available. I fear that by the time I’m 50, I’ll become a person who, despite having all material comforts, is incredibly poor. The problem in our reality is that there are many highly educated people with no culture, and many impoverished individuals with countless numbers on their bank accounts. That&amp;rsquo;s really what&amp;rsquo;s wrong with this era. True poverty isn&amp;rsquo;t frightening because there’s a forward direction and hope. This is why I say that a lack of morality and human failings are the root cause. Therefore, I believe scientists invented so much not because they initially carried great missions, but out of curiosity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to be able to figure it out myself. So I&amp;rsquo;ve always encouraged myself to be curious, especially around 50 years old. That’s why I’m happy now. One thing that bothers me is persistence – as you were saying you’re still persisting. I said don’t say that persistence leads to death. In the past, we used to say ‘persistence equals success,’ and ‘China football will persevere even during the black minutes,’ or ‘persevere,’ but it loses its fun and method, so we rely on perseverance. Sometimes persistence is important, but often it has an opposite side. I’m afraid that when I do something, like chatting with people, I&amp;rsquo;ll persist in finishing what I started – which is now too late for my time, but I’m curious to see how these conversations will turn out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I give myself a small keyword and engage in conversation with others. At 50 years old, as long as you can still maintain a great deal of curiosity, there&amp;rsquo;s no problem. I like all fun things, but not necessarily the most popular things today. Trendy terms change quickly – do you remember some of them? Will a media outlet on the internet 10 years from now become a traditional media outlet? So fun things always have their own intrinsic appeal. I respect everyone’s preferences; there must be a reason behind it, but when viewed over the long term, we see that Chinese people most enjoy playing mahjong. If you also like eating fast food, then restaurants serving large meals will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many things aren&amp;rsquo;t just about expressing an emotion and moving on. How much fragmented reading do you get from your daily mobile phone use? How much longer-form reading do you have? But this is also a process – the mobile phone is becoming our handcuffs. So, seeing shorter content more often leads to short-sightedness. However, I don’t worry about ‘content is king.’ It will always return. You won&amp;rsquo;t keep entertaining yourself until your 40s, like I see teenagers drinking soda and telling them to drink less, but you know they will still drink it. On the other hand, I’m optimistic – he’ll eventually return to a tea-drinking lifestyle. This is the life of a Chinese person.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s normal, but I hope the transformation will happen faster. We just express an emotion, and there are fewer investigative reporters now. You don&amp;rsquo;t read investigations. Thank you everyone.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What will Chinese football be like in 20 years?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:59:32 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/china-football-in-20-years/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The supplementary reader responses were mostly hastily written in 2021. The time it took to transcribe Wang Yi’s speeches at the beginning of the pandemic was still when things were just starting – don&amp;rsquo;t say twenty years later, or even a year or two later; the world is always beyond people’s expectations. Now that the epidemic has ended domestically in China, the overseas ones are still making a fuss. Regarding football, Chinese national team played quite well over the past few years; the coach dared to give them free rein and attack, which was much better than when they were just starting out and accompanying Grandpa to watch games was somewhat interesting. What kind of experience is it that a national team’s game makes even an old man unwilling to change channels?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Go to Youku Search, and no further links will be provided.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Are you still curious about Chinese football? Curious, very curious, what could be the difference? So you find that Chinese football plays badly because everyone is afraid to lose the ball in their own area and pass it to others, leaving themselves out; there&amp;rsquo;s no such way of playing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, this is just one of many small reasons. When talking about 20 years of football, 20 years from now China’s football seems so distant – the first expansion became 48 teams, and China might go or not go; the best age for a national team is 26-30, so 20 years later, those children aged 6 to 10 will be considered optimistic, but 20 years later it’s definitely going to be fine. When I mention children aged 6-10 today, you immediately look serious. Therefore, cause and effect – what are we planting today? What will grow if we plant soybeans today? We almost planted soybeans that would make the national team play in the league, and what would come out of it? Whoever initiates this action will be prepared to be dismissed; this goes against the rules, so I didn’t think about it too much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But you should really think about those children aged 6-10 today – are they playing football? If you know what Chinese football will be like in 20 years…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Ethical deficit, erosion of humanity</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 01:20:34 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/moral-deficit-humanity-loss/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“To do things properly, first and foremost, you need to have a clear conscience. This allows you to sleep soundly, without minor ailments or major issues. It&amp;rsquo;s best to avoid making mistakes in the first place. If you do make a mistake, it should be about trying to rectify it, not concealing it or hoping to forget it yourself – humans are also capable of excellent memory. Inner peace is the destination; being able to answer your own questions with integrity allows you to live more lightly.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjQ4NA==.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;. If there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this text; this document is solely for translating the text transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;transcript&#34;&gt;Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I have eight words to say that are quite heavy, and I feel we’re currently experiencing a moral deficit, a depletion of humanity, and the times are constantly presenting problems that require solutions – a completely resolved logical cycle forward. You need patience to wait for its shuffling. For a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process, so don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic about change; it&amp;rsquo;s being shuffled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These past few days, China has been battling two typhoons: one was intangible, and the other was tangible. The intangible typhoon is the vaccine, which is impacting our inner security dam. The other typhoon rarely landed in Shanghai, and then caused trouble for Beijing and Tianjin – a rare occurrence over several decades. This is an aside; next, you need to consider whether you can improve yourself, whether you’ve undergone significant changes, and whether you have many answers. If the surrounding environment remains unchanged, will you be happy? I have eight words to say that are quite heavy: I feel we currently have a moral deficit and a depletion of humanity – this is the biggest deficit and the greatest loss at present.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, people expect the vaccine’s safety risks to be completely resolved. This is like the case with melamine milk powder, so sometimes you need to look at history and understand that you know about the establishment and formation of the US Food and Drug Administration, which is closely related to the initial unsafe milk and dairy products. The Sanlu Milk Powder incident forced China to undergo significant changes in the dairy industry. While vaccines are not happening one after another, I hope this time it’s a halt. You need to know that times always present problems, solve them completely – this is the logical cycle forward; otherwise, what do reporters do? What do citizens do?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I believe that each of us can do is to be concerned. But the problem is that Chinese people are easily forgetful, like I just said, after bumping into someone’s car, we stop on the side of the road and run away; no one blocks us. Our neighbors and colleagues have a large proportion of these kinds of people. So we need to change slowly. And as ordinary citizens, what we can do is to pay attention and not forget. I don&amp;rsquo;t think it’s a lack of something; when you’re hungry and cold, you talk about ideals all the time – that doesn’t have persuasive power. But when he’s full and warm, he turns himself into China’s number one country for diabetes and high blood pressure, etc., you realize that Chinese people start running and dieting, and you ask the ladies present here, who hasn&amp;rsquo;t experienced the hardship of not being able to lose weight because they didn&amp;rsquo;t eat a good meal? This is a small change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We are talking about the spiritual level, which must be the same principle. When you’re full and warm, you start running and dieting, then your spiritual needs will gradually increase. For example, I used to smoke, but after I started running, I unconsciously found that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t smoked for 20 days. I haven’t smoked since. Of course, I wouldn’t deliberately say, “I completely quit smoking,” because it feels too ritualistic; it doesn’t rule out occasionally smoking two or three cigarettes during the year. When your lifestyle changes, many things will change with it. I think for Chinese people, you need patience to wait for its shuffling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More and more people feel unhappy and unwilling to indulge themselves. Although depression is increasing, on the other hand, isn’t there also an increasing number of people seeking positive ways to live? At this time, spiritual things will grow. Don&amp;rsquo;t be pessimistic; look at the same thing in different ways. I often see drivers cutting people off in traffic, and I feel frustrated. But then I realize that the queue on the other side is longer than before – this is how it is. You are sitting here on a rainy evening, willing to chat about useless things, isn’t that fun?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is also a transformation; therefore, many things need to be thought of in a different way. Of course, I think there will be more and more things to grow in the future, such as when you start a business, who doesn&amp;rsquo;t start a business? Everyone&amp;rsquo;s life is starting a business. Su Shi wasn’t starting a business? Li Bai wasn’t starting a business? - Data Mining&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deep Learning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Neural Network&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s the English translation of the text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“There will be countless failures throughout a lifetime, and ultimately, creating your own brand is what matters. Most failures don&amp;rsquo;t matter if you don’t create them, as long as you live a life full of flavor and believe it’s worth it. I feel that China particularly lacks a good value system: failure is another form of success. People only accept the successful outcome, but failing well is also a success – they don’t accept this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s why I find it difficult; you see many reasons why Chinese football isn’t playing well, and one of them is that everyone is afraid to lose possession and pass it to someone else. There’s no such strategy. Of course, this is just a small part of the problem. As I get older, at 30 years old, writing about the preface and happiness doesn&amp;rsquo;t come quickly; now at 50, there’s some urgency because time is passing too fast, and you expect many things to become reality. But on the other hand, I understand that for a country like China, many things are a slow shuffling process. You see older generations – some were once nothing more than traffic lights, but occasionally you&amp;rsquo;ll see children pulling their fathers along as they change. They’re changing and being shuffled; so I think you need to be patient.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Regarding time, you need to read many books to find the answers.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:27:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/about-time-and-books/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In general, the country is getting better and stronger, richer – and that’s without diminishing the importance of individual vanity. Looking back from the 1990s to now, within the families I’ve encountered, people&amp;rsquo;s lives have undeniably improved significantly. Simultaneously, the number of wealthy individuals has increased. As market-oriented economic development inevitably leads to widening income inequality, issues like class solidification and blocked upward mobility are prevalent globally.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is often discussed – such as rigid social strata and limited opportunities for advancement – are common problems worldwide. However, it’s important to acknowledge the Communist Party&amp;rsquo;s contributions to people’s basic welfare and social security, something everyone should take note of. Life will continue to improve; if you don’t want to buy a house, you can rent one. There are still inequalities in educational resources for children, requiring choices between better job opportunities, improved work environments, or more time with family. Don&amp;rsquo;t impose your own ideas on others, including your children and family members. Sit down and talk it through – life will inevitably get better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video-transcript&#34;&gt;Video Transcript
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://v.youku.com/v_show/id_XNDI5MzA4NjcyNA&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Click here to view the original video link&lt;/a&gt;, if there is any infringement, please contact the author to remove this article; this text is only for the translation of the transcript.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;thirty-years-old&#34;&gt;Thirty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/30%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;503&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;30 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;427px&#34;
	
&gt;
I’m now exactly 50 years old this year, and in the past I never thought about it; I felt that this was an old man. Now I realize it&amp;rsquo;s truly an old man – this is what I looked like at 30. When I was 30, I didn’t feel very young, good-looking, and when I was 50 years old, looking back, it’s not bad; the biggest life lesson at 30? Looking back. I think it&amp;rsquo;s subtraction – the key word is subtraction.  Somehow, &amp;ldquo;painfully happy&amp;rdquo; is also a kind of subtraction, letting you experience and write down many things, then leave them there on a new blank sheet, or running; but for me, at 30, I really feel that whether it’s about myself or reminding others, subtraction is very important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m currently guiding college students from China Central Television (CCTV), and I often remind them to &amp;ldquo;go all out&amp;rdquo; to add before they turn 30 – to try things, you don&amp;rsquo;t know what kind of possibilities you have, you don’t know what opportunities fate will give you. It’s not about knowing; but some people work hard in their twenties, adding everything, but forget to stop when it’s time for subtraction. I think 30 is a very important period in life – after doing a series of additions and running around everywhere, you need to do a significant subtraction; otherwise, it&amp;rsquo;s too late. Why do you need to subtract? Not everything suits you, not everything is suitable for you; you should do all things, but not necessarily &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How far can 8 lines of rope hold you if they’re tangled?
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/%E5%BB%89%E4%BB%B7.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;505&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Cheap&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;425px&#34;
	
&gt;
By the time I was 30, I had been promoted to a full professor – in other words, academically speaking, it&amp;rsquo;s called a professor; as for journalism, it&amp;rsquo;s a senior journalist. I was promoted at 29, and this kind of thing is rare now, but I started to feel a huge confusion when I did the Sydney Olympics in 2000.  I suddenly felt that everything wasn’t right. I had to ask myself, “What exactly do you want to do? Which things should be discarded?” That year, I made an important subtraction – I stopped my show for a year, without appearing anywhere, and at that time people told me, &amp;ldquo;As a host, if you don&amp;rsquo;t appear on screen for a month, it’s okay; if you don’t appear for six months, no one will remember you.” I said, “My face is really cheap.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That year, I started to develop new programs. This was after finishing “Painfully Happy” in 2001 – I stopped for a whole year. Everything I see today is a reflection on that time of subtraction. At that time, I could do many things – I could do sports, I could do E (likely referring to the internet), I could do many other fun things, and be a producer; but I said no, I realized I could only do news, and I should do news most of all.  Then I was the producer for three programs, and I quit them overnight, and that’s what I am today. I became simpler. Just recently, I was chatting with a colleague, and I said, “When I was in my 30s, I made a very important decision – not just because there were many things I could do, but I felt like I was just doing news; this deep well is something that might promote you to deputy director; I refused it, and returned to a normal level.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/%E6%9C%AC%E7%A7%91%E7%94%9F.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;896&#34;
	height=&#34;502&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;Undergraduate Student&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;178&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;428px&#34;
	
&gt;
Now, I’m a central television station&amp;rsquo;s senior editor – not someone who graduated from university (undergraduate). You know our system, but I refused. I wanted to see how far a bachelor’s degree could go, and why a bachelor’s degree shouldn’t constantly learn and take students as assistants? Yes, now I have 11 students under my guidance, this is the result of subtraction.  Of course, it&amp;rsquo;s a reflection looking back. It’s also easy to feel in your youth that everything should be obtained – if anything hasn’t been obtained, if something has a defect, you’ll feel very uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please don’t learn to subtract yourselves; when you’re about to turn 30, at 28, when I saw the Olympics in 1996, I came up with a sentence: “Defect is an important part of “The moon is best when it’s not yet full. But for ordinary people, it will always be seen as a flaw, not perfect enough, not reaching the extreme. The worst way to ruin someone is to make them pursue perfection and reach the ultimate goal.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;flower-not-fully-open.jpg&#34; &gt;Flower Not Fully Open&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“This world isn’t like that; the most wonderful time is when the flower hasn&amp;rsquo;t fully bloomed. When it’s full, it’s close to falling; when the moon starts to become full, it’s close to becoming a waning crescent. Therefore, I think this was a very important boost and inspiration for me at 30. 40 wasn’t as beautiful then. But I felt relaxed. More free. Why not stop dressing in suits and ties, why not always be black and white? Let&amp;rsquo;s start asking about happiness?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;forty-years-old&#34;&gt;Forty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/40%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;894&#34;
	height=&#34;499&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;40 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;179&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;429px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Chinese say that 40 is not confused, while 30 is about subtraction. 40 is about confusion, not wisdom. I think in today’s era, 40 is likely the most confused age. My midlife crisis started surprisingly early, around thirty-six or seventy, when I began to question whether everything I had done was valuable and meaningful. I wondered what happiness I truly desired. This book was born out of this confusion – you&amp;rsquo;ll find that at 30, many of your happiness goals are tied to material possessions. “Thirty and established” refers to having your education firmly in place. You need a car and a house; otherwise, your mother-in-law won’t consider marrying off your wife to you—it’s very materialistic. However, &amp;ldquo;40 is not confused&amp;rdquo; is difficult to achieve. I think ancient people had longer life expectancies than we do now, so they condensed 40 years into one, hence the lack of confusion. I&amp;rsquo;m currently 40 and feeling confused, &lt;strong&gt;and material things haven’t brought me happiness as I thought they would.&lt;/strong&gt; Similarly, when many people ask me at 40, “Are you happy?” My book title is &amp;ldquo;Happiness Waves,&amp;rdquo; which represents a question—it reflects my inner turmoil. The emergence of the midlife crisis: at 40, you need to answer yourself many questions, talk to yourself frequently, and read extensively to find answers. I’m fortunate that when I was thirty-six or seventy, I entered the world of the &lt;em&gt;Tao Te Ching&lt;/em&gt;. In &lt;em&gt;White Talk&lt;/em&gt;, I already discussed this; at 40, if your surroundings don&amp;rsquo;t change, especially the soft environment – if you can stroll out of the house with a good mood and encounter countless red lights—buying something is often fake, getting vaccinated is questionable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I said that recently China has been battling two typhoons, one visible and one tangible. The invisible typhoon is vaccines, which attacks our inner security dam. The other typhoon, Chinese typhoons rarely land in Shanghai – this is a tangent; next, you need to think about whether you can focus on your own well-being. If your surroundings don’t change, will you be happy? &lt;strong&gt;I have an eight-character idiom that I find quite heavy: we are currently experiencing a deficit of morality and a loss of humanity—this is the biggest deficit and loss at present.&lt;/strong&gt; Recently, I witnessed two cars colliding; it wasn&amp;rsquo;t too serious. The responsible party was because he had stopped on the side of the road, and the other driver was preparing to stop. But the car in front sped away without stopping him. Is that a responsible father? Is that a responsible son? Never mind how he would be a responsible citizen—he might even be your colleague. This is the deficit of morality and loss of humanity, which inevitably affects you. No matter how great a person you are, unless you haven’t left your home, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t prevent your children from getting vaccinated, or sending takeout that may have problems!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, how can Chinese people learn to transform from an ordinary citizen into a citizen—this might be at my 40, both asking myself and posing an important question to society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If 30 is about subtraction, 40 is about confusion, I think 50 should be about curiosity. 50 is awkward; you’re neither in the village nor out of it – you can attack if you go forward, retreat if you go back, and blend in if you stay put. If you lie down for ten years on something you&amp;rsquo;ve achieved, perhaps until retirement, that seems possible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently I read a book that said that truly successful entrepreneurs in Silicon Valley are often older—50s or 60s. This is different from our concept. How can China stop treating entrepreneurship as a young career—just like how China doesn’t treat youth volunteers as youth volunteers. Last week, I did a program to recruit retired primary and secondary school teachers; they receive a subsidy of two or three hundred thousand yuan per year and go teach in rural areas – and must be excellent. This is truly opening the door for retirees to find new employment—of course, it’s not just charity, but getting back to 50 is still a distance away. How do you move forward?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/about-time-and-books/50%E5%B2%81.jpg&#34;
	width=&#34;899&#34;
	height=&#34;506&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;50 years old&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;177&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;426px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More importantly, for a 50-year-old person, there are two challenges: the first is yourself – are you still curious about many things? What is your outlook on life? I think my biggest gain at 50, or the way I’m living now, is to treat every today well. Twenty years old tends to live in tomorrow, and at 50, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to dwell on yesterday. But I try to restrain myself, neither living in tomorrow nor in yesterday; I treat every today well. A 50-year-old shouldn’t always say “we’ll talk about it tomorrow” or “it was better back then!”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back now, I realize I was young once too, I had so many hair, so I should cherish every day of today, because when you look back two years later, it&amp;rsquo;s best to see yourself as you are.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just like Shen Shing said, &amp;ldquo;When my legs couldn’t walk anymore, I sat in a wheelchair and constantly reminisced about the time when I could run and play basketball. Every day was filled with pain in my memories.&amp;rdquo;
Years later, I developed bedsores on my wheelchair and felt miserable. At that time, I always remembered those peaceful moments of sitting quietly on the wheelchair.
After even more years, I got kidney failure and had to go dialysis. At that time, I would always remember the days when I only had bedsores on the wheelchair. If I hadn’t reached the point of treating every today well at 50, those next 50 years would have been wasted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fifty-years-old-1&#34;&gt;Fifty Years Old
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I actually feel that it’s not until you reach 50 to truly understand this principle; you should grasp it in your 30s or 40s, as all things are easily missed if you wait. Whether it&amp;rsquo;s a meal during a trip – if you don’t eat it, you can still have it thirty years later, and even then, it might not be the same taste. Therefore, I believe treating every day with kindness is my first feeling at 50.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second point is curiosity. I’ve realized that I can stop being curious about many things at any time, because I&amp;rsquo;ve seen so much and experienced so much, but I encourage myself to remain curious. So when I do a lot of things now, I approach them with a sense of curiosity – can you hold your phone up for a shot? Yes, you can. You can do live reporting, attend seemingly large and solemn conferences, and even make the connection easier. It’s more fun and makes a bigger impression. You can then use new media to disseminate it. I believe curiosity is the most important driving force for human progress. Why shouldn&amp;rsquo;t it be the most important driving force for individual progress? A nation will wither if it loses its curiosity. On a broader level, 50 is an important test. What kind of vested interests do you become at forty or fifty years old in China? I’m very worried that many people around me had dreams when they were young and went to achieve them, but once they achieved their dreams and became vested interests, they turned into those who blocked others from achieving their dreams, right? They would suddenly treat young people and things in the way they used to dislike.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, several years ago, I started recruiting one graduate student each year as a volunteer, and they’ve stayed for two years; now five groups have graduated, with 55 pure graduate students. I believe it&amp;rsquo;s a happy thing to become a vested interest – you have certain insights, you can also guide them. After every class, I invite them to dinner, which doesn’t cost much. But this is what a good vested interest should do: a vested interest can be two aspects—one is to pave the way again. I once said that I don&amp;rsquo;t want to say thank you too often to those who helped me, because I want to repay them tenfold with new young people. This is how I express my gratitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you’re constantly saying “thank you” and then become a blocker…&lt;/strong&gt; The next thing is to pave the way for others. I hope that in China, whether it&amp;rsquo;s material, economic, ideological, or cultural, all vested interests – when you become one, what should you do? Yesterday, someone was pushing a cart; today they’re blocking the train. This has happened throughout Chinese history. It won’t be like this; sometimes it will even be worse, so I call on all vested interests to return to how they felt when they were young – to do things as they did then. Perhaps I wasn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, but I thought about it, did it, and said it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
