<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Cinema-Theatres on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/cinema-theatres/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Cinema-Theatres on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/cinema-theatres/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Spring Festival Blockbuster Movie Ticket Price Mystery: The Difference Between Online and Offline Prices</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-movie-ticket-price-mystery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 00:02:02 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/chinese-new-year-movie-ticket-price-mystery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Spring Festival, a family of seven or eight people wanted to go see a movie. They originally planned to buy tickets on Taopiaopiao and Maoyan. When they looked at the price, it was 60 yuan. Luckily, they had a cinema recharge card that required them to purchase tickets at the cinema’s front desk. They thought about asking the front desk if there were any discounts, but unexpectedly, the same showtime cost only 35 yuan when purchased at the front desk. The price difference was quite surprising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-hidden-add-on-of-platform-service-fees&#34;&gt;The “Hidden Add-on” of Platform Service Fees
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While online ticketing platforms are convenient, platform service fees cannot be ignored. They provide users with a seamless booking experience, such as precise seat selection and the ability to view purchase history at any time – all of which require investment in maintenance. These costs are then passed on to consumers through increased ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;cinema-differentiation-operation-strategies&#34;&gt;Cinema Differentiation Operation Strategies
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;With the explosive demand for movie-watching during the Spring Festival, cinemas adopted differentiated pricing strategies to maximize revenue. Online platforms have a large volume of traffic, and many people are accustomed to purchasing tickets online in advance; therefore, cinema ticket prices were set higher on these platforms. Meanwhile, those buying tickets directly at the box office – walk-in customers – received lower prices to attract this segment of the audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-price-logic-behind-revenue-sharing&#34;&gt;The Price Logic Behind Revenue Sharing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Revenue sharing models between online platforms and cinemas impact ticket prices. For an online platform to take a slice of the box office revenue – in order to maintain profitability – they will typically raise ticket prices. Conversely, cinema box offices have no intermediary sales process, resulting in lower costs, which naturally leads to more affordable ticket prices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;consumer-ticket-buying-tips&#34;&gt;Consumer Ticket Buying Tips
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Don’t just look at online platforms when buying tickets. Call the cinema&amp;rsquo;s front desk to inquire about prices, or go directly to the front desk and ask – you might find a surprise! If you frequently watch movies, get an auditorium membership card to enjoy member discounts and save money.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
