<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Gift on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Gift on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/gift/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Monetization models based on traffic: Raffles</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Host giving away iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift giveaways?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three things mentioned above, which don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have much connection, are actually different monetization models for free traffic, with a bit of a financial game feel&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;win-gifts-through-platform-lottery&#34;&gt;Win gifts through platform lottery
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users reset to obtain platform currency, purchase gifts for their favorite streamers. Each platform also has another gameplay: after users acquire platform currency, they no longer directly send gifts but can spend a certain amount of currency to participate in lottery events and obtain limited-edition, high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem has already appeared. Understanding online lotteries simply means the platform is running a casino. With enough participants, it will definitely not lose money. &lt;strong&gt;Commoner&lt;/strong&gt; users are playing with a &amp;ldquo;give it a shot&amp;rdquo; mentality, hoping to win a big prize and then send gifts, showing off and acting like they&amp;rsquo;re in charge!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gift-from-streamer-physical-item&#34;&gt;Gift from streamer (physical item)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The platform&amp;rsquo;s lottery mentioned earlier is aimed at users’ writing. Anchors have monthly activity and popularity tasks; enabling the gifting lottery feature, fans who send designated gifts or gifts of a specified amount will have the opportunity to participate in the lottery, which could be high-end phones or cash rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular streamers, this event is quite profitable; it&amp;rsquo;s essentially a temporary free gift campaign. With enough participants, the streamer can still make money. This tests the streamer’s operational capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another way to play – with high rewards (cash value). Many outdoor streamers use this approach; it’s a disguised form of online gambling. People don’t care about the content of the live stream; users only care whether they can win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from hosts specializing in fashion shows, ordinary game streamers find it difficult to stimulate player spending through PK mode. Playing games and watching streams are leisure activities; people don&amp;rsquo;t want to spend extra money, especially with &lt;strong&gt;competitive games&lt;/strong&gt;. Lottery-style promotions can cultivate users’ charging habits and consumption habits, occasionally leading to impulse purchases (with generous rewards, hoping to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini-program ranking rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini-program with some pointless processes or offer partial game-related support services. All of this is just a cover—to pass Tencent&amp;rsquo;s review, incorporate a ranking mechanism into the mini-program’s gameplay. Users earn points by browsing incentive ads and completing tasks; the backend sets rankings based on these points, and users with higher rankings receive designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core logic: Advertising revenue &amp;gt; Operating costs + Reward expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mini programs can also operate normally, providing reasonable services, and earning income through appropriate advertising. The earnings may not be much, but a trickle of water can still accumulate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
