<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Academic on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/academic/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Academic on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Blog IDE environment and random thoughts</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 13:54:27 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This article introduces the basic concepts of Markdown and its applications in various software. It recommends using VSCode as an IDE and lists recommended plugins. The author shares their experience switching from Hexo to Hugo, emphasizing Hugo&amp;rsquo;s flexibility and customization capabilities. Finally, it provides some tips for quickly getting started with new technologies and shares a trick for resolving the issue of Hugo theme styles not updating.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;preface&#34;&gt;Preface
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;Markdown
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A lightweight markup language that allows people to write documents in a readable and writable plain text format&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Detailed Markdown syntax will not be elaborated on in this article; a recommended ebook is available, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://markdown-zh.readthedocs.io/en/latest/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many software on the market already support md as a writing format. The CSDN blog system launched an online editor that supports md syntax, and it comes with an introductory article about md syntax when you use it for the first time, which I think is pretty good; Evernote added support for md notes in 2018, with various md tag options in the quick bar, making it feel similar to editing regular articles, and the overall interactive process is friendly to beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ide-recommendations&#34;&gt;IDE recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;When writing this article, it&amp;rsquo;s already 2020. You must have heard of VS Code, after all, anyone who considers using Git Page to build a blog system is an industry professional. In earlier years, Sublime and Atom were also good choices. With two years of community support, VS Code has developed rapidly and gradually become the preferred entry point for beginners.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The relationship between Microsoft and the open-source community has transitioned from a state of separation to a honeymoon period: embracing open source. The company I work for has also actively introduced the Java ecosystem in recent years; in other words, the Java ecosystem is genuinely appealing for business development within China now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;vs-code-extension-recommendations&#34;&gt;VS Code extension recommendations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Plugin List&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plugins all have their own Readme files, introducing basic usage and core features; some plugin authors also provide dynamic effect demonstration images&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very convenient to introduce images using the image plugin method of Hugo&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t memorized the shortcuts, so I opened the VS Code shortcut management menu and searched for &amp;ldquo;md,&amp;rdquo; looking at it several times; I reviewed the plugin usage instructions again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hugo&#34;&gt;hugo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a writer, I&amp;rsquo;ve switched from &lt;code&gt;Hexo&lt;/code&gt; to &lt;code&gt;Hugo&lt;/code&gt;. My nature is to tinker and I simply couldn’t stand writing articles quietly without constantly experimenting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo supports placing images and md documents in separate folders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Academic themes support various types of article styles in design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Various convenient custom extensions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;academic&#34;&gt;academic
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The website defaults to &lt;code&gt;exampleSite&lt;/code&gt;, menu integration uses the &lt;code&gt;#component&lt;/code&gt; method, and using &lt;code&gt;url&lt;/code&gt; is recommended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The URL pattern allows for single-page jumps when clicking on navigation, rather than scrolling on the homepage—this is purely a matter of personal preference&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Styles: Essays, Speeches, E-books&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Flexibility: Customize overall style, customize CSS styles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This theme&amp;rsquo;s support for Chinese is not yet very complete, mainly from a visual perspective – the font size isn&amp;rsquo;t quite in line with Chinese reading habits. However, Hexo’s developers are mostly Chinese, which gives it an advantage over Hugo in this regard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, it&amp;rsquo;s about doing things yourself and providing for your own needs. Inspect the browser elements. Once you’ve located the element, to know the CSS style name that needs modification, click &lt;strong&gt;Insert Style Rule Below&lt;/strong&gt; in the sidebar. Even with deeply nested CSS, you can easily get the node name.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing &lt;strong&gt;custom.css&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introducing &lt;strong&gt;custom_js&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The theme&amp;rsquo;s built-in syntax highlighting settings, &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/#highlighting-options.&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;official link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The little one is about to complain again – why are you being so vague from beginning to end, not mentioning any details?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I want to say is, these things will be enough for you&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Official manual&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plugin Description&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To quickly get started with new technologies, it&amp;rsquo;s recommended to first read the official documentation. Don’t worry about understanding everything on the first pass; at least get a general idea. Search engine results may not always be consistent with the latest version and could potentially mislead you. The same applies to reading new books – look at the table of contents first to understand what the author intends to cover. Sometimes, reading the preface is helpful; in some foreign works translated into Chinese, the translator&amp;rsquo;s preface often summarizes the book’s content and core ideas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;easter-egg&#34;&gt;Easter egg
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Switching to the built-in Hugo Academic style didn&amp;rsquo;t change the appearance when published to the site. Clever users probably already figured it out: clear your local browser cache, and the problem is solved. The ingenious me: F12 developer mode, switch to &lt;code&gt;network&lt;/code&gt;, check &lt;code&gt;disable cache&lt;/code&gt;, refresh, done!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/blog-ide-environment-and-ramblings/2020-03-31-14-27-15.png&#34;
	width=&#34;399&#34;
	height=&#34;142&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;network&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;280&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;674px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
