<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Position / Layout on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/position-/-layout/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Position / Layout on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:28:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/position-/-layout/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Reverse Human Nature Trading Review: Xiaomi’s “Black Swan” Incident – T&#43;0 Compliance Practices, and the Neglected Hong Kong Stamp Duty</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reverse-human-nature-trading-review-xiaomis-black-swan-incident-t0-compliance-practices-and-the-neglected-hong-kong-stamp-duty/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:53:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/reverse-human-nature-trading-review-xiaomis-black-swan-incident-t0-compliance-practices-and-the-neglected-hong-kong-stamp-duty/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Write a wrap-up record to translate investment thinking into text, clarifying one’s thoughts and resisting emotional biases. &lt;strong&gt;Trading itself is anti-human&lt;/strong&gt;, requiring us to maintain clarity, objectivity, and discipline. Through recording and review, we can systematically examine the decision-making process, avoiding emotional pitfalls.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As previously mentioned, the sharp drop in US equities on Friday last week, and concerns regarding a potential “trade war 2.0,” have now settled as the market opened this Monday – essentially a “false alarm.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;index-funds-executing-the-plan&#34;&gt;Index Funds: Executing the Plan
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially anticipating a significant downturn, I added positions in the沪深300 (Shanghai-Shenzhen Stock Exchange 300) and恒生科技指数 (Hang Seng TECH ETF) through Alipay. However, most of the declines in the trailing market were recovered. Given the relatively small size of the initial capital allocation, I will not make any additional operations for now. Future index fund replenishment strategies will be more conservative and gradual, primarily utilizing fixed-income plus products for asset allocation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hong-kong-stocks-rapid-response-and-disciplined-trading-to-black-swans&#34;&gt;Hong Kong Stocks: Rapid Response and Disciplined Trading to “Black Swans”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the current Hong Kong stock positions, if further declines persist, we will need to deploy new funds into trading.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;xiaomi-event-and-cognitive-correction&#34;&gt;Xiaomi Event and Cognitive Correction
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Today, Xiaomi experienced a “black swan” event: a fatal car accident involving one of its electric vehicles. My initial cognition was that the volume of traffic accidents is massive, and given the increasing vehicle fleet size for Xiaomi, isolated incidents are a matter of probability. &lt;strong&gt;As long as subsequent investigations rule out design flaws in the vehicle itself, the long-term impact on the stock price should be manageable.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This morning, Xiaomi’s decline was significantly greater than that of other stocks in the Hong Seng Technology sector. I missed the initial reaction due to being busy eating and not switching the Futu App interface to the news section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on technical analysis, I selected a range I considered a dense accumulation zone for potential bottoms, placing an order to buy at the next price differential. My plan was likely to wait for tomorrow’s traffic police notification, but unexpectedly, the investigative results were released in the afternoon – the driver involved was suspected of drunk driving and speeding. This news caused the stock price to rebound sharply.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trading-summary-reinforce-discipline&#34;&gt;Trading Summary: Reinforce Discipline
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disciplined Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; This entry was explicitly defined as &lt;strong&gt;short-term speculation (“gambling”).&lt;/strong&gt; Its core objective was to: &lt;strong&gt;If successful, quickly realize profits and exit with minimal risk to lower the average cost of existing holdings; If unsuccessful, decisively cut losses and exit.&lt;/strong&gt; The original plan was to fulfill it today or tomorrow, ultimately completed within today’s market rebound.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back at previous trades: Compared to the initial capital planning, the position is now nearing full allocation. Reviewing Meituan and Xiaomi transactions from half a month ago, we found that several previous &lt;strong&gt;short-term purchases followed by declines, failing to timely cut losses and instead irrationally holding onto hopes of recouping losses&lt;/strong&gt;, which is a significant problem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;The biggest progress in this trading was: being able to “not greedily chase profits” with short-term positions; strictly adhering to the trading plan, without blindly adding to positions at unsuitable times.&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;transaction-fees-for-short-term-trading&#34;&gt;Transaction Fees for Short-Term Trading
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the past, during the development of brokerage systems, I had extensively researched transaction fees but never carefully considered their impact from a trader’s perspective. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until today, when conducting a standard T+0 turnaround trade, that I deliberately calculated the returns and clearly realized that &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong stamp duty&lt;/strong&gt; (one-tenth of the transaction amount) is the largest component of trading costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking back, my career began in developing brokerage systems for Hong Kong and US stocks. I deeply understood the importance of transaction fees within the system, but lacked firsthand experience as a trader regarding whether they were &lt;strong&gt;more or less&lt;/strong&gt;, nor did I ever delve into how the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Exchange (HKEX)&lt;/strong&gt; generated profits as a listed company. When opening HKGS (Hong Kong Gold Shares) at the beginning of the year, my investment goals remained focused on the Hang Seng Tech Index without considering buying shares in HKEX itself. This mindset resembled a stubborn “wherever I fall, I’ll stand up” attitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been proven that &lt;strong&gt;limited knowledge framed the initial investment choices.&lt;/strong&gt; Considering that the Shanghai and Shenzhen Stock Exchanges, both under the China Securities Regulatory Commission, are not listed companies, I had actually considered similar industries – domestic brokerage firms. Choosing a brokerage firm was primarily guided by the media narrative of “market makers,” but if comparisons were made, &lt;strong&gt;exchanges&lt;/strong&gt; as market infrastructure have inherent scarcity and monopoly characteristics, undoubtedly making them a better choice than brokerages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>A Complete Guide to Positioning, Replenishing Positions, and Stop-Loss Orders</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:39:23 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For investors seeking to steadily progress in the Hong Kong stock market, success doesn’t stem from precisely predicting every fluctuation of the market, but rather from establishing a scientific, rational, and strictly adhered-to investment system. This system&amp;rsquo;s core consists of three pillars: &lt;strong&gt;reasonable position control&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;intelligent rebalancing strategies&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unwavering trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt;. This article will consolidate these key elements to provide investors with a comprehensive and detailed operational guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control--the-cornerstone-of-resilient-investing&#34;&gt;Position Control – The Cornerstone of Resilient Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary goal of resilient investing is “to preserve capital and develop afterwards.” Position control serves as the “shield” to achieve this, determining your ability to withstand market volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall-allocation-dependent-on-risk-tolerance-and-market-temperature&#34;&gt;Overall Allocation: Dependent on Risk Tolerance and Market Temperature
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Risk Tolerance:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the fundamental determinant of your allocation ceiling. Risk-averse investors should maintain a total position no higher than &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt;, even in bull markets. Investors with slightly higher risk tolerance can set their ceilings at &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt;. At all times, maintain at least &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; cash as a strategic reserve to capitalize on extreme opportunities or unforeseen needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High/Bubble Phase (Market Mania):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation should be reduced to &lt;strong&gt;30%-50%&lt;/strong&gt; or lower. Preserving profits is the priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral/Choppy Phase (Uncertain Direction):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation can remain at &lt;strong&gt;50%-70%&lt;/strong&gt;, making structural adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low/Panic Phase (Valuation Bottoming):&lt;/strong&gt; This is the golden time to increase allocation, potentially reaching &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt; or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;individual-stock-and-industry-exposure-diversify-risk-avoid-overconcentration&#34;&gt;Individual Stock and Industry Exposure: Diversify Risk, Avoid Overconcentration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Stock Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Regardless of how optimistic you are about a particular stock, the recommended position size for any single stock should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the total investment portfolio. For companies with limited understanding or higher risk profiles, the position size should be further reduced to &lt;strong&gt;5%-10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Industry Exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Given the high concentration of industries in Hong Kong (such as finance and technology), it’s important to diversify. The total exposure to any single industry should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;30%-40%&lt;/strong&gt; to mitigate the impact of industry-specific “black swan” events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buyback-strategy--the-art-of-transforming-passivity-into-proactivity&#34;&gt;Buyback Strategy – The Art of Transforming Passivity into Proactivity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A buyback strategy is the “lever” for prudent investors to accumulate high-quality positions in a declining market. However, this requires &lt;strong&gt;only operating on companies with sound fundamentals and uncompromised core competitiveness.&lt;/strong&gt; For companies with deteriorating fundamentals or “penny stocks,” the only correct action is to cut losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-much-to-buy-on-dips-for-adding-to-position&#34;&gt;How much to buy on dips for adding to position?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of accumulating during a decline is “buying lower,” but this must be executed with a plan and discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pyramidal Accumulation Strategy (Wide Base, Narrow Top):&lt;/strong&gt; This is a relatively conservative approach where the amount purchased increases as the price falls further.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Position Building:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish a &lt;strong&gt;base position&lt;/strong&gt; within a reasonable valuation range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops 15%-20% from the initial position building price. This is a common re-entry point, filtering out normal market fluctuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the first refill price (cumulative decline of approximately 30%-40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the second refill price (cumulative decline potentially reaching around 50%). At this point, it’s typically extreme panic. If the company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals remain solid, it’s a great buying opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-it-reasonable-to-add-to-the-position-a-few-times&#34;&gt;Is it reasonable to add to the position a few times?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To avoid overinvesting capital in a wrong decision, the number of times to add to the position should not be excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended number of additions: 2-3 times is appropriate.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk control:&lt;/strong&gt; If the stock price still doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve after 2-3 major add-on purchases, you must re-examine your initial investment logic. Unlimited adding may lead to a single holding ratio being too high, dragging down the entire investment portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain cash reserves:&lt;/strong&gt; Excessive additions will quickly deplete available funds, causing you to miss other better opportunities that appear in the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trading-discipline--the-core-for-newbies-progression&#34;&gt;Trading Discipline – The Core for Newbies’ Progression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If position sizing and stop-lossing are “techniques,” then trading discipline is the “way.” For novice traders, adhering to discipline is a decisive factor in whether they can survive in the market long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planning-and-execution-discipline-never-go-into-battle-without-a-plan&#34;&gt;Planning and Execution Discipline: Never Go into Battle Without a Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan Before Trade:&lt;/strong&gt; Every trade must be preceded by a clear understanding of the &lt;strong&gt;buy rationale, target price (take profit), and stop-loss level&lt;/strong&gt;. During the trade, strictly adhere to the plan and avoid emotional interference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Riding the Wave and Panic Selling:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcome the fear of missing out (FOMO) and panic selling emotions. Only execute trades at points that align with your plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-and-capital-management-discipline-survival-is-the-priority&#34;&gt;Risk and Capital Management Discipline: Survival is the Priority
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strict Stop-Loss, No Hesitation:&lt;/strong&gt; A stop-loss is the lifeline for protecting your capital. The most dangerous habit for beginners is to hold onto losing trades. Set your stop-loss levels at &lt;strong&gt;-5% to -10%&lt;/strong&gt;, and execute without hesitation upon reaching them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Add to Losing Trades to Average Down to Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a fatal error. If a trade proves to be wrong (falling below the stop-loss), the correct approach is to exit, not to invest more money to “dilute the cost.” This can turn a small mistake into a major disaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mindset-and-emotional-control-discipline-be-the-master-of-your-emotions&#34;&gt;Mindset and Emotional Control Discipline: Be the Master of Your Emotions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept Losses as Part of Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; No one can win every battle. View small losses as a necessary cost of trading, focusing on the long-term overall profit/loss ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Get Greedy from Profits, Don’t Be Bitter from Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; Break free from a “gambling mentality,” don&amp;rsquo;t take risks due to profits, and don’t retaliate with impulsive trades due to losses. Maintain a calm mindset and remain consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-and-review-discipline-continuous-evolution&#34;&gt;Learning and Review Discipline: Continuous Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain a Trading Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;  Detailed record of your thought process and results for each trade, with regular reviews to analyze successes and failures. This is the most effective way to self-improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stick to Your Circle of Competence:&lt;/strong&gt; Only invest in areas you understand and can truly comprehend. Avoid unfamiliar fields and complex financial products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patience-and-discipline-are-superior-to-everything-else&#34;&gt;Patience and Discipline are Superior to Everything Else
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a prudent Hong Kong stock investor, your goal isn’t to be a speculator dancing on the crest of market waves, but rather to be like a discerning general, orchestrating strategy from behind the scenes. Please treat &lt;strong&gt;position control&lt;/strong&gt; as your steadfast shield, &lt;strong&gt;opportunistic buying strategies&lt;/strong&gt; as your sharp spear, and &lt;strong&gt;trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt; as an immutable military code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the initial stages of trading, &lt;strong&gt;prioritize “minimizing losses” over “making big profits.”&lt;/strong&gt; Through continuous learning, practice, and review, you will ultimately achieve long-term, steady wealth appreciation in this market brimming with opportunities and challenges. Remember, patience and discipline are always more important qualities than predicting the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Black Swan Goose Returns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:10:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, investors focused on financial news. Since Trump’s return, they also needed to pay attention to his Twitter (a private version). The trade war continued to escalate, leading to a sharp decline on April 7th, which was quickly followed by a rebound. This time, though, are people still willing to jump in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-review&#34;&gt;Background Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 7, 2025, following the impact of the U.S. implementation of an “equivalency tariff” policy, global stock markets experienced a “Black Monday.” The A-share market plunged, with the Shanghai Composite Index falling by 7.34% and the Shenzhen Component Index plummeting by 12.5%, with over 4,300 stocks declining by more than 9%. The Hang Seng Index in Hong Kong also fell by 13.22%, along with European and U.S. stock indices exceeding declines of 4%. China subsequently stabilized the market through state-owned enterprise (SOE) purchases and intervention by Huishang Securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 10th, U.S. stocks suffered another significant decline, with Chinese HShares falling by 6%, driven primarily by expectations of escalation in the U.S.-China trade war. Trump signaled a further increase in tariffs on China, and the U.S. would also impose hefty fees on Chinese ships. China announced retaliatory measures and levied special port fees, compounded by a government shutdown, declining consumer confidence, and market panic selling for safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115351840469973590&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Original Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/black-swan-goose-returns/20251011142053.png&#34;
	width=&#34;586&#34;
	height=&#34;766&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;realDonaldTrump&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;76&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;183px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control&#34;&gt;Position Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the state of short selling in A-shares isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete short position; there’s a small portion invested in index funds within Fixed Income Plus, but the bulk is still in the Hong Kong market. Xiaomi has already incurred principal losses, and Meituan remains a shareholder. The position control is somewhat unbalanced. Should we jump in and gamble on Monday? It&amp;rsquo;s a question to consider – currently, we don’t have enough cash flow. If we need to enter, we would rely on old friends like Alipay’s Jiebei for bridging funds. &lt;strong&gt;Greedy snakes swallow elephants&lt;/strong&gt; – the position control is extremely unreasonable, and we should look for opportunities to reduce our holdings later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to April 7th, the current position isn&amp;rsquo;t considered a low-level one; many stocks are at relatively high levels, particularly the technology stocks within the Heng Seng Tech index. If we were to add to positions, it would be more appropriate to use an ETF rather than individual stocks – for example: &lt;strong&gt;Turned around and couldn’t find anything suitable; gains were 20%-30%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the domestic market, long-term trends point towards a period of consolidation and decline, with potential for significant rallies in the short term. To make profits, it&amp;rsquo;s best to execute profit-taking operations within this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;associated-term-definitions&#34;&gt;Associated Term Definitions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-swan&#34;&gt;Black Swan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Black Swan&amp;rdquo; originates from Nassim Nicholas Taleb’s book &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to events that are &lt;strong&gt;extremely unlikely&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt;, but upon occurring, they generate &lt;strong&gt;extreme impact and disruptive consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rarity/Unpredictability:&lt;/strong&gt; These events have no precedent or warning signs before they occur, exceeding all conventional expectations and model predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extreme Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once they happen, they can cause catastrophic effects on markets, economies, and even societies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-hoc Rationalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite being impossible to predict beforehand, people tend to find reasons and explanations after the event occurs, making it appear “understandable.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Legend:&lt;/strong&gt; Before the discovery of Australia, Europeans believed all swans were white until black swans were discovered in Australia, completely overturning thousands of years of knowledge. Therefore, the Black Swan symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;unforeseen and cognitive breakthroughs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;9/11&amp;rdquo; terrorist attack in 2001 (a short-term shock to global markets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The initial impact of &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt; on the global economy and markets (although some argued it had grey rhino characteristics, its sudden outbreak and global spread, as well as the extent of its impact, were largely considered Black Swans).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gray-rhino&#34;&gt;Gray Rhino
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “Gray Rhino” was coined by Michele Wucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to a potential crisis that is &lt;strong&gt;highly probable&lt;/strong&gt;, has a &lt;strong&gt;significant impact&lt;/strong&gt;, and yet is &lt;strong&gt;ignored&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;selectively delayed in addressing&lt;/strong&gt; due to its &lt;strong&gt;obvious warning signs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Probability/Predictability:&lt;/strong&gt; The event has clear indicators and evidence before it occurs, making it a &lt;strong&gt;known&lt;/strong&gt; risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily Ignored:&lt;/strong&gt; Because it’s not sudden but rather long-term or slowly developing, people become numb, exhibit optimism bias, or procrastinate, failing to take timely action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once it erupts, due to the lack of effective responses beforehand, it triggers a chain reaction and causes severe destructive consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Allusion:&lt;/strong&gt; A gray rhino is large in size and has a slow reaction time; people can see it from afar, but often fail to avoid it because of negligence or indifference. Once it charges towards you, it will cause a fatal collision. Therefore, the gray rhino symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;obvious yet ignored&lt;/strong&gt; major threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2008 &lt;strong&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/strong&gt; (many experts had already warned about the high risk of the US subprime mortgage market, but were largely ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sovereign Debt Crises&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;severe asset bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;systemic risks from climate change&lt;/strong&gt; (these are long-accumulated, traceable major risks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
