<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Raffle-Draw on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/raffle-draw/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Raffle-Draw on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/raffle-draw/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Monetization Model: Raffles/Sweepstakes</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 07:04:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/traffic-monetization-business-models-lottery/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Host giveaways of iPhones? Mini-program ranking rewards? Various live streaming platform gift lotteries?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These seemingly unrelated things are, in essence, different monetization models for free traffic, with a hint of financial engineering&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;win-gifts-through-platform-lottery&#34;&gt;Win gifts through platform lottery
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In typical scenarios, users obtain platform currency to purchase gifts for their favorite streamers. Platforms also offer another approach: instead of directly gifting, users can spend the acquired currency to enter raffles and win exclusive, high-value gifts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s already a problem – online lotteries are essentially platforms running casinos. With enough participants, they’re guaranteed to be profitable. &lt;strong&gt;屌丝&lt;/strong&gt; Users participate hoping for a big win, intending to show off and gain status!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gift-from-streamer-physical-item&#34;&gt;Gift from streamer (physical item)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The platform&amp;rsquo;s lottery focuses on user content. Hosts have monthly activity and popularity tasks. Enabling the gifting lottery allows fans who send designated gifts or amounts to participate, with prizes like high-end phones or cash rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For popular streamers, this event is quite profitable – essentially a zero-cost purchase with enough participants to generate income. It tests the streamer&amp;rsquo;s operational skills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s another way to play—with high rewards (cash value)—and many outdoor streamers use this method, essentially a form of online gambling. People don’t care about the content; users only care if they can win.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aside from show-focused hosts, ordinary game streamers struggle to drive player spending through PK mode. Gaming and watching streams are leisure activities; people don&amp;rsquo;t typically want to spend extra money. Especially lotteries can cultivate users’ charging habits and consumption habits, occasionally leading to impulse purchases (with generous prizes, creating a desire to win).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mini-program-ranking-rewards&#34;&gt;Mini-program ranking rewards
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Design a mini-program with trivial processes or offer limited gaming support. These are all cover tactics to pass Tencent&amp;rsquo;s review; the gameplay should include a ranking system. Users earn points by viewing incentivized ads and completing tasks, and the backend uses these points to determine rankings. High-ranking users receive designated rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Core logic: Advertising revenue &amp;gt; Operating costs + Reward expenses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even small programs can operate effectively, providing reasonable services and earning income through appropriate advertising. The earnings may not be substantial, but a steady trickle can still work.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
