<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stock-Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stock-Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Broad-based index investing: Broker ETFs, Hang Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I always wanted to buy a solid blue-chip stock and just leave it, but I never managed to do it. When it fell, I didn&amp;rsquo;t add to my position, and when it rose, I sold it off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding suitable blue-chip stocks is troublesome; it&amp;rsquo;s better to choose a broad index and buy an ETF. The current plan is: securities ETF, Hang Seng Tech Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trading strategy has a professional term: left-side dip buying&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;broker-etfs&#34;&gt;Broker ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Securities ETF refers to exchange-traded funds (ETFs) that primarily invest in listed securities broker stocks within the Chinese stock market. Securities ETFs typically track a specific securities brokerage index, such as the China Securities Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I bought it before, but chased after the price and ended up losing money, so I cleared out my position. In China&amp;rsquo;s market, every bull market sees brokerages rise; how much they rise depends on investor sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-technology-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Technology Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is a stock index launched by the Hong Kong Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology sector in the Hong Kong market. It includes major tech companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering areas such as internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituents and their weightings in the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) are as follows (data compiled from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;舜宇集团 (舜宇光学科技集团有限公司) (01810.HK): Approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China Resources Pharmaceutical Holdings (00700.HK): Approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Country Garden (09988.HK): Approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;京东集团-SW&lt;/strong&gt; (09618.HK): Approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;舜宇光学科技集团有限公司 (Sunvision Technology Co., Ltd.) (03690.HK): Approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(01024.HK): Approximately 6.10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bold (02015.HK): Approximately 6.09%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;中芯国际&lt;/strong&gt; (00981.HK): Approximately 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(09999.HK): Approximately 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Approximately 4.48%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approximately 66.6% (some sources indicate a combined share of the top ten between 68%-69%, with differences due to varying statistical time points)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-notes&#34;&gt;Key Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index caps the weighting of any single stock at 8%. For example, SMIC&amp;rsquo;s weighting previously exceeded 8% before adjustments in March 2025 but was subsequently reduced to comply with this limit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On May 16, 2025, Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD (01211.HK) will be added to the index and China Literature (00772.HK) removed. The adjustment will take effect on June 6. Therefore, as of today (May 20), the constituent stocks are based on the pre-adjustment list; BYD is not yet included.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The top ten components are dominated by internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, and Meituan), with significant weighting in new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Li Auto) and semiconductors (SMIC), reflecting the index&amp;rsquo;s coverage of technology and the new economy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Differences in data from various sources are primarily due to differing statistical time points. For example, data from March 2025 shows the top ten combined share at approximately 69.4%, while data from May 14th indicates 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on weighting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;add-to-position-on-a-pullback-on-the-left-side&#34;&gt;Add to position on a pullback (on the left side)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A &amp;ldquo;left-side topping up&amp;rdquo; strategy is an investment approach where investors buy in batches during a sustained stock price decline, anticipating the price is nearing a bottom to reduce holding costs and profit from future price increases&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method falls under the category of &amp;ldquo;left-side trading,&amp;rdquo; meaning taking a counter-trend position before the market has clearly bottomed out. In practice, investors typically employ a &amp;ldquo;pyramid&amp;rdquo; accumulation strategy, gradually increasing buy quantities as the price declines to lower their average holding cost. For example, initially buying a certain number of shares; if the price continues to fall, they increase their buying volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buying in batches during a downturn can lower average cost basis and set the stage for future profits&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Establishing positions before the market reverses can yield greater returns when the trend improves if your judgment is correct&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If the stock price continues to fall, it may lead to greater losses&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Adequate financial support is required for continuous restocking, and there&amp;rsquo;s a risk of funds being locked up long-term&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, &amp;ldquo;right-side trading&amp;rdquo; involves buying after a clear market trend and price recovery signal, offering lower risk but potentially missing early gains. Therefore, investors should choose a strategy that aligns with their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance, aiming to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies and provide a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and formulate corresponding investment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method is based on the expected future cash flows of an asset, which are then discounted to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes intrinsic value and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method assesses a company&amp;rsquo;s relative value by comparing its valuation metrics (e.g., P/E, P/B, P/S) to those of comparable companies in the same industry. Relative valuation is easy to implement and widely used for quick assessments and peer comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method determines a company&amp;rsquo;s value by assessing its net asset value, which is the difference between total assets and liabilities. The asset-based approach is suitable for asset-dominant companies such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and formulate buy-or-sell strategies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influencing its success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The company needs to fairly value its assets and liabilities to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial statements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that valuation results are influenced by various factors, including market conditions, company operations, and macroeconomic indicators. Therefore, a comprehensive consideration of all factors, combined with qualitative and quantitative analysis, is necessary to achieve more accurate assessments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Making money takes time; rushing it wont help</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading, while I haven&amp;rsquo;t made a fortune, I also haven&amp;rsquo;t lost too much. The biggest issue is an unreasonable cash flow plan and unstable mindset. Currently, my primary income comes from work – a fixed salary. My tolerance for financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; buying too little means you won’t profit when prices rise, while buying too much leads to losses when they fall. A stable mindset is therefore crucial; it helps steady our ship of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing through stock trading: The importance of mindset&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Besides dabbling in small-cap and newly listed stocks when I first started, the investments I&amp;rsquo;ve focused on since have been primarily blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hengan Electronics, ZTE, and various large-cap index funds&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, it stemmed from greed wanting more—rushing to increase holdings at the start, then facing a cash flow crisis. Expenses like insurance, buying property, and getting married were major drains on funds; the overall plan lacked sufficient financial buffer, leading to later shortages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Buy blue-chip stocks, it&amp;rsquo;s like relying on [someone] dependable&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Evergrande ran into problems, bank stocks plummeted, allowing for a successful opportunity to sell off. However, this demonstrates a flawed understanding of the broader economy – real estate&amp;rsquo;s share in the national economy is too significant, with far-reaching implications that cannot be ignored. The subsequent market decline and the sustained rise of dividend stocks over roughly two years reflect this.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The early stages of the trade war saw significant damage, with stock prices falling sharply, but they gradually recovered afterward&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This stock belongs to the former employer. After Ant Financial&amp;rsquo;s divestiture, the price dropped significantly, but it has market makers who can push it up several times a year. With proper position sizing, losses will be minimal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-that-devours-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The &amp;ldquo;monster&amp;rdquo; that devours reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When stock prices rise steadily and investors&amp;rsquo; paper profits increase, greed quietly takes root. Many, seeing prices already at high levels, still fantasize about continued upward trends and seek greater returns, unwilling to take profits. Blinded by greed, they forget market rules and the existence of risk. For example, during speculative surges in certain hot-topic stocks, some investors, witnessing short-term doubling or even multiple times increases, become deeply involved, continuously adding positions with the hope of being the last winners. However, markets don&amp;rsquo;t stay exuberant forever; when bubbles burst and prices plummet, these greed-driven investors often suffer heavy losses. Greed robs them of their ability to analyze and decide rationally, turning them into &amp;ldquo;gamblers&amp;rdquo; rather than wise investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-shackles-binding-your-hands-and-feet&#34;&gt;Fear: Shackles binding your hands and feet
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the opposite of greed. Fear is equally destructive in the stock market. When market conditions turn sharply downward and prices plummet, investors easily panic. This fear erodes their confidence; even with fundamentally sound stocks, they rush to sell to avoid further losses. For example, during the global financial crisis, many high-quality blue-chip stocks also fell dramatically. Some investors, overwhelmed by fear, failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies and sold their shares at rock-bottom prices, missing out on substantial returns from subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses but can also create a lasting psychological shadow, deterring them from re-entering the market and causing them to miss investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blindly-following-trends-a-fog-that-obscures-direction&#34;&gt;Blindly following trends: A &amp;ldquo;fog&amp;rdquo; that obscures direction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Blindly following the crowd is another common psychological trap for investors in stock trading and wealth management. In an era of information overload, investment advice, market rumors, and trending news abound. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment skills, blindly imitating others&amp;rsquo; actions. Seeing others profit from buying a particular stock, they rush to buy without careful consideration; hearing so-called &amp;ldquo;insider tips,&amp;rdquo; they invest everything they have. This blind following neglects the necessary research and analysis of individual stocks, leaving investors lost like ships in fog, losing their direction. For example, some concept stocks may generate short-term gains for followers initially, but as hype fades, prices plummet, turning those unaware and blindly following into &amp;ldquo;bag holders.&amp;rdquo; They fail to realize that each investor has different risk tolerance, investment goals, and time horizons; what works for others might not work for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-a-hidden-shoal&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: A Hidden &amp;ldquo;Shoal&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is a significant issue in the mindset of stock and financial investments. After experiencing initial investment successes, some investors become inflated with pride, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict price movements. They disregard the complexity and uncertainty of the market, leading to excessive trading, blindly expanding their investment scale, and even using high leverage for speculation. However, the market is unpredictable, and overconfident investors often suffer significant losses from unexpected market fluctuations. For example, inexperienced but initially successful investors may believe they possess professional investment skills and begin frequent buying and selling while continuously increasing their investments. When systemic risks or negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to stop their losses in time due to their overconfidence, resulting in substantial capital erosion. Overconfidence is like a submerged reef, appearing calm and harmless on the surface but capable of wrecking an investor&amp;rsquo;s financial ship unexpectedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-sound-financial-management&#34;&gt;How to adjust your mindset for sound financial management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish a correct investment philosophy: Investors should understand that stock trading and wealth management are for the long-term, stable growth of assets, not for getting rich quick. Through learning investment knowledge, understanding market patterns, and adopting value investing and long-term investment principles, avoid being swayed by short-term gains and market sentiment. For example, thoroughly research a company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals – its profitability, industry position, management team, etc. – to select stocks with long-term investment value, rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a sound investment plan: Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable plan. Clearly define key elements such as investment amount, timeframe, expected return, and stop-loss point, and adhere to the plan strictly. This helps avoid impulsive decisions driven by emotional fluctuations. For example, limit each stock&amp;rsquo;s allocation to a certain percentage of your total assets; take profits when prices reach your target gains, and cut losses decisively when they hit your stop-loss level.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Control your emotions and stay calm: When facing market volatility, learn to manage your emotions and remain calm and rational. Relieve investment pressure through methods like distraction, exercise, and communication. Avoid letting emotions negatively impact your investment decisions. When the market experiences significant fluctuations, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine your investment strategy with the fundamentals of the stocks, and make a rational judgment instead of blindly following trends or panicking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous learning and reflection are essential in the ever-evolving stock market. Investors must consistently acquire new knowledge and skills, stay informed about macroeconomic trends, industry developments, and company information to improve their investment capabilities. Regularly reflecting on investment behavior, summarizing lessons learned, identifying issues with mindset and decision-making, and making timely adjustments are also crucial. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze successes and failures, and consider how to avoid similar errors in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in the stock market is a long and challenging journey where mindset plays a crucial role. Maintaining rationality, composure, humility, and independent thinking are essential for navigating market volatility and achieving wealth preservation and growth. Investors should consider cultivating a positive mindset as a fundamental part of their investment process, enabling them to steer their financial future successfully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Increased scrutiny of third-party investment advisors; will those behind the TikTok stock trading scheme face repercussions?</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The sledgehammer is falling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage services, boosted by short videos, may be entering a period of rapid growth&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In late September, following a surge in A-share market performance, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s stock recommendations received widespread attention&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Several financial commentators, including &amp;ldquo;Da Lan,&amp;rdquo; gained popularity on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in the capital market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The rise of popular financial commentators is also supported by third-party investment advisory firms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using traffic strategies to attract viewers to watch their educational videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing related investment advisory products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rumors suggest that a certain third-party investment advisory firm earned 1 billion yuan in revenue this October alone, exceeding its earnings for the entire first half of the year&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But &amp;ldquo;good times&amp;rdquo; are facing more uncertainties&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since November, various departments have issued documents requiring securities service providers to strengthen compliance management of social media accounts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 15th evening, Tonghua Shun (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the securities regulatory commission for livestreaming activities involving implied stock recommendations
This could be signaling that regulators are tightening their oversight
The promotion of third-party investment advisory firms, including Nine Square Wisdom Investment (9636.HK), may face increased pressure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring&#34;&gt;Close monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin has amplified emotional expression and indirectly influenced trading behavior&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to data from Jullian Analytics, during the period of September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volume reached a new high, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, more than doubling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The actions of third-party investment advisors are attracting regulatory attention amid this situation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brokerage employees recommending individual stocks during livestreams is a frequent violation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend the acceptance of new clients from a company due to instances of &amp;ldquo;suggesting stock recommendations&amp;rdquo; during its livestream&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 14th, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued a notice titled &amp;ldquo;Inadequate Live Stream Control Results in Business Suspension,&amp;rdquo; directly pointing out that certain institutions with securities advisory qualifications had inadequate controls during live stream promotional activities, including recommending specific stocks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Live stock recommendations are prohibited. Live streaming falls under public media dissemination, and live streamers, regardless of whether they are registered securities investment advisors, are not permitted to recommend individual stocks during broadcasts. - Guangdong Securities &amp;amp; Futures Association.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a penalty notice disclosed by the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau also included one case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An investigation by regulators revealed that Wang Yong, an investment consultant at Haitun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd. Shanghai Branch, published misleading video content on WeChat Video Number, which violated professional conduct guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau took supervisory measures, issuing a warning letter to Wang Yong&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to sources, some unqualified investment advisors who were recommending stocks on Douyin (TikTok) by affiliating with brokerages have been suspended&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some individuals in the industry are doing livestreams on Douyin, operating under brokerage firms to obtain investment consultant qualifications. They then use these livestreams to attract customers and sell investment consultant product packages offline. However, they were suspended after being caught recommending specific stocks during a livestream. Reputable brokerages typically only discuss sector conditions in their educational livestreams, but avoid mentioning individual stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau has notified that some institutions or individuals within the industry have been found to be engaging in illegal stock recommendations and other violations through self-media. To further regulate the operation and management of securities investment consulting agencies&amp;rsquo; self-media within its jurisdiction, each agency should strengthen their own self-media operations management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may bring more challenges to the promotion of third-party wealth management services&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;traffic-businesses-are-illegal&#34;&gt;Traffic businesses are illegal
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether investors lured into the market by short videos have made money remains to be seen, but as &amp;ldquo;water sellers,&amp;rdquo; third-party investment advisory firms are already seeing their value rise in the secondary market&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a leading player in online investment education, Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s market capitalization has surged from 287.8 million yuan in early September to 1.2464 billion yuan as of the close on November 13th, representing a gain of 333.08% over 49 trading days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mid-year report shows that in the first half of this year, Jiufang Zhi Tou conducted brand exposure on social media platforms like Douyin and Xiaohongshu, reaching 488 accounts and 0.46 billion followers by the end of June&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; (Mr. Hong), as Chief Investment Consultant for Jiufang Zhito, has 2.26 million followers on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We focus on MCN operations, prioritizing users and collaboratively driving the comprehensive development of traffic, brand, and product. Jiu Fang Zhi Tou notes that by deeply integrating new media tools like live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we can effectively achieve efficient conversion of traffic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jiufang Zhitu&amp;rsquo;s advisory courses range in price from several thousand to over ten thousand yuan. Their most expensive package, &amp;ldquo;Super Investor,&amp;rdquo; is priced at 139,600 yuan/six months and includes exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Jiumfang Intelligence Investment&amp;rsquo;s advisory products have a refund rate exceeding 10%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for Jiu Fang Zhi Tou&amp;rsquo;s flagship series and Qinyulong series were 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether Jiufang Intelligent Investment&amp;rsquo;s business expansion will be affected remains to be seen amidst regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recent media reports indicate that accounts under third-party investment advisors like Jiufang Zhi Tou have been affected&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, media reported that &amp;ldquo;Hong Tou&amp;rdquo; was suspended from streaming&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 15th, TradeWind01 searched for the account and found that appointments for the livestream on November 18th were still available on &amp;ldquo;Hong Gangzhu&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; live broadcast page&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Market news also indicates that regulatory authorities have inspected Jufeng Intelligent Investment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sources close to Nine Square Exit confirmed to TradeWind01 (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection was a routine check and has concluded&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company recently rumored to be caught up in this round of regulatory scrutiny&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reports indicate that Tonghua Shun is under investigation for alleged illegal stock recommendations, potentially leading to a suspension of its business operations
Tonghua Shun responded on November 15th, stating that &amp;ldquo;there is no illegal stock recommendation situation and there has been no investigation.&amp;rdquo;
That evening, however, Tonghua Shun announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tonghuashun Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau with a three-month suspension of acquiring new clients due to inadequate compliance management during live streaming promotions and instances of implied stock recommendations
This may also indicate that regulatory bodies are increasing their scrutiny of stock recommendations on platforms like Douyin Live&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, short video platforms are also attracting investment firms, but their involvement is currently limited by regulatory requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A source from a securities firm told TradeWind (ID: TradeWind01) that the company is exploring short video operations and traffic acquisition methods, and has even sent personnel to learn from short video platform companies. However, due to compliance requirements, it remains in the exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, regulatory compliance requirements stem from the emotional nature of short video platform content, while investment requires a rational approach – a conflict inherent in their natures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Allowing emotions to influence the capital market can easily trigger sharp fluctuations, which is detrimental to its long-term healthy development&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How securities firms can navigate the rise of short videos while avoiding regulatory breaches remains a challenging question for all parties involved&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
