<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stock-Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stock-Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Wide Base Exponential Fixed Investment (also known as “Buy and Hold”): Brokerage ETF, Heng Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/broad-based-index-etf-investing/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/broad-based-index-etf-investing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to do things, like buying a suitable blue-chip stock and just letting it sit, waiting for it to drop so I could see the situation and not add more if it rose, but ultimately never managed to execute that. It&amp;rsquo;s much easier to find an appropriate broad market index fund – buy an ETF instead. My current plan is: a brokerage ETF and the Hong Kong Technology Index ETF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kind of trading strategy described above has a professional name: bottom-up buying during a downtrend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As for what’s next, my plan is to completely practice this by choosing a broad market index fund that can outperform the returns of regular savings accounts.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brokerage-etfs&#34;&gt;Brokerage ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A brokerage ETF is an Exchange Traded Fund (ETF) whose primary investment target is Chinese securities companies. It primarily invests in the listed stocks of Chinese securities companies in the stock market. Brokerage ETFs typically track a specific brokerage company index, such as the China Securities Brokerage Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously bought one, but it was at a peak and ultimately resulted in losses, so I liquidated my position. In the Chinese market, whenever there’s a bull run, brokerage companies are bound to rise – and by how much, depends on investor sentiment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-tech-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is an equity index launched by the Hong Kong Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology industry in Hong Kong markets. The index includes major technology companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering areas such as internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituents of the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) and their weightings are listed below (data sourced from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tencent Holdings&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00700.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00700.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09988.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09988.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JD Group-SW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09618.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09618.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kuaishou-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01024.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01024.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 6.10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Li Auto-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://02015.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;02015.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 6.09%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMIC (Semiconductor Manufacturing International Corporation)&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00981.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00981.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetEase-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09999.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09999.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ctrip Group-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09961.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09961.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 4.48%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Total Weighting:&lt;/strong&gt; Approximately 66.6% (Some sources show the top ten weighting between 68%-69%, due to differences in statistical timing.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-notes&#34;&gt;Key Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Cap Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt; The Hang Seng Tech Index sets an 8% weight limit for individual stocks. For example, before the adjustment on March 2025, SMIC’s weighting exceeded 8%, but was subsequently passively reduced to comply with the limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constituent Stock Adjustments:&lt;/strong&gt; On May 16, 2025, the Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01211.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01211.HK&lt;/a&gt; ) will be included in the index and that Ruyi Group (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00772.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00772.HK&lt;/a&gt;) will be excluded. The adjustment will take effect on June 6th. Therefore, the current (May 20th) constituent stocks are based on the pre-adjustment list, and BYD has not yet been included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry Distribution:&lt;/strong&gt; Among the top ten constituent stocks, internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, Meituan) dominate, with new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Ideal) and semiconductors (SMIC) having significant weights, reflecting the index’s coverage of technology and the new economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Data Timeliness:&lt;/strong&gt; Differences in data from different sources are mainly due to differences in statistical timing points. For example, the data shown in March 2025 shows that the top ten combined accounted for approximately 69.4%, while the data on May 14th was 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on weights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-put-cover&#34;&gt;Short Put Cover
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“Short Put Cover” is an investment strategy that refers to a trader’s proactive buying of stocks in a declining price trend, anticipating the stock price approaching its bottom and aiming to reduce their average cost per share. This approach falls under “short-side trading,” which involves taking opposing positions before the market has clearly established a bottom. Specifically, investors often employ a “pyramiding” or “tiered accumulation” strategy, gradually increasing their purchase volume as the stock price declines, thereby reducing their average cost basis. For example, initially buying a certain number of shares, if the price continues to fall, the investor increases the purchase volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; By purchasing in batches during a downtrend, the average cost per share is reduced, creating conditions for future profits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Early Positioning:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing positions before the market reverses can yield larger gains when the market rebounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; If the stock price continues to fall, it could lead to greater losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Tie-Up:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires sufficient capital to support continued covering and may face situations where funds are long-term locked up.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to “long-side trading,” which involves buying after the market trend is clear and there are signs of a price rebound, the short-side strategy carries lower risk but may miss out on some initial gains during a rally. Therefore, investors should choose a suitable trading strategy based on their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation Theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance that aims to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies, providing a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and develop appropriate investment strategies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Valuation Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method is based on the cash flows expected to be generated by an asset over its future period and discounts these cash flows to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes intrinsic value and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable earnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relative Valuation Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method assesses a company’s relative value by comparing it to other companies in the same industry based on valuation metrics such as Price-to-Earnings (P/E) ratio, Price-to-Book (P/B) ratio, and Price-to-Sales (P/S) ratio. The relative valuation method is straightforward and widely used for quick assessments and industry comparisons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset-Based Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method determines a company’s value by evaluating its net asset value – the total assets minus liabilities. The asset-based method is suitable for asset-oriented companies, such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Applications of Valuation Theory:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Decisions:&lt;/strong&gt; Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and develop buy or sell strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions (M&amp;amp;A):&lt;/strong&gt; In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influences the success or failure of the deal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies need to assess the fair value of their assets and liabilities to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial statements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s important to note that valuation results are influenced by various factors, including market conditions, company operations, and macroeconomic indicators. Therefore, when conducting a valuation, it is necessary to consider these factors in combination with both qualitative and quantitative analysis to achieve more accurate assessments.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and even if you’re anxious, it won’t help.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs. My ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Write an article: Addressing the mental issues in stock trading finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the initial entry into the market, I encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, I focused on blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hong Kong Electronics, ZTESC, and various large-stock index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Expected annualized returns were touted as matching a bank’s three-year fixed deposit,” but in reality, there was greed wanting more, leading to hasty increases from the beginning, followed by depletion of cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represented significant outflows of capital, resulting in insufficient liquidity overall, causing problems later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in blue chips is like aligning with “old money”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Evergrande faced issues, bank stocks plummeted dramatically, successfully capitalizing on the washout phase. This reflects a lack of understanding regarding the economic impact of real estate, which accounts for a significant portion of China’s economy, and it was impossible to “force a landing.” The subsequent sustained decline in the stock market saw blue-chip stocks like Industrial Bank continue to rise for about two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of trade wars, ZTESC suffered severe damage, with its stock price also falling sharply. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hong Kong Electronics, a long-standing company, experienced a significant drop in its stock price after Ant Financial’s departure, but this stock was manipulated by a major shareholder, allowing it to surge upwards several times per year. With reasonable position sizing, losses could be minimized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-that-devours-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The &amp;ldquo;Monster&amp;rdquo; That Devours Reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Greed is the most common problem in a stock trading mindset. When stock prices rise steadily, and investors’ account profits continuously increase, greed quietly takes root. Many people still fantasize about continued price increases even when stocks are already at high levels, craving more gains and unwilling to cut their profits. They are blinded by greed, forgetting the laws of the market and the existence of risk. For example, during the hype of certain hot-themed stocks, some investors see prices double or even multiply within a short period, falling into it, constantly adding to their positions, hoping to be the last winner. However, the market will not always go crazy; when the bubble bursts and stock prices plummet sharply, these investors driven by greed often suffer heavy losses. Greed causes them to lose their ability to rationally analyze and make decisions, turning them into &amp;ldquo;gamblers&amp;rdquo; in the stock market rather than wise investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-the-chain-that-restricts&#34;&gt;Fear: The “Chain” That Restricts
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the counterpart to greed. It possesses a powerful destructive force in the stock market as well. When market conditions suddenly plummet and stock prices fall sharply, investors are prone to panic. This fear erodes their confidence in the market, even when the fundamentals of their holdings are sound, leading them to hastily sell off their shares out of a fear of further losses. For example, during periods of global financial crises, even high-quality blue-chip stocks saw significant declines alongside the broader market. Some investors were consumed by fear and failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies, selling their stock at extremely low prices and missing out on substantial returns from subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses for investors but can also create a lasting psychological shadow over the stock market, making them hesitant to re-enter, thus losing out on investment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blind-following-losing-direction-in-the-fog&#34;&gt;Blind Following: Losing Direction in the &amp;ldquo;Fog&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In stock trading and wealth management, blindly following trends is another psychological pitfall that investors easily fall into. In an era of information explosion, various investment suggestions, market rumors, and hot topics are rampant. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment abilities, blindly following others&amp;rsquo; operations. When they see their peers making money by buying a particular stock, they immediately follow suit without further thought; when they hear so-called &amp;ldquo;insider news,&amp;rdquo; they readily share it. This blind following behavior ignores the research and analysis of the underlying stocks, causing investors to be like lost ships in the fog, losing their own direction. For example, some concept stocks can indeed generate short-term profits for followers during market hype. However, as the hype fades and stock prices plummet, those who are unaware and blindly follow will become &amp;ldquo;cash absorbers.&amp;rdquo; They didn&amp;rsquo;t realize that everyone’s risk tolerance, investment goals, and investment horizons are different, and a strategy suitable for others may not be suitable for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-the-hidden-shallow&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: The Hidden &amp;ldquo;Shallow&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is also a significant issue in the investment and financial mindset. Some investors, after achieving several successful investments, begin to inflate their egos, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict stock movements. They ignore the complexity and uncertainty of the market, engage in excessive trading, blindly expand their investment scale, and even use high leverage for speculation. However, the market is ever-changing, and overconfident investors often suffer severe setbacks in a single unexpected market fluctuation. For example, some investors with limited experience who achieved an initial victory believe they possess professional investment capabilities and begin to frequently buy and sell stocks, constantly increasing their investment amount. When systemic risks or sudden negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to cut their losses promptly due to overconfidence, leading to a significant reduction in their principal capital. Overconfidence is like hidden reefs beneath the surface of the water – seemingly peaceful and harmless, but can unexpectedly cause an investor&amp;rsquo;s wealth vessel to run aground.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-stable-financial-planning&#34;&gt;How to Adjust Your Mindset for Stable Financial Planning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establish the Right Investment Philosophy:&lt;/strong&gt; Investors should clearly understand that stock investing and wealth management are about achieving long-term, stable asset appreciation, not overnight riches. By learning investment knowledge, understanding market patterns, adopting value investing and long-term investment philosophies, and avoiding being swayed by short-term gains and market sentiment, you can make more informed decisions. For example, thoroughly research a company’s fundamentals, paying attention to its profitability, industry position, management team, and other relevant factors, choosing stocks with long-term investment potential rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Develop a Reasonable Investment Plan:&lt;/strong&gt; Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable investment plan. Clearly define key elements such as investment amount, investment period, expected returns, and stop-loss points, and strictly execute the plan. This prevents impulsive decisions driven by emotional fluctuations during investing. For example, set the investment proportion of each stock to no more than a certain percentage of your total assets, and promptly take profits when the price rises to your expected return, and decisively cut losses when it falls to your stop-loss point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Control Your Emotions and Stay Calm:&lt;/strong&gt; When facing market volatility, learn to control your emotions and maintain calmness and rationality. You can relieve investment pressure through methods such as diverting attention, engaging in physical exercise, or communicating with others, avoiding negative impacts of emotions on investment decisions. When the market experiences significant fluctuations, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine your investment strategy and stock fundamentals, and make rational judgments instead of blindly following trends or panic selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continue Learning and Reflecting:&lt;/strong&gt; The stock market is constantly evolving, so investors need to continuously learn new investment knowledge and skills, pay attention to macroeconomic conditions, industry dynamics, and company information, and constantly improve their investment level. At the same time, regularly reflect on your investment behavior, summarize experiences and lessons, identify problems in your mindset and decision-making, and promptly adjust and improve them. For example, after each investment, review the entire investment process, analyze the reasons for success and failure, and think about how to avoid similar mistakes in future investments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealth management is a long and challenging journey, and mindset plays a crucial role. Only by maintaining rational, calm, humble, and independent thinking can you steadily advance in the stock market’s waves and achieve wealth preservation and appreciation. Investors should consider cultivating their mindset as an essential course in the investment process, using a good mindset to steer the ship of wealth, and moving forward steadily on the path of stock investing and wealth management.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Increased scrutiny of third-party advisor regulation, and the beneficiaries behind the ‘Douyin (TikTok) stock trading’ phenomenon face a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following the surge of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In late September, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, Douyin (TikTok) recommendations for stocks garnered attention from various parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous financial commentators have risen to prominence on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behind these rapidly rising financial commentators lies a significant force: third-party investment advisory service companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s understood that many third-party advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (投流) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are even rumors that one third-party advisory firm achieved revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, “good times” are facing more uncertainties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since November, multiple departments have issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliance management of self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On November 15th, Futu Securities (300033.SZ) announced that a subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in suggestive stock recommendations through livestreaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be signaling a stricter regulatory environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The expansion of third-party investment advisory service firms like Fangyuan Intelligence Investment (9636.HK) is likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring-by-regulators&#34;&gt;Close Monitoring by Regulators
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant Network, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the “stirring up” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulatory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment advisors recommending stocks through live broadcasts constitutes a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took measures to suspend new clients for a company’s livestreaming that presented “implicit stock recommendations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14th evening, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued an announcement titled &amp;ldquo;Live Streaming Control Lacking Effectiveness, Institutions Suspended Business,&amp;rdquo; directly addressing situations where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate controls during live streaming operations and engaged in recommending stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association stated: “Strictly prohibit livestreaming stock recommendations. Livestreaming is a public media dissemination platform, and livestreaming personnel, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, shall not recommend stocks during live broadcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau disclosed a penalty notice involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated professional norms by publishing misleading videos through WeChat Video No., which contradicted industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau subsequently issued a supervisory management measure to issue a warning letter to Wang Yong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wind (ID:TradeWind01) information, some unqualified investment advisory firms have been using “rented” brokerage accounts to promote stocks on Douyin and have since been suspended from broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people are livestreaming in the industry, but they are actually renting under a brokerage firm, which gives them investment advisor qualifications, then they use live streaming to generate leads, and sell investment advisory product bundles offline,” said a consultant from South China to Wind (ID:TradeWind01). “However, because they recommended stocks during the livestreaming, they were discovered and subsequently suspended.” Regular brokerages typically discuss sector trends but do not involve individual stock recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that some institutions or individuals were using self-media to illegally recommend stocks, in order to further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies in the辖区, all institutions should further strengthen company self-media operation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for the business development of various third-party investment advisory service firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors who were attracted by short videos made a profit remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “China’s first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence’s market capitalization rose from 2.878 billion yuan at the beginning of September to 12.464 billion yuan on November 13, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report showed that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by the end of June, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhuxi” has 2.26 million fans on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on users, and synergistically promote the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products,” JiuFang Intelligence stated. “By deeply integrating live streaming, short videos, and other new media tools, leveraging AI technology to build a fan network, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory course packages cover price ranges from tens of yuan to more than ten万元. The most expensive package, “Super Investor,” is priced at 139,600 yuan per six months, including exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory product refund rate is above 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for JiuFang Intelligence’s flagship series and JiuFang Intelligence’s Qionglong Series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, under regulatory scrutiny, whether JiuFang Intelligence&amp;rsquo;s business development will be affected remains to be further observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports said that accounts belonging to third-party investment advisory companies such as JiuFang Intelligence have been impacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a media report stated that “Hongbangzhuxi” was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th, XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the appointment for “Hongbangzhuxi’s” livestream on November 18th was still available in the livestream interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market sources said that relevant departments have entered JiuFang Intelligence for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a close source to JiuFang Intelligence told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection belonged to routine inspections and had already ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company involved in this round of regulatory storm rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities was investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may suspend business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th, “There were no illegal stock recommendation cases, and there was no investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that same evening, Tianhong Securities announced that its subsidiary Zhejiang Tianhong Cloud Software Co., Ltd. was penalized with a three-month new customer suspension due to inadequate compliance controls in the promotion of livestreaming business and the existence of scenarios suggesting recommendations of stocks, by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also mean that regulatory departments are further focusing on荐股 (recommendation of stocks) content on social media platforms such as Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the cake of short videos has also attracted many securities firms, but due to compliance requirements, securities firms are currently cautious about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the company is exploring methods for short video operations and lead generation, and it has organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning, but due to compliance requirements, it is still in an exploratory stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements is because the content on short video platforms has a distinct emotional color, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality, and the two exist in a natural conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If uncontrolled emotions influence the capital market, it can easily trigger violent fluctuations in the market, which goes against the long-term healthy development of the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What manner should securities holding institutions embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “stepping on red lines”? This is clearly a difficult question for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
