<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stock Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stock Trading on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 18:23:27 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-trading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Why the concept of “settlement” is necessary in traditional stock trading?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/why-the-concept-of-settlement-is-necessary-in-traditional-stock-trading/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:18:46 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/why-the-concept-of-settlement-is-necessary-in-traditional-stock-trading/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s era of the global digital wave, we&amp;rsquo;ve become accustomed to instant transfers and near-instant payments. Therefore, many people are confused: why, after clicking “sell” on a stock, does my funds not immediately clear in full and become available, but instead takes one or two business days? This is precisely a crucial and historically significant concept within traditional stock trading – &lt;strong&gt;settlement&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;prompt: Why does traditional stock trading require the concept of settlement?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Trading” and “Settlement” are two separate steps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; This refers to the moment you place a buy or sell order on an exchange that is successfully matched. At this point, you and your counterparty have reached a legally binding contract committing to exchanging stocks and funds at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Settlement:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the process of fulfilling the terms of the agreed-upon contract – namely, the ownership of the stock officially and irrevocably transfers from seller to buyer, while the funds are officially and irrevocably transferred from the buyer’s account to the seller’s.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The need for these two separate steps and a time lag (such as T+1, T+2 systems) stems from historical evolution and rigorous risk management in finance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-roots-originating-in-the-paper-era&#34;&gt;Historical Roots: Originating in the “Paper” Era
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Prior to the widespread adoption of computer systems, stocks were tangible &lt;strong&gt;paper certificates&lt;/strong&gt;. Following a trade executed orally or through gestures at an exchange, subsequent work was incredibly laborious:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Physical Transportation:&lt;/strong&gt; The seller’s brokerage firm needed to retrieve the corresponding stock certificate from its vault.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Endorsement Transfer:&lt;/strong&gt; Signing and endorsing the back of the certificate to verify ownership transfer.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Manual Delivery:&lt;/strong&gt; These certificates and associated checks had to be delivered by personnel (couriers) throughout the city to the buyer&amp;rsquo;s brokerage firm.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Verification &amp;amp; Reconciliation:&lt;/strong&gt; The buyer’s brokerage firm needed to verify the authenticity of the certificates and the accuracy of the transaction details.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The entire process involved a significant amount of manual labor and physical transfer, riddled with delays and uncertainty. Consequently, an settlement cycle of several days (initially as long as T+5) was established to complete these complex processes. In the late 1960s, Wall Street was plunged into a “Paperwork Crisis” due to a surge in trading volume; a large number of trades could not be completed on time, even forcing exchanges to shorten trading hours. This directly spurred the establishment of modern electronic clearing systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;modern-core-an-unreplaceable-risk-management&#34;&gt;Modern Core: An Unreplaceable Risk Management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Despite all transactions being electronic today, the T+N settlement system remains in place because its core function has evolved from “waiting for logistics” to &lt;strong&gt;managing the massive risks of the financial system&lt;/strong&gt;. This process is primarily carried out by a key player – &lt;strong&gt;Central Counterparty (CCP) Clearinghouses&lt;/strong&gt;, such as the Depository Trust &amp;amp; Clearing Corporation (DTCC) and the China Securities Depository and Clearing Corporation (CSDC) in the United States and China, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The settlement system is mainly designed to mitigate the following core risks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;counterparty-risk&#34;&gt;Counterparty Risk
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is the most fundamental risk. If you sell shares, how can you be 100% certain that the buyer will pay on time? Conversely, how can the buyer be 100% certain that the seller will deliver genuine shares? If either party defaults, it could trigger a chain reaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; The intervention of a Central Counterparty (CCP).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After a trade occurs, the CCP steps in between the buyer and seller, &lt;strong&gt;acting as both the seller’s “buyer” and the buyer’s “seller.”&lt;/strong&gt; Through this legal arrangement called “novation,” the original buyer-seller relationship is no longer direct; instead, each party is responsible to the CCP.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Seller:&lt;/strong&gt; As long as shares are delivered to the CCP, they will definitely receive money from the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the Buyer:&lt;/strong&gt; As long as money is delivered to the CCP, they will definitely receive shares from the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this way, the default risk of a single participant is absorbed by the highly creditworthy central institution – the CCP – and does not spread throughout the market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;clearing--netting&#34;&gt;Clearing &amp;amp; Netting
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;A large brokerage firm handles millions of transactions in a single day, involving both buying and selling. If each transaction were processed individually, the system would be overwhelmed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Solution:&lt;/strong&gt; “Clearing” is performed before settlement date.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the trading day (T-day), clearing agencies consolidate all buy and sell transactions for each broker, known as &lt;strong&gt;“netting” or “clearing &amp;amp; netting.”&lt;/strong&gt; For example, a brokerage firm might have bought $10 billion worth of stock and sold $9.8 billion on a given day. On settlement day, it only needs to pay a net difference of $20 million in cash, rather than engaging in a $19.8 billion exchange. Similarly, securities settlements are also processed on a net basis. This significantly improves the efficiency of the entire market and reduces liquidity requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-complete-lifecycle-of-a-stock-transaction&#34;&gt;The Complete Lifecycle of a Stock Transaction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s take a simple example to see the entire process from trade to settlement (using a T+2 model):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T Day (Trading Day):&lt;/strong&gt; You click “Buy” 100 shares of a company&amp;rsquo;s stock in the morning and it immediately executes. At this point, you reach an agreement with the seller, but &lt;strong&gt;ownership of the stock and funds has not yet transferred.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T Day Aftermarket ~ T+1 Day (Clearing Period):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exchange sends your trade data to the Central Clearing Corporation (CCP).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP confirms the transaction information is accurate and performs a “contract swap,” becoming your counterparty for the trade.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP calculates the net amount of all your trades on that day through your brokerage firm, and notifies your broker how much money and securities you need to deliver by T+2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;T+2 Day (Settlement Day):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In the morning, your broker transfers the net settlement funds to the CCP.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The CCP confirms receipt of the funds and instructs the Securities Custody Agency to transfer 100 shares of stock from the seller’s brokerage account to your brokerage account.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your broker updates your account information internally, showing that you now hold these 100 shares of stock.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, settlement is complete, and you officially become the legal owner of these 100 shares of stock, with the right to receive dividends, participate in voting, etc.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, the traditional concept of “settlement” in stock trading is a product of historical practice combined with modern risk control theory. It evolved from a mechanism to solve the problem of paper-based certificate circulation into a core system that uses a central counterparty and net settlement to ensure the stability and efficiency of the entire financial market. This seemingly &amp;ldquo;delayed&amp;rdquo; design is actually the key firewall protecting every investor from counterparty default risks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and getting anxious won’t help either.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs, and my ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; and if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from when I first entered the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my focus shifted to blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hisense Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in blue chips is like aligning with “old money”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Evergrande’s problems arose, bank stocks plummeted alongside it, successfully identifying the exit point. This reflected a lack of understanding regarding the broader economic market; real estate accounted for too much of China&amp;rsquo;s economy, and the implications were too extensive to simply “land” – the subsequent continued decline in the stock market saw blue-chip stocks like Industrial Bank continue to rise for about two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, ZTESC suffered a severe blow, with its share price also falling dramatically. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hisense Electronics is an old veteran; after Ant Financial withdrew, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock had a controlling shareholder manipulating it, and it could surge several times each year. With reasonable position sizing, you wouldn’t lose much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bond-investment&#34;&gt;Bond Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say it was a lucky outcome, essentially benefiting from falling interest rates. There were changes at my job in Hangzhou, leading me to abandon the idea of buying a house and liquidate my existing bank term deposits. I then focused on reinvesting previously held bonds, significantly increasing my bond investment ratio. Fortunately, interest rates have been declining for several years, allowing me to capitalize on the “bull market” in bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my six months back in Hangzhou, I had plenty of time to reflect and gain clarity. Real estate isn’t a necessity, nor is staying in a particular location – my ability to handle stress was thus improved. If I were to lose my job, the mortgage would be like a mountain to climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-return-expectations&#34;&gt;Investment Return Expectations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The expected annualized oral commitment is comparable to a three-year fixed bank deposit,” but in reality, it’s greedy and wants more. From the initial frantic increase (adding positions), to later exhausting cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represent significant outflows of capital, and overall, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough capital flow left over, leading to insufficient funds later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subsequent plan is to long-term hold &lt;strong&gt;brokerage ETFs&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index&lt;/strong&gt;, with an asset allocation that still includes insurance as a base, medium-to-long term bonds, and stock funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Increased scrutiny of third-party advisor regulation, and the beneficiaries behind the ‘Douyin (TikTok) stock trading’ phenomenon face a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Following the surge of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In late September, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, Douyin (TikTok) recommendations for stocks garnered attention from various parties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Numerous financial commentators have risen to prominence on Douyin, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Behind these rapidly rising financial commentators lies a significant force: third-party investment advisory service companies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s understood that many third-party advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (投流) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There are even rumors that one third-party advisory firm achieved revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, “good times” are facing more uncertainties.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Since November, multiple departments have issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliance management of self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On November 15th, Futu Securities (300033.SZ) announced that a subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in suggestive stock recommendations through livestreaming.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This may be signaling a stricter regulatory environment.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The expansion of third-party investment advisory service firms like Fangyuan Intelligence Investment (9636.HK) is likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;close-monitoring-by-regulators&#34;&gt;Close Monitoring by Regulators
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant Network, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice that amount.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under these circumstances, the “stirring up” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulatory authorities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investment advisors recommending stocks through live broadcasts constitutes a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took measures to suspend new clients for a company’s livestreaming that presented “implicit stock recommendations.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 14th evening, the Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association issued an announcement titled &amp;ldquo;Live Streaming Control Lacking Effectiveness, Institutions Suspended Business,&amp;rdquo; directly addressing situations where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications had inadequate controls during live streaming operations and engaged in recommending stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Guangdong Securities and Futures Industry Association stated: “Strictly prohibit livestreaming stock recommendations. Livestreaming is a public media dissemination platform, and livestreaming personnel, regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors, shall not recommend stocks during live broadcasts.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated case.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau disclosed a penalty notice involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated professional norms by publishing misleading videos through WeChat Video No., which contradicted industry standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Shanghai Securities Regulatory Bureau subsequently issued a supervisory management measure to issue a warning letter to Wang Yong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Wind (ID:TradeWind01) information, some unqualified investment advisory firms have been using “rented” brokerage accounts to promote stocks on Douyin and have since been suspended from broadcasting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Some people are livestreaming in the industry, but they are actually renting under a brokerage firm, which gives them investment advisor qualifications, then they use live streaming to generate leads, and sell investment advisory product bundles offline,” said a consultant from South China to Wind (ID:TradeWind01). “However, because they recommended stocks during the livestreaming, they were discovered and subsequently suspended.” Regular brokerages typically discuss sector trends but do not involve individual stock recommendations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are closely monitoring illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Bureau recently notified that some institutions or individuals were using self-media to illegally recommend stocks, in order to further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies in the辖区, all institutions should further strengthen company self-media operation management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for the business development of various third-party investment advisory service firms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors who were attracted by short videos made a profit remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As “China’s first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence’s market capitalization rose from 2.878 billion yuan at the beginning of September to 12.464 billion yuan on November 13, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report showed that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by the end of June, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhuxi” has 2.26 million fans on Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on users, and synergistically promote the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products,” JiuFang Intelligence stated. “By deeply integrating live streaming, short videos, and other new media tools, leveraging AI technology to build a fan network, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory course packages cover price ranges from tens of yuan to more than ten万元. The most expensive package, “Super Investor,” is priced at 139,600 yuan per six months, including exclusive insights and private advisor services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, JiuFang Intelligence’s investment advisory product refund rate is above 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the refund rates for JiuFang Intelligence’s flagship series and JiuFang Intelligence’s Qionglong Series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, under regulatory scrutiny, whether JiuFang Intelligence&amp;rsquo;s business development will be affected remains to be further observed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports said that accounts belonging to third-party investment advisory companies such as JiuFang Intelligence have been impacted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a media report stated that “Hongbangzhuxi” was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th, XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the appointment for “Hongbangzhuxi’s” livestream on November 18th was still available in the livestream interface.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market sources said that relevant departments have entered JiuFang Intelligence for inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a close source to JiuFang Intelligence told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the inspection belonged to routine inspections and had already ended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company involved in this round of regulatory storm rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities was investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may suspend business.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th, “There were no illegal stock recommendation cases, and there was no investigation.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, that same evening, Tianhong Securities announced that its subsidiary Zhejiang Tianhong Cloud Software Co., Ltd. was penalized with a three-month new customer suspension due to inadequate compliance controls in the promotion of livestreaming business and the existence of scenarios suggesting recommendations of stocks, by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also mean that regulatory departments are further focusing on荐股 (recommendation of stocks) content on social media platforms such as Douyin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the cake of short videos has also attracted many securities firms, but due to compliance requirements, securities firms are currently cautious about this.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told XinFeng (ID:TradeWind01) that the company is exploring methods for short video operations and lead generation, and it has organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning, but due to compliance requirements, it is still in an exploratory stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements is because the content on short video platforms has a distinct emotional color, but investment requires market participants to maintain rationality, and the two exist in a natural conflict.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If uncontrolled emotions influence the capital market, it can easily trigger violent fluctuations in the market, which goes against the long-term healthy development of the capital market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What manner should securities holding institutions embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “stepping on red lines”? This is clearly a difficult question for all parties.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
