<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Centos on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/centos/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Centos on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/centos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>CentOS 8 Stream EOL</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 23:24:50 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/centos-8-stream-eol/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;CentOS Stream&lt;/code&gt; is the upstream open-source development platform prior to Red Hat’s &lt;code&gt;Linux&lt;/code&gt; distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first noticed the open-source operating system lifecycle &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/&#34; &gt;redhat and centos life cycle&lt;/a&gt; had ended, and I was wondering what was going on? Besides security issues, dnf wasn’t working, and I recently encountered failures when installing tools – checking the repository sources revealed that &lt;code&gt;CentOS 8 Stream&lt;/code&gt; had reached its end of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;centos-stream-introduction&#34;&gt;CentOS Stream Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;positioning-and-roles&#34;&gt;Positioning and Roles
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream sits between Fedora Linux (upstream development) and RHEL (Red Hat Enterprise Linux, downstream development), acting as a bridge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It can be considered a version for experiencing the latest Red Hat-based Linux features, suitable for those who want to try out new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;origins-and-background&#34;&gt;Origins and Background
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Over time, Red Hat began to seek more effective ways to develop its enterprise-grade Linux platform, leading to the launch of CentOS Stream.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS 8 ended maintenance at the end of 2021, and CentOS Stream continued to be updated as its successor, becoming the future direction of the CentOS project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;features-and-advantages&#34;&gt;Features and Advantages
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is a rolling release Linux distribution that provides faster updates. It offers greater transparency and more opportunities for community, partner, and customer participation, allowing users to contribute to Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) more quickly and directly.
The content of CentOS Stream is software that Red Hat intends to include in the next stable version of RHEL, therefore it provides a stable ABI/API for developers and testers within the community.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;use-cases-and-target-users&#34;&gt;Use Cases and Target Users
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;CentOS Stream is suitable for those CentOS users who want to continue receiving the latest Linux feature updates, as well as developers and partners who wish to participate in Red Hat Enterprise Linux development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also aims to help community members, Red Hat partners, and others fully leverage innovative open-source software in a more stable and predictable Linux ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-of-lifehttpsendoflifedatecentos-stream&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://endoflife.date/centos-stream&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;End of Life&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Active Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Security Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;3 years ago (15 Sep 2021)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ends in 2 years and 6 months (31 May 2027)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;end-of-lifehttpsendoflifedatecentos-stream-1&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://endoflife.date/centos-stream&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;End of Life&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Release&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Released&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Active Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Security Support&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5 years ago (24 Sep 2019)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Ended 5 months and 3 weeks ago (31 May 2024)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;8&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;solutions&#34;&gt;Solutions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rather than bothering with upgrades, we opted for the long-term support version of &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu 24.04&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>docker-two-three-things</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/docker-two-three-things/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2021 09:26:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/docker-two-three-things/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Having worked with CentOS for many years, content may not apply to macOS or Ubuntu users in some cases.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can refer to the documentation from Tsinghua University for installation guidance: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://mirrors.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/help/docker-ce/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://mirrors.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/help/docker-ce/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation&#34;&gt;Installation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to unknown mysterious forces, domestic Docker installation is recommended to set the cloud vendor&amp;rsquo;s repository address. Here we recommend using &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;set-repository-source-address&#34;&gt;Set Repository Source Address
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;deploy-the-latest-version&#34;&gt;Deploy the Latest Version
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Docker is a commonly used background service, recommended to be set as startup on boot. The current command applies to CentOS 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;deploying-a-specific-version&#34;&gt;Deploying a Specific Version
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The releases of &lt;code&gt;kubernetes&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt; are not fully synchronized. If you need to deploy &lt;code&gt;kubernetes&lt;/code&gt; subsequently, please refer to the &lt;code&gt;kubernetes&lt;/code&gt; deployment instructions and install a specific version of &lt;code&gt;docker&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;add-docker-permissions-for-regular-users&#34;&gt;Add Docker Permissions for Regular Users
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;uninstall&#34;&gt;Uninstall
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;everyday-use&#34;&gt;Everyday Use
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;mirror-acceleration&#34;&gt;Mirror Acceleration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s still an unknown mysterious force causing slow image pulls. At this time, domestic cloud vendors have emerged and provided many acceleration services, which are still recommended – &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba Cloud&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can manage your own registered Alibaba Cloud account to obtain this service, which is free. Alibaba Cloud also offers a free image build service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;recommended-dashboards&#34;&gt;Recommended Dashboards
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;common-mirror-image-collection&#34;&gt;Common Mirror Image Collection
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;common-command-combinations&#34;&gt;Common Command Combinations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/docker/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://docs.docker.com/engine/reference/commandline/docker/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;View container running status, append the &lt;code&gt;format&lt;/code&gt; parameter to view detailed container information, without focusing on image information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stop all containers with one click
Delete all images with one click&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Export Image
Export Image and Compress
Import Image&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Red Hat and CentOS Lifecycle</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 20:02:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/redhat-centos-lifecycle/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Production environment operating systems, with Red Hat and CentOS being the mainstream choices. The documentation includes links to two system lifecycles and shares experience upgrading from CentOS 8 to CentOS Stream 8.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the current domestic environment, Red Hat and CentOS are the mainstream choices for production online operating systems. After experiencing the retirement of Red Hat 6 two years ago, this record specifically documents the official website links for the lifecycles of these two systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;main-content&#34;&gt;Main Content
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://access.redhat.com/support/policy/updates/errata&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Red Hat Enterprise Linux Life Cycle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wiki.centos.org/zh/About/Product&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;CentOS Product Specifications&lt;/a&gt;
Red Hat Enterprise Linux (RHEL) and CentOS are the mainstream choices for enterprise servers. RHEL provides stable support and update cycles, suitable for enterprise applications. CentOS as RHEL&amp;rsquo;s community edition, offers similar features and stability but without official support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;follow-up&#34;&gt;Follow-up
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When publishing this article, I didn’t expect to update it two years later. Just a few days ago, I upgraded my daily virtual machine from CentOS 8 to CentOS 8 Stream. I can&amp;rsquo;t say much about what to choose in production – I prefer to keep the latest version in my local environment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CentOS 8 Stream is a rolling release version that offers faster updates and new features than traditional CentOS, making it suitable for development and testing environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
