<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Anti-Corruption on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/anti-corruption/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Anti-Corruption on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/anti-corruption/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Prelude to Financial Anti-Corruption</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Committee of the Communist Party of China: will intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, and thoroughly rectify “the four prevailing tendencies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chinese-communist-party-politburo&#34;&gt;Chinese Communist Party Politburo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Political Bureau of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China held a meeting on September 27th, reviewing the “Comprehensive Report on the Situation of the First Round of Inspection of the Twelfth Collective Congress.” Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Communist Party of China, chaired the meeting. The meeting emphasized that the inspection and oversight work should be used as an opportunity to further strengthen the leadership of the Communist Party of China, encourage inspected party organizations to raise their political stance, conscientiously fulfill the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Central Committee, continuously enhance the core functions and competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the important material and political foundations of socialism with Chinese characteristics, intensify the financial sector’s service to the real economy and national strategies, and promote high-quality development. It was stressed that development and security should be coordinated, a bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking approach should be adopted, and effective measures should be taken to prevent and mitigate major risks, firmly safeguard the safety red line. To further advance the comprehensive and strict Party self-discipline towards greater depths, we must consolidate and strengthen the responsibility of Party Committee Secretaries as the primary persons in charge, the “dual-tasks” responsibility of leading members of the Party’s Leading Groups, and the supervisory responsibilities of disciplinary and inspection organizations. We must highlight strengthening oversight of all levels of “principals,” intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, thoroughly rectify “four prevailing styles,” deepen reform and governance based on cases, promote corruption prevention, elimination, and aversion, and advance the integrated promotion of daring to be corrupt, not being corrupt, and not wanting to be corrupt. We must earnestly implement the Party’s organizational guidelines in the New Era, strengthen leading group construction, personnel talent team building, and grassroots Party organization building. We must comprehensively utilize the results of oversight, deepen reform and improve systems, promote source governance, and facilitate targeted and comprehensive solutions. (Xinhua)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Created Major Financial Risks! Former Chairman of China Bank, Liu Liange, has been expelled from the Communist Party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;communist-party-of-china-central-politburo&#34;&gt;Communist Party of China Central Politburo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection of China, with approval from the Communist Party of China Central Committee, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection of China has initiated an investigation into the serious disciplinary and illegal conduct of Liu Liange, former Secretary of the Disciplinary Committee of the People’s Bank of China and Chairman. - Following investigation, Liu Liange abandoned his ideals and beliefs, betrayed his original aspirations and mission, lacked determination and integrity in implementing the Central Committee’s decision-making and deployment, compromised on key issues, and recklessly interfered with credit projects, illegally disbursed loans, causing significant financial risks. He failed to fulfill his responsibilities as a leading body for strict Party discipline, seriously disrupted the political ecology of his unit, privately brought prohibited materials into the country; deliberately resisted organizational review; ignored the spirit of the Central Committee’s Eight-Point Regulation by accepting gifts and presents, entering private clubs, and receiving skiing and tourism arrangements; long-term use of management objects&amp;rsquo; vehicles; failed to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, did not truthfully explain issues when questioned by the organization, shielded unqualified personnel in recruitment and promotion; engaged in illegal commercial activities; illegally interfered with capital lending, privately retained confidential materials; corrupted morals, improper family ethics, neglected supervision and education of relatives; lacked ideological bottom line and abused power, “eating off financial resources” by exploiting his position for personal gain in loan financing, project cooperation, and illegally obtained large sums of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;central-committee-of-the-communist-party-of-china&#34;&gt;Central Committee of the Communist Party of China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liu Liange seriously violated the Party’s disciplinary rules and regulations, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline, and lifestyle discipline, constituting a serious violation of Party discipline and involving suspected bribery, illegal loan issuance, and criminal offenses. Furthermore, after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, he did not renounce illicit gains or curb his corrupt practices, which was of severe nature, had a bad influence, and warranted serious handling. In accordance with relevant provisions of the &lt;em&gt;Disciplinary Rules of the Chinese Communist Party&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Criminal Law of the People’s Republic of China&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Administrative Procedure Law for Public Office Personnel&lt;/em&gt;, after deliberation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) convened at its plenary meeting and approval by the CPC Central Committee, a decision was made to expel Liu Liange from the Party; cancel his benefits in accordance with regulations; terminate his eligibility as a delegate to the Twenty-First National Congress of the Communist Party of China; recover his illegally obtained income; and transfer his suspected criminal issues to the Public Prosecutor’s Office for investigation and prosecution, along with related assets. - The former secretary of the Party Committee and chairman of China CITIC Group was dismissed from party membership and public office for serious violations and abuses of power (CCTV News).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission reported that, according to a statement from the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Investigation and Supervision, Li Zhi Ming, former secretary and chairman of Guizhou Bank, is suspected of seriously violating and abusing his position and is currently under disciplinary investigation and supervision by the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Investigation and Supervision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-an-eight-year-hiatus-huijin-boosts-holdings-in-the-big-four-banks&#34;&gt;After an Eight-Year Hiatus, Huijin Boosts Holdings in the Big Four Banks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, Industrial Bank, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, and Construction Bank – the four major state-owned commercial banks – respectively announced that Huijin Company had increased its holdings, totaling 276.1 million shares, 372.7 million shares, 248.9 million shares, and 183.8 million shares, respectively. Huijin Company plans to continue increasing its holdings in the Big Four Banks on the secondary market over the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
