<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mysql on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mysql/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mysql on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Linux Server, Reset MySQL Password</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/linux-server-reset-mysql-password/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 14:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/linux-server-reset-mysql-password/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had an idle Tencent Cloud server that was expiring at the end of the year and I hadn&amp;rsquo;t planned to renew it. So, I decided to deploy a MySQL database for development purposes. When reinstalling the system, I wanted to save time and chose a third-party image provided by Tencent Cloud, which already had MySQL installed. I thought the system should include a Readme file or similar documentation explaining the password and deployment path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Tencent Cloud server reinstalled very quickly, taking about a minute. Once logged in, &lt;code&gt;systemctl status mysql&lt;/code&gt; showed that the service was running. I started searching for the password but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it anywhere, and I began to panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I thought, since I had already accessed the server with root privileges, there must be a way to reset the password. I searched through documentation and found a forum post on Alibaba Cloud’s forum, continuing to tinker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reset-password&#34;&gt;Reset Password
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the configuration file &lt;code&gt;vim /etc/my.cnf&lt;/code&gt;, add the following configuration to the &lt;code&gt;mysqld&lt;/code&gt; node: &lt;code&gt;skip-grant-tables&lt;/code&gt;, and execute the command to restart the database: &lt;code&gt;systemctl restart mysql&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, log in directly to the data using &lt;code&gt;mysql&lt;/code&gt;, after which everything will proceed normally. To reset the &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user password and enable allowing remote login simultaneously:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;USE mysql;
UPDATE user SET authentication_string = password(&#39;pass&#39;) WHERE User = &#39;root&#39;;
GRANT ALL PRIVILEGES ON *.* TO &#39;root&#39;@&#39;%&#39; IDENTIFIED BY &#39;pass&#39; WITH GRANT OPTION;
FLUSH PRIVILEGES;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To revert the modified configuration file, restart the database, and you’re done.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/42520.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/42520.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
