<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Mysql on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mysql/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Mysql on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/mysql/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Resetting MySQL password on a Linux server</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/linux-server-reset-mysql-password/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Sep 2022 14:27:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/linux-server-reset-mysql-password/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have an idle Tencent Cloud server that is due to expire at the end of the year, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t plan on renewing it. I deployed a MySQL database for development purposes. When reinstalling the system, I chose a third-party image provided by Tencent Cloud to save time; it already had the MySQL database installed. I assumed there would be a Readme file or something similar in the system, explaining the password and deployment path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quick to reinstall the system on Tencent Cloud, it notifies you that it’s been reinstalled in about a minute. I logged in and &lt;code&gt;systemctl status mysql&lt;/code&gt; shows the service has already started. I looked everywhere for the password but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find it, and slowly started feeling hopeless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about it, I&amp;rsquo;ve already gained access to the server with &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; privileges; there has to be a way to reset the password. I flipped through some documents and found a post on the Alibaba Cloud forum – time to keep troubleshooting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reset-password&#34;&gt;Reset password
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Edit the configuration file &lt;code&gt;vim /etc/my.cnf&lt;/code&gt;, add the following configuration to the &lt;code&gt;mysqld&lt;/code&gt; node: &lt;code&gt;skip-grant-tables&lt;/code&gt;, and execute the command to restart the data: &lt;code&gt;systemctl restart mysql&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;code&gt;mysql&lt;/code&gt; to log in to the data again, and then proceed with normal operations. Reset the &lt;code&gt;root&lt;/code&gt; user password and enable remote login as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-sql&#34;&gt;USE mysql;
UPDATE user SET authentication_string = password (&#39;pass&#39;) WHERE User = &#39;root&#39;;
grant all privileges on *.* to &#39;root&#39;@&#39;%&#39; identified by &#39;pass&#39; with grant option;
flush privileges;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revert the configuration file, restart the database, and it&amp;rsquo;s done&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reference-materials&#34;&gt;Reference materials
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/42520.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://help.aliyun.com/document_detail/42520.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
