<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>National Interest on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/national-interest/</link>
        <description>Recent content in National Interest on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:23:48 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/national-interest/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Daily Musings</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 19:07:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/daily-musings/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;AI has been integrated into daily development workflows, and recent investments have shifted focus from external funds to internal stocks and ETFs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;open-source-projects&#34;&gt;Open Source Projects
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;project-log&#34;&gt;Project Log
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Last week, I was bored and tried to obtain GitHub badges, starting to use the Issue module. Previously, when writing code, I always wanted to find a place to record the content of each AI modification, but creating a separate document to record it felt disorganized. Now that we have the Issue module, tagging them to distinguish between bugs, features, enhancements, etc., has made the records clear and efficient. Even if I might not need them in the future, recording them is still a form of accumulation.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/issues?q=is%3Aissue&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;View Issue List&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;release-notes&#34;&gt;Release Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Release record, find the most recent related commits. Since all commits are AI-generated, copy all recent commit records from the web interface and give them to AI to organize – this is a good release record.
&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://github.com/ttf248/comic-reader/releases/tag/v1.9.0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;engagement&#34;&gt;Engagement
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;That time it was featured on GitHub’s personal page, it passively increased the motivation to write code – after all, the data visualization made things quite fascinating. Even simple positive feedback could provide the impetus to keep going.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trae&#34;&gt;Trae
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Paid for a monthly trial, honestly, it’s better in VSCode using Claude4. The practical effect is also better. Sometimes, even with the same problem, Trae gives better answers. Should I buy an annual subscription later? Given my current chaotic usage frequency, Trae might not be enough; don&amp;rsquo;t think about it too much, we’ll see when we run out. Byte should still have other paid plans and purchase more call volumes.
&lt;del&gt;Simple small issues can be solved using Microsoft, GitHub Copilot, and various models can also be called.&lt;/del&gt;
The plan is to fail – GitHub Copilot is now starting to limit the number of calls &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/about-github-copilot/plans-for-github-copilot#models&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;618 opened restrictions&lt;/a&gt;
How to check &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://docs.github.com/zh/copilot/managing-copilot/understanding-and-managing-copilot-usage/monitoring-your-copilot-usage-and-entitlements#downloading-a-monthly-usage-report&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;current usage&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, I couldn’t resist. Since the Hong Kong Connect channel was opened, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t traded in the Hong Kong market, and I bought some Xiaomi stock thinking about their upcoming new car launch. It rose a bit, so I sold it, and when it fell, I bought it back again, repeating this process several times before the new car was released, making a small profit on the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, I didn’t know what to do but look at the cross-border capital flows of Hong Kong Connect, watching Meituan&amp;rsquo;s net inflow of funds, and followed suit by buying it in, successfully becoming a shareholder, forgetting to look at the overall capital flow, only a part of the domestic purchases, and there were still many foreign investors in the Hong Kong market. This time it was just an opportunity to practice with blue-chip stocks, slowly holding on to the final gains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Controlling positions and losses are &lt;strong&gt;contrary to human nature&lt;/strong&gt;, slow down, slow down, don’t rush. If Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s new car doesn’t perform well, should I sell? That’s a question. My investment cognition is still insufficient, and I need to read more books and learn more. The Fed isn’t planning on cutting interest rates, and the Hong Kong market plunged once, if I missed the entry time? That wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be right, what if the news came out that interest rates were being cut and the Hong Kong market soared? This is investment, testing human nature.
&lt;code&gt;A phrase I often repeat: buying is for national fortune, but I don’t really believe in national fortune.&lt;/code&gt;
Aside from the belief in national fortune, &lt;strong&gt;another one is attention&lt;/strong&gt;. Since you&amp;rsquo;re going to do long-term investing, frequent monitoring of the market is pointless. Ten minutes in the morning and ten minutes at the close are enough. What is the final expected return rate? There’s still no clear stop-loss position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the market falls sharply, Tencent is a hot commodity, with capital flocking to it.
| 00700 | Tencent Holdings | 498.600 | 80.08 billion |&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-1&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;03690&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;128.100&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;6.881 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-2&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09992&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Bubble Mate&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;247.200&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;5.703 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-3&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Volume&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;09988&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;109.800&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;532.2 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-4&#34;&gt;Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Code&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Latest Price&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Turnover&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;01810&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;53.050&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;41.05 Billion&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
