<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Regulation-Oversight on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/regulation-oversight/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Regulation-Oversight on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/regulation-oversight/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>“Third-party custodian regulation is intensifying, and the behind-the-scenes winners of the ‘Douyin Stock Trading’ incident are facing a crackdown?”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 02:59:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/third-party-wealth-managers-scrutiny-tiktok-stock-winners-crackdown/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The hammer is falling.
Following the wind of short videos, investment advisory services are reportedly entering a fast lane.
In late September this year, after a period of intense activity in the A-share market, recommendations on Douyin (TikTok) have attracted attention from various parties.
Leading financial commentators on Douyin have risen to prominence, indirectly causing some volatility in capital markets.
However, the rapid rise of these financial commentators is not to be ignored – it’s largely driven by third-party investment advisory firms.
According to reports, many third-party investment advisory firms operate multiple accounts on short video platforms, using content distribution (PV) to attract users to watch investment teaching videos and boost enthusiasm for purchasing corresponding advisory products.
There are even rumors that one third-party investment advisory firm generated revenue of 10 billion yuan in October alone, exceeding its first-half revenue this year.
But “good times” are facing more uncertainties. Since November, multiple departments have successively issued notices requiring securities service institutions to strengthen the compliant management of their self-media accounts.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the evening of November 15th, Tianhong Securities (300033.SZ) announced that its subsidiary was penalized by the China Securities Regulatory Commission for engaging in behavior such as hinting at recommending stocks through livestreaming operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may be signaling to the market a stricter regulatory approach.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The expansion prospects of third-party investment advisory service institutions, such as JiuFang ZhiTu (9636.HK), are also likely to face greater pressure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tight-regulation-monitoring&#34;&gt;Tight Regulation Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The rise of short video platforms like Douyin (TikTok) has amplified emotional voices and indirectly impacted trading behavior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to Giant League of Finance’s monitoring, from September 27th to October 8th, when transaction volumes hit record highs, the Douyin A-share keyword search index soared from 4.2384 million to 12.7786 million, expanding by more than twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Under such circumstances, the “pushing and pulling” behavior of third-party investment advisory firms is attracting the attention of regulators.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The practice of investment advisors recommending stocks through various means during live broadcasts is a high-frequency violation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 8th, the Guangdong Securities Regulatory Bureau took regulatory measures to suspend new clients for a company that was found to be “hinting at stock recommendations” during a livestream. On November 14th, the Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 (Guangdong Securities and Futures Association) issued a notice titled “Live Streaming Control Lapses, Institutions Suspended Business,” directly addressing instances where some institutions with securities consulting qualifications exhibited inadequate control during live streaming operations. The notice also cited instances of recommending individual stocks within the live streams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The practice of recommending stocks through live streaming is strictly prohibited. Given that live streaming constitutes public media dissemination, all livestream presenters – regardless of whether they are registered as securities investment advisors – shall not recommend individual stocks during live broadcasts.” The Guangdong Securities Futures业协会 stated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not an isolated incident.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, the Shanghai Stock Exchange also disclosed a penalty notice detailing one case involving illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following regulatory investigation, Wang Yong, a consultant at Haishun Securities Investment Consulting Co., Ltd.’s Shanghai branch, violated industry norms by publishing misleading videos via WeChat Video Account, which contradicted professional standards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;tight-regulation-monitoring-1&#34;&gt;Tight Regulation Monitoring
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to information obtained by Wind (ID: TradeWind01), some ineligible investment advisory firms were using “front-running” brokers (ID:TradeWind01) on Douyin (TikTok) to recommend stocks, and they have since been suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Industry insiders are livestreaming, but in reality, they’re operating under the umbrella of a broker, which granted them investment advisor qualifications. They then use these livestreams to generate leads and sell advisory product bundles,” said a consultant from South China who spoke to Wind (ID: TradeWind01). “However, because they were recommending stocks during the livestream, it was discovered, leading to their suspension. Regular brokers typically discuss sector trends in investor education livestreams but wouldn’t delve into individual stocks.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, regulators are maintaining close scrutiny of illegal stock recommendations on social media platforms. For example, recent notices from the Shenzhen Securities Regulatory Commission have revealed that some individual institutions or individuals are engaging in illegal stock promotion through self-media, among other violations. To further regulate the self-media operations of securities investment consulting agencies within its jurisdiction, all institutions must strengthen their company’s self-media management.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may pose more challenges for third-party wealth management service providers&amp;rsquo; business expansion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-a-scam&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is a Scam
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether retail investors attracted by short videos have made money remains unknown, but the valuation of third-party investment advisory service companies as &amp;ldquo;water sellers&amp;rdquo; in the secondary market has soared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As China’s “first online teaching stock,” JiuFang Intelligence has seen its market capitalization rise from 2878 million yuan on September 9th to 12464 million yuan as of November 13th, with an increase of 333.08% over 49 trading days.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The semi-annual report shows that in the first half of the year, JiuFang Intelligence conducted brand exposure on social media platforms such as Douyin and Xiaohongshu, and by June 30th, it had 488 accounts and 46 million followers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, as JiuFang Intelligence’s Chief Investment Advisor, “Hongbangzhu” (commonly known as “Hong”) has amassed 2.26 million followers on Douyin (TikTok).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We have deeply cultivated MCN operations, focusing on the user-centric approach and synergistically promoting the comprehensive development of traffic, brands, and products.” “Nine Fang Intelligence Investment pointed out, “By deeply integrating new media tools such as live streaming and short videos, leveraging AI technology to build fan networks, and actively exploring e-commerce models, we effectively achieve the efficient conversion of traffic.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant course packages cover a price range from several hundred yuan to over ten hundred thousand yuan. The most expensive package, ‘Super Investor,’ priced at 1396,000 yuan for six months, includes exclusive insights and private consulting services.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, Nine Fang Intelligence Investment’s investment consultant products have a return rate of over 10%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the first half of 2024, the return rates for the flagship series and ‘Nine Fang Intelligent Dragon’ series reached 14.7% and 18.5%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the impact of regulatory headwinds on Nine Fang Intelligence Investment&amp;rsquo;s business development remains to be observed.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-false&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is False
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Recently, media reports have stated that accounts belonging to third-party custodians such as Jiu Fang Zhi Tu have been affected recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On November 7th, a report by a media outlet stated that &amp;ldquo;Hong Bangzhu&amp;rdquo; (洪帮主) was suspended from live streaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, on November 15th at 3:00 PM, Xin Feng (ID:TradeWind01) searched the account and found that the “Hong Bangzhu” livestream interface still allowed bookings for a livestream on November 18th.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, market news indicated that relevant departments have intervened in Jiu Fang Zhi Tu’s inspection.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, a source close to Jiu Fang Zhi Tu told Xin Feng (ID:TradeWind01) that the investigation was a routine check and had already concluded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is not the only company caught up in the rumors surrounding this regulatory storm.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are reports that Tianhong Securities has been investigated for illegal stock recommendations and may be suspended from operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In response, Tianhong Securities stated on November 15th that “there was no illegal stock recommendation situation and no investigation.” “However, that evening, Tianhe Securities announced that its subsidiary, Zhejiang Tianhe Securities Cloud Software Co., Ltd., was penalized by the Zhejiang Securities Regulatory Bureau for violations during its livestreaming promotional activities, specifically due to inadequate compliance controls and instances of hinting at recommended stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This may also signify a further escalation in regulatory scrutiny regarding stock recommendations on social media platforms like Douyin (TikTok) Live.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, the short video market is attracting many brokerage firms, but due to compliance requirements, brokers are currently being cautious.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-flow-business-is-forbidden&#34;&gt;“The Flow Business” is Forbidden
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A securities industry insider told Wind Info (ID:TradeWind01) that the company was exploring short video operations and lead generation methods, and had organized personnel to visit short video platform companies for learning. However, due to regulatory compliance requirements, it is currently in an exploratory phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, behind the various regulatory compliance requirements, is because short video content has a distinctly emotional color. But investors need to maintain rationality when dealing with it, and there is a natural conflict between the two.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If emotional forces influence capital markets, it can easily trigger violent market fluctuations, which goes against the long-term healthy development of capital markets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What way should securities firms embrace the arrival of the short video era to avoid “crossing the red line”? It’s clearly a difficult question for all parties involved.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
