<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Central-Bank on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/central-bank/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Central-Bank on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/central-bank/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the exchange rate of the Renminbi and a decline in the Shanghai Composite Index may be related to developments at global central banks, an unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss National Bank, performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors interact together in the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to volatility in the Renminbi and a decline in A-shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant fluctuations. Here&amp;rsquo;s the detailed information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through&lt;/strong&gt;: At the opening of trading, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar to offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and 7.22360 respectively during intraday trading, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of reporter release by Lianhe Finance, the dollar to offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 level, with a lowest reported price of 7.2639, and the trend remained strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Price Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the RMB/USD midpoint quotation at 7.1004, a depreciation of 62 basis points, expanding the adjustment magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened lower and continued to decline, with declines exceeding 1%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Forex Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment firm stated that volatility in the forex market was primarily due to the Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cutting interest rates, which boosted the dollar, coupled with strong US economic growth and the potential for inflationary persistence delaying rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;: This week is a “super central bank week” for global markets, with the U.S., Japan, UK, Australia, and other countries’ central banks all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cut rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, breaking market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RMB Trend Forecast&lt;/strong&gt;: Guotai Securities Financial Markets Department Researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent fluctuations in the RMB, the overall amplitude is significantly smaller than that of the U.S. dollar and other major currencies. Short-term volatility will not change the RMB’s steady uptrend this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
