<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Flag-Status on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/flag-status/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Flag-Status on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/flag-status/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>C&#43;&#43; Bitwise Operations Fundamentals: Bitwise Extraction and Flag Setting</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/cpp-bitwise-operations-basics-flags/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 02:23:56 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/cpp-bitwise-operations-basics-flags/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In actual C++ development, bitwise operations are a common technique, especially when dealing with system states, flags, or control bits. Bitwise operations can provide highly efficient solutions. This article will illustrate how to use bitwise operations to retrieve and set specific flags through an example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;bitwise-operations-fundamentals&#34;&gt;Bitwise Operations Fundamentals
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;In computers, data is stored in binary bits (0 and 1). Bitwise operations are operations performed on these binary bits. C++ provides several commonly used bitwise operators:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise AND (&amp;amp;)&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to check if a particular bit is set to 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise OR (|)&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to set a particular bit to 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise XOR (^)&lt;/strong&gt;: Used to flip a particular bit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise NOT (~)&lt;/strong&gt;: Inverts all the bits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Left Shift (&amp;laquo;)&lt;/strong&gt;: Shifts all the bits to the left by a specified number of positions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Right Shift (&amp;raquo;)&lt;/strong&gt;: Shifts all the bits to the right by a specified number of positions.
In this example, we need to perform a series of bitwise operations on an &lt;code&gt;unsigned short&lt;/code&gt; variable &lt;code&gt;wInfo&lt;/code&gt; to represent different states using various flags.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirement-analysis&#34;&gt;Requirement Analysis
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the description, we have a 16-bit flag to represent different states. These states are represented by various binary bits, with each binary bit corresponding to a specific meaning. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bit0&lt;/strong&gt;: Failure status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bit1&lt;/strong&gt;: Compression status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bit2&lt;/strong&gt;: Incremental status&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bit3&lt;/strong&gt;: Presence of subsequent packets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;bit5&lt;/strong&gt;: Normal request or cancellation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;using-bitwise-operations&#34;&gt;Using Bitwise Operations
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;We will use bitwise operations to set and retrieve these flags. Specifically:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise AND:&lt;/strong&gt; Retrieve the value of a particular bit (0 or 1).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise OR:&lt;/strong&gt; Set a particular bit to 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bitwise XOR:&lt;/strong&gt; Set a particular bit to 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first define an &lt;code&gt;unsigned short&lt;/code&gt; type variable &lt;code&gt;wInfo&lt;/code&gt; to store these flags. Then, we use bitwise operations to check and set the corresponding flags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;c-example-code&#34;&gt;C++ Example Code
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Execute the code, recommended for old friends: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://wandbox.org/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://wandbox.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-explanation&#34;&gt;Code Explanation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flag Definition&lt;/strong&gt;: Use shift operations (&lt;code&gt;1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; n&lt;/code&gt;) to define each flag bit. For example, &lt;code&gt;1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 0&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to &lt;code&gt;bit0&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;1 &amp;lt;&amp;lt; 1&lt;/code&gt; corresponds to &lt;code&gt;bit1&lt;/code&gt;, and so on. This way, we allocate a unique binary position for each flag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Check a Bit&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;code&gt;isBitSet&lt;/code&gt; function uses the bitwise AND operation (&lt;code&gt;wInfo &amp;amp; bitMask&lt;/code&gt;) to check if a specific flag is set to 1. If the bit is 1, the function returns &lt;code&gt;true&lt;/code&gt;, otherwise it returns &lt;code&gt;false&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Set a Bit&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;code&gt;setBit&lt;/code&gt; function uses the bitwise OR operation (&lt;code&gt;wInfo |= bitMask&lt;/code&gt;) to set a specific flag bit to 1.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clear a Bit&lt;/strong&gt;: The &lt;code&gt;clearBit&lt;/code&gt; function uses the bitwise AND operation (&lt;code&gt;wInfo &amp;amp;= ~bitMask&lt;/code&gt;) to clear a specific flag bit to 0.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Through bitwise operations, we can efficiently handle multiple state flags. This technique is particularly useful in practical development. For example, in embedded development, network protocols, and system status management scenarios, bit flags are often used to represent multiple binary states, saving space and improving efficiency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We hope this blog post helps you understand how to use bitwise operations in C++ to perform bitwise selection and setting, and mastering these skills is very helpful for writing efficient and maintainable code!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
