<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Central-Political-Bureau on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/central-political-bureau/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Central-Political-Bureau on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/central-political-bureau/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The Opening of Financial Anti-Corruption</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain-rise/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 14:53:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/financial-anti-corruption-curtain-rise/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Central Committee of the Communist Party of China: will intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, and thoroughly rectify “the four prevailing tendencies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;communist-party-of-china-central-politburo&#34;&gt;Communist Party of China Central Politburo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Communist Party of China Central Politburo held a meeting on September 27th, reviewing the “Comprehensive Report on the Situation of the First Round of Inspection of the Twelfth Collective Congress.” Xi Jinping, General Secretary of the Communist Party of China, chaired the meeting. The meeting emphasized that the inspection and oversight work should be used as an opportunity to further strengthen the overall leadership of the party, encourage inspected party organizations to raise their political stance, conscientiously fulfill the responsibilities and missions assigned by the Central Committee, continuously enhance the core functions and competitiveness of state-owned enterprises, consolidate the important material basis and political foundation of socialism with Chinese characteristics, intensify the financial sector’s service to the real economy and national strategies, and promote high-quality development. It was stressed that development and security should be coordinated, a bottom-line thinking and extreme thinking should be established, effective measures should be taken to prevent and mitigate major risks, and the safety red line must be firmly defended. To further advance the comprehensive and strict Party self-discipline towards greater depths, we must tighten and consolidate the responsibility of Party Committee Secretaries as the primary persons in charge, implement dual responsibilities for leading members of the Party Committee, strengthen supervision by disciplinary and supervisory organs, focus on supervising all levels’ “chief” positions, intensify anti-corruption efforts in state-owned enterprises and the financial sector, thoroughly rectify “four prevailing styles,” deepen reform through investigation results, improve systems, promote root-cause prevention, and achieve both qualitative and quantitative improvements. (Xinhua)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poses a major financial risk! Liu Liange, former Party Secretary and Chairman of China Bank, has been expelled from the Communist Party.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;communist-party-of-china-central-politburo-1&#34;&gt;Communist Party of China Central Politburo
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;According to the website of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection of China, with approval from the Communist Party of China Central Committee, the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection of China has initiated an investigation into the serious disciplinary and illegal conduct of Liu Liange, former Secretary of the Disciplinary Committee of the People’s Bank of China and Chairman. - Following investigation, Liu Liange abandoned his ideals and beliefs, betrayed his original aspirations and mission, lacked determination and integrity in implementing the Central Committee’s decision-making and deployment, compromised on key issues, and recklessly interfered with credit projects, illegally disbursed loans, causing significant financial risks. He failed to fulfill his responsibilities as a leading body for strict Party discipline, seriously disrupted the political ecology of his unit, privately brought prohibited materials into the country; deliberately resisted organizational review; ignored the spirit of the Central Committee’s Eight-Point Regulation, accepted gifts and presents, frequented private clubs, and received skiing and tourism arrangements; long-term used the vehicles of those under his management; failed to report personal matters in accordance with regulations, did not truthfully explain issues when questioned by the organization, showed favoritism in appointing and promoting personnel; engaged in illegal commercial activities; illegally interfered with capital lending, privately retained confidential materials; behaved immorally, had an improper family ethos, neglected supervision and education of relatives; lacked ideological bottom line and abused power, “consumed finance with finance,” took advantage of his position to seek benefits for others in loan financing, project cooperation, etc., and illegally received large sums of money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;central-committee-of-the-communist-party-of-china&#34;&gt;Central Committee of the Communist Party of China
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Liu Liange seriously violated the Party’s disciplinary rules and regulations, organizational discipline, integrity discipline, work discipline, and lifestyle discipline, constituting serious violations of Party discipline and involving bribery, illegal loan issuance, and criminal offenses. Furthermore, after the 18th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, he did not renounce illicit gains or curb his corrupt practices, which was of a severe nature, had a detrimental impact, and warranted serious handling. In accordance with relevant provisions of the &lt;em&gt;Disciplinary Rules of the Chinese Communist Party&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Criminal Law of the People’s Republic of China&lt;/em&gt; and the &lt;em&gt;Administrative Procedure Law for Public Office Personnel&lt;/em&gt;, after deliberation by the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) convened at its plenary session and approval by the CPC Central Committee, a decision was made to expel Liu Liange from the Party; cancel his benefits in accordance with regulations; terminate his eligibility as a delegate to the 20th National Congress of the Communist Party of China; recover his illegally obtained income; and transfer his criminal issues to the Public Prosecutor’s Office for investigation and prosecution, along with related assets. - The former Party Secretary and Chairman of China CITIC Group was dismissed from the Communist Party and public office for serious violations and abuses of power (CCTV News).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection and National Supervisory Commission reported that, according to a statement from the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision, Li Zhi Ming, former Party Secretary and Chairman of Guizhou Bank, is suspected of seriously violating and abusing his position and is currently under disciplinary investigation and supervision by the Guizhou Provincial Commission for Discipline Inspection and Supervision.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-an-eight-year-hiatus-huijin-boosts-holdings-in-the-big-four-banks&#34;&gt;After an Eight-Year Hiatus, Huijin Boosts Holdings in the Big Four Banks
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On October 11th, Industrial Bank, Agricultural Bank of China, Bank of China, and Construction Bank – the four major state-owned commercial banks – respectively announced that Huijin Company had increased its holdings, totaling 276.1 million shares, 372.7 million shares, 248.9 million shares, and 183.8 million shares, respectively. Huijin Company plans to continue increasing its holdings in the Big Four Banks on the secondary market over the next six months.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
