<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Ethnic-Pride on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/ethnic-pride/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Ethnic-Pride on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/ethnic-pride/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Spring Festival box office Nezha Goes Wild (Nezha Strikes Back)</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ne-zha-breaks-through-during-spring-festival/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:40:07 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/ne-zha-breaks-through-during-spring-festival/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation of the provided Chinese text:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;As Chinese people, every Spring Festival, we gather with our families for reunion dinners and watching movies has become an indispensable entertainment activity. This year’s Spring Festival box office hit, &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt;, exploded out of its niche, sparking discussions on streets and in alleys. The scale is impressive, reminiscent of the previous blockbuster, &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, carrying a strong patriotic theme that inexplicably evokes a sense of national pride.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Write an article, topic: The explosive popularity of &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt; at the Spring Festival box office, the inexplicable feeling of national pride, similar to previous films like &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt;, with a patriotic theme. While there has been significant progress, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t reached this level. As gamers, many aspects seem greasy, and the combat scenes are heavily influenced by online games. There have already been people who bought movie tickets for &lt;em&gt;Ne Zha&lt;/em&gt; solely because of its box office revenue but didn’t actually watch it.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-combat-scene-lacked-texture&#34;&gt;The Combat Scene Lacked Texture
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a gamer, I’m usually immersed in various online game worlds, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t have high expectations for movies. However, with the huge buzz around &lt;em&gt;The Water Margin&lt;/em&gt;, everyone around me was talking about it, and I thought, “Let me take a look.” When I entered the cinema, as soon as the scene came on screen, my heart sank. Although the production quality had improved compared to before, some scenes looked a bit greasy, and the combat scenes… well, they were too heavily influenced by games. Having played so many years of games, the visual style was too similar to certain scenes in those games, lacking the texture that a movie should have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crazy-fanatics&#34;&gt;Crazy Fanatics
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching the movie, I went out to see what people were saying online. Apparently, some people bought tickets for &lt;em&gt;The Soul of the Demon&lt;/em&gt; solely to boost its box office revenue. Seriously, I have to admit that I’m impressed – it seems like everyone is incredibly passionate about supporting this film and willing to do something for it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;storyline&#34;&gt;Storyline
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s reflect on it: back when &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt; came out, Wu Jing shouted “Anyone who dares to harm China will be punished, no matter how far away,” and countless people felt a surge of patriotism, believing that our Chinese military was incredibly powerful and our country exceptionally strong. Although &lt;em&gt;The Battle Between Heaven and Earth&lt;/em&gt; didn’t have such a direct patriotic slogan, it vividly showcased traditional Chinese culture. Characters like Nezha and Ao Bing, mythological figures we&amp;rsquo;ve grown up hearing stories about since childhood, had their feuds, loves, and growth journeys depicted with flesh and blood in the film. This is precisely the charm of Chinese culture, isn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s take Nezha as an example. He was misunderstood and ostracized from a young age, but he refused to give up, shouting “My destiny is not determined by others, but by myself,” which resonates so strongly with the resilience ingrained in every Chinese person. No matter what difficulties we face, we don&amp;rsquo;t bow down; instead, we strive to change our fate through our own efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;advancements-in-animated-films&#34;&gt;Advancements in Animated Films
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Although &lt;em&gt;The Fire on the Mountain&lt;/em&gt; (Nezha) had some imperfections, it effectively combined traditional Chinese culture with modern film techniques, allowing us to see significant progress in Chinese animated films. Just as &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt; demonstrated China’s breakthrough in the action film genre. This kind of advancement makes us feel that Chinese cinema can emerge onto the international stage and allows foreigners to witness the brilliance of Chinese culture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As Chinese people, no matter where we go, we carry our nation and culture within us. Films like &lt;em&gt;Nezha&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Wolf Warrior&lt;/em&gt; are like keys that unlock the deep-seated sense of national pride within us. They allow us to feel the strength of our country and the charm of our culture while laughing and enjoying ourselves, also inspiring us to work hard in our respective roles and contribute our share to the prosperity and flourishing of our nation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
