<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Emotion on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/emotion/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Emotion on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:53:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/emotion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A Complete Guide to Positioning, Replenishing Positions, and Stop-Loss Orders</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Oct 2025 18:39:23 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/a-complete-guide-to-positioning-replenishing-positions-and-stop-loss-orders/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For investors seeking to steadily progress in the Hong Kong stock market, success doesn’t stem from precisely predicting every fluctuation of the market, but rather from establishing a scientific, rational, and strictly adhered-to investment system. This system&amp;rsquo;s core consists of three pillars: &lt;strong&gt;reasonable position control&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;intelligent rebalancing strategies&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;unwavering trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt;. This article will consolidate these key elements to provide investors with a comprehensive and detailed operational guide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control--the-cornerstone-of-resilient-investing&#34;&gt;Position Control – The Cornerstone of Resilient Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The primary goal of resilient investing is “to preserve capital and develop afterwards.” Position control serves as the “shield” to achieve this, determining your ability to withstand market volatility.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;overall-allocation-dependent-on-risk-tolerance-and-market-temperature&#34;&gt;Overall Allocation: Dependent on Risk Tolerance and Market Temperature
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personal Risk Tolerance:&lt;/strong&gt; This is the fundamental determinant of your allocation ceiling. Risk-averse investors should maintain a total position no higher than &lt;strong&gt;60%&lt;/strong&gt;, even in bull markets. Investors with slightly higher risk tolerance can set their ceilings at &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt;. At all times, maintain at least &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; cash as a strategic reserve to capitalize on extreme opportunities or unforeseen needs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Temperature:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High/Bubble Phase (Market Mania):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation should be reduced to &lt;strong&gt;30%-50%&lt;/strong&gt; or lower. Preserving profits is the priority.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neutral/Choppy Phase (Uncertain Direction):&lt;/strong&gt; Allocation can remain at &lt;strong&gt;50%-70%&lt;/strong&gt;, making structural adjustments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Low/Panic Phase (Valuation Bottoming):&lt;/strong&gt; This is the golden time to increase allocation, potentially reaching &lt;strong&gt;70%-80%&lt;/strong&gt; or higher.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;individual-stock-and-industry-exposure-diversify-risk-avoid-overconcentration&#34;&gt;Individual Stock and Industry Exposure: Diversify Risk, Avoid Overconcentration
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Stock Position:&lt;/strong&gt; Regardless of how optimistic you are about a particular stock, the recommended position size for any single stock should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;20%&lt;/strong&gt; of the total investment portfolio. For companies with limited understanding or higher risk profiles, the position size should be further reduced to &lt;strong&gt;5%-10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maximum Single Industry Exposure:&lt;/strong&gt; Given the high concentration of industries in Hong Kong (such as finance and technology), it’s important to diversify. The total exposure to any single industry should not exceed &lt;strong&gt;30%-40%&lt;/strong&gt; to mitigate the impact of industry-specific “black swan” events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buyback-strategy--the-art-of-transforming-passivity-into-proactivity&#34;&gt;Buyback Strategy – The Art of Transforming Passivity into Proactivity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A buyback strategy is the “lever” for prudent investors to accumulate high-quality positions in a declining market. However, this requires &lt;strong&gt;only operating on companies with sound fundamentals and uncompromised core competitiveness.&lt;/strong&gt; For companies with deteriorating fundamentals or “penny stocks,” the only correct action is to cut losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;how-much-to-buy-on-dips-for-adding-to-position&#34;&gt;How much to buy on dips for adding to position?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The core of accumulating during a decline is “buying lower,” but this must be executed with a plan and discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pyramidal Accumulation Strategy (Wide Base, Narrow Top):&lt;/strong&gt; This is a relatively conservative approach where the amount purchased increases as the price falls further.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Position Building:&lt;/strong&gt; Establish a &lt;strong&gt;base position&lt;/strong&gt; within a reasonable valuation range.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;First Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops 15%-20% from the initial position building price. This is a common re-entry point, filtering out normal market fluctuations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Second Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the first refill price (cumulative decline of approximately 30%-40%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Third Refill:&lt;/strong&gt; When the price drops another 15%-20% from the second refill price (cumulative decline potentially reaching around 50%). At this point, it’s typically extreme panic. If the company&amp;rsquo;s fundamentals remain solid, it’s a great buying opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;is-it-reasonable-to-add-to-the-position-a-few-times&#34;&gt;Is it reasonable to add to the position a few times?
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;To avoid overinvesting capital in a wrong decision, the number of times to add to the position should not be excessive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommended number of additions: 2-3 times is appropriate.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Risk control:&lt;/strong&gt; If the stock price still doesn&amp;rsquo;t improve after 2-3 major add-on purchases, you must re-examine your initial investment logic. Unlimited adding may lead to a single holding ratio being too high, dragging down the entire investment portfolio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain cash reserves:&lt;/strong&gt; Excessive additions will quickly deplete available funds, causing you to miss other better opportunities that appear in the market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;trading-discipline--the-core-for-newbies-progression&#34;&gt;Trading Discipline – The Core for Newbies’ Progression
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;If position sizing and stop-lossing are “techniques,” then trading discipline is the “way.” For novice traders, adhering to discipline is a decisive factor in whether they can survive in the market long-term.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;planning-and-execution-discipline-never-go-into-battle-without-a-plan&#34;&gt;Planning and Execution Discipline: Never Go into Battle Without a Plan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plan Before Trade:&lt;/strong&gt; Every trade must be preceded by a clear understanding of the &lt;strong&gt;buy rationale, target price (take profit), and stop-loss level&lt;/strong&gt;. During the trade, strictly adhere to the plan and avoid emotional interference.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Avoid Riding the Wave and Panic Selling:&lt;/strong&gt; Overcome the fear of missing out (FOMO) and panic selling emotions. Only execute trades at points that align with your plan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;risk-and-capital-management-discipline-survival-is-the-priority&#34;&gt;Risk and Capital Management Discipline: Survival is the Priority
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strict Stop-Loss, No Hesitation:&lt;/strong&gt; A stop-loss is the lifeline for protecting your capital. The most dangerous habit for beginners is to hold onto losing trades. Set your stop-loss levels at &lt;strong&gt;-5% to -10%&lt;/strong&gt;, and execute without hesitation upon reaching them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Add to Losing Trades to Average Down to Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a fatal error. If a trade proves to be wrong (falling below the stop-loss), the correct approach is to exit, not to invest more money to “dilute the cost.” This can turn a small mistake into a major disaster.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;mindset-and-emotional-control-discipline-be-the-master-of-your-emotions&#34;&gt;Mindset and Emotional Control Discipline: Be the Master of Your Emotions
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Accept Losses as Part of Trading:&lt;/strong&gt; No one can win every battle. View small losses as a necessary cost of trading, focusing on the long-term overall profit/loss ratio.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don’t Get Greedy from Profits, Don’t Be Bitter from Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; Break free from a “gambling mentality,” don&amp;rsquo;t take risks due to profits, and don’t retaliate with impulsive trades due to losses. Maintain a calm mindset and remain consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;learning-and-review-discipline-continuous-evolution&#34;&gt;Learning and Review Discipline: Continuous Evolution
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maintain a Trading Journal:&lt;/strong&gt;  Detailed record of your thought process and results for each trade, with regular reviews to analyze successes and failures. This is the most effective way to self-improve.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stick to Your Circle of Competence:&lt;/strong&gt; Only invest in areas you understand and can truly comprehend. Avoid unfamiliar fields and complex financial products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;patience-and-discipline-are-superior-to-everything-else&#34;&gt;Patience and Discipline are Superior to Everything Else
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a prudent Hong Kong stock investor, your goal isn’t to be a speculator dancing on the crest of market waves, but rather to be like a discerning general, orchestrating strategy from behind the scenes. Please treat &lt;strong&gt;position control&lt;/strong&gt; as your steadfast shield, &lt;strong&gt;opportunistic buying strategies&lt;/strong&gt; as your sharp spear, and &lt;strong&gt;trading discipline&lt;/strong&gt; as an immutable military code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the initial stages of trading, &lt;strong&gt;prioritize “minimizing losses” over “making big profits.”&lt;/strong&gt; Through continuous learning, practice, and review, you will ultimately achieve long-term, steady wealth appreciation in this market brimming with opportunities and challenges. Remember, patience and discipline are always more important qualities than predicting the market.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
