<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Inner-Network-Penetration on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/inner-network-penetration/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Inner-Network-Penetration on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/inner-network-penetration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>ZeroTier for Remote Local Area Networks</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/zero-tier-remote-lan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 04:58:03 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/zero-tier-remote-lan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Acquired a new __INLINE_CODE_0__主机，想着配置配置环境方便，在家偶尔也有访问的需求，临时部署内网穿透。按照以往的经验，部署__INLINE_CODE_1__服务，指定端口转发，需要一台公网的服务器，连接的质量取决于公网服务器的宽带质量。折腾一点新鲜的__INLINE_CODE_2__虚拟机局域网，类似于&lt;code&gt;VPN&lt;/code&gt; in the office, created a virtual network card locally, and added all machines to a virtual network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zerotier&#34;&gt;What is ZeroTier?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can easily connect multiple computers, servers, and devices to a virtual, encrypted network as if they were on the same local area network. This allows programmers and IT professionals to securely share data and resources between different locations without complex network setups or VPN configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ZeroTier Network is a virtual, global local area network that allows different devices to connect together over the internet as if they were on the same physical network. This network can include multiple subnets, with all devices connected through ZeroTier&amp;rsquo;s technology.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Planet servers are key components of the ZeroTier network. They are global in scope, responsible for maintaining and managing the entire ZeroTier network&amp;rsquo;s topology, routing information, and network status. Planet servers act as a global network control center but do not directly transmit data. User devices need to connect to at least one planet server to participate in the ZeroTier network.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relay servers are auxiliary nodes in the Zerotier network, helping devices establish direct communication channels. When devices cannot connect directly, they can transmit data through a relay server, improving network reachability and performance. Relay servers are typically located worldwide, acting as data transfer hubs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Zerotier creates virtual local area networks globally, enabling secure and fast communication between devices through planetary and relay servers. Planetary servers manage the global network, while relay servers help establish connections when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-deployment&#34;&gt;Installation Deployment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the ZeroTier official website (link) for installation files and documentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install the ZeroTier One client for your operating system. It supports Windows, macOS, Linux, and many other platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch the ZeroTier One client after installation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a ZeroTier account if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one. You can create an account within the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in to your ZeroTier account and create a new network. The network will have a unique 16-character ID that you need to remember.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this network on your device. You can enter the network ID in the client or use the QR code scanning function.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devices installed with and configured with the ZeroTier client will be added to the same virtual network. These devices can now communicate directly, as if they were on the same local area network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can manage network settings, add devices, and monitor network traffic through ZeroTier&amp;rsquo;s control panel&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;install-deployment-moon&#34;&gt;Install deployment moon
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many domestic carriers prohibit this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;curl -s https://install.zerotier.com/ | sudo bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Verify installation success&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join local network&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli join network-id
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cd /var/lib/zerotier-one &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo zerotier-idtool initmoon identity.public &amp;gt; moon.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the configuration file, adjust the __INLINE_CODE_0 node, &amp;ldquo;public server IP/9993&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generate signature configuration, create &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; folder, move existing files here, and restart the service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo zerotier-idtool genmoon moon.json
mkdir moons.d &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mv 000000eb444ec0d8.moon moons.d/
systemctl restart zerotier-one.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client nodes join the Moon server; their ID is taken from the ID field in the preceding JSON configuration file&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli.bat orbit ztaddr ztaddr
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# 观察是否出现新的 mooon 节点，id 和信息为服务器配置的相同
[root@idv-36f9d5 ~]# zerotier-cli listpeers
200 listpeers &amp;lt;ztaddr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;path&amp;gt; &amp;lt;latency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;role&amp;gt;
200 listpeers 0cccb***** 35.236.*.*/64393;110;10726 327 1.6.3 LEAF
200 listpeers 3a46f***** 185.180.*.*/9993;110;757 -1 - PLANET
200 listpeers 3ed7c***** 39.97.*.*/9993;172;79 32 1.6.3 MOON
200 listpeers 4f838***** - -1 - LEAF
200 listpeers 62f86***** 50.7.*.*/9993;110;4796 351 - PLANET
200 listpeers 778cd***** 103.195.*.*/9993;5148;4887 253 - PLANET
200 listpeers 992fc***** 195.181.*.*/9993;10161;4921 226 - PLANET
200 listpeers 9d2b5***** - -1 - LEAF
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, launch the terminal with administrator privileges and use the &lt;code&gt;zerotier-cli.bat&lt;/code&gt; command-line tool; on Linux, use the &lt;code&gt;zerotier-cli&lt;/code&gt; command. The &lt;code&gt;peers&lt;/code&gt; subcommand displays connections, and &lt;code&gt;listpeers&lt;/code&gt; shows all nodes. Nodes marked as &lt;strong&gt;INLINE_CODE_0&lt;/strong&gt; indicate successful joining.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-uninstall&#34;&gt;How to uninstall
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It appears you&amp;rsquo;ve provided a string of formatting codes rather than actual Chinese text. Without the Chinese characters, I cannot translate. Please provide the Chinese text you want translated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove zerotier-one service using dpkg&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo dpkg -P zerotier-one
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deleting the zerotier-one folder, which stores the address, will result in a new address being obtained upon reinstallation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo rm -rf /var/lib/zerotier-one/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, everything was already uninstalled. When the server arrived, there were no suitable service agents available. To boost sales, Alibaba Cloud offered a developer-exclusive server with modest specs and an affordable price of $99 per year. We used it for two years, primarily because of the server&amp;rsquo;s bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wnark.com/archives/152.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.wnark.com/archives/152.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cnblogs.com/Yogile/p/12642423.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.cnblogs.com/Yogile/p/12642423.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
