<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Inner-Network-Penetration on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/inner-network-penetration/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Inner-Network-Penetration on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/inner-network-penetration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>ZeroTier SD</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/zero-tier-remote-lan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 04:58:03 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/zero-tier-remote-lan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I recently got a &lt;code&gt;mini&lt;/code&gt; host for the office, thinking it would be convenient to configure an environment and have occasional access at home. I temporarily deployed internal network penetration using &lt;code&gt;frp&lt;/code&gt; – specifying port forwarding, which requires a public server with a connection quality dependent on its bandwidth. Instead of that, I experimented with a fresh &lt;code&gt;Zerotier&lt;/code&gt; virtual LAN, similar to a &lt;code&gt;VPN&lt;/code&gt;, where I created a virtual network card locally and all machines joined it into a single virtual network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zerotier&#34;&gt;What is ZeroTier
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/code&gt; is a software-defined wide area network (SD-WAN) solution that allows users to create secure virtual networks between devices in different geographic locations. Through &lt;code&gt;ZeroTier&lt;/code&gt;, you can easily connect multiple computers, servers, and devices into a virtual, encrypted network – as if they were on the same local network. This can help developers and IT professionals securely share data and resources across different locations without complex network setups or VPN configurations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ZeroTier Networks&lt;/strong&gt;: A ZeroTier Network is a virtual, global LAN that allows different devices to connect together over the internet, as if they were on the same physical network. This network can contain multiple subnets, with all devices connected together using ZeroTier technology. &lt;strong&gt;Planet Server:&lt;/strong&gt; The Planet Server is a key component of the Zerotier network. It’s global in scope, responsible for maintaining and managing the entire Zerotier network&amp;rsquo;s topology, routing information, and network state. The Planet Server acts as a central control center for the network, but does not directly transmit data. User devices need to connect to at least one Planet Server to participate in the Zerotier network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-zerotier-1&#34;&gt;What is Zerotier
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relay Server:&lt;/strong&gt; A relay server is an auxiliary node in the Zerotier network that helps establish direct communication channels between devices. When devices cannot connect directly, they can use a relay server to transmit data. This helps improve network reachability and performance. Relay servers are typically located around the globe, acting as data transmission hubs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, Zerotier uses the assistance of planet servers and relay servers to allow devices to create virtual local networks globally, enabling secure and fast communication between devices. The planet server is responsible for global network management, while the relay server helps devices establish connection when needed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation--deployment&#34;&gt;Installation &amp;amp; Deployment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit the ZeroTier official website (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.zerotier.com/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.zerotier.com/&lt;/a&gt;) to obtain installation files and documentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download and install the ZeroTier One client according to your operating system. It supports Windows, macOS, Linux, and many other platforms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Launch the ZeroTier One client after installation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Register a ZeroTier account if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one. You can create an account within the client.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Log in with your ZeroTier account and create a new network. The network will have a unique 16-character ID, which you need to remember.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join this network on your device. You can either enter the network ID in the client or use the QR code scanning feature.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Devices with the installed and configured ZeroTier client will be added to the same virtual network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-and-deployment-of-moon&#34;&gt;Installation and Deployment of Moon
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Many domestic operators have banned &lt;code&gt;UDP&lt;/code&gt; tunneling, and the &lt;code&gt;frp&lt;/code&gt; service is stable due to using the &lt;code&gt;TCP&lt;/code&gt; protocol. The &lt;code&gt;Zerotier&lt;/code&gt; middle server deployment can also achieve similar effects, requiring firewall opening of &lt;code&gt;UDP 9993&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;curl -s https://install.zerotier.com/ | sudo bash
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check installation success:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli info
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join the local network:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli join network-id
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;moon&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;cd /var/lib/zerotier-one &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo zerotier-idtool initmoon identity.public &amp;gt; moon.json
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Edit the configuration file, adjust the &lt;code&gt;stableEndpoints&lt;/code&gt; nodes to &amp;ldquo;server public IP/9993&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generate signature configuration, create the &lt;code&gt;moons.d&lt;/code&gt; folder, and move the previous files into it, then restart the service.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-and-deploying-moon&#34;&gt;Installing and Deploying Moon
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo zerotier-idtool genmoon moon.json
mkdir moons.d &amp;amp;&amp;amp; mv 000000eb444ec0d8.moon moons.d/
systemctl restart zerotier-one.service
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client nodes join the Moon server, ID taken from the ID field in the preceding JSON configuration file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;zerotier-cli.bat orbit ztaddr ztaddr
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installing-and-deploying-moon-1&#34;&gt;Installing and Deploying Moon
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;# Observe if new moon nodes appear, with IDs and information matching server configuration.
[root@idv-36f9d5 ~]# zerotier-cli listpeers
200 listpeers &amp;lt;ztaddr&amp;gt; &amp;lt;path&amp;gt; &amp;lt;latency&amp;gt; &amp;lt;version&amp;gt; &amp;lt;role&amp;gt;
200 listpeers 0cccb***** 35.236.*.*/64393;110;10726 327 1.6.3 LEAF
200 listpeers 3a46f***** 185.180.*.*/9993;110;757 -1 - PLANET
200 listpeers 3ed7c***** 39.97.*.*/9993;172;79 32 1.6.3 MOON
200 listpeers 4f838***** - -1 - LEAF
200 listpeers 62f86***** 50.7.*.*/9993;110;4796 351 - PLANET
200 listpeers 778cd***** 103.195.*.*/9993;5148;4887 253 - PLANET
200 listpeers 992fc***** 195.181.*.*/9993;10161;4921 226 - PLANET
200 listpeers 9d2b5***** - -1 - LEAF
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation-and-deployment-of-moon-1&#34;&gt;Installation and Deployment of Moon
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Windows, launch the terminal with administrator privileges and operate using the &lt;code&gt;zerotier-cli.bat&lt;/code&gt; command-line interface. On Linux, use the &lt;code&gt;zerotier-cli&lt;/code&gt; command. The &lt;code&gt;peers&lt;/code&gt; subcommand displays connections, while &lt;code&gt;listpeers&lt;/code&gt; shows all nodes, successfully indicating a successful join.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;uninstalling&#34;&gt;Uninstalling
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;How to uninstall on the &lt;code&gt;Windows&lt;/code&gt; platform is beyond the scope of this document, as it follows standard operating procedures – typically through the Control Panel. We will focus on the &lt;code&gt;Ubuntu&lt;/code&gt; instructions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remove the zerotier-one service using dpkg:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo dpkg -P zerotier-one
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete the zerotier-one directory, which stores the address information; deleting it will result in a new address upon reinstallation:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;sudo rm -rf /var/lib/zerotier-one/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;They were originally all decommissioned, arriving at the server location without suitable service nodes to act as proxy servers. Alibaba was focused on sales and provided development trial servers with low configurations, costing only 99 yuan per year and used for two years. The key factor was the bandwidth offered by the servers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.wnark.com/archives/152.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.wnark.com/archives/152.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://www.cnblogs.com/Yogile/p/12642423.html&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://www.cnblogs.com/Yogile/p/12642423.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
