<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>League of Legends on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/league-of-legends/</link>
        <description>Recent content in League of Legends on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 14:23:20 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/league-of-legends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>What is regret?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-is-regret-in-olympic-games/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 13:51:33 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-is-regret-in-olympic-games/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday after watching the match, the feeling of “unsettledness” lingered in my heart for a long time. I happened to see a netizen’s words and felt a deep connection – he started his engagement with this sport from elementary school, while I only began to get involved in university.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I sat down to write, I thought of the &amp;ldquo;legendary twins&amp;rdquo; from the Yueshan Badminton Academy – Lin Dan and Li Zongwei. And Faker, he is like the “evergreen pine” or “perennial tree” in the esports world, a perfect combination of talent and extreme self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He wasn’t without losses, but we hadn&amp;rsquo;t lost to LPL; when a friend asked me, was it because of a particular team’s fans? Not really. The domestic education system’s nurturing supports our own teams, which is natural. It’s not about a specific player or team’s fanbase – we like watching high-quality matches featuring the Chinese team.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Commentators largely guide viewers&amp;rsquo; emotions; their embellishment of key match moments has magnified that feeling of unsettledness many times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;!-- more --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##转载&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article was something I saw on TikTok and didn’t know how to paste the original link.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Starting with S3, I started playing League of Legends when I was in sixth grade because at that time we didn&amp;rsquo;t have a good computer and felt it would affect my studies, and I thought I wouldn’t get into university, so I played it sporadically. My rank consistently remained Gold and Silver. However, I also continued to watch tournaments intermittently. As a small kid, I was moved to tears watching it. But I always remember that year of Royal Never Give Up (RNG) and OMG relentlessly attacking the rookie version of Faker. The confident Faker easily took down two teams with a single play. Following that, the Samsung Blue vs. White match, the gap between the two regions’ broken players was overwhelming and couldn&amp;rsquo;t be compensated for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After going to university before enlisting in the army, I continued to be obsessed with League of Legends. I searched online for small and medium-sized videos, wanting to become a master player. But I would also be distracted by other small and medium-sized things. However, I clearly remember the night RNG won the championship, when I woke up the next day and saw the slice video, I burst into tears because it felt like LPL really had a chance. When I was in the army, I also heard about FPX winning the championship, as the situation was special at the time, so I didn&amp;rsquo;t pay much attention. To be honest, when EDG won the championship, I wasn’t particularly surprised, considering that a non-all-Chinese team had already achieved a championship once, and I hoped for an all-Chinese team to achieve a true championship. The fleeting RNG won all the games in that year, but lost the most crucial game, where Faker consecutively made five kills with Galio, and in the last game, he perfectly timed his “closing eyes to pray” play, completely destroying Uzi’s champion dream. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how many hearts were broken and players quit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After returning from military service, I followed the competition year after year, always unable to catch up with Faker. From WBG in the year of my postgraduate entrance exam to BLG last year, and now AL in today’s top eight, as I watched Faker use Xerath to get kills and steal Ethan&amp;rsquo;s Baron Nashor, I knew this game was lost. Honestly, it makes me feel really bad watching him. I really have a lot of feelings for the League of Legends game. Not only do I play well, but I also know the background stories of most major heroes. I also know the stories of LPL and LCK teams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oh, LPL this region is obviously lagging behind LCK in terms of atmosphere and strength comparison. I also hope that LPL will have a full Chinese team win the championship.  I’ll end with Wang Duo Duo&amp;rsquo;s words: “Maybe one day we will lose confidence in electronic sports like League of Legends because the Korean control is still continuing today, but it won’t be today.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I still hold onto the dream of an all-Chinese team winning the championship, just as I have fantasies about some things in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Review Log 20151031</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No trading activity within the venue; awaiting the release of next month’s financial reports. Taking a half-day break this afternoon with no specific plans – simply wanting to rest and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;years-have-passed&#34;&gt;Years Have Passed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last watched League of Legends (LOL) matches live, and suddenly it feels like four or five years have passed.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous articles related to games, I always had a complex feeling towards LPL teams (the domestic region). The frequent low-level mistakes made by many players in major tournaments felt lacking in professional demeanor, which diminished the viewing experience of the matches – this is why I gradually drifted away.
This afternoon, on a whim, I took a half day off to tidy up my room, and the summer clothes were still unorganized. While cleaning, I decided to watch some matches. The quarterfinals were still T1, that formidable mountain standing in front of LPL teams, seemingly impossible to overcome. Looking back, LPL has never won Bo5 (best-of-five) key matchups against them in the Worlds series, and any team facing them felt immense pressure.
Writing these words, the match had just entered its “classic” fifth game – LPL was leading 2-1 and in a great position to win, but their opponent tied it up, and they were about to enter a brutal final deciding game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update before publishing: The operation wasn’t too bad, but their build strategy was completely crushed. The Queen composition led to Ashe being dominant early on, preventing the piglet from grouping for team fights – it was so difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; Performance was stable with minimal fluctuation, punctuated by a brief rally.
&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; This decline was largely driven by a confluence of negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro Drag:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall pullback in the Hong Kong tech sector (such as NetEase, Alibaba, and Tencent) performed poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The new energy vehicle sector experienced intensified “internal competition” (“intense competition”), and market expectations for growth in companies like BYD have peaked.  Xiaomi’s automotive future space is also under pressure.
&lt;strong&gt;Industry Observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UBS&amp;rsquo;s pre-earnings report highlighted the rising prices of solid-state drives and memory. The extent to which this cost increase will erode profit margins in mobile business remains to be revealed by the earnings report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, one thing is certain: In a market as intensely “competitive” as this, the Android smartphone ecosystem no longer has the luxury of raising prices arbitrarily.
&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Backlash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, returning to Xiaomi itself, its automotive business is facing reputation issues. The project’s early promotional volume was immense, with almost no negative feedback. Now, it seems to be experiencing a wave of public “backlash” following excessive exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
