<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>League of Legends on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/league-of-legends/</link>
        <description>Recent content in League of Legends on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 19:53:26 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/league-of-legends/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Review Log 20151031</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 18:58:21 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/review-log-20151031/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;No trading activity within the venue; awaiting the release of next month’s financial reports. Taking a half-day break this afternoon with no specific plans – simply wanting to rest and recharge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;years-have-passed&#34;&gt;Years Have Passed
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It’s been a long time since I last watched League of Legends (LOL) matches live, and suddenly it feels like four or five years have passed.
As I&amp;rsquo;ve mentioned in my previous articles related to games, I always had a complex feeling towards LPL teams (the domestic region). The frequent low-level mistakes made by many players in major tournaments felt lacking in professional demeanor, which diminished the viewing experience of the matches – this is why I gradually drifted away.
This afternoon, on a whim, I took a half day off to tidy up my room, and the summer clothes were still unorganized. While cleaning, I decided to watch some matches. The quarterfinals were still T1, that formidable mountain standing in front of LPL teams, seemingly impossible to overcome. Looking back, LPL has never won Bo5 (best-of-five) key matchups against them in the Worlds series, and any team facing them felt immense pressure.
Writing these words, the match had just entered its “classic” fifth game – LPL was leading 2-1 and in a great position to win, but their opponent tied it up, and they were about to enter a brutal final deciding game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Update before publishing: The operation wasn’t too bad, but their build strategy was completely crushed. The Queen composition led to Ashe being dominant early on, preventing the piglet from grouping for team fights – it was so difficult.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;review&#34;&gt;Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan:&lt;/strong&gt; Performance was stable with minimal fluctuation, punctuated by a brief rally.
&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; This decline was largely driven by a confluence of negative factors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Macro Drag:&lt;/strong&gt; The overall pullback in the Hong Kong tech sector (such as NetEase, Alibaba, and Tencent) performed poorly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The new energy vehicle sector experienced intensified “internal competition” (“intense competition”), and market expectations for growth in companies like BYD have peaked.  Xiaomi’s automotive future space is also under pressure.
&lt;strong&gt;Industry Observations:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UBS&amp;rsquo;s pre-earnings report highlighted the rising prices of solid-state drives and memory. The extent to which this cost increase will erode profit margins in mobile business remains to be revealed by the earnings report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;However, one thing is certain: In a market as intensely “competitive” as this, the Android smartphone ecosystem no longer has the luxury of raising prices arbitrarily.
&lt;strong&gt;Reputation Backlash:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finally, returning to Xiaomi itself, its automotive business is facing reputation issues. The project’s early promotional volume was immense, with almost no negative feedback. Now, it seems to be experiencing a wave of public “backlash” following excessive exposure.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
