<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Chatgtp on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/chatgtp/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Chatgtp on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/chatgtp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Prompt Engineer</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/prompt-engineer/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 26 Mar 2023 20:46:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/prompt-engineer/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as we needed to learn the techniques of searching engines back then, we also need to learn some techniques for communicating with &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt;, providing reasonable and sufficient constraints, and efficiently obtaining the answers we need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you look at it from a different angle, current &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; is like a very good student with excellent memory – it has the ability to memorize everything. What we need to do is learn how to communicate with &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; correctly, effectively, and precisely describe our needs to help &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; generate the expected results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##科普
The incredibly popular &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; – specifically &lt;code&gt;Generative Pre-Training&lt;/code&gt; – literally translates to generative pre-training. It’s a deep learning model that trains text generation based on internet-available data, used for tasks like question answering, text summarization generation, machine translation, classification, code generation, and conversational AI. Currently, there have been various versions of models such as GPT-1, GPT-2, GPT-3, and GPT-4, each larger and more powerful than the previous one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;does-it-really-have-intelligence&#34;&gt;Does it Really Have Intelligence?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Similarity is high, accuracy increases accordingly.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic, repetitive tasks, after specific training, no longer require human intervention.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Generative AI is a technology that utilizes existing data such as text, audio, and images to create new content. It can be used for various tasks including text generation, speech synthesis, image generation, and dialogue systems. The logical reasoning of Generative AI depends on its training data and model structure. Generally, Generative AI can follow grammar, logic, and common sense to a certain extent, but it may also produce errors, biases, or unrealistic content. Therefore, the output of Generative AI requires human judgment and verification; it should not be blindly trusted or used.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;prompt-engineer&#34;&gt;Prompt Engineer
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time flows only forward, and people need to learn to adapt to the current. You can think of &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; as not intelligent, lacking logic, and often producing unusable code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you shift your perspective, the current &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; is like a child with excellent memory – it has the ability to memorize after reading something repeatedly, much like copying homework. What we need to do is learn how to communicate correctly, effectively, and with &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt;, precisely describing our needs to help &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; generate the desired results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dialogue-patterns&#34;&gt;Dialogue Patterns
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, when GitHub Copilot was released, no one could have imagined that two years later, OpenAI would appear out of nowhere, allowing humans to recognize the capabilities of large language models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on &lt;strong&gt;comment-based programming&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;conversational programming&lt;/strong&gt;, the interaction logic is completely different. The dialogue pattern offers a user-friendly experience for novice users, and it’s essential to mention NewBing providing follow-up prompts after each question. Microsoft is attempting to guide users to obtain more content from the AI knowledge base.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;lets-illustrate-with-an-example&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate with an example
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario:&lt;/strong&gt; A long high-speed train journey, and coding is a good choice. With limited traffic, processing a few images, obtaining image materials, downloading software to process the images is a bit extravagant, and network conditions aren’t ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a batch of image materials with transparent backgrounds that need to be used as navigation bars for small programs. The selected state is colored, and the unselected state is black and white. The materials are all in color, and they need to be preprocessed. &lt;strong&gt;Prompt:&lt;/strong&gt; Write a Python code to read all images from a folder, convert them to black and white while maintaining the transparent background, optimize image quality, reduce file size, and display the before-and-after file size comparison in the console.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; quickly provided an answer that looked very beautiful and worked well; an experienced programming source would find the code less generic and unable to be deployed into production:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parameters were fixed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There were no log files, all information was printed to the console.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The image processing task was suitable for a multi-threaded model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;NewBing&lt;/code&gt; appeared, based on the prompt, choosing a question: &lt;strong&gt;What improvements can be made to this code?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This time, the answer was honest and completely exceeded expectations; typical optimization measures that programmers would think of were all provided by &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt;, and corresponding suggestions were given.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A friendly response was given, considering there are differences in the deployment environment, it allowed for not supporting multi-processes. ## Let&amp;rsquo;s illustrate with an example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario:&lt;/strong&gt; A long high-speed train journey, coding is a good choice. With limited traffic, processing a few images, obtaining image materials, downloading software to process the images is a bit extravagant, and network conditions aren’t ideal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt; There’s a batch of image materials with transparent backgrounds intended for use as navigation bars in small programs. The selected state is colored, and the unselected state is black and white. The materials are all in color, and they need to be preprocessed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Due to local development being on a &lt;code&gt;windows&lt;/code&gt; system, the first answer given by &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt; did not include the &lt;code&gt;main&lt;/code&gt; function and lacked &lt;code&gt;multiprocessing.freeze_support&lt;/code&gt;. The code was fixed after following up and encountering an error.
Just as learning search engine techniques required effort, we also need to learn how to communicate with &lt;code&gt;AI&lt;/code&gt;, providing reasonable and sufficient constraints to efficiently obtain the desired answers.
Note: &lt;strong&gt;If you are a programming beginner, if you still don&amp;rsquo;t understand certain parts of the code based on the given comments, please continue to ask related questions.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
