<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Life on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Life on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 May 2025 02:57:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>From Games to Family: Why We Gradually Disconnect from Virtual Worlds as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Thinking about when gaming is most enjoyable, is it sneaking away as a child to play Tank Battle, Super Mario, and Contra on the family TV, or secretly playing Age of Empires with my cousin on the family computer, or perhaps later in college, playing games like Devil May Cry and League of Legends with my roommates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you were a child, free from life&amp;rsquo;s worries, when you played, you really put your whole heart into it – that sense of immersion is something you can never find again as an adult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As times change and society progresses, we who were once active in the virtual world are gradually realizing that the gaming platform, once full of joy and competition, seems to be drifting away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players gradually moving on, is not only due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves, but also because of a shift in the center of our lives. As we grow older, we become busy with marriage and having children, and the main focus of life gradually shifts from personal entertainment to family responsibilities. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the deeper reasons behind this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many people&amp;rsquo;s youth, games were more than just entertainment; they were a way to socialize. A popular online multiplayer game not only provided in-game challenges and competition but also connected players from all over the world, building virtual social circles. In that era, playing dungeons and team PKing with friends was part of life. Those late-night voice chats and sharing daily experiences became part of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as time passed, more and more players discovered that this virtual social experience didn&amp;rsquo;t have lasting appeal. With game updates and the diversification of social platforms, players gradually found more ways to interact outside of games. Friends made in games slowly disappeared from our lives, and many connections once active within the games were silently severed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;games-and-responsibility-a-shift-in-lifes-focus-after-adulthood&#34;&gt;Games and Responsibility: A Shift in Life&amp;rsquo;s Focus After Adulthood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering adulthood, the responsibilities in life gradually increase. Many young people once invested a lot of time in games, but with the start of their careers or living together with partners and starting families, these previously seemingly essential leisure activities begin to be squeezed by the responsibilities of real life. Marriage, having children, or even caring for parents – these major responsibilities in life force people to make choices about energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming has become a thing of the past, replaced by the prioritization of family life. Many young people who once &amp;ldquo;struggled&amp;rdquo; in games are gradually realizing that real-life is the most important subject. Especially after having children, the center of gravity in their lives completely shifts towards family, and gaming is gradually squeezed to the periphery of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-family-how-changes-in-life-affect-our-entertainment-habits&#34;&gt;From Games to Family: How Changes in Life Affect Our Entertainment Habits
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our life experiences, family is one of the most important components. Once we enter family life, the allocation of time and energy becomes more specific and limited. To take care of children and spend time with their partners, many young parents find that they no longer have enough time to focus on the games they once loved. Sometimes, they even stop pursuing game updates and new features. Gradually, social platforms and offline interactions with friends and family become the preferred choice for socializing for more people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we’ve completely abandoned entertainment, but rather chosen ways that are more suitable for our current life stage. Many friends who used to maintain connections through games may now choose other ways to stay in touch due to different life paths, such as family gatherings, meals together, and short trips.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;farewell-to-the-virtual-world-how-do-we-view-this-transition&#34;&gt;Farewell to the virtual world: How do we view this transition?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who once immersed themselves in gaming, saying goodbye to game-related social interactions isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. After all, that virtual world that once brought us joy and a sense of accomplishment has long become part of our memories. However, farewell doesn’t mean severing ties completely; instead, as life changes, we begin to make different choices to balance our roles in real life. As we grow older, we transition from inexperienced youths into responsible adults, and while gaming still holds value, it can no longer be the main theme of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, this shift also reflects an aspect of human adaptability—our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle according to different stages. When responsibility and family become the core of life, gaming socialization is no longer a priority but rather a form of occasional leisure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-gaming-perhaps-it-will-usher-in-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;The future of gaming: perhaps it will usher in another wave of &amp;ldquo;sense of belonging.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, with social development and technological advancements, the forms and content of games are also constantly evolving. For example, current online multiplayer games have begun to move towards more relaxed and flexible approaches, and some even emphasize family interaction and parent-child relationships in their design. In the future, we may see more game formats that better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people still feel nostalgia and passion when talking about &amp;ldquo;childhood games,&amp;rdquo; perhaps in the future, we too may unexpectedly pick up those old games again, entering that virtual world once more with new understanding and insights&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-is-changing-but-love-remains&#34;&gt;Life is changing, but love remains
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s games or family, the changes in life always accompany our growth. In this process, we gradually realize that although the virtual world brings us endless joy and excitement, ultimately, we return to reality, to that warmest place – family. We don’t need to regret leaving games behind, because every stage of life has its own unique meaning. And these changes are precisely what make us become more complete individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Going out for a walk is always good</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had followed my family&amp;rsquo;s plans and diligently studied electrical engineering without venturing into coding, I probably would have been a typical obedient son&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shaking off the dust of memories, it all started with a conversation with my roommate near Chinese New Year, and I took the opportunity to reflect on these past years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gaokao results weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly good or bad. I graduated from a 211 university, and according to my dad’s original plan, I should have studied power grids diligently and returned to work at the local power supply bureau in our hometown. As mentioned earlier, I forgot to mention one key aspect of how I ended up on the IT path: my views on money and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still in a rural school in the first year of junior high, my family arranged for me to transfer to a city school by the second year. It felt like Liu姥姥 visiting the Grand View Garden—I had trouble adjusting to the bustle of the city. I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone to the cinema many times as a child, and certainly not with my parents; relatives did take me occasionally. Luckily, I made friends with several like-minded guys. Though we don’t keep in touch much now, that time of youth looks back fondly. After weekend tutoring, we would collect plastic bottles from the classroom, expertly crushing them with our feet before packing them into backpacks to bring home for my mom to save. Once we had enough, we&amp;rsquo;d find someone who collected recyclables to take care of them. We played chess, badminton, and Dou Di Zhu (a card game), and the losers would do push-ups as punishment. I was a little grateful then that my dad had been getting me to do various exercises since I was young. From this point on, my view of money became slightly skewed, and I felt a bit insecure. But these small misfortunes were fleeting. My family wasn’t wealthy; we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much pocket money, and sometimes I couldn’t play with the other students, especially on weekends. My parents’ efforts were visible to the naked eye as we moved from the village to the city. The seeds had been planted, waiting to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As someone not particularly bright, I was generally very happy during my time studying. Just like many people don&amp;rsquo;t realize until after they graduate, studying isn’t that difficult; the conversion between input and output is relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Layering memories of the imperial era from childhood, and then encountering a laptop during university was like opening Pandora&amp;rsquo;s Box. I came into contact with games and formed connections with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, purchasing goods upstream and slowly selling them through my own network to make a little money. Gradually, I understood the entire chain’s operational logic. The goods we sold were nothing more than those batch-incubated by upstream programs, their costs approaching zero. At this point, things started going slightly off track. Within my major, there were specialized subfields – on one side was power grids, and on the other, automation (a very diverse field including chip programming and factory electrical automation). I realized that programs could make a lot of money, not just a little, and upstream channels indeed earned a great deal. Coupled with my existing programming background, I started dabbling here and there, making some small sums of money. When choosing a specialization, it naturally led me to automation. I skipped many of the required courses in my junior year, my mind constantly focused on writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article last year mentioned that, driven by a romanticized view of hackers and with the kindness of IT experience outside of formal education, I dabbled in assembly, penetration testing, game hacks, DLL hijacking, and account theft, becoming familiar with various black and gray industries. My parents taught me how to be a good person, and the law still advised me; I didn&amp;rsquo;t go completely astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous link: [That Year We Were Young]({&amp;lt; relref &amp;ldquo;/post/2023/01-09-那时少年&amp;rdquo; &amp;gt;}})&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had one relationship during college, but looking back now, it was more about longing for the kind of love seen in TV dramas. At that time, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t mature enough to understand how to truly love someone, let alone build a family and establish myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been fortunate amidst the tide of time. After a period of upheaval during my university years, I naturally couldn’t pursue graduate studies and started working right after graduation. Riding the wave of the IT industry, things have gone smoothly. It’s already been eight years since I started working, and as the hot money in the industry disappears, it&amp;rsquo;s gradually coming to a close. Sometimes I wonder if my initial choices were wrong; perhaps entering the power grid as my father suggested would have been a better option. I might have had those thoughts during the first five years of my career, but they slowly faded away. Joining Hang Seng through campus recruitment, I didn’t change companies for five years. There are definitely shortcomings in terms of technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following arrangements from the Hangzhou headquarters, I went to the Shenzhen branch, where I experienced a workplace struggle (only later did I understand the underlying issues – both sides lost, and the ultimate winner was the board). Driven by my passion for technology, I returned to Hangzhou, carrying a bit of youthful naivete, and then left Hangzhou, moving to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle down, register household registration, and buy a house in Hangzhou. With interest rates at their peak and housing prices at their highest, entering the market would mean being stuck with a mortgage right away. My family savings are limited, so I can’t afford this kind of financial strain. The thought of getting married while carrying that mortgage burden, combined with the downturn in the industry, makes me emotionally unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After so many years, having seen so much, I&amp;rsquo;ve been foolish and reckless myself. Currently, things are going well. Going through some experiences and encountering certain people has gradually matured me. If I had stayed at home all this time, I wonder in what form the flaws in my personality would have erupted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>That young man, perhaps had some talent, but not much</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been seven years since I started working, and the positive feedback from writing code isn&amp;rsquo;t as much as it used to be. Looking back on how I got on this &amp;ldquo;coding&amp;rdquo; path.
The more choices a person makes, especially when they are young, the more they tend to follow positive feedback, actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city, encountering computer books? Hacker materials? Becoming familiar with the Windows system? These are all later stories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I should be transported back to when I was a kid, sneaking around with my cousin using our family&amp;rsquo;s computer to play games; my cousin’s uncle ran a shop in the computer district
We started using computers relatively early on, so we developed a basic understanding of them. Later, in school and during computer classes, I also had quite an interest.
I heard about the computer competitions in junior high school, and thought they were really cool. After transferring schools, that matter was put on hold.
When I was in junior high, I was familiar with basic computer operations and could easily stand out during computer class
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with it, yes, you haven&amp;rsquo;t mistaken yourself, not skilled, but familiar with Microsoft Office software, that would be even more impressive&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving&#34;&gt;Moving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the moving situation, once I got into the city, due to my neighbors, I came into contact with the library. Although I read a lot of novels, I also read many magazines.
Computer News, Popular Software
I&amp;rsquo;ve become increasingly interested in computers, and as a child I had a great admiration for hackers, actively learning related knowledge at school
Understanding the basics of operating systems: Control Panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;Computer World&amp;rdquo; magazine&amp;rsquo;s beginner-friendly content is quite suitable; it always uses case studies to explain system operations
《Popular Software》recommends various software, industry news, &lt;strong&gt;and of course, game news; the initial motivation also planted the seeds for games.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;three-high-school&#34;&gt;Three. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in my second year of high school, &lt;strong&gt;Boge transferred to our class; several senior students had been directly admitted through the computer competition for the previous two years&lt;/strong&gt;, and the school leaders also valued this competition
There&amp;rsquo;s also a foundational hardware aspect; an alumnus of ours donated a building to the school, a new library, a new computer lab – it’s all so coincidental
With Bo’s popular science explanation, he would be considered a computer expert in the class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A top student with computer skills, knowing how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable surveillance software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition, despite its challenges, made it to the finals. I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully understand everything, and the questions were mostly about basic algorithms, but I did gain some insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still just half a bucket of water, it’s like taking a trip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-college&#34;&gt;Four, College
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it came time to choose a major in college, I listened to my family and chose automation, but what I really wanted was to study high-voltage electricity. After returning home, I entered the power supply bureau, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t learn much from my coursework.
Self-directed learning ability is practically non-existent in professional courses, but when it comes to computer science courses in large lectures, I find them very easy and natural&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping required courses, studying computer science diligently, and spending my days on forums like &amp;ldquo;Jingyi Forum&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;52PoP.&amp;rdquo;
Combining my knowledge of assembly and C++ from my studies, I started earning money by taking on projects from forums. It&amp;rsquo;s been going well, with increasing positive feedback, and it’s gotten to the point where it’s difficult to turn back.
In the end, Xiao Professional chose to write code for chips; my family didn&amp;rsquo;t interfere much and let me choose myself&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At this time, &lt;strong&gt;the third key figure: Tangge&lt;/strong&gt;, with a high level of education, joined Baidu
My older sister understands me; she knows I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a state of mind to think and research, so she told me to talk it over with my cousin
Figure out the development path for next steps, don&amp;rsquo;t go home for summer vacation, stay with the mentor and work on projects to gain experience
Relied on a still-decent transcript, I got into Hengan Electronic&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five, Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a key point, I know I took courses on wall-climbing and elective subjects: Computer Information Retrieval, knowing how to quickly find and locate materials and problems
A helpful person appeared at work, &lt;strong&gt;Shuo&lt;/strong&gt;, who gave me time to learn on my own, troubleshoot and get to the root of problems, and introduced me to the experts at the R&amp;amp;D center
This also laid the groundwork; Shenzhen Branch believes I&amp;rsquo;m very capable, and I successfully took responsibility for the transaction channel team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where the problem lies; I have a lack of foundational knowledge in areas like computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design
It&amp;rsquo;s all based on my own historical experience, not systematic learning
It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make mistakes, constantly revising and negating previous code designs, lacking a guiding principle for module design. After seven years, I’m starting to feel burnt out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right, you are a person and an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your sense of calm. We don’t discuss those great individuals who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;me-now&#34;&gt;Me now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average wages, or even considering salaries back home, my current income is already far above average – what more could I possibly be unsatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning a million; when you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think about earning ten million. This is human nature, and people must confront their own inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s that red-eyed thing, is it a more relaxed way of making money: short videos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see here is a short video, but what you don’t see is the scriptwriting and filming behind it. But everyone has a dream of being a genius, believing they are suited for that industry, that they are naturally gifted.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-to-contact&#34;&gt;Begin to contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve watched so many videos. If you analyze the shots a little bit with your own brain, it’s obvious they have professional editing techniques and a very strong cinematic feel. Basically, that means some of them are from film school backgrounds. Of course, there’s logic behind grassroots success stories, but that doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, there are also many videos teaching you how to make videos. It&amp;rsquo;s then that people realize things – if it were truly profitable, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithm&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithm
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, when Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm recommended movie clips and anime clips, I would keep watching them and find them quite interesting. But then, when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began recommending all sorts of tutorial videos non-stop, filling my entire recommendation feed. And I’m in the IT industry myself. At this point, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t help but wonder if those guys who designed the algorithm had a problem with their heads – are you suggesting that I&amp;rsquo;m stupid or that they&amp;rsquo;re stupid? The key thing is, it keeps finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money using Douyin, trying different angles and types. This article is being written by me at 3 AM, and I didn’t even want to write it. I just wonder how long this business model can last, and for how long can it consume everyone&amp;rsquo;s time?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s laughable when you lecture others on how to do things, but can’t control yourself when it comes to your own actions. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically. Here, I just casually rant. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least now, in terms of real-time news dissemination and promotion of national policies, they are actively cooperating. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to when I was studying, it strikes me. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology here. If you can see this line, you’ll notice that the entire draft is very conversational. And honestly, I just kept reading it until it was finished. I used to use Sogou Input Method, for about seven or eight years. But when it comes to voice input, I have to say that iFlytek is still the professional choice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? Having a dream that the number of articles this year can exceed one hundred – that’s a dream for me. It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles, just some records. I examine myself three times a day; you’ll surely think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is it that we spend our whole lives pursuing?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Master Wang Xizhi said: A woman&amp;rsquo;s companionship, over a lifetime of looking up and down, may be found in the depths of one’s heart through understanding her words; or it may be entrusted to someone and exist beyond the confines of the body&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s life is like a flash of lightning, fleeting and ephemeral. Like grass and trees flourishing in spring and withering in autumn, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, in this life, I have so many desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lying by the stream as a child, peeling lotus pods, busily releasing kites in the east wind, chasing after yellow butterflies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He also leaned against mulberry trees to learn how to grow melons; returning with a full meal after dusk, he would still lie beneath the bright moon without taking off his raincoat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I hope to achieve distinction in the imperial examinations, have a beautiful companion by my side, enjoy endless wealth, rise through the ranks steadily, be surrounded by esteemed guests, and celebrate every night with music and revelry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing old, yet desiring health and longevity – welcome servants, await children, a game of chess, a close friend, a pot of wine, a courtyard, and enjoying family life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see how people rush about, all for a few pieces of silver. Yet those few pieces of silver can resolve countless sorrows in the world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A large number of people are still struggling to make a living, where do they have time to pursue meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fact, a person&amp;rsquo;s life is just an experience, like grass, trees, and the sun and moon, experiencing the cycle of desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not understanding life leads to the feeling that one is like a mayfly adrift in the universe, a grain of sand in the vast ocean. Sorrow for the brevity of my existence, envy of the endlessness of the Yangtze River. Understanding life brings joy in what you encounter, satisfaction with what you gain, contentment and self-sufficiency, unaware of approaching old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, you can pursue poetry, wine, flowers, and tea; you can pursue the clear breeze on the river, or the bright moon in the mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But don&amp;rsquo;t be overly concerned with the outcome, as outcomes are fleeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To exhaust a lifetime, arriving in this world, striving to experience as much of life’s joys and sorrows, birth, aging, sickness, and death as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this line from Big Fish &amp;amp; Begonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are very short, and we will eventually lose them, so why not be a little bolder? Love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream. There are many things in life that have no answers, so why not be a little bolder?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like “The Pavilion of Prince Shaobo” and “Ode to the Red Cliffs.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The cause of the feeling that arises when recalling people of the past is as if it were a contract. I have never failed to feel grief and regret upon contemplating literature, unable to fully grasp it in my mind. Indeed, I know that life and death are vain conceits, and equating all lives is a foolish fabrication. Those who come after will view us as we now view those of the past. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lost</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at a certain stage in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. In the mundane routine of work, they gradually lose sight of the pursuit of meaning in their profession. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations. Back then, I would have said without hesitation that I longed to write code—code that could amaze and be incredibly impressive. However, since starting work, I&amp;rsquo;ve been exposed more to business-related matters, much of which is thanks to the benefits brought about by industry development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t included marriage, having children, and establishing a family or career within my sphere of thought. My mind is almost empty, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. Every weekend, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day staying at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something in their life that they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-a-house&#34;&gt;Buy a house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was still thinking about saving up to buy my own house and carefully calculating every expense towards that goal. However, seeing the prices of houses continue to rise, I went from initial anxiety and resentment to eventually becoming numb. I gradually felt that even if I bought a house, it would just be another heavy burden on me, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was to achieve small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, buying a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. But now, I approach saving money with a more relaxed attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses, eating what I want when I see it, and daring to try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I longed for most in my heart was simply to go home. It didn&amp;rsquo;t require doing anything special, just returning to that familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
