<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Social-Media on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/social-media/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Social-Media on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Era of Wild Capitalism: The League of Legends Esports Era Concludes</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-era-league-of-legends-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid growth over the past decade, becoming a significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Games like League of Legends (LOL) have not only provided players with competitive entertainment but also fueled capital investment, driving the development of various esports platforms and events. However, this trajectory is now entering a gradual decline alongside the influx of capital and the rise of the pan-entertainment industry. The rise and fall of Panda TV, as well as the competition between Douyu and Huya, mark the end of an era of &amp;ldquo;wild capitalism,&amp;rdquo; suggesting shifts in the favorable conditions for the esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-investment&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The early esports industry had humble beginnings, particularly in China. Many players participated in competitions for games like StarCraft and Dota fueled by their passion. However, esports truly began to rise with the release and promotion of League of Legends. After League of Legends officially entered the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community into part of mainstream culture. Especially starting in 2013, the LPL (Chinese professional league) steadily developed, making League of Legends the cornerstone of China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2015 marked a turning point for the esports industry in China. The influx of capital transformed esports from simple competitions into a much larger ecosystem. Panda TV, as one example, became a product of excess capital. Founded with investment from Wang Sicong, Panda TV rapidly gained popularity by attracting viewers and users with its innovative content and substantial investments. However, this also exemplified the &amp;ldquo;barbaric&amp;rdquo; influx of capital – a relentless pursuit that often lacks patience and long-term vision. While significant short-term achievements were made through considerable financial and human resources, Panda TV ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019 due to management issues and overreliance on capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The fall of Panda TV did not lead to a decline in the esports streaming industry, but rather spurred the rise of platforms like Douyu and Huya. These two giants quickly became leaders in the esports sector, with increasingly fierce competition between them. Douyu initially gained prominence through livestreaming League of Legends professional matches and signing top streamers, setting a benchmark for esports broadcasting. Huya, by increasing investment in esports events and diversifying its platform, gradually narrowed the gap with Douyu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Capital played a significant role in this process. Bilibili successfully went public in 2018, and Huya also conducted an IPO that same year. The rapid flow of capital led to high industry concentration and intense competition between platforms for streamers and copyrights, resulting in a &amp;ldquo;capital war.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-convergence-of-pan-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Convergence of Pan-Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With increased investment in the esports industry, esports platforms are gradually diversifying their content. Esports hosts are expanding beyond game commentary and event streaming to include various entertainment formats such as singing, dancing, and interactive live streams. This has resulted in a richer content ecosystem centered around esports but incorporating diverse entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, the trend towards broad entertainment has brought problems—the originally focused gaming culture of esports is gradually being marginalized, replaced by a trend prioritizing entertainment above all else. This shift has caused some viewers who were deeply passionate about esports culture to feel alienated, and capital is increasingly turning its attention to other entertainment sectors. Excessive investment and profit-seeking are blurring the essence of the esports industry, weakening the core value proposition centered on competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the rise of short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and other pan-entertainment industries, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to broader entertainment content. Consequently, giants like Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance are no longer solely reliant on esports projects for profit but have increased investment in areas such as film, music, and short videos. Notably, ByteDance&amp;rsquo;s rise, fueled by the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin, has overshadowed esports’ prominence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-generational-shift-the-fading-era-of-dividends&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends&amp;rsquo; &amp;ldquo;Generational Shift&amp;rdquo;: The Fading Era of Dividends
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since League of Legends entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has become synonymous with the esports industry, fostering countless professional players, teams, and events, and driving a massive esports ecosystem. However, over a decade later, as a leading project in Chinese esports, League of Legends is entering a stage of generational transition. Notably, its influence has been gradually declining in recent years, even showing signs of significant decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
The most noticeable change is a generational shift in the player base. Initially, esports&amp;rsquo; rapid growth was fueled by a large cohort of young players, many of whom became professional players or viewers thanks to League of Legends. This generation grew up during a period of &amp;ldquo;demographic dividend,&amp;rdquo; immersed in the game’s competitive appeal and driving industry expansion. However, as time passed, these players matured, entered society, and shifted their focus towards other aspects of life and careers. Simultaneously, younger generations show less enthusiasm for League of Legends, resulting in an evident age gap and declining interest within the esports audience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!
Despite numerous updates and revisions, League of Legends&amp;rsquo; content innovation is struggling to keep pace. Annual version updates, hero balance adjustments, and the introduction of new gameplay features have failed to fundamentally address players’ need for novelty. Simultaneously, the MOBA market is becoming saturated, and other game genres like Honor of Kings and Peacekeeper Elite have rapidly gained popularity, diverting a significant number of players away from League of Legends. This competitive landscape has left League of Legends perpetually in a “chaser” role.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-what-is-the-future-of-the-esports-industry&#34;&gt;Conclusion: What is the future of the esports industry?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that seemingly sprung up overnight. Excessive capital wanders within the internet sector, seeking the next opportunity, and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China&amp;rsquo;s demographic dividend, the industry achieved rapid success, but this success lacks a solid foundation. Over-investment in capital, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering healthy development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before college, I didn&amp;rsquo;t play many games. League of Legends accompanied a generation’s growth; I watched so many finals. As an outsider, comparing Chinese and Korean players—especially Faker—Chinese players always felt hesitant during major tournaments. I understand the psychological pressure on players, but after more than ten years of development in this industry, mental health should be prioritized by teams. However, it hasn&amp;rsquo;t been, and gameplay still relies on players’ innate talent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Games to Family: Why We Gradually Drift Away from Virtual Worlds as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-drift-away-from-virtual-worlds/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What were the happiest times playing games – sneaking to play Tank Battle, Super Mario, and Contra on our family&amp;rsquo;s TV as a child, or secretly playing Age of Empires on our family’s computer with my cousin, or later in college, playing Devil May Cry and League of Legends with my roommates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Childhood had no worries, and when you played, you were completely absorbed in it – a level of immersion that&amp;rsquo;s impossible to find again as an adult&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As times change and society progresses, we who were once active in virtual worlds are gradually realizing that the game platform filled with joy and competition seems to be drifting away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players&amp;rsquo; gradual departure, is not only due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves, but also because of a shift in our life’s focus. As we grow older, we become busy with marriage and having children, and the main thread of life gradually shifts from personal entertainment to family responsibilities. Today, let&amp;rsquo;s discuss the underlying reasons behind this trend.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many, games weren&amp;rsquo;t just entertainment during their youth; they were a social outlet. Popular online multiplayer games offered challenges and competition while connecting players worldwide, creating virtual communities. Playing dungeons and team battles with friends was part of life back then, as were late-night voice chats and sharing daily experiences – memories we cherish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, with time, more and more players have found that this virtual social experience lacks lasting appeal. As games are updated and new platforms emerge, players increasingly find more interactive ways to socialize outside of gaming. In-game friendships gradually fade from view, and many previously active social connections within the game eventually dissolve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;games-and-responsibility-a-shift-in-lifes-focus-after-adulthood&#34;&gt;Games and Responsibility: A Shift in Life&amp;rsquo;s Focus After Adulthood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Entering adulthood, responsibilities gradually increase. Many young people once invested significant time in games, but with the start of their careers or shared living/family formation, these previously essential leisure activities are squeezed by life&amp;rsquo;s obligations. Marriage, having children, and even caring for parents – these major responsibilities require choices regarding energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming has become a thing of the past, replaced by the prioritization of family life. Many young people who once &amp;ldquo;struggled&amp;rdquo; in games are gradually realizing that real-life is the most important matter. Especially after having children, the focus of their lives shifts completely to family, and gaming is pushed to the periphery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-family-how-changes-in-life-affect-our-entertainment-choices&#34;&gt;From Games to Family: How Changes in Life Affect Our Entertainment Choices
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In our life experiences, family is one of the most important components. Once entering family life, time and energy become more specific and limited. To care for children and spend time with their partners, many young parents find they no longer have enough time to focus on games they once loved. Sometimes, they even lose interest in game updates and new releases. Gradually, social media platforms and offline interactions with friends and family become the preferred way for many people to socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean we’ve completely abandoned entertainment, but rather chosen ways more suitable for our current life stage. Many friends who used to connect through games may now maintain contact via other means—family gatherings, meals together, or short trips—due to diverging life paths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;farewell-to-the-virtual-world-how-do-we-view-this-shift&#34;&gt;Farewell to the virtual world: How do we view this shift?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who once immersed themselves in gaming, saying goodbye to game-related social connections isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. That virtual world, which brought us joy and a sense of accomplishment, has become part of our memories. However, farewell doesn’t mean severing ties completely; it means making different choices as life changes, balancing our roles in the real world. As we mature from youthful boys to responsible adults, while games still hold value, they can no longer be the main theme of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this shift reflects a facet of human adaptability—our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle according to different stages. When responsibilities and family become central to life, gaming socialization is no longer a priority but rather an occasional pastime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;future-games-may-usher-in-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;Future games: may usher in another wave of &amp;ldquo;sense of belonging.&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, with social development and technological advancements, the forms and content of games are constantly evolving. For example, modern online multiplayer games are increasingly moving towards more relaxed and flexible approaches, and some even prioritize family interaction and parent-child relationships. In the future, we may see more game formats that better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people still feel nostalgia and passion when talking about &amp;ldquo;childhood games,&amp;rdquo; perhaps we, in the future, will also unexpectedly revisit those past games, bringing new understanding and experience, and re-enter that virtual world&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-is-changing-but-love-remains&#34;&gt;Life is changing, but love remains
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it&amp;rsquo;s games or family, life’s changes consistently accompany our growth. We gradually realize that while virtual worlds offer endless joy and excitement, we ultimately return to reality, to the warmest place – home. There’s no need to regret leaving games, as each stage of life has its own unique meaning. These changes are what make us more complete.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of games: A convergence of psychological development and social entertainment</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment-intersection/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today&amp;rsquo;s digital age, gaming has evolved beyond a simple form of entertainment and become an integral part of daily life. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of people across various age groups and are closely linked to social interaction and recreation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental state
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in a stage of exploring themselves and establishing their identity, therefore games can allow them to try on different roles and lives, satisfying curiosity and the desire for exploration. As they age, personal interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;At the same time, gaming has become a social activity, especially for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, which serve as a bridge for socializing. However, as people age, their social circles stabilize and social needs may be met through more mature means, diminishing the role of gaming in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;taking-a-girl-out&#34;&gt;Taking a girl out
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In China, due to a lack of relationship education, children are pressured to focus solely on academics by their parents, then immediately pushed into relationships upon graduation—a very common phenomenon&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lacking stable emotional relationships due to busy schedules, work commitments, or a lack of social skills can lead to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;However&lt;/strong&gt;, by helping and protecting female players, they experience a sense of being needed and valued, achieving emotional fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the same time, the game&amp;rsquo;s clear interaction rules and controllable environment offer certainty and a sense of security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real life, reducing fears about unpredictable social interactions. However, prolonged reliance on virtual gratification within games may negatively impact their ability to form and maintain healthy emotional relationships in reality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reality-pressure&#34;&gt;Reality pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games offer a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of reality. This is particularly true for young people facing academic stress, family issues, or relationship difficulties, for whom games may be a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are often designed to provide players with a sense of accomplishment and recognition for completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they offer a feeling of being appreciated and acknowledged, which they may lack in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;after-getting-older-they-dont-like-playing-anymore&#34;&gt;After getting older, they don&amp;rsquo;t like playing anymore
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing more time and energy for gaming. As they enter the workforce and start families, increased responsibilities make time and energy more valuable, potentially leading to gaming being seen as a time sink rather than a preferred leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests evolve. What might appeal to someone in their youth—fast-paced, visually impressive games—may later give way to a preference for strategic, story-driven, or more complex experiences. If the market fails to meet these changing needs, interest will naturally decline.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right – you are a person, and also an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; possessing feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your essence. We won’t discuss the great individuals who willingly sacrifice themselves for society or for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;right-now&#34;&gt;Right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering average wages, or even those in my hometown, my current income is already significantly above average. What more could I possibly want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning a million; once you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning ten million. This is human nature, and one must confront their own inner desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s causing all the envy? It’s the easy money of short videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see is this short video, but you don’t see the scriptwriting and filming behind it. Yet, everyone dreams of being a genius, believing they are naturally suited for that field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-contact&#34;&gt;Begin contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching so many videos, a little analysis reveals clear professional editing and a strong cinematic feel. This suggests they have formal training. While there&amp;rsquo;s logic to grassroots success stories, it doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, you&amp;rsquo;ll find countless videos teaching you how to make videos. That’s when reality sinks in: if this could really make money, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime edits, which were enjoyable to watch. But when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began relentlessly recommending instructional videos, flooding my feed. As someone in the IT industry myself, I couldn’t help but wonder if the team behind the algorithm had lost their minds. Is this recommendation strategy meant to imply that users are foolish? And the fact that they keep suggesting ways to earn money through Douyin, from various angles and types… This piece is being written at 3 AM, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even intend to write it. I just question how long this business model can last and how much time it will consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preaching one thing when instructing others, but failing to control oneself – that&amp;rsquo;s a joke. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven’t published much domestically. Here, I’m just casually complaining. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least currently, it actively assists with the spread of real-time news and the promotion of state policies. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to my school days now. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In today’s era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology. If you can see this line, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the entire draft is very conversational. Honestly, I just read it aloud and wrote it down. I used Sogou Input Method for years, but when it comes to voice input, iFlytek is undoubtedly more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 was changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? It&amp;rsquo;s a dream that the number of entries this year could exceed one hundred – it really is a dream. They aren’t exactly articles, more like records. I examine myself three times a day; you surely can think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
