<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Social-Media on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/social-media/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Social-Media on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/social-media/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>The End of the Age of Barbaric Capital: The End of the League of Legends Esports Era</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:19:39 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/end-of-league-of-legends-era/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The esports industry has experienced rapid development over the past decade and a half, becoming an increasingly significant cultural phenomenon worldwide. Particularly games like &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; (LoL), a MOBA title, have not only provided players with competitive enjoyment but also injected substantial momentum into capital investment, driving the flourishing development of various esports platforms and events. However, this all entered a phase of gradual decline alongside increased capital influx and the rise of the broader entertainment industry. The rise and fall of PandyTV, the competition between DouYu and Huya, marked the end of the “wild capitalism era,” and it seems that the favorable conditions – time, place, people, and heaven – for esports are also beginning to change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.1 Early Esports: From Grassroots to Professionalization&lt;/strong&gt;
The early esports industry started relatively grassroots, especially in the Chinese market. Many players participated in competitive games like &lt;em&gt;StarCraft&lt;/em&gt; and Dota, driven by their love for gaming. However, the true rise of esports began with the release and promotion of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. Following the official entry of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; into the Chinese market in 2011, esports gradually evolved from a niche community to become part of mainstream culture. Notably, starting in 2013, the LPL (China Professional League) began to form, and &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; became the cornerstone of China’s esports industry.
&lt;strong&gt;1.2 Capital Flood: The Rise of PandaTV and Esports Streaming Platforms&lt;/strong&gt;
2015 marked a watershed moment for China&amp;rsquo;s esports industry. The influx of capital transformed esports from purely competitive events into a much larger ecosystem. Pandahua (PandaTV), as one representative, became a product of excessive capital. Funded by Wang Sicong (one of the founders of PandaLive), Pandahua quickly rose to prominence with its innovative content and massive investment, attracting a large number of viewers and users. However, this was also a typical example of capital “barbaric” inflow – the market’s frantic pursuit of capital often lacks patience and long-term vision. Although Pandahua&amp;rsquo;s financial and human resources achieved certain results in the short term, it ultimately declared bankruptcy in 2019 due to management issues and excessive reliance on capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1.3 Live Streaming Platform Competition: The “Capital War” between DouYu and Huya&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-the-rise-of-esports-and-capital-injection-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1: The Rise of Esports and Capital Injection
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The decline of PandaTV did not lead to a decline in the esports live streaming industry; instead, it fueled the rise of platforms like DouYu and Huya. The two major live streaming platforms quickly became leaders in the esports industry, with competition between them intensifying. DouYu initially established itself as a benchmark for esports live streaming through its broadcasts of professional &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; tournaments and by signing top streamers. Meanwhile, Huya gradually narrowed the gap with DouYu through increased investment in esports events and its own diversified platform layout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout this process, capital played a significant role once again. In 2018, DouYu successfully went public, and Huya also completed an IPO the same year. The rapid flow of capital led to industry consolidation and resulted in intense competition between platforms regarding streamers and copyrights, forming a “capital battle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-2-the-fusion-of-mass-entertainment-and-esports&#34;&gt;Chapter 2: The Fusion of Mass Entertainment and Esports
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2.1 The Trend Towards Mass Entertainment: Capital Flows into Diversified Entertainment Projects&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With significant capital investment in the esports industry, esports platforms are gradually moving towards mass entertainment. Esports anchors no longer limit themselves to match commentary and event broadcasts; they begin to expand into singing, dancing, live interaction, and other forms of entertainment. The content on the platform becomes more diverse, gradually forming an ecosystem centered around esports but incorporating various entertainment elements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this trend towards mass entertainment has also brought problems – the original focus of esports culture is being marginalized, replaced by a trend of “entertainment above all.” This trend has caused some fans who originally loved esports culture to feel alienated, and capital is increasingly turning its attention to other entertainment fields. - Excessive capital influx and profit-seeking have gradually blurred the essence of the esports industry, with core values centered around competition weakening.
&lt;strong&gt;2.2 The Rise of Pan-Entertainment Industry: Capital Withdrawal and Transformation&lt;/strong&gt;
As short video platforms, live streaming platforms, and the entertainment industry (including K-pop) have risen, capital has gradually shifted funds from esports to a broader range of entertainment content. In this process, giants such as Tencent, Alibaba, and ByteDance no longer rely solely on esports projects for profit, but have increased their investments in areas such as film, music, and short videos.  In particular, the rise of ByteDance, through the explosive growth of platforms like Douyin (TikTok), has overshadowed esports with other entertainment content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three-league-of-legends-yellow-doesnt-follow-yellow-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter Three: League of Legends’ “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; entered the Chinese market in 2011, it has almost been synonymous with China’s esports industry, achieving countless professional players, teams, and events, and also spawning a massive esports ecosystem. However, after more than a decade, as a leading project in Chinese esports, &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; has entered a phase of “Yellow Doesn&amp;rsquo;t Follow Yellow.” Particularly in recent years, the influence of &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; is gradually declining, even exhibiting obvious signs of decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.1 The “Fracture” in Player Demographics&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most noticeable change is the fragmentation of player demographics. Initially, the rapid development of esports relied on the support of a large number of young players who became professional players or spectators thanks to &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;. That generation of internet addiction teenagers almost grew up under the “timeshare dividend,” immersed in the competitive appeal of League of Legends. This, in turn, drove the rapid expansion of the entire industry. However, as time passed, these players gradually matured and entered society, shifting towards other life and career paths. Simultaneously, a new generation of young players didn’t show the same fervor for &lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt; as in previous years, and the esports audience has developed a noticeable age bias and decline in interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-3-league-of-legends-yellow-never-follows-green-the-decline-of-the-eras-advantage&#34;&gt;Chapter 3: League of Legends’ “Yellow Never Follows Green”: The Decline of the Era’s Advantage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3.2 The “Stagnation” of Game Content&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;League of Legends&lt;/em&gt;, despite numerous updates and revisions, has begun to show signs of stagnation in its competitive appeal. Annual version releases, hero balance adjustments, and the introduction of new gameplay mechanics seem unable to fundamentally address players&amp;rsquo; demand for fresh content. Simultaneously, the MOBA market has become increasingly saturated, with other games (such as &lt;em&gt;Honor of Kings&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;PUBG Mobile&lt;/em&gt;) rapidly rising in popularity and diverting a significant portion of League of Legends’ player base. This competitive landscape has left League of Legends perpetually playing the role of “follower,” unable to break free from its position.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-where-does-the-esports-industry-go-from-here&#34;&gt;Conclusion: Where Does the Esports Industry Go From Here?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The esports industry is like a skyscraper that sprung up seemingly overnight. Excessive capital roams within the internet industry, searching for the next big trend, and esports has become one of their targets. Leveraging China’s demographic dividend, the esports industry achieved tremendous success in a short period. However, this success wasn&amp;rsquo;t built on a solid foundation. Over-investment by capital, talent shortages, and weak game content are all hindering the healthy development of the esports industry. Prior to university, I didn’t play many games, and the League of Legends was essentially a companion throughout my growth. I watched so many World Championships, and as an outsider, comparing Chinese and Korean players, especially Faker, domestic players always felt apprehensive and hesitant during major tournaments. I also understand that professional gamers face immense psychological pressure, but this industry has developed for over ten years, and their mental health issues should be prioritized by the teams – which they weren’t. Domestic gameplay still relies on individual player talent.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Games to Home: Why We Gradually Distance Ourselves from the Virtual World as We Grow Up</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-leave-virtual-worlds-as-we-grow-up/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 07:11:05 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-games-to-family-why-we-leave-virtual-worlds-as-we-grow-up/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;When did I ever feel the most joy playing games? As a child, sneaking onto my parents’ TV to play Tank War, Super Mario, and Space Invaders, or secretly using our computer with my cousin to play Age of Empires – or even in college, playing Devil May Cry and League of Legends with my roommates?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a child, there were no worries about life, and when we played, we truly immersed ourselves completely. That sense of immersion is something you can never find again as an adult.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With the changes in times and social progress, those of us who once thrived in the virtual world have gradually realized that the platform filled with joy and competition seems to be drifting away from our lives. The disconnection of game social links, accompanied by players falling out of line, is not only due to technological advancements and the replacement of games themselves, but also because of a shift in our center of gravity in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-disappearance-of-gaming-socialization-a-tug-of-war-between-virtual-and-real-worlds&#34;&gt;The Disappearance of Gaming Socialization: A Tug-of-War Between Virtual and Real Worlds
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many people’s youth, games were more than just entertainment; they were a social way to connect. A popular multiplayer online game didn&amp;rsquo;t just offer in-game challenges and competition – it connected players from all over the world, building virtual social circles. Back then, playing dungeons together, forming teams for PvP combat, was part of everyday life. Those late-night voice chats and sharing of daily experiences became a cherished part of our memories.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, as time went on, more and more players realized that this experience of virtual socialization didn’t have lasting appeal. With the constant updates and evolution of games, and the diversification of social platforms, players gradually found more interactive ways to connect outside of gaming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;gaming-and-responsibility-the-shift-in-focus-of-adult-life&#34;&gt;Gaming and Responsibility: The Shift in Focus of Adult Life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As you enter adulthood, responsibilities gradually increase. Many young people once invested a significant amount of time in games, but as their careers begin or they start living with partners and forming families, these activities that previously seemed indispensable entertainment are increasingly squeezed by the demands of real-life responsibility. Marriage, having children, even caring for parents, all these major life responsibilities force individuals to make choices about their energy and time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaming becomes a thing of the past, replaced by the priority of family life. Many young people who once “fought” in games gradually discover that real life is the most important subject. Especially after having children, the focus of life completely shifts towards family, and gaming is gradually pushed to the periphery of life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;from-games-to-home-how-life-changes-influence-our-entertainment&#34;&gt;From Games to Home: How Life Changes Influence Our Entertainment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within our life experiences, the family is one of the most important components. And once you enter family life, the division of time and energy becomes more specific and limited. Many young parents find that they no longer have enough time to focus on games they used to love, especially in order to care for children and spend time with their spouses. They often even stop chasing updates and new features in games. Gradually, social platforms and offline interactions with friends and family have become the preferred way for more people to socialize.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This doesn’t mean we completely abandon entertainment activities; it simply means we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen ways that better suit our current life stage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-farewell-of-virtual-worlds-how-do-we-view-this-transition&#34;&gt;The Farewell of Virtual Worlds: How Do We View This Transition?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For many who were once immersed in games, saying goodbye to gaming social wasn’t easy. After all, the virtual world that had once brought us joy and accomplishment had long become a part of our memories. However, farewell doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily mean complete severance; it’s about making different choices as life changes, balancing our roles in real-life. As we grow older from our youthful beginnings into responsible adults, games may still have their value, but they can no longer be the main rhythm of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In reality, this transition also reflects a facet of human adaptability – our ability to adjust our focus and lifestyle as different stages of life unfold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-future-of-gaming-perhaps-well-see-another-wave-of-sense-of-belonging&#34;&gt;The Future of Gaming: Perhaps We’ll See Another Wave of “Sense of Belonging”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Of course, as society and technology continue to develop, the forms and content of games are constantly evolving. For example, modern multiplayer online games have begun to evolve towards more relaxed and flexible ways, with some designs even focusing on family interaction and parent-child relationships. In the future, we may see more game formats that can better integrate into family life and provide players with healthier, more balanced social experiences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Just as many people reminisce about “games from their childhood” with nostalgia and passion, perhaps in a moment of unintentional discovery, we will pick up those games again, bringing with us new understanding and insight, and re-enter that virtual world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;living-in-change-yet-still-loving&#34;&gt;Living in Change, Yet Still Loving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Whether it’s games or family life, the changes in our lives always accompany us as we grow. In this process, we gradually realize that, although the virtual world brings us endless joy and excitement, ultimately, we will return to reality, back to the warmest place of all – family. We don&amp;rsquo;t need to regret leaving games behind because every stage of life has its own unique meaning. And these changes are what make us a more complete person.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The multifaceted nature of gaming: the intersection of psychological development and social entertainment.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2024 15:07:45 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/games-multidimensionality-psychological-development-social-entertainment/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In today’s digital age, games have evolved far beyond a simple form of entertainment and have become an indispensable part of people&amp;rsquo;s daily lives. From a psychological perspective, games play different roles in the mental development of individuals across various age groups, while also being closely intertwined with social and recreational activities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mental-state&#34;&gt;Mental State
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Young people are in the stage of self-exploration and identity formation. &lt;strong&gt;Games provide them with a low-cost environment to try and explore.&lt;/strong&gt; Through games, they can experiment with different roles and lifestyles, satisfying their curiosity and desire for exploration. As they grow older, individuals’ interests and values gradually stabilize, and games may no longer align with their life goals and interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes&#34;&gt;Social Attributes
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Simultaneously, the game has also become a part of social activities, particularly for young people. They make friends and build social networks through games, making games a bridge for socialization. However, as people age, their social circles gradually stabilize, and social needs may be met through more mature ways, leading to a relative reduction in the role of games in socialization.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;social-attributes-bringing-a-sister-with-a-female-player&#34;&gt;Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister (with a female player)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of adequate dating education, parents often simply expect you to study well and then immediately want you to start a relationship after graduation. This phenomenon is very common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, gaining emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real-life interactions, reducing fear of the uncertainties in real-world relationships. ## Social Attributes: Bringing a Sister (with a female player)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within China, due to a lack of adequate dating education, parents often only taught you to study diligently and then immediately expected you to start a relationship after graduation. This phenomenon is quite common.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of busy studies, work, or a lack of social skills, individuals haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to establish stable emotional relationships in real life, leading to feelings of loneliness and a desire for attention. &lt;strong&gt;The “bringing a sister” behavior within games provides an outlet to release this craving.&lt;/strong&gt; By helping and protecting female players, they can experience being needed and valued, achieving emotional satisfaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the interactive rules within games are clearly defined, and the environment is controllable, offering a sense of certainty and security compared to the complexity and uncertainty of real-life interactions, reducing fears associated with the unpredictability of real relationships.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;real-world-pressure&#34;&gt;Real-World Pressure
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Games provide a virtual world where players can temporarily escape the pressures, challenges, or unpleasant emotions of real life. Particularly for young people facing academic pressure, family issues, or interpersonal relationship challenges, games may become a way to seek comfort and relaxation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Games are typically designed to give players a sense of accomplishment and recognition when completing tasks, leveling up, or defeating opponents. Young people may become addicted to games because they can experience a feeling of being appreciated and recognized within them – a feeling that may be lacking in their real lives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;dislike-playing-after-getting-older&#34;&gt;Dislike Playing After Getting Older
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When young, individuals face relatively fewer social responsibilities and pressures, allowing them more time and energy to invest in gaming. As they enter the workforce, start families, and take on other societal responsibilities, time and energy become increasingly valuable, and games may be seen as a drain rather than a preferred leisure activity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As people age, their cognitive abilities and interests also change. They might have been interested in fast-paced, visually stunning games when younger, but with increased experience, they may prefer strategy games, those with strong storylines, or games with greater depth. If the market doesn’t meet these changing needs, interest naturally diminishes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, but also a bipedal animal, complete with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everyday sensibilities&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is far above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you think about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you think about earning one billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but what you don’t see is the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are becoming more aware. If they could really earn money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling. It felt surprisingly engaging, to the point where you’d start to find it interesting yourself. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone who also works in the IT industry, this made me feel like the algorithm overlords were having a bit of a problem – you know, recommending things in this way. They’d constantly find new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they were trying to figure out whether I was stupid or they were. The question is, how long can this business model last? How much time can you drain from people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, just quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet down and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It can&amp;rsquo;t really be called articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must always come up with something, doesn’t it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
