<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Competitive-Gaming on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/competitive-gaming/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Competitive-Gaming on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 05:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/competitive-gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Gaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-esports/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pay-to-Win games, which will not be discussed here within the gaming community; a collective term for “People’s Warriors,” requiring an affluent wallet rather than understanding of game settings. Their enjoyment lies in the surrounding throng of smaller players and the thrill of “raid.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Competitive games with large audiences, such as League of Legends, DOTA, Honor of Kings, and PUBG – these types of games have complete worldviews and their esports events are in a healthy cycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is indeed a key field in game design, with social psychology being particularly important. Understanding people’s behavior, needs, and motivations can help design more engaging gaming experiences. Regarding the relationship between “bragging” and social psychology, we can look at it from the following angles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Validation:&lt;/strong&gt; People often seek to establish a sense of belonging within social groups. In games, if designed to allow players to feel accomplished in certain areas and attract the attention of other players, this can increase their social validation. This may manifest as boasting skills or showcasing earned rewards.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games employ elements of social competition, encouraging players to showcase their achievements within a social network. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate competitive psychology between players, which may lead some players to perform even more impressively in order to gain social recognition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Expression:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games allow players to express themselves through customization options like character avatars and virtual items. This self-expression isn’t just about showing off; it can also be a way to express personality and engage in social interaction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork:&lt;/strong&gt; Certain games emphasize teamwork, achieving game objectives through social interaction. In these scenarios, boasting behavior may not be encouraged but rather emphasizes collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological Reward Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design can utilize psychological reward systems to incentivize positive social behaviors. For example, rewarding players or granting them privileges to encourage active participation in social interactions.
Overall, the application of social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interaction and social experiences. Fluffing (or showing off) behavior can sometimes occur in certain contexts, but game designers typically strive to balance this behavior to ensure the gaming experience is positive and enjoyable for all players.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to get sidetracked when thinking about things; without a complete outline, it does tend to become a bit disorganized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The author’s frequently played League of Legends is considered one of our generation&amp;rsquo;s cherished childhood memories. Most parents don’t like their children playing games, as they haven’t deeply understood or experienced this type of game, and naturally, it has to do with the game’s setting. Each match is a fresh start, and for many kids, when playing, they don’t bring much thought into it, opting for a self-exploratory style of gameplay. Under this mode, the outcome of the game often depends more on the child&amp;rsquo;s inherent gaming talent. Based on the author’s personal experience, a significant portion of players fall into this category; for them…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost isn’t money, it’s time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s also a casual mode within the game, designed to meet the needs of entertainment players.
League of Legends, this competitive game, for me, was more about realizing a “Three Kingdoms dream.” Starting with an empty purse, relying on my own understanding, I farmed, supplemented, spent money, controlled vision, set traps for the enemy team, and it was primarily a game played with my mind – without exceptional gaming talent, I could still have a lot of fun. The feeling of controlling the overall situation, and the joy of turning a disadvantage into a victory. There are also many viewers who often mention “ghost players” – they no longer play the game but still watch the matches during major world championship events.
Here, we must also talk about “game time.” “I’m not talking about the time of a single game, but rather the time you log in. This includes weekend afternoons and evenings between 7 PM and 10 PM during weekdays – at this time, you&amp;rsquo;ll generally find that you can communicate normally with your teammates, receiving their signals and getting responses back. If you switch to other times, such as late-night gaming sessions, you’re more likely to encounter ‘gaming addicts,’ favorable wind conditions (where nothing happens), and players who will greet you with insults when you&amp;rsquo;re behind. Even through the screen, you can feel their ‘hostility.’”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“As someone working in the IT industry and having played many different types of games, I’ve always preferred to play competitive games using my brain – it’s about strategy and execution rather than reaction speed or raw talent. Compared to younger players or professionals, my response time is slower, and I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to leading a team through coordinated strategies.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, how would you describe the current game environment? It’s quite frantic and lacks the pure essence of what it used to be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After graduating, playing high-level games was really exhausting – it required complete focus throughout the entire match, thinking about the opponent’s plans and how to counter their setups. It&amp;rsquo;s that feeling where you don&amp;rsquo;t want to continue after finishing a game.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you say you play very well, without professional competition, it wouldn’t have much impact on one’s life trajectory. While it can be used as a social tool, it cannot provide a livelihood or establish oneself in society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player and online games are two different types of games with significant differences in gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the distinction between single-player and online games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection Method:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-player Games (Offline/Single-player):&lt;/strong&gt; These games are played on a local device alone, without requiring an internet connection. Players can enjoy the game experience even without network connectivity. - &lt;strong&gt;Online/Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; These games typically require an internet connection because players need to interact in real-time with other players. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online social interaction and esports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player Interaction:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players primarily interact with in-game artificial intelligence, pre-set tasks, or hostile elements. The gaming experience is typically more personalized and influenced by the game’s design and storyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include collaborating on missions, competing against each other, participating in esports, and social elements such as chat, guild systems, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design and Content:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design focuses more on providing a complete and independent storyline and gaming experience. Game content is typically pre-designed, and players explore, solve puzzles, or engage in combat within the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multiplayer Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design needs to consider real-time interaction and player competition or collaboration. Game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically can run offline with relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connection.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Require a strong internet connection and have high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Model:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically employ a one-time purchase or download model, where players buy the game to play it fully on their local devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; May utilize various business models such as free-to-play, advertising, item purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content.
Understanding these distinctions helps players clarify their preferences when choosing games and enables game designers to better meet player expectations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
