<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Competitive-Gaming on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/competitive-gaming/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Competitive-Gaming on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/competitive-gaming/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Game Psychology: Competitive Gaming</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2023 10:26:22 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/game-psychology-competitive-gaming/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Games of the &amp;ldquo;pay-to-win&amp;rdquo; type, here we will not discuss this; within the gaming community, this is collectively referred to as “Renminbi Warriors” – requiring an affluent wallet rather than understanding game settings. Their enjoyment lies in the entourage of smaller players surrounding them and the thrill of “raid.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Competitive games with a large audience, such as: League of Legends, DOTA, Honor of Kings, PUBG, these types of games have complete worldviews and their game competitions have entered a benign cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Psychology is indeed a key field in game design, and social psychology is particularly important. Understanding people’s behavior, needs, and motivations can help design more engaging gaming experiences. Regarding the relationship between “showing off” and social psychology, we can look at it from the following angles:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Identity:&lt;/strong&gt; People often seek to establish a sense of identity within social groups. In games, if designs allow players to feel they are outstanding in some way, attracting the attention of other players, this may increase their social identity. This could manifest as boasting skills or showcasing earned rewards.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Social Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games have adopted social competition elements, encouraging players to showcase their achievements on social networks. This can be achieved through leaderboards, achievement systems, or multiplayer battles. Such designs stimulate competitive psychology between players and may lead some players to perform more impressively to gain social recognition.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Self-Expression:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games allow players to express themselves through customizing characters, virtual items, etc. This self-expression is not just for showing off; it can also be a way of expressing personality and social communication.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teamwork:&lt;/strong&gt; Some games emphasize teamwork, achieving game goals through social interaction. In such situations, boasting behavior may not be encouraged but rather emphasizes collaboration and mutual support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Psychological Reward Systems:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design can adopt psychological reward systems to stimulate positive social behaviors in players. For example, rewarding or granting privileges to players to encourage them to actively participate in social interactions.
Overall, social psychology in game design can be used to shape player interaction and social experiences. Boasting behavior may exist in some situations, but game designers typically strive to balance this behavior to ensure that the gaming experience is positive and interesting for all players.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking about where I was writing, without a complete outline, it’s a bit chaotic.
The author often plays League of Legends, which is a memory of our generation. Most parents don&amp;rsquo;t like their children playing games because they haven&amp;rsquo;t deeply understood or experienced this type of game; of course, it has to do with the game settings. Each game is a new beginning, and for many children, when they play, they don’t bring much thought into it, belonging to self-exploration gameplay. Under this mode, the outcome of the game depends more on the child&amp;rsquo;s inherent gaming talent. Based on my actual experience, a large part of the players belong to this type, for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The biggest cost is not money, but time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There’s also entertainment mode within the game, designed to cater to recreational players. League of Legends, this competitive game, for me, was more about realizing a “Three Kingdoms dream.” Starting off, you have nothing in your pockets, relying on your own understanding, farming, spending money, controlling vision, setting traps and ambushes for the opponent – it’s largely about thinking your way through the game. Without exceptional gaming talent, you can still find immense enjoyment. The feeling of commanding the overall situation, the joy of turning a losing game around. And there are also many viewers who often mention “casual players” – they no longer play the game but still watch the matches during major world events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It’s worth mentioning “game time.” This isn&amp;rsquo;t referring to the duration of a single match, but rather the amount of time you spend in the game – on weekends in the afternoons, or evenings between 7 pm and 10 pm after work. You’ll find that you can usually communicate normally with your teammates, and your signals are understood and responded to. If you switch to other times, such as playing through the night, you&amp;rsquo;re more likely to encounter “gaming addicts,” favorable situations where nothing happens, and in unfavorable situations, they’ll complain about you to your family – you can almost feel their resentment through the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As someone who works in the IT industry and plays a lot of games, I’ve tried various types, always preferring to think my way through the game rather than relying on reaction speed or talent. Compared to professionals or younger players, my reactions are slower, and I&amp;rsquo;m accustomed to coordinating with teammates and taking command of the team’s strategy. When I first started playing, it was during my student years, guided by older brothers from an YY guild.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, regarding the current game environment, it feels quite agitated and lacks the purity of before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After graduating, playing high-level segment games was really exhausting. The entire game required intense focus, thinking about the opponent&amp;rsquo;s plans, and how to counter their setups. It’s that kind of experience where you don’t want to continue after finishing it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Let’s be honest, if you’re considered a very good player, without professional competition, it wouldn’t have much impact on your life trajectory. While it can serve as a social tool, it&amp;rsquo;s not something you can make a living from or establish yourself in society.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Single-player games and online games are two different types of games that differ significantly in their gameplay, experience, and technology. Here are some key aspects to understand the differences between single-player and online games:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Connection Method:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games (Offline/Single-player):&lt;/strong&gt; These games are played on a local device alone, without requiring an internet connection. Players can enjoy the game experience even without network connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games (Online/Multiplayer):&lt;/strong&gt; This type of game typically requires an internet connection because players need to interact with other players in real time. Online games can be cooperative or competitive, involving online social interaction and esports.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Player Interaction:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players primarily interact with artificial intelligence, pre-set tasks, or opposing elements within the game. The gaming experience is generally more personalized, influenced by the in-game design and storyline.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Players can interact with other real players from around the world. This may include collaborating on missions, competing against each other, or participating in esports competitions, as well as social elements like chat, guild systems, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Game Design and Content:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design focuses more on providing a complete, independent storyline and gaming experience. The game content is typically pre-designed, and players explore, solve puzzles, or fight within the game.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Game design needs to consider real-time interaction and player competition or collaboration. The game content may be more dynamic, including regular updates, online events, and social interactions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Technical Requirements:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Generally run offline, with relatively low requirements for device performance and internet connectivity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Require a strong internet connection and high demands on server and network performance to ensure smooth real-time interaction.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Models:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Single-Player Games:&lt;/strong&gt; Typically use one-time purchase or download business models, where players buy the game to play it fully on their local devices.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Online Games:&lt;/strong&gt; May employ various business models such as free-to-play, advertising, item purchases, or subscriptions to maintain server operations and continuously update game content.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these differences helps players clarify their preferences when choosing games and allows game designers to better meet player expectations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
