<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 22:38:09 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>- Four people in a university dormitory, and ten years later they went in four different directions.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/university-dormitory-four-people-ten-years-later-they-went-in-four-different-directions/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2025 21:37:30 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/university-dormitory-four-people-ten-years-later-they-went-in-four-different-directions/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Lightstone debuted today, and a former roommate from university has been working inside for many years, leading the hardware development of a particular product.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding expertise, Lightstone’s core business is sports cameras, which is most closely related to his undergraduate major: &lt;strong&gt;Automation&lt;/strong&gt;. Automation is a broad field; during his sophomore year, it was divided into smaller specializations. Regarding his former roommate, there were two groups – the first group were freshman roommates, and the second group were sophomore roommates, who were re-assigned when the majors were split up. Our specialization covers embedded systems, engineering automation control, and circuit design—basically a very diverse range.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After graduating from university, four people went in four different directions. Although they were all majoring in automation, each person’s choice was unique. It happened to be a fortunate coincidence that the four roommates – myself and three others – had briefly reunited in Shenzhen for two years. I was assigned to the Shenzhen branch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Myself&lt;/strong&gt; As I&amp;rsquo;ve written in previous articles, I started working in financial IT immediately after graduation, always focusing on Hong Kong and US stocks. The related business content updates on the site are relatively infrequent. To put it another way, while I understand the business and have some knowledge of it, it’s not deep enough. I’ve consistently done transactional-related work, and later expanded to maintaining and monitoring system bottom-layer communications, doing a lot of miscellaneous tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate A&lt;/strong&gt; It seems he started in Ningbo, working on HVAC hardware sales, then moved to Shenzhen. I don&amp;rsquo;t know the details of his previous jobs, but he jumped to ZTE once, leaving during his probation period before it even ended, and then worked at Yijing Technology for several years, leading the R&amp;amp;D of a certain sports camera’s hardware.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate B&lt;/strong&gt; I don’t know his background experiences, currently involved in automotive hardware R&amp;amp;D in Wuhan, having done so for many years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roommate C&lt;/strong&gt; Currently working at Vanke in Shenzhen, doing construction supervision for real estate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-choices&#34;&gt;Life Choices
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’m not really sure about the regrets of the other two, as we haven&amp;rsquo;t been in much contact – the last time I spoke to them was when they were leaving Shenzhen. We had a chaotic dinner with three “idiots” (a playful term) for our friend from Wuhan, and I made him a video call.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Back during university, several of us always said, &amp;ldquo;I shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have gone into automation; I should have gone straight to the computer science department. I really loved writing code here, and we won’t go into detail about why I didn’t choose computer science – I’ve written about it in previous articles.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m this age, money is an unavoidable topic. When I left Shenzhen, it was because of the high housing prices, with the intention of settling down in Hangzhou. Due to a lucky coincidence, I never settled in Hangzhou and instead worked in Shanghai for income. It was fortunate that I didn&amp;rsquo;t buy a property at a high level when Hangzhou’s houses were being absorbed. When I left Shenzhen, it coincided with the hottest period for Chinese-American stocks. I jumped from one company to another and received a salary increase, but lacked clear industry understanding: &lt;strong&gt;domestic lead flow is a gray area, with policy risks.&lt;/strong&gt; Simply put, I circumvented the Hong Kong Connect and traded directly in Hong Kong and American stocks. In 2021, the government abruptly shut down domestic lead flow, causing Chinese brokerage firms to transform and their Hong Kong and American stock businesses to shrink significantly. Basically, in finance, you must comply with regulations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the reason for writing this article, Jieson Group surged dramatically – &lt;strong&gt;270%&lt;/strong&gt; – leading to an offer from within the company to subscribe. The specific amount here is not discussed. I can only say that Roommate A’s down payment on a house in Shenzhen was likely secured. Although we didn&amp;rsquo;t delve deeply into this subscription matter, I was also tempted to subscribe through his channels, but the scale of the investment was too large and I couldn’t handle the risk. Ultimately, Roommate A chose a safer subscription scheme.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We don’t have much capital, so we can’t withstand large losses; even if we could endure it, what good would it do to throw in fifty and try our luck? This kind of opportunity might not come around again in a lifetime.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;life-choices-1&#34;&gt;Life Choices
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To say I haven’t made any money in the past ten years is a lie – I do occasionally envy those who make more, and this decade has been happy because I&amp;rsquo;ve done what I wanted to do, without experiencing any workplace bullying or manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Real estate inevitably brings up the topic of money; after all, a 30% down payment is sitting there, and whether you can make money depends not only on your effort but also on the industry’s cycle and whether it can trend upwards. That would have been an opportunity to invest in Jushi (影石), as they were early on, focusing on overseas products while their domestic reputation was still lacking. The circle of Hong Kong-American stocks had become accustomed to a relaxed lifestyle, and I&amp;rsquo;d essentially given back most of my specialized skills to the school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s a rambling mess; it’s hard for young people to understand an entire industry, let alone formulate ten-year career plans.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;going-global-with-products&#34;&gt;Going Global with Products
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make money in foreign trade, the same products can sell for 1,000 RMB domestically, 3,000 RMB abroad, and even more. Considering the current intense price competition within China, it’s even more advantageous. Jingjie (JingShi) and DJI have already started focusing on the panoramic camera sector.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Both Jingjie and DJI, aside from leveraging the advantages of the Shenzhen industrial chain, product going global is also a crucial factor. The domestic market is fiercely competitive with severe price wars, while foreign markets offer higher prices and larger profit margins, making it easier to survive in the early stages.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Getting out for a walk is always good.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-for-a-walk-is-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If things had gone as the family planned, I would have stuck to studying power grids honestly and diligently, without venturing into coding. Had I erased the dust from my memory, it all stemmed from a chat with my roommate near the Spring Festival, which led to a review of my experiences over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the &lt;em&gt;gaokao&lt;/em&gt; (national college entrance examination) couldn’t be described as good or bad; I got into a 211 university, and according to Dad&amp;rsquo;s original plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work for the local electricity supply bureau. Earlier accounts had also mentioned how to gradually transition onto the IT path – something that hadn’t been fully articulated before: financial perspective and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started my education in a rural school, and after primary school two, my family arranged for me to transfer to a school in the city district. Like Grandma Liu entering the Grand View Garden, I initially struggled to adapt to the bustling prosperity of the city. I hadn’t been to the cinema very often, and specifically, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone with my parents, but relatives would take me. Heaven always bestows luck upon you; back then, I met a few like-minded friends, though we lost contact later on. Looking back, that period of youth was truly wonderful. After weekend tutoring, we’d clean out the classroom plastic bottles, quickly stepping on them to flatten and pack them into our backpacks to take home for Mom to save up – accumulating them until they were enough to find a waste collector to handle disposal. We&amp;rsquo;d play chess, badminton, and Mahjong together, with push-ups as punishment for losing, which we still felt a little fortunate about; Dad had been taking me through various exercises since childhood. From this point on, my financial perspective was slightly skewed, I felt somewhat inferior, but these small misfortunes quickly passed. Our family wasn’t struggling financially, and we didn&amp;rsquo;t have much pocket money, sometimes couldn’t join our classmates in their activities, especially on weekends. Seeing our parents’ efforts as they moved us from the village to the city. At this time, the seed had been planted, waiting for it to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My simple-minded self was generally very happy during my studies, much like many graduates can only appreciate after graduation – studying wasn&amp;rsquo;t really a difficult task; the investment and output converted relatively easily.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one-1&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I layered in the memories of the Age of Empires, and during university, I encountered a laptop – it was like Pandora’s Box opening, introducing me to games and connecting me with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, sourcing goods upstream and selling them through my own community channels, earning a little money. Later, I gradually understood the operational logic of the entire chain. The products we sold were simply mass-produced by upstream programs, and their costs approached zero. At this point, the road had already started to veer off course; there were further subdivisions within the field – on the left was power grids, and on the right was automation (very complex, chip programming, factory electrical automation) – I realized that software could make money, but it wasn’t much. Although the upstream channels did earn a lot, combined with my previous background in programming, I started tinkering here and there, making a little money. When choosing between specialized fields, I naturally chose automation. After finishing my third year of coursework, I didn&amp;rsquo;t attend many classes, constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in last year’s article, inspired by the beautiful vision of hackers, I came into programming through self-study – I learned assembly language, penetration testing, game cheats, DLL hijacking, and data theft, familiarizing myself with various blackware and greyware. My parents taught me how to be a good person, and the law ultimately dissuaded me from going too far down that path; the road didn’t completely deviate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous Post Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/&#34; &gt;That Time When I Was Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also talked about a brief romance during university. Looking back, it was mostly longing for the love depicted in television dramas. As an immature mind at the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand how to love someone, let alone achieve: settling down and starting a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amidst the torrent of times, I was fortunate – university’s tribulations led me to not pursue graduate studies; I immediately entered employment and enjoyed a smooth career path riding the wave of IT. It&amp;rsquo;s now my eighth year in this profession, but the hype money vanished as the industry matured, leading to its decline. Sometimes, I question whether my initial choice was correct – perhaps entering the power grid as suggested by my father would have been a better option. Such thoughts might linger during the first five years of employment, but they gradually fade away with time. My recruitment into HSBC lasted five years without a change of company, which resulted in certain deficiencies regarding technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following arrangements from the Hangzhou headquarters, I relocated to the Shenzhen branch, experiencing a workplace struggle (which, upon reflection, proved detrimental to both sides – ultimately benefiting the board) fueled by my passion for technology. I returned to Hangzhou with a youthful exuberance, only to later withdraw and head to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Initially, I planned to settle in Hangzhou, register, and purchase property during the highest interest rates and peak housing prices, risking being trapped; my finances were limited, making it impossible to bear the burden of mortgage payments, compounded by an industry downturn, leading to emotional instability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having been around for so many years, having seen so much, I’ve made my own mistakes and wasted time. Currently, I&amp;rsquo;m doing well. Through experiences and through people, one inevitably grows and matures. If I were to remain at home all the time, I don’t know what form my flaws would manifest in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Back then, as a young boy, he might have had talent, but it wasn’t common.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/that-boy-talent-maybe-but-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s my seventh year in the job, and I’m not getting as much positive feedback on the code I write. Let me reflect on how I ended up on this &lt;code&gt;coding&lt;/code&gt; path. People’s choices, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re younger, tend to follow positive reinforcement more closely – actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city and coming into contact with computer books? Hacker’s materials? Meeting Windows systems – these are all anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time should be positioned around childhood and sneaking around with my cousin to play games on our parents&amp;rsquo; computer.&lt;/strong&gt; My cousin and I ran a shop with our uncle at the computer store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started having exposure to computers relatively early, and basic understanding was established. Later, in school, taking the microcomputer course also sparked an interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In middle school, I heard about computer competitions, which seemed really cool, but after transferring schools, this fell by the wayside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my junior high years, I was familiar with basic computer operations, and I could easily stand out during microcomputer classes. If you’re still familiar, yes, you&amp;rsquo;ve noticed, it wasn’t proficiency – being familiar with office software would be even more impressive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-moving--relocation&#34;&gt;II. Moving / Relocation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the moving situation. When we moved to the city center, due to the neighbors, we came into contact with the library. Although we read quite a few novels, we also read a lot of magazines, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;大众软件&lt;/em&gt; (Greatest Software)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This led to an increasingly growing interest in computers as a product. The childhood fascination with hackers was actively pursued through relevant knowledge at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned the basics of operating systems: control panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt; is suitable for beginners; each time it explains system operations in the form of case studies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greatest Software&lt;/em&gt; recommends various software, industry news, &lt;strong&gt;and of course, game news – this was the initial motivation, and it also planted the seed for gaming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, Bo Ge transferred to our class, and &lt;strong&gt;several seniors had been guaranteed admission through computer competitions in the previous two years&lt;/strong&gt;. The school leaders also paid a lot of attention to this competition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a prerequisite hardware foundation – an alumnus from America donated a building to the school, which resulted in a new library and a new computer lab; it all seemed so coincidental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plus Bo Ge’s popular science lectures, he was considered the computer guru in our class at that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scholar + computer expert, knew how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable classroom surveillance software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school-1&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The competitions were bumpy and ultimately ended in the finals, where I didn’t quite understand the material and the questions were mostly basic algorithms. However, it was still a worthwhile experience – like taking a short trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-university&#34;&gt;Four. University
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Waiting for university major selection, I chose automation based on my parents&amp;rsquo; recommendation, but I actually wanted to pursue electrical engineering, intending to join the power supply bureau upon graduation. I didn’t learn much in the courses of my major.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My self-driven learning ability was almost non-existent within the major courses; however, I found computer courses within the large curriculum very easy to grasp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attended classes for the major course while skipping lectures and diligently studied computer courses. I spent my daily time browsing forums: “JingYi Forum” (“I Love Crack”),
Combining what I learned from that bit of assembly and C++ knowledge with the skills gained from taking on orders from the forums, I earned more positive feedback and went further and further down this path, unable to be pulled back.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, the choice of a minor led me to choose writing code for chips, and my parents didn’t interfere much, letting me make my own decision.
At that time, &lt;strong&gt;the third key figure: my cousin&lt;/strong&gt; had a high education and worked at Baidu.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My elder sister understood me and knew that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t been focused on research back then, so she encouraged me to talk to my cousin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I confirmed the future development path, didn’t go home during the summer vacation, followed my advisor to work on projects, and gained experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thanks to my still-passable grades, I was admitted to Hengsheng Electronics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five. Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a key point I know – I learned how to bypass firewalls, took elective courses in Computer Information Retrieval, and quickly found and located information and problems. A valuable colleague, &lt;strong&gt;Mr. [硕哥&amp;rsquo;s nickname]&lt;/strong&gt;, appeared at work, gave me time to learn independently, troubleshoot issues down to their roots, and introduced me to the leaders of the R&amp;amp;D center.
These experiences laid the groundwork; in Shenzhen, everyone outside viewed me as exceptionally skilled, successfully leading the transaction channel group.
That’s where the problem lies: I lacked systematic learning in computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design. All my knowledge was based on my own past experience.
This led to frequent self-doubt regarding my code designs, a lack of guidelines for module design, and ultimately, fatigue after seven years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, and also a bipedal animal, with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everydayness&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average salaries or my hometown wages, my current income is significantly above the average – what’s there to be dissatisfied with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you start thinking about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you start thinking about earning a billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not easy to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but you don’t see the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own mind, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are starting to wake up. If they could really make money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling – you’d start to find them interesting. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone in the IT industry myself, I began to feel that the “big brothers” behind these algorithms were having a bit of a problem – you recommend like this, are you thinking I’m stupid or are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; stupid? Crucially, they keep finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, covering different angles and various types. It&amp;rsquo;s as if they&amp;rsquo;re constantly trying to figure out the most effective way to exploit my time. I started wondering how long this business model could last, and how much time they could drain from me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet their minds and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It&amp;rsquo;s not really articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must be able to think of some things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What we have been seeking throughout our lives is…</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/what-we-seek-throughout-life/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang Yi-zi said: Human relationships, spanning a lifetime of mutual support and dependence, may be held within one’s embrace, understood in the confines of one room; or they may arise from entrusted messages, dissolving into the vastness beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a lifetime, like a fleeting flower. Like grass and trees blossoming and withering, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet, in this life, desires are numerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a child, I lay under lotus plants and hemp in the stream, busy catching the east wind to fly kites, chasing yellow butterflies in haste,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also learned to grow gourds by the shade of mulberry trees, returning home with a full meal after dusk, not shedding my cloak to lie beneath the moonlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I grew older, I hoped to be inscribed on the gold list, to have a beautiful woman accompany me, to have endless wealth, to rise continuously, to have a full table of guests, to sing and play every night.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When old, I wanted health and longevity, welcome childhood servants, young children waiting at the door, a chessboard, a confidant, a bottle of wine, a courtyard, enjoying family harmony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see people rushing about in a panic, only seeking a few taels of broken silver. Yet, this broken silver, can it dispel all kinds of melancholy in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half the people are still struggling with their lives, where do they have time to seek meaning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, human life is just an experience, like plants, sun and moon – experiencing the cycle of desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t understand it, you’ll feel like a fleeting moment in the vastness of the world, a tiny grain of sand on the Yangtze River. When you understand it, you’re happy with what you encounter, temporarily possessing yourself, content and self-sufficient, unaware of your approaching old age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, flowers, and tea. You can pursue the clear breeze on the river or the bright moon in the mountains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But don’t overly concern yourself with the results; they will all eventually pass away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a lifetime of hardship, when you arrive in this world, try to experience the joys and sorrows, birth, old age, sickness, and death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like the quote from The Tale of the Sea Deer:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are short, and we will eventually lose them, so why not be a little bolder – love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream – there are many things with no answers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed &lt;em&gt;The Analects of Zan Gong&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Red Cliff&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the rise of past generations, one feels a sense of longing; if only they could be brought together as one, never to have lamented or mourned, unable to convey it within my heart. I know that dying in one’s lifetime is an absurdity, and the tragedy of Zang and Peng is a false fabrication. Those who look upon us now are like we look upon them then. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Lost/Confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, at some stage of life, people find themselves in a state of confusion, not knowing what they truly want, and gradually losing their pursuit of the meaning of work amidst the mundane daily routines. Looking back to when I first graduated, my heart was full of fervent aspirations – then I would without hesitation say, “I yearn to write code, to create brilliant, eye-catching code.” However, working until today, I’ve had more exposure to business-level affairs, which is largely due to the benefits brought by industry development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my lifestyle, I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet included marriage and having children, or establishing a family, in my thinking; my mind is almost blank, only focused on enjoying the present moment. Whenever weekends arrive, I enjoy quietly playing games, often spending an entire day staying at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In life, we always need something we truly love and dedicate ourselves to wholeheartedly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-house&#34;&gt;Buying a House
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was full of enthusiasm and planned to save diligently to buy my own property. I meticulously budgeted every day towards this goal. However, as house prices continued to rise, I transitioned from initial anxiety and disappointment to eventually becoming numb, gradually feeling that even if I bought a house, it would simply be a heavy burden I’d been carrying around – ultimately leading me to abandon the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saving-money&#34;&gt;Saving Money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving some small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, purchasing a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. However, now I approach saving with a more relaxed and “chill” attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses – I indulge in things I want to eat and boldly try new and exciting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;returning-home&#34;&gt;Returning Home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I most longed for deep down was simply to go home. There wasn’t anything particularly to do, just returning to that familiar place, feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
