<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 06:00:45 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Getting out for a walk is always good.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If things had gone as the family planned, I would have stuck to studying power grids honestly and diligently, without venturing into coding. Had I erased the dust from my memory, it all started with a chat with my roommate near the Spring Festival, which led to a review of my experiences over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The results of the college entrance exam couldn’t be described as good or bad; I ended up graduating from a 211 university, and according to my father&amp;rsquo;s initial plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work for the local power supply bureau in our hometown. There had also been mentions earlier about how to step by step take this path into the IT industry – something that hadn’t been mentioned before: financial views and self-control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I went to school in a rural town in elementary and middle school, and my family arranged for me to transfer to a school in the city district in middle school, much like Grandma Liu entering the Grand View Garden; there was some initial difficulty adapting to the hustle and bustle of the city. I hadn’t been to a movie theater very often, to be precise, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t gone to the movies with my parents, but relatives would take me. Heaven always gives you luck; back then, I met several friends who were just like me, although we lost contact later on, that period of my youth is now seen as beautiful. After catching up on tutoring over the weekend, we’d gather to tidy up the classroom, expertly kicking flattened plastic bottles into our backpacks to take back to Mom for storage. As they accumulated, we&amp;rsquo;d find a waste collector to handle them. We’d play chess, badminton, and Mahjong – if I lost, I’d do a few push-ups; it was a small consolation at the time. Dad had been taking me through all sorts of exercises since I was little. At this point, my understanding of money was slightly skewed, and I felt a bit insecure, but these minor setbacks quickly passed. Our family wasn&amp;rsquo;t struggling – we simply didn’t have much pocket money, and sometimes couldn’t join our classmates in their activities, especially on weekends. Seeing our parents’ efforts as we moved from the village to the city… it was like planting a seed, waiting for it to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a simple-minded individual, I found my time studying to be generally very happy, much like many people can only truly appreciate after graduating – reading isn’t actually that difficult of a task, and the conversion of investment into output is relatively easy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one-1&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I absorbed the memories of the Age of Empires era. During university, encountering a laptop was like opening Pandora’s Box – I discovered games and connected with game merchants. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, sourcing goods upstream and selling them through my own community channels to earn a little money. Later, I gradually understood the operational logic of the entire chain. The products we sold were merely mass-produced by upstream programs, and their costs approached zero. At this time, the road had already started to slant a bit. Within the field of expertise, there were increasingly specialized sub-disciplines: on the left was power grids, and on the right was automation (very complex – chip programming, factory electrical automation). I understood that programs could make money, but it wasn’t a huge sum; the upstream channels definitely made a lot of money. Adding to this my previous foundation in programming, I started experimenting with various things, making a little money here and there. When the time came for specialization, I naturally chose automation. After completing most of my senior-level courses, many of which I didn’t attend, I was constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s article mentioned a fascination with hackers, leading me to contact programming. Without formal training in IT, I used compassion to learn assembly language, penetration testing, game cheats, DLL hijacking, and phishing – familiarizing myself with various black-hat and gray-hat products. My parents taught me how to be a good person, which ultimately dissuaded me from completely straying down the wrong path.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-1-1&#34;&gt;Chapter 1
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previous Post Link: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/&#34; &gt;That Time When I Was Young&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had a brief relationship during university. Looking back, it was more about yearning for the romance depicted in television dramas. As an immature young man at the time, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t understand how to love someone, let alone achieve: settling down and starting a family.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Amidst the torrent of times, I was fortunate – university’s tribulations led me to a direct entry into employment rather than graduate school. Upon graduation, I joined the workforce, riding the wave of IT’s prosperity with smooth and steady progress. Now in my eighth year of work, the industry&amp;rsquo;s speculative heat dissipated, inevitably leading to decline. Sometimes, I question whether my initial choice was correct; perhaps entering a utility company as suggested by my father would have been a better path. If these thoughts were prevalent during the first five years of my career, they gradually faded away with time. Through campus recruitment, I joined HSBC, remaining with the same company for five years without switching roles. This has resulted in certain deficiencies regarding technological understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness of one’s capabilities. Following the arrangement of the headquarters in Hangzhou, I went to the Shenzhen branch, experiencing a workplace struggle (after clarifying the situation, both sides lost out, and the board of directors ultimately benefited), returning to Hangzhou with a passion for technology, carrying a touch of youthful naiveté, having run off to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle down in Hangzhou, purchase property, and register, at the highest interest rates and peak housing prices, it was intended to be a trap – my finances were limited and I couldn’t afford it. If I had been burdened with mortgage payments while the industry was declining, my emotions would have become unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having been around for so many years, having seen so much, I’ve made my own mistakes and wasted time, and currently, things are still going well. Experiencing things, experiencing people – it all leads to gradual growth. If you were to stay at home constantly, I wonder what form the flaws in my personality would manifest themselves in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Back then, as a young boy, he might have had talent, but it wasn’t common.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s my seventh year in the job, and I’m not getting as much positive feedback on the code I write. Let me reflect on how I ended up on this &lt;code&gt;coding&lt;/code&gt; path. People’s choices, especially when they&amp;rsquo;re younger, tend to follow positive reinforcement more closely – actively avoiding harm and seeking benefit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;i-childhood&#34;&gt;I. Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving to the city and coming into contact with computer books? Hacker’s materials? Meeting Windows systems – these are all anecdotes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The time should be positioned around childhood and sneaking around with my cousin to play games on our parents&amp;rsquo; computers&lt;/strong&gt;, my cousin and I’s uncle ran a shop in a computer store.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been exposed to computers from a young age, and the basic understanding was established. Later, in school, taking microcomputer courses also sparked an interest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In middle school, I heard about computer competitions, which seemed really cool, but after transferring schools, this fell by the wayside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my junior high years, I was familiar with the basics of computer operation, and I could easily be the center of attention in microcomputer classes. If you’re still familiar, yes, you haven&amp;rsquo;t made a mistake – being proficient in office software is even more impressive!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ii-moving--relocation&#34;&gt;II. Moving / Relocation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s revisit the moving situation. When we moved to the city center, due to the neighbors, we came into contact with the library. Although we read quite a few novels, we also read many magazines, such as:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;大众软件&lt;/em&gt; (Greatest Software)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We became increasingly interested in computers as a product. The childhood admiration for hackers was very active, and we proactively sought out relevant knowledge at school.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We learned the basics of operating systems: control panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computer News&lt;/em&gt; is suitable for beginners; each time it presents information in the form of case studies, explaining system operations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Greatest Software&lt;/em&gt; recommends various software, industry news, and &lt;strong&gt;of course, game news – this was initially our motivation, and it planted the seed for gaming.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When I was in high school, Bo Ge transferred to our class, and &lt;strong&gt;in the previous two years, he secured several predecessors as direct qualifiers for the computer competition&lt;/strong&gt;, which was highly valued by the school leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was also a foundational hardware base, with an alumnus from America donating a building that became the new library and new computer lab – it all felt incredibly coincidental.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combined with Bo Ge’s popular science education, he was essentially the go-to guy for computers in our class at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A scholar + computer master, knew how to hack into other people&amp;rsquo;s computers and disable the classroom surveillance software.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;iii-high-school-1&#34;&gt;III. High School
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The competitions were bumpy and ultimately ended in the finals, where I didn’t quite understand the material and the questions were mostly basic algorithms. However, it was still a worthwhile experience – like taking a short trip.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-university-arrived--university-major-selection-following-parental-guidance-choosing-automation-actually-wanted-to-pursue-power-electronics-intending-to-join-the-local-electricity-bureau-upon-graduation-little-coursework-was-studied-self-driven-learning-ability-was-virtually-nonexistent-in-professional-courses-computer-courses-within-large-courses-were-very-easy-to-learn-attended-class-regularly-while-skipping-professional-classes-and-diligently-studying-computer-courses-spent-daily-time-on-forums-jingyi-forum-i-love-crack-combining-what-little-assembly-and-c-knowledge-was-learned-from-the-forums-to-take-on-line-orders-for-profit-receiving-increasingly-positive-feedback-and-gradually-became-more-involved--unable-to-be-pulled-back-eventually-choosing-a-niche-profession--writing-code-for-chips--the-family-didnt-pay-much-attention-allowing-me-to-choose-it-myself-at-this-time-the-third-key-figure-my-cousin--high-education-working-at-baidu-grandma-also-understood-me-knowing-that-i-hadnt-been-focused-on-research-since-a-young-age-so-i-talked-to-him-about-it&#34;&gt;Four. University Arrived – University Major Selection, Following Parental Guidance, Choosing Automation; Actually Wanted to Pursue Power Electronics, Intending to Join the Local Electricity Bureau Upon Graduation. Little Coursework Was Studied, Self-Driven Learning Ability Was Virtually Nonexistent in Professional Courses, Computer Courses Within Large Courses Were Very Easy to Learn. Attended Class Regularly, While Skipping Professional Classes and Diligently Studying Computer Courses; Spent Daily Time on Forums: “JingYi Forum,” “I Love Crack,” Combining What Little Assembly and C++ Knowledge Was Learned from the Forums to Take On-Line Orders for Profit, Receiving Increasingly Positive Feedback, And Gradually Became More Involved – Unable to Be Pulled Back. Eventually, Choosing a Niche Profession – Writing Code for Chips – The Family Didn’t Pay Much Attention, Allowing Me to Choose It Myself. At This Time, &lt;strong&gt;The Third Key Figure: My Cousin&lt;/strong&gt; – High Education, Working at Baidu. Grandma Also Understood Me, Knowing That I Hadn&amp;rsquo;t Been Focused on Research Since a Young Age, So I Talked to Him About It.
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;five-graduation&#34;&gt;Five. Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here’s a key point I know – I learned how to bypass firewalls, took elective courses in Computer Information Retrieval, and quickly found and located information and problems. A valuable colleague appeared in my work, &lt;strong&gt;Mr. [硕哥&amp;rsquo;s Pinyin - Shuo Ge]&lt;/strong&gt;, who gave me time to learn independently and troubleshoot issues from the ground up, taking me to meet with the leaders of the R&amp;amp;D center.
These experiences laid the groundwork; in Shenzhen, everyone perceived me as highly capable, successfully leading the transaction channel group.
That’s where the problem lies: I lacked systematic learning in computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design. All my knowledge was based on my own past experience. This led to frequent contradictions and rejections of my code designs, a lack of guidelines for module design, and ultimately, fatigue after seven years.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social animals, that’s right – you are an individual, but also a bipedal animal, with strong social attributes; you have feelings of inferiority and vanity, and society is constantly changing and eroding your &lt;strong&gt;everydayness&lt;/strong&gt;. We don&amp;rsquo;t discuss those great figures, those who willingly burn themselves for society or the nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Looking at average wages or my hometown’s salaries, my current income is significantly above the average – what more could I possibly want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn one million, you start thinking about earning one hundred million; once you earn one hundred million, you start thinking about earning a billion. This is natural for ordinary people; we must face our inner selves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-current-situation-1&#34;&gt;My Current Situation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;What’s red are the more relaxed ways to make money: short videos. Everyone knows it&amp;rsquo;s not simple to enter an industry. What you see is short video content, but what you don’t see is the behind-the-scenes work of filming and copywriting. But everyone has their own dream – I’m suited for that industry, I was born to be in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;getting-started&#34;&gt;Getting Started
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I’ve watched so many videos. If you analyze a lot of the shots with your own brain, you can clearly see professional editing techniques and strong cinematic elements. Basically, some of them are from people who have formal training – film school graduates, for example. Of course, there&amp;rsquo;s also the logic of grassroots success, but that doesn’t apply to most people, does it?
On TikTok, you’ll also find many videos teaching you how to make videos. At this point, people are starting to wake up. If they could really make money, why would they teach others how to do it instead of doing it themselves?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-Human Recommendation Algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, the Douyin algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime clips while I was scrolling. It felt surprisingly engaging, to the point where you’d start to find it interesting yourself. However, when I looked into how Douyin makes money, it started recommending various tutorial videos non-stop, flooding my entire recommendation stream. As someone who also works in the IT industry, this made me feel like the algorithm “big brothers” were having a bit of a problem – you’re essentially suggesting this to me, are you thinking I&amp;rsquo;m stupid or are &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; stupid? The key thing is that it keeps finding new ways to recommend videos on how to make money with Douyin, from different angles and across various types. It’s like they’re constantly adapting. This draft was written at 3 AM, and frankly, I didn’t want to write it in the first place. I started wondering how long this business model could last – how much time can you siphon away from people?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finding-clarity&#34;&gt;Finding Clarity
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When teaching people how to do things, presenting a set of rules for them and then being unable to control yourself when doing it is ridiculous. As I’m not a purely technical blog writer, I haven&amp;rsquo;t published some things domestically, so here I casually rant. If one day I get banned, that can only be said to move somewhere else. I can’t say I haven’t done anything with Douyin – at least now it actively cooperates in the dissemination of real-time news and the propaganda of national policies, because in our country, you can&amp;rsquo;t defy the Communist Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now think back to when you were studying. When you truly can’t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In this era, how many people can still quiet themselves down and quietly read books?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the progress of science and technology. If you’re seeing this line, you’ll realize that the entire manuscript is very colloquial. And I really just kept writing and writing it. The input method I usually used was Sogou Input Method, which I&amp;rsquo;d been using for about seven or eight years. However, when it came to voice input, it had to be said that Xunfei was more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 2022, the article number was changed to 002. Why did it have two zeros? There’s a dream – this year I wanted to break the hundred articles, which is just a dream, right? It&amp;rsquo;s not really articles; it’s more like records. I reflect on myself every day, and you must be able to think of some things, right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What we have been seeking throughout our lives is…</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wang Yi-zi said: Human relationships, spanning a lifetime of mutual support and dependence, may be held within one’s embrace, understood in the confines of one room; or they may arise from entrusted messages, dissolving into the vastness beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In a lifetime, like a fleeting flower. Like grass and trees blossoming and withering, like the rising and setting of the sun and moon.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yet, in this life, desires are numerous.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As a child, I lay under lotus plants and hemp in the stream, busy catching the east wind to fly kites, chasing yellow butterflies in haste,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Also learned to grow gourds by the shade of mulberry trees, returning home with a full meal after dusk, not shedding my cloak to lie beneath the moonlight.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;As I grew older, I hoped to be inscribed on the gold list, to have a beautiful woman accompany me, to have endless wealth, to rise continuously, to have a full table of guests, to have nightly singing and dancing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When old, I wanted health and longevity, welcome childhood servants, young children waiting at the door, a chessboard, a confidant, a bottle of wine, a courtyard, enjoying family harmony.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You see people rushing about in a hurry, only seeking a few taels of broken silver. Yet, this broken silver, can it dispel all kinds of melancholy in the world?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Half the people are still struggling to make ends meet, where do they have time to pursue meaning?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In fact, human life is just an experience, like plants, the sun and moon – experiencing the cycle of desire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you don’t understand it, you’ll feel like a gnat in the vast universe, a grain of sand on the Yangtze River. When you do understand, you can be happy with what you encounter, enjoy what you have temporarily, find contentment in yourself, and live joyfully until old age.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, flowers, and tea. You can pursue the clear breeze on the river or the bright moon in the mountains.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;But don’t overly concern yourself with the results; they will all eventually pass away.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After a lifetime of hardship, when you arrive in this world, try to experience the joys and sorrows, birth, old age, sickness, and death.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I really like this quote from The Tale of the Sea Stallion – A Princess’s Love.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I greatly enjoyed &lt;em&gt;The Analects of Zan Gong&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Romance of the Three Kingdoms&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on the rise of past generations, one feels a sense of longing; if only one could truly connect with them, never lamenting their fate, unable to explain it within one’s heart. One knows that dying as one’s life is illusory, and the tragedy of Zang and Peng is merely fabricated. When posterity looks upon us now, we are like we are now looking upon them. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>lost-and-confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, at some stage in life, people find themselves lost in a haze, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose their pursuit of meaning and purpose. Looking back to when I first graduated, my heart was full of fervent aspirations – I wouldn’t hesitate to say that I longed to write code, to create brilliant, eye-catching code. However, as I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for so long, I’ve had more exposure to business-level affairs, which has largely benefited from the advantages brought about by industry development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my life philosophy, I haven’t yet incorporated marriage and having children, or establishing a family, into my thinking. My mind is almost empty, simply focused on enjoying the present moment. Whenever weekends arrive, I enjoy quietly playing games, often spending an entire day at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-house&#34;&gt;Buying a House
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was full of enthusiasm, planning to save diligently and buy my own property. I meticulously budgeted every day towards this goal. However, as housing prices continued to skyrocket, my anxiety and resentment gradually turned into numbness, leading me to feel that even if I bought a house, it would simply be a heavy burden on my shoulders. Consequently, I abandoned this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saving-money&#34;&gt;Saving Money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving some small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, purchasing a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. However, now I approach saving with a more relaxed and “chill” attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses – I indulge in things I want to eat and boldly try new and exciting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;returning-home&#34;&gt;Returning Home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I most longed for deep down was simply to go home. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything particularly to do, just to return to that familiar place and feel the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
