<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Life-Lessons on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/life-lessons/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Getting out and about is generally good</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 10:30:43 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/come-out-and-walk-around-its-always-good/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;If I had followed my family&amp;rsquo;s plans and stuck with studying electrical engineering instead of writing code, I probably would have been a typical obedient son&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dusting off memories, sparked by the approaching Spring Festival and a conversation with my roommate, prompting a review of these past years&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-one&#34;&gt;Chapter One
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Gaokao results weren&amp;rsquo;t particularly good or bad. I graduated from a 211 university, but according to my father’s original plan, I should have studied power grids and returned to work at the local electricity bureau. As mentioned earlier, I&amp;rsquo;ll briefly touch on how I ended up in IT—I forgot to mention one key factor: my values and self-discipline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still in a rural school during my first year of junior high, my family arranged for me to transfer to a city school by my second year. It felt like Liu姥姥 visiting the Grand View Garden – I struggled to adapt to the city&amp;rsquo;s vibrancy. I hadn’t gone to the cinema many times as a child, certainly not with my parents; relatives had taken me occasionally. Fortunately, I made friends with several like-minded guys. Though we don&amp;rsquo;t keep in touch much now, those youthful days were still good. After tutoring on weekends, we would collect plastic bottles from the classroom, expertly crushing them with our feet and packing them into bags to take home for my mom to save. Once we had enough, we’d find someone to recycle them. We played chess, badminton, and Dou Di Zhu (a card game), and the losers had to do push-ups. I was even a little grateful then that my dad had been getting me involved in various sports since I was young. That&amp;rsquo;s when my perspective on money started to shift, and I felt slightly inferior. But these minor misfortunes were fleeting. My family wasn’t wealthy; we didn’t have much pocket money, and sometimes I couldn’t play with the other kids, especially on weekends. My parents’ hard work was visible – we moved from the village to the city. The seeds had been planted, waiting to sprout.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite being a simple person, I was generally very happy during my studies—a feeling many don&amp;rsquo;t experience until after graduation. Studying isn’t particularly difficult; the conversion of effort to results is relatively straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Combining childhood memories of the imperial era with university life, encountering a laptop felt like opening Pandora&amp;rsquo;s Box. I was introduced to games and connected with the role of a game merchant. Initially, I was a low-level salesperson, purchasing goods upstream and selling them through my own network, earning small sums. Gradually, I understood the entire operational logic of the chain. The goods we sold were essentially batch-incubated by upstream programs with near-zero costs. At this point, things started to veer off course. My major had specialized branches – electrical grids on one side, and automation (a broad field including chip programming and factory electrical automation) on the other. Realizing that programming could make significant money, and seeing how much profit was made upstream, combined with my existing programming background, I began experimenting and earning small amounts of money. During major selection, I naturally chose automation. I skipped many required courses in my junior year, constantly thinking about writing code to make money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last year&amp;rsquo;s article mentioned that, driven by a romanticized view of hackers and with the kindness of IT experience, I delved into assembly, penetration testing, game hacks, DLL hijacking, and account theft, becoming familiar with various black and gray industries. My parents taught me ethics, and the law still guided me; I didn&amp;rsquo;t go completely astray.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Previous article link:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During university, I had one relationship. Looking back, it was more about longing for the kind of love seen in TV dramas. At that time, my emotional maturity wasn&amp;rsquo;t ready to understand how to truly love someone, let alone build a family and establish a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-two&#34;&gt;Chapter Two
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also been fortunate. My university years didn&amp;rsquo;t lead to graduate school; I started working right after graduation and benefited from the boom in the IT industry. It’s been eight years now, but the hype has faded and the era is coming to a close. Sometimes I wonder if I made the wrong choice, perhaps entering the power grid as my father suggested would have been better. That thought lingered for the first five years, but gradually disappeared. Joining HSBC through campus recruitment, I didn’t switch companies for five years – this left gaps in my technical understanding, industry knowledge, and self-awareness. Following instructions from headquarters in Hangzhou, I went to Shenzhen, experienced a workplace power struggle (which I later realized was a loss for everyone involved, with the board ultimately winning), and returned to Hangzhou fueled by a passion for technology. With a touch of youthful naivete, I left Hangzhou and moved to Shanghai.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally planned to settle, register residency, and buy a home in Hangzhou. With interest rates at their peak and housing prices at their highest, entering the market would likely lead to being stuck with a mortgage; my family savings are too thin to handle it. The thought of marrying under that kind of financial pressure, compounded by industry downturns, makes me emotionally unstable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;chapter-three&#34;&gt;Chapter Three
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After so many years, witnessing so much, experiencing my own foolishness and recklessness, I&amp;rsquo;m currently doing well. Through experiences and encounters with people, I’ve gradually matured. Staying at home would have left those personality flaws to erupt in some unknown way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>At that time, he was young; perhaps he had talent, but not much</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jan 2023 13:45:09 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/then-boy-talent-not-much/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In my seventh year of working, the positive feedback from coding isn&amp;rsquo;t as frequent anymore. Looking back on how I ended up down this path.
The choices we make, especially in childhood, tend to follow positive feedback – proactively avoiding harm and seeking benefit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;one-childhood&#34;&gt;One, Childhood
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Moving downtown, encountering computer books? Hacker resources? Becoming familiar with Windows systems? Those are later stories&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My brother&amp;rsquo;s uncle runs a shop in the computer market
We started using computers early on, so we developed a basic understanding of them. Later, in school and during computer classes, I remained quite interested.
I heard about the computer competitions in junior high, thought they were really cool, but then after transferring schools, I put that idea aside
During my first year of junior high, I was familiar with basic computer operations and often stood out in computer class
If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with it – yes, you read that right, not proficient, but familiar – with Microsoft Office suite, that would be even better&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;moving&#34;&gt;Moving
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Regarding the move, once I got into the city, I ended up frequenting the library due to my neighbors. While I read a lot of novels, I also looked at many magazines.
Computer News, Popular Software
Increasingly interested in computers, with childhood admiration for hackers and actively learning related knowledge at school
Understanding the basics of operating systems: Control Panel, CMD commands, VBS scripts&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This magazine is quite suitable for beginners; it explains operations systematically using case studies
software reviews, industry news, and more&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;high-school&#34;&gt;High school
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In my second year of high school, [this competition], the school leaders also paid it considerable attention
There&amp;rsquo;s also a foundational hardware aspect – an alumnus donated a building to the university, including a new library and computer lab. It’s all so coincidental.
With Bo&amp;rsquo;s explanations, he would be considered a computer expert in the class&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Academic whiz + computer expert, knows how to hack computers and disable classroom surveillance software&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competition, despite its challenges, reached the finals. While I didn&amp;rsquo;t fully grasp everything, the questions focused on basic algorithms, but I did gain some valuable insights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s still just half a bucket, like taking a trip&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;four-college&#34;&gt;Four. College
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;When it came time to choose a major in college, I followed my family&amp;rsquo;s suggestion and chose automation. I actually wanted to study high-voltage electricity, hoping to work for the power company after graduation, but I didn’t learn much of the coursework.
Self-directed learning is scarce in professional courses, but computer science courses within those programs come naturally&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skipping required courses, studying computer science diligently, and spending time daily on forums like &amp;ldquo;Jingyi Forum&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;52PoP.&amp;rdquo;
Combining knowledge of assembly language and C++,
Ultimately, Xiao Zheng&amp;rsquo;s choice was to write code for chips, and my family didn&amp;rsquo;t interfere; they let me choose&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At that time, [name redacted], with a high level of education, joined Baidu
My older sister understands me; she knows I wasn&amp;rsquo;t in a state to think or research, so she told me to talk it over with my cousin
Finalize the future development path; skip going home for summer vacation, stay with the mentor, work on projects, and gain experience
Entered Hengan Electronic based on a still-acceptable academic record&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;graduation&#34;&gt;Graduation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the key – I took courses in information retrieval, knowing how to quickly find and locate materials and issues
A helpful mentor appeared at work, gave me time to learn independently, troubleshoot issues thoroughly, and introduced me to experts at the R&amp;amp;D center
This laid the groundwork, and now Shenzhen branch believes I&amp;rsquo;m impressive – I successfully took charge of the trading channel team&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here lies a problem; my foundational knowledge of computer operating systems, algorithms, and software engineering design…
Without systematic study, it&amp;rsquo;s all based on personal experience
Frequently redesigning code, lacking a consistent approach to module design – after seven years, I&amp;rsquo;m starting to feel burnt out&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>When you want to make money</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 27 Mar 2022 03:23:53 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/when-you-want-to-make-money/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ordinary people are social creatures, that&amp;rsquo;s right – you are a person, and also an upright-walking animal with strong social attributes; possessing feelings of inferiority and vanity. Society is constantly changing and eroding your essence. We won’t discuss the great individuals who willingly sacrifice themselves for society or for their country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;right-now&#34;&gt;Right now
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Considering average wages, or even those in my hometown, my current income is already significantly above average. What more could I possibly want?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once you earn ten thousand, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning a million; once you earn a million, you&amp;rsquo;ll think of earning ten million. This is human nature, and one must confront their own inner desires.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What&amp;rsquo;s causing all the envy? It’s the easy money of short videos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone understands that entering this industry isn&amp;rsquo;t easy. What you see is this short video, but you don’t see the scriptwriting and filming behind it. Yet, everyone dreams of being a genius, believing they are naturally suited for that field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;begin-contact&#34;&gt;Begin contact
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;After watching so many videos, a little analysis reveals clear professional editing and a strong cinematic feel. This suggests they have formal training. While there&amp;rsquo;s logic to grassroots success stories, it doesn’t apply to most people, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On Douyin, you&amp;rsquo;ll find countless videos teaching you how to make videos. That’s when reality sinks in: if this could really make money, why wouldn’t they do it themselves instead of teaching others?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;anti-human-recommendation-algorithms&#34;&gt;Anti-human recommendation algorithms
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Previously, Douyin&amp;rsquo;s algorithm would recommend movie clips and anime edits, which were enjoyable to watch. But when I started looking into how to make money on Douyin, it began relentlessly recommending instructional videos, flooding my feed. As someone in the IT industry myself, I couldn’t help but wonder if the team behind the algorithm had lost their minds. Is this recommendation strategy meant to imply that users are foolish? And the fact that they keep suggesting ways to earn money through Douyin, from various angles and types… This piece is being written at 3 AM, and I didn&amp;rsquo;t even intend to write it. I just question how long this business model can last and how much time it will consume.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;understand-life&#34;&gt;Understand life
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Preaching one thing when instructing others, but failing to control oneself – that&amp;rsquo;s a joke. Not a pure technical blog writer, so I haven’t published much domestically. Here, I’m just casually complaining. If this gets shut down someday, I guess I’ll find another place. I can’t say Douyin hasn’t done anything; at least currently, it actively assists with the spread of real-time news and the promotion of state policies. After all, in China, you can&amp;rsquo;t go against the Party, right?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thinking back to my school days now. When you truly can&amp;rsquo;t find the meaning of life, quietly reading a book is enough. In today’s era, how many people can still sit down and read quietly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;afterword&#34;&gt;Afterword
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;I also want to thank the advancements in science and technology. If you can see this line, you&amp;rsquo;ll notice the entire draft is very conversational. Honestly, I just read it aloud and wrote it down. I used Sogou Input Method for years, but when it comes to voice input, iFlytek is undoubtedly more professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article number for 2022 was changed to 002. Why are there two extra zeros? It&amp;rsquo;s a dream that the number of entries this year could exceed one hundred – it really is a dream. They aren’t exactly articles, more like records. I examine myself three times a day; you surely can think of something, right?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>What is it that we spend our whole lives pursuing?</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Aug 2021 21:09:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/we-exhaust-ourselves-chasing/</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s interactions with their spouse can last a lifetime—sometimes arising from shared ideals and understanding within the home, sometimes stemming from entrusting one’s fate and wandering beyond societal constraints&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person&amp;rsquo;s life is like a fleeting moment; like grass and trees, flourishing in spring and withering in autumn; like the rising and setting of the sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yet, I have so many desires in this life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lying by the stream as a child, peeling lotus pods, while eagerly releasing kites in the east wind, chasing after yellow butterflies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He leaned against mulberry trees to learn about melons, returned with a full meal after dusk, and slept under the bright moon without taking off his raincoat&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Growing up, I hope to achieve great success, have a beautiful partner, enjoy abundant wealth, rise through the ranks, host lavish gatherings, and celebrate every night with music and revelry&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aging, yet desiring health and longevity – welcome servants, await children, a game of chess, a close friend, a pot of wine, a courtyard, and the enjoyment of family life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People rush about, chasing after a few coins. Yet those very coins can ease all sorts of worldly sorrows.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most people are struggling just to make ends meet; who has time to pursue meaning?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, life is merely an experience—like grass, trees, the sun, and moon—a cycle of desires&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Not understanding life leads to the feeling that we are like mayflies adrift in the universe, a grain of sand in the vast ocean. We lament our fleeting existence and envy the endless flow of the Yangtze River. Understanding life brings joy in what is encountered, satisfaction with what one gains, contentment without seeking more, unaware of approaching old age.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can pursue wealth and fame, or poetry, wine, and tea; you can chase the clear breeze on the river, or the bright moon in the mountains&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be overly concerned with the outcome; results are fleeting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To exhaust a lifetime, arriving in this world to experience as much joy and sorrow, birth and death as possible&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like this line from Big Fish &amp;amp; Begonia&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our lives are short, and we will inevitably lose them, so let&amp;rsquo;s be bold – love someone, climb a mountain, chase a dream. There are many things in life with no answers, so let’s be bold.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I really like &amp;ldquo;The Pavilion of Prince Shaobo&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Ode to the Red Cliffs.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The causes of grief over the passing of others are like a binding agreement; I have never faced literature without lamenting, unable to contain it within my heart. Indeed, knowing that life and death are illusory and that equating ages is futile. Those who come after will view us as we now view those gone before. Alas!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>lost-and-confused</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at some point in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose sight of their pursuit of meaning. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations; back then, I would have confidently said that I longed to write code—remarkable, exceptional code. However, in my current role, I’ve primarily dealt with operational matters, largely benefiting from the dividends of industry growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t considered marriage, having children, or establishing a career. My mind is mostly blank, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. On weekends, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day at home, immersed in my own world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to in life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-house&#34;&gt;Buy house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was determined to save enough money to buy my own home and meticulously planned every expense. However, seeing house prices continually rise, I went from anxiety and resentment to numbness. Eventually, I realized that even if I bought a property, it would just be another heavy burden, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving small goals – like building a powerful desktop computer, buying a camera I&amp;rsquo;d long wanted, or taking an impromptu trip. Now, I approach saving with a more relaxed attitude, worry less about daily expenses, indulge in what I want to eat, and boldly try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I truly longed for was simply to go home. No special occasion needed, just returning to a familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
