<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Stock-Crash on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-crash/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Stock-Crash on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/stock-crash/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>A dramatic market shift before and after National Day: soaring highs followed by plunging lows</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/national-holiday-stock-market-rollercoaster/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 03:42:26 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/national-holiday-stock-market-rollercoaster/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of China&amp;rsquo;s National Day holiday in 2024, the stock market saw a remarkable surge, followed by a dramatic plunge after the break. This &amp;ldquo;rollercoaster&amp;rdquo; experience for investors has prompted deep reflection on policy, economics, and market dynamics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the English translation: &amp;ldquo;Written as a news report, this blog post focuses on the stock market surge preceding last year’s National Day holiday, followed by the subsequent sharp decline after the holiday.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stock-market-surge-before-national-day-a-policy-driven-frenzy&#34;&gt;Stock market surge before National Day: A policy-driven frenzy
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the five trading days leading up to China&amp;rsquo;s National Day in 2024, the Chinese stock market surged from a slump into a &amp;ldquo;boiling&amp;rdquo; state. On September 30th, A-share markets saw broad gains with significant volume; major indices all reached historic highs. The Shanghai Index rose 8.06%, the Shenzhen Component Index climbed 10.67%, and the Growth Enterprise Market Index soared 15.36%. The B share index set a record for the largest single-day increase, jumping 22.84%. Market sentiment was extremely bullish, with daily turnover on Shanghai, Shenzhen, and Beijing exchanges reaching 2.61 trillion yuan – a substantial increase of 1.1559 trillion yuan from the previous trading day. Over 5300 stocks across all markets rose collectively, creating a &amp;ldquo;sea of red&amp;rdquo; scenario.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The driving force behind this recent market rally stems from the concentrated release of a series of unexpected government policies and the resulting shifts in market expectations. On September 24th, the People&amp;rsquo;s Bank of China announced measures including cutting the reserve requirement ratio, lowering interest rates, reducing mortgage rates on existing loans, and unifying minimum down payment ratios for mortgages. The Central Political Bureau meeting on September 26th emphasized increasing counter-cyclical adjustments through fiscal and monetary policies to boost capital markets and encourage long-term funds to enter the market. On September 30th, a cluster of four real estate support policies were introduced. These measures demonstrate the government&amp;rsquo;s determination to stabilize the market and economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;post-national-day-stock-market-plunge-calmness-and-adjustment-after-the-celebration&#34;&gt;Post-National Day Stock Market Plunge: Calmness and Adjustment After the Celebration
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;However, market sentiment plummeted after the National Day holiday. On October 8th, A-shares opened strongly with near limit-up gains, but following this sharp opening, the market experienced significant volatility, ultimately closing higher than it opened but lower than it closed. Since then, the market&amp;rsquo;s focus has continued to decline; as of October 16th, the Shanghai Composite Index saw a swing of over 15% and a cumulative drop of more than 470 points. From October 8th to 10th, core A-share indices across the board declined, with the Growth Enterprise Market Index falling by 6.21%.
This recent sharp decline is due to a combination of factors: digesting risks accumulated from previous rapid gains, and adjustments in market expectations regarding policy. Some investors believe the short-term effects of policies are already apparent, while long-term results remain to be seen. Volatility in overseas markets has also impacted A-shares. On October 9th, the Hang Seng Index plummeted 9.41% and the A50 futures contract fell 10.4%, further intensifying the market&amp;rsquo;s downturn.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflection-on-and-prospects-for-the-market&#34;&gt;Reflection on and Prospects for the Market
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The sharp market fluctuations before and after National Day have prompted deep reflection on policy, the economy, and market dynamics. While policy stimulus has shown a significant short-term effect, its long-term impact remains to be seen. The rapid market rises and falls also serve as a reminder for investors to remain rational and avoid emotional investing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether A-share market can achieve a genuine &amp;ldquo;long-term bull&amp;rdquo; trend still depends on whether policies effectively reach the real economy and ultimately drive substantial improvements in economic fundamentals. Investors should closely monitor policy implementation and changes in economic data, adjusting their investment strategies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stock market&amp;rsquo;s surge and subsequent crash around National Day were a contest between policy and the market, as well as a test of investor psychology. This &amp;ldquo;extreme&amp;rdquo; volatility revealed both the power of the market and the influence of policy. We will see how the market unfolds next.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
