<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Alibaba on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/alibaba/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Alibaba on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 01:28:47 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/alibaba/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Alibaba Large Model Strategy</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/alibaba-large-model-strategy/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 22:07:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/alibaba-large-model-strategy/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alibaba (Ali) has released numerous large models, not simply a matter of “volume chasing,” but a carefully planned &lt;strong&gt;“Model-as-a-Service” (MaaS) ecosystem strategy.&lt;/strong&gt; There are multiple considerations behind this, which can be summarized as “internal empowerment and external ecosystem building.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;internal-business-driven-inward-empowerment&#34;&gt;Internal Business Driven (Inward Empowerment)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alibaba possesses an extremely vast and diverse business landscape, including e-commerce (Taobao &amp;amp; Tmall), finance (Ant Financial), logistics (Cainiao), cloud computing (Aliyun), and entertainment (Youku), among others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario Customization:&lt;/strong&gt; A single, general-purpose large model cannot efficiently meet the fine-grained needs of all vertical scenarios. For example, the requirements for an e-commerce customer service model, an advertising creative generation model, a financial risk control model, and a logistics route planning model are entirely different.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Efficiency &amp;amp; Cost:&lt;/strong&gt; Training specialized “small models” for specific tasks (such as coding or diagramming) is more cost-effective and responsive than continuously calling upon a large “all-in-one” model.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Therefore, Alibaba needs a &amp;ldquo;Model Matrix&amp;rdquo; with “Tongyi” (Tongyi) foundational model at its core, to derive specialized models tailored to different businesses, enabling an AI transformation of internal operations.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-a-cloud-service-ecosystem-external-ecosystem-building&#34;&gt;Building a Cloud Service Ecosystem (External Ecosystem Building)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is Alibaba’s core strategy. Large Models are the “operating system” of the AI era, while computing power (cloud services) are like “water and electricity.” The goal of Alibaba Cloud is to become a leading “compute + model” infrastructure provider in the AI era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Building a &amp;ldquo;Model Supermarket&amp;rdquo;:&lt;/strong&gt;  Alibaba not only provides its own “Tongyi” series models (such as Tongyi Qianwen, Tongyi Wanxiang, and Tongyi Lingma), but also gathers a large number of third-party and open-source models through the “MoDaBu”(ModelScope) community. By releasing numerous models, it’s intended to showcase its powerful model research capabilities and rich model library, attracting enterprises to move to the cloud.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;“Open Source + Closed Source” Parallel Strategy:&lt;/strong&gt; Alibaba&amp;rsquo;s (such as open-sourcing the Qwen series of “Tongyi Qianwen”) open-source strategy is aimed at rapidly building a developer community, capturing market share, accelerating technological iteration, and competing with international open-source forces like Meta’s Llama. After developers “practice” on open-source models, they are likely to choose Alibaba Cloud&amp;rsquo;s paid computing power and closed-source commercial models for final deployment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In short, Alibaba’s release of numerous large models is characterized by a strategy of: building a core self-developed model matrix centered around the “Tongyu” series to deeply empower its vast and diverse internal businesses. Simultaneously, through “open source” and “Model as a Service” platforms, it&amp;rsquo;s constructing an open and thriving AI ecosystem on Alibaba Cloud, with the ultimate goal of &lt;strong&gt;driving growth in its core cloud computing business.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Hang Seng Index Crash, Meituan Considering Exit? Examining Xiaomi, Alibaba, and Meituan’s New Valuation Anchors Through “Ecological Premium”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hang-seng-index-sharp-decline-meituan-considering-exit-examining-xiaomi-alibaba-and-meituans-new-valuation-anchors-through-ecological-premium/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 21:50:44 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/hang-seng-index-sharp-decline-meituan-considering-exit-examining-xiaomi-alibaba-and-meituans-new-valuation-anchors-through-ecological-premium/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, Xiaomi’s third-quarter financial report was released, with little expectation beyond the usual. The US situation is unsettled, Hong Kong stocks have recently experienced liquidity stagnation, and the Hang Seng Technology Index has retreated significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a major participant in the food delivery war, Alibaba, which bears the highest e-commerce taxes, hasn’t generated much discussion online.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t remember if I wrote any previous articles, when I bought Xiaomi, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really think about what supported Xiaomi’s market capitalization at that time – perhaps after watching too many TikTok-related videos?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, the Hang Seng Technology Index has been falling, and electric vehicle stocks in Hong Kong are also declining. Xiaomi has multiple buffs stacked on top of each other, with negative news flying everywhere, and its stock price has naturally fallen significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, it’s also been changing the head of its public relations department – conspiracy theories: they&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to change it for a long time, but the stakes are too high, and there are still many KOLs involved; if they suddenly make some wild claims, it will be difficult to resolve the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article primarily analyzes the valuation logic of &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group&lt;/strong&gt; and the market and policy challenges faced by &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt; recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original draft contained too much complex content, collecting information from various sources and edited based on AI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;xiaomi-the-logic-behind-the-surge-in-valuation-platform-premium&#34;&gt;Xiaomi: The Logic Behind the Surge in Valuation (Platform Premium)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Argument:&lt;/strong&gt; The capital market has given Xiaomi a surge in valuation, driven by its “platform-type company” and “ecosystem empowerment” premium – something that vertical manufacturers (like Xiaopeng, Zotye) lack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Valuation Anchor Differences:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi:&lt;/strong&gt; Anchored on the scarcity of “technology platforms” and “human-vehicle-home ecosystem.” The automotive business is viewed as a crucial step in ecological expansion, with risks dispersed across mobile and internet businesses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Automotive Manufacturers (Xiaopeng/Zotye):&lt;/strong&gt; Anchored on “vehicle sales” and “unit profitability,” with valuation curves directly linked to the automotive industry cycle.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ecosystem Empowerment Value:&lt;/strong&gt; Xiaomi possesses a massive, highly engaged user base of over 100 million, with extremely high order conversion efficiency from cars, and low marketing costs. Its seamless &amp;ldquo;human-vehicle-home&amp;rdquo; synergy is viewed by the market as superior to the industry average differentiation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Market Expectations:&lt;/strong&gt; The market is buying into Xiaomi’s potential to successfully enter the trillion-dollar new “track entry ticket” and “ecosystem synergy value” in the next decade, reshaping its overall valuation logic.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituan-considering-exit&#34;&gt;Meituan: Considering Exit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, the phrase &amp;ldquo;capable of bringing together all things, deeply ingrained in people&amp;rsquo;s hearts&amp;rdquo; was seen as a strong moat. However, it now appears that this moat isn’t as deep as initially thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Situation:&lt;/strong&gt; When buying, little consideration was given; recently, the stock price has fallen, and a decision on whether to “cut losses” will be made after reviewing the third quarter financial results.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;alibaba-e-commerce-tax-policy-impact&#34;&gt;Alibaba (E-commerce Tax Policy Impact)
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tax Policy Changes:&lt;/strong&gt; China’s recent “e-commerce tax” is primarily focused on two areas:
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cross-border E-commerce Retail Import Duty (“Haotai”):&lt;/strong&gt; The preferential exemption for items below 50 RMB has been cancelled, leading to an approximate 11.9% price increase for haotai goods and driving industry compliance.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Domestic E-commerce Tax Information Reporting Standards:&lt;/strong&gt; Platforms are now required to report sales information from merchants, effectively preventing C2C individual sellers who previously hid income from continuing, &lt;strong&gt;marking the entry of the industry into a core reshaping phase focused on compliance.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impact on Platforms:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Taobao (C2C):&lt;/strong&gt; May eliminate small businesses unwilling to comply in the short term, but in the long run, it will improve platform quality and consumer trust.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tianmao/Jingdong (B2C):&lt;/strong&gt; Long-term benefit, as these large B2C platforms and merchants are already regular tax payers, and this new policy creates a fairer competitive environment for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Merchant Losses:&lt;/strong&gt; Losses are concentrated in merchants &lt;strong&gt;originally relying on tax evasion to gain price advantages.&lt;/strong&gt; For merchants eligible for small microenterprise preferential policies, the tax burden should be low or exempt after compliant reporting. &lt;strong&gt;Being eliminated is an inevitable step towards fair competition.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>From Meituan’s Losses to Bond Mismatch</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 19:19:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/from-meituans-losses-to-bond-mismatch/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the turbulent and unpredictable stock market, we often use faith and expectations as our compass, attempting to navigate through the fog and reach the shores of wealth. However, when our voyage deviates from the guidance of the compass, it’s easy to lose direction, even to run aground. This essay is about one such journey, beginning with an unwavering obsession with &lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi&lt;/strong&gt;, which rose and fell repeatedly amidst the waves of capital.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-clash-of-faith-and-reality-xiaomis-gains-and-losses&#34;&gt;The Clash of Faith and Reality: Xiaomi&amp;rsquo;s Gains and Losses
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In June, I bought into Xiaomi with unwavering &lt;strong&gt;faith&lt;/strong&gt; in Lei Jun and a hopeful vision for the company’s electric vehicles. At the time, faith was a powerful force, temporarily blinding me to Lei Jun’s shrewdness as a capitalist and overlooking the risks posed by the High-Level Flash Lightning Distribution Platform. Fortunately, several &lt;strong&gt;wave trading&lt;/strong&gt; operations ended with modest profits, giving me a sweet taste of entering the Hong Kong stock market for the first time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, this self-confidence soon followed. After making a small profit on &lt;strong&gt;Jiu Fang&lt;/strong&gt; stocks, I became somewhat &lt;strong&gt;dazed&lt;/strong&gt;, relying solely on the flow of net buying funds from the &lt;strong&gt;Hong Kong Connect&lt;/strong&gt; indicator instead of rational analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;meituans-waterloo-and-blind-re-positioning&#34;&gt;Meituan&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Waterloo&amp;rdquo; and Blind Re-positioning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Guided by the flow of funds, I turned my attention to &lt;strong&gt;Meituan&lt;/strong&gt;. However, this time, I didn’t delve into the company’s &lt;strong&gt;financial data&lt;/strong&gt;, its &lt;strong&gt;historical trends&lt;/strong&gt;, or even realize the raging &lt;strong&gt;food delivery war&lt;/strong&gt; that was unfolding. When the stock price began to fall, I failed to cut my losses in time and instead blindly &lt;strong&gt;added to my position&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shares trading at HK$20,000-30,000, limitations on capital prevented me from managing my positions freely, which undoubtedly exacerbated my losses in Meituan. This lesson deeply made me realize that in the Hong Kong stock market, blind re-positioning is like trying to fill a constantly leaking bathtub with more water – it only accelerates the loss.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;stupid-people-are-lucky---an-unexpected-gain&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Stupid People Are Lucky&amp;rdquo; - An Unexpected Gain
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;While I was worrying about Meituan&amp;rsquo;s losses, an unexpected turn of events occurred – I bought &lt;strong&gt;Alibaba&lt;/strong&gt;. Although I didn’t hold onto it, I quickly sold it and used the profit to offset some of Meituan’s losses. This might be what’s meant by “stupid people are lucky,” allowing me to temporarily escape Meituan&amp;rsquo;s predicament.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;finance-more-important-fundamentals-than-investing&#34;&gt;Finance: More Important Fundamentals Than Investing
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This experience also made me re-examine my &lt;strong&gt;financial management&lt;/strong&gt; approach, aside from the ups and downs of the stock market. At the time, I invested a sum intended for short-term emergency funds into &lt;strong&gt;Chinese bonds&lt;/strong&gt;. This money was meant to be used for payment within two months, but the short-term holding yield on the bonds wasn&amp;rsquo;t high, and it also posed liquidity issues. If I had instead chosen to deposit this money into a &lt;strong&gt;money fund&lt;/strong&gt;, I could have earned more stable returns and readily redeemed it, better meeting my funding needs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
