<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Pelosi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pelosi/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Pelosi on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:38:14 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/pelosi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Pelosi Visits Taiwan</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 22:57:54 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/pelosi-visits-taiwan/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t know politics, don’t make comments, record this “carnival” on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;musings&#34;&gt;Musings
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;Tangshan Assault Incident&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Primary School Textbook Cultural Invasion Incident&lt;/strong&gt; – I wonder how many people even remember them anymore. These trending news stories have become numbingly commonplace, without much feeling, and I just watch TV as usual after work, observing the spectacle. The economic situation is already dire; a war wouldn’t make things any better.  I don&amp;rsquo;t understand politics or offer commentary, simply recording this internet-fueled “carnival.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wiki-overviewhttpszhwikipediaorgwiki2022e5b9b4e58d97e8a5bfc2b7e8a3b4e6b49be8a5bfe8a8aae5958fe58fb0e781a3&#34;&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/2022%E5%B9%B4%E5%8D%97%E8%A5%BF%C2%B7%E8%A3%B4%E6%B4%9B%E8%A5%BF%E8%A8%AA%E5%95%8F%E5%8F%B0%E7%81%A3&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Wiki Overview&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nancy Pelosi&amp;rsquo;s visit to Taiwan in 2022, also known as the Pelosi visit to Taiwan, refers to U.S. House Speaker Nancy Pelosi’s 2022 trip to Asia, specifically her itinerary including a visit to Taiwan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Due to the U.S. House Speaker being considered the third-highest official in the United States and plans to visit Taiwan, the date was approaching the Chinese People&amp;rsquo;s Liberation Army&amp;rsquo;s (PLA) Founding Day on August 1st, and long-term it was approaching the Communist Party of China’s Twentieth National Congress, the 2022 U.S. elections, and the 2022 Republic of China local elections. The People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China side strongly protested, dispatching destroyer task forces to the northeast waters of the Taiwan Strait and mobilizing the Shandong and Liaoning aircraft carrier strike groups. The Eastern Theater Command and the Southern Theater Command respectively conducted large-scale live ammunition exercises in the East Sea and South China Sea. On the U.S. side, the Ronald Reagan aircraft carrier strike group arrived near the Taiwan Strait to guard against Pelosi’s possible visit to Taiwan, and dispatched several batches of reconnaissance aircraft and aerial refueling tankers to standby at the US Kadena Air Force Base. Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Joe Biden had a video meeting prior to the visit, which covered the issue of Taiwan. Taiwanese and international media revealed that Speaker Pelosi and the House of Representatives delegation would arrive at Songshan Airport in Taipei on the 2nd, stay overnight, and meet with Taiwan’s Presidential Office leader Tsai Ing-wen and other senior government officials on the 3rd.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;08-11&#34;&gt;08-11
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;By today, this has pretty much settled down. During this time, the headlines were dominated by various naval exercises, and Zhihu was putting in a lot of effort to update its trending charts every day, talking about all of this. Let the reporters work hard.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
