<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Lost-and-Confused on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Lost-and-Confused on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/lost-and-confused/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>lost-and-confused</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often, at some point in life, people fall into a state of confusion, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose sight of their pursuit of meaning. Remembering when I first graduated, my heart was filled with fervent aspirations; back then, I would have confidently said that I longed to write code—remarkable, exceptional code. However, in my current role, I’ve primarily dealt with operational matters, largely benefiting from the dividends of industry growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding my outlook on life, I haven&amp;rsquo;t considered marriage, having children, or establishing a career. My mind is mostly blank, and I just want to enjoy the present moment. On weekends, I like to play games quietly and often spend the whole day at home, immersed in my own world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone needs something they love and wholeheartedly dedicate themselves to in life&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buy-house&#34;&gt;Buy house
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A couple of years ago, I was determined to save enough money to buy my own home and meticulously planned every expense. However, seeing house prices continually rise, I went from anxiety and resentment to numbness. Eventually, I realized that even if I bought a property, it would just be another heavy burden, so I gave up on the idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;save-money&#34;&gt;Save money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving small goals – like building a powerful desktop computer, buying a camera I&amp;rsquo;d long wanted, or taking an impromptu trip. Now, I approach saving with a more relaxed attitude, worry less about daily expenses, indulge in what I want to eat, and boldly try new things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;go-home&#34;&gt;Go home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I truly longed for was simply to go home. No special occasion needed, just returning to a familiar place and feeling the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
