<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Lost-and-Confused on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Lost-and-Confused on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jun 2025 15:17:30 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/lost-and-confused/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>lost-and-confused</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 26 Aug 2021 18:01:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/lost-and-confused/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Often, at some stage in life, people find themselves lost in a haze, unsure of what they truly want. Amidst the mundane routines of work, they gradually lose their pursuit of meaning and purpose. Looking back to when I first graduated, my heart was full of fervent aspirations – I wouldn’t hesitate to say that I longed to write code, to create brilliant, eye-catching code. However, as I&amp;rsquo;ve worked for so long, I’ve had more exposure to business-level affairs, which has largely benefited from the advantages brought about by industry development.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of my life philosophy, I haven’t yet incorporated marriage and having children, or establishing a family, into my thinking. My mind is almost empty, simply focused on enjoying the present moment. Whenever weekends arrive, I enjoy quietly playing games, often spending an entire day at home, immersed in my own little world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;buying-a-house&#34;&gt;Buying a House
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Two years ago, I was full of enthusiasm, planning to save diligently and buy my own property. I meticulously budgeted every day towards this goal. However, as housing prices continued to skyrocket, my anxiety and resentment gradually turned into numbness, leading me to feel that even if I bought a house, it would simply be a heavy burden on my shoulders. Consequently, I abandoned this idea.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;saving-money&#34;&gt;Saving Money
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initially, saving money was about achieving some small goals, such as building a high-performance desktop computer, purchasing a long-desired camera, or taking an impromptu trip. However, now I approach saving with a more relaxed and “chill” attitude, no longer worrying too much about daily expenses – I indulge in things I want to eat and boldly try new and exciting things.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;returning-home&#34;&gt;Returning Home
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the end, I realized that what I most longed for deep down was simply to go home. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t anything particularly to do, just to return to that familiar place and feel the warmth and tranquility of home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
