<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/investment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 07:41:32 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war abruptly called a pause</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of trade war tariffs in 2025 presented a “escalation – counter-repressive measures – negotiations” cycle, with the US-China rivalry shifting from tariff confrontation to competition over rules. Despite short-term easing that alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty remains, and it’s crucial to monitor WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical shifts&amp;rsquo; sustained impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t earn money beyond their own cognitive expectations; the stock market crash triggered by the launch of the trade war this year has largely been recovered, but countless small investors have been buried along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 Trade War Tariff Timeline Overview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a timeline of the trade war tariff events, combining key events involving the US and China, and other countries, to present the dynamic evolution of tariff policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-upgrade-and-countermeasures-on-tariffs&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Upgrade and Countermeasures on Tariffs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Tariff Measures Against China&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2nd:&lt;/strong&gt; The Trump administration signed Executive Order No. 14257, announcing the imposition of a 34% “retaliatory tariff” on goods exported from China to the U.S., covering products originating in Hong Kong and Macao.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 8th:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States further increased the “retaliatory tariff” rate on Chinese goods from 34% to 84%, and signed Executive Orders No. 14259 and 14266, imposing tariffs on additional products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 10th:&lt;/strong&gt; The White House amended the executive order, increasing the total tariff amount against China to 145%, and raising the tariff rate on small packages (such as goods priced below $800 from 90% to 120%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China’s Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 4th:&lt;/strong&gt; China announced the imposition of a 34% tariff on all goods originating in the United States, covering sectors such as agricultural products, automobiles, and energy. - &lt;strong&gt;April 10th&lt;/strong&gt;: China will retaliate against the tariff rate increase from 34% to 84%, in sync with the US side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 12th&lt;/strong&gt;: China cancels the additional tariffs imposed on U.S. goods by 91% (corresponding to some of the cancellation by the US side) and suspends the implementation of 24% tariffs for 90 days, retaining 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-tariff-upgrade-and-countermeasures&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Tariff Upgrade and Countermeasures
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tariff Games Involving Other Countries&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US-Canada Trade War:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States imposes 25% tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum products, and Canada retaliates by taxing goods worth $298 billion from the US, as well as filing a WTO dispute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU &amp;amp; Japan:&lt;/strong&gt; The EU imposes maximum 25% tariffs on US goods, while Japan expresses concern over auto tariffs imposed by the US, calling the trade war “harming both sides.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-de-escalation&#34;&gt;II. May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff De-escalation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US-China High-Level Trade Talks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 10-11:&lt;/strong&gt; The US and China held a 16-hour meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, reaching the “Joint Statement on the US-China Economic Dialogue” (also known as the Geneva Accord).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 12:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides announced a suspension of some tariffs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The United States paused its 24% tariff on Chinese goods (for 90 days), retaining 10%, and rescinded the additional tariffs imposed on April 8th and 9th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China simultaneously suspended its 24% retaliatory tariffs, retaining 10%, and lifted non-tariff measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishment of a Consultation Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides agreed to hold regular trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reduction and rulemaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic Impact &amp;amp; Policy Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Domestic Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; High tariffs led to the closure of small and medium-sized enterprises (such as Amazon sellers forced to close due to tariff surges) and rising inflation expectations (core PCE is expected to rise to 3…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WTO and Multilateral Responses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China both lodged WTO disputes against the U.S. steel and aluminum tariffs and “retaliatory tariffs,” alleging violations of non-discrimination principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Azevedo warned that U.S. tariffs could cause a 1% contraction in global trade volumes by 2025, exacerbating difficulties for developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exemption Lists and Industry Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Excluded Goods:&lt;/strong&gt; A 37-page list covering strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT balls exposed supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Tariffs:&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. imposed 25% tariffs on imported automobiles, leading to an estimated 2% decline in global auto production and a 9% reduction in North American output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political and Strategic Maneuvering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through “retaliatory tariffs,” but was criticized as unilateral bullying, triggering backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States imposes additional tariffs of 34% on goods from Hong Kong and Macau.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-1&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 8th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States raised tariffs on Chinese imports to 84% and added new executive orders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-2&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 10th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China retaliates by imposing a 34% tariff, later raised to 84%; the US adjusts tariffs to 145%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-3&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States waived some goods (such as technology products), China lifted 91% of the counter-tariffs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-4&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 10-11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US-China talks in Geneva, reaching a joint statement on suspending tariffs by 24% (90 days).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-5&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both sides announced a suspension of tariffs and the establishment of a consultation mechanism, easing trade tensions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;five-trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Five. Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-Term Relief and Long-Term Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; The suspension of US-China tariffs sent positive signals, but structural issues (such as high technology and energy) remain, with midterm elections or policy continuity impacting the medium term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Supply Chain Restructuring:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies are accelerating adjustments to their supply chains, with Mexico and Southeast Asia benefiting from “nearshoring,” but rising costs may dampen recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multilateral Mechanism Dilemmas:&lt;/strong&gt; The WTO dispute resolution mechanism is limited, regional trade agreements (such as the US-UK agreement) are emerging as alternative options, but this could exacerbate fragmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Tariff storm, stock market crash</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 03:49:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/tariffs-storm-stock-market-crash/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, the global stock markets have experienced significant volatility, primarily due to new measures announced by U.S. President Donald Trump regarding a new round of comprehensive tariffs, which has triggered market concerns about a global trade war and economic recession.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tariff Policy Sparks Market Panic&lt;/strong&gt;
President Trump announced last week the imposition of high tariffs on all imported goods, with up to 50% tariffs added on imports from China, aimed at correcting what he termed an unfair global trading system. This move led to panic selling across global markets as investors worried that escalating trade tensions would stifle global economic growth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Stock Markets Plunge Sharply&lt;/strong&gt;
In the United States, major indices suffered heavy losses. The Dow Jones Industrial Average fell by more than 1,200 points, the Nasdaq Composite declined by 4%, and the S&amp;amp;P 500 dropped 3.8%, entering bear market territory. Asia and Europe were no exception, with the Nikkei 225 in Japan down nearly 8% and European stocks down 6%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investors Seek Safe-Haven Assets&lt;/strong&gt;
Faced with market turmoil, investors have been turning to safe-haven assets such as bonds and the Japanese yen. However, the VIX (Volatility Index) surged to above 60, indicating heightened market panic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economists Warn of Stagnation Risk&lt;/strong&gt;
Economists warn that trade policies could lead the U.S. economy into “stagflation” – a situation where economic growth stagnates, inflation rises, and unemployment remains high.  JPMorgan has raised the probability of a US recession in 2025 to 60%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reactions from Governments and Corporations&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Governments around the world have indicated they will take retaliatory measures. For example, the European Union’s trade chief stated that tariffs would be imposed on U.S. goods starting April 15th. Businesses have also expressed concerns, with Wall Street firms like Goldman Sachs raising the probability of a U.S. economic recession to 45%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Currently, the global market is facing unprecedented challenges, and investors must closely monitor trade policy developments and market fluctuations, and implement effective risk management and asset allocation strategies.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Wide Base Exponential Fixed Investment (also known as “Buy and Hold”): Brokerage ETF, Heng Seng Tech Index</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 21:58:59 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/etf-wide-index-dzt-broker-etfs-hangsheng-tech-index/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve always wanted to do things, like buying a suitable blue-chip stock and just letting it sit, waiting for it to drop so I could assess the situation before adding more, and selling when it rose. The result was that I never managed to do it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finding an appropriate blue-chip stock is troublesome; it’s better to choose a broad market index ETF. Currently, my plan is to invest in a brokerage ETF and the Hong Kong Technology Index ETF.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The kind of trading strategy described above has a professional name: bottom fishing (buying back during a leftward decline).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As for the next step, I plan to select a broad market index to thoroughly practice it – achieving an annualized return that outperforms the regular savings account interest rate is the goal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;brokerage-etfs&#34;&gt;Brokerage ETFs
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;A brokerage ETF is an exchange-traded fund (ETF) primarily invested in Chinese securities companies as the main investment target. It mainly invests in the listed stocks of Chinese securities companies in the stock market. Brokerage ETFs typically track a specific brokerage company index, such as the China Securities Brokerage Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I previously bought it once, but at that time I was chasing highs and ultimately suffered losses, so I liquidated the position. The Chinese market – whenever there’s a bull run, brokerage companies are bound to rise, and how much they will rise depends on investors&amp;rsquo; emotions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-tech-index&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Hang Seng Tech Index is an equity index launched by the Hong Kong Exchange, designed to reflect the overall performance of the technology industry in Hong Kong markets. The index includes major technology companies listed on the Hong Kong Stock Exchange, covering areas such as internet, e-commerce, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As of May 20, 2025, the top ten constituent stocks of the Hang Seng Tech Index (code: 800700) and their weightings are listed below (data sourced from multiple authoritative sources):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Xiaomi Group-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01810.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01810.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.82%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tencent Holdings&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00700.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00700.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 8.14%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alibaba-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09988.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09988.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.72%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JD Group-SW&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09618.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09618.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.60%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meituan-W&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://03690.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;03690.HK&lt;/a&gt;): approximately 7.35%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kuaishou-W&lt;/strong&gt; ([01024.HK](http://01024.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;hang-seng-tech-index-1&#34;&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ol start=&#34;8&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ASML Holding&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00981.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00981.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 5.70%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;NetEase-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09999.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09999.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 4.59%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ctrip Group-S&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://09961.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;09961.HK&lt;/a&gt;): Approx. 4.48%
&lt;strong&gt;Total Percentage:&lt;/strong&gt; Approx. 66.6% (Note: Some sources show the top ten combined percentage between 68%-69%, due to differences in statistical timing points.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-notes&#34;&gt;Key Notes
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Weight Cap Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;: The Hang Seng Tech Index sets an 8% weight limit for individual stocks. For example, before the adjustment on March 2025, SMIC’s weighting exceeded 8%, but was subsequently passively reduced to comply with the limits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Constituent Stock Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;: On May 16, 2025, the Hang Seng Index Company announced that BYD ( &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://01211.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;01211.HK&lt;/a&gt; ) will be included in the index and Guolian Group (&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;http://00772.HK&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;00772.HK&lt;/a&gt;) will be excluded. The adjustment will take effect on June 6th. Therefore, as of today (May 20th), the constituent stocks are still based on the pre-adjustment list, and BYD has not yet been included.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry Distribution&lt;/strong&gt;: Among the top ten constituent stocks, internet technology companies (such as Tencent, Alibaba, Meituan) dominate, with significant weights in new energy vehicles (Xiaomi, Ideal) and semiconductors (SMIC), reflecting the index’s coverage of technology and the new economy. &lt;strong&gt;Data Timeliness:&lt;/strong&gt; The primary differences in data from various sources stem from differing statistical time points. For example, data from March 2025 showed a combined top ten share of approximately 69.4%, while data from May 14th indicated 68.82%, reflecting the dynamic impact of market fluctuations on the weighting distribution.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;short-put-cover&#34;&gt;Short Put Cover
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The “Short Put Cover” strategy is an investment approach where investors, anticipating a stock price nearing its bottom as it continues to decline, actively buy in batches to reduce their average cost basis, waiting for future price recovery and profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This method falls under the category of “Short Trading,” which involves counter-trend operations before the market has clearly established a bottom. Specifically, investors typically employ a “pyramid” or stepped-up buying strategy, gradually increasing the quantity purchased as the stock price declines to dilute the average cost basis. For example, initially purchasing a certain number of shares, if the price continues to fall, the investor increases the purchase volume at a lower price, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reduce Cost Basis:&lt;/strong&gt; By buying in batches during the decline, the average cost basis is diluted, creating conditions for future profits. - &lt;strong&gt;Pre-positioning:&lt;/strong&gt; Establishing positions before the market reverses, aiming to secure larger profits when the market rebounds.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Risk:&lt;/strong&gt; If stock prices continue to fall, it could lead to greater losses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Capital Tie-up:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires sufficient funds to continuously add to positions and may face the risk of capital being long-term trapped.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Relatively speaking, “right-side trading” involves buying after market trends become clear and there are definite signs of a price rebound, which carries lower risk but could miss out on initial gains during a rally. Therefore, investors should choose a suitable trading strategy based on their risk tolerance, financial situation, and market judgment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory&#34;&gt;Valuation Theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Valuation theory is a core concept in finance that aims to assess the intrinsic value of assets or companies, providing a basis for investment decisions. Through valuation, investors can determine whether the current market price of an asset is reasonable and develop appropriate investment strategies accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Key Valuation Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Discounted Cash Flow (DCF) Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method is based on the cash flows expected to be generated by an asset over its future period and discounts these cash flows to their present value using an appropriate discount rate. The DCF method emphasizes intrinsic value and is suitable for evaluating companies with stable and predictable earnings.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Relative Valuation Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method assesses a company&amp;rsquo;s relative value by comparing valuation metrics such as Price-to-Earnings (P/E) ratio, Price-to-Book (P/B) ratio, and Price-to-Sales (P/S) ratio with those of other companies in the same industry. - Relative Valuation Method is straightforward to operate, widely used for rapid assessment and comparison within the same industry.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Asset Basis Method:&lt;/strong&gt; This method determines a company’s value by evaluating its net assets – total assets minus liabilities. The Asset Basis Method is suitable for asset-driven companies such as real estate firms or capital-intensive businesses.
&lt;strong&gt;Application of Valuation Theories:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Decisions:&lt;/strong&gt; Through valuation, investors can identify undervalued or overvalued assets and develop buy or sell strategies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Corporate Mergers &amp;amp; Acquisitions:&lt;/strong&gt; In M&amp;amp;A transactions, valuation is key to determining the transaction price and influences the success or failure of the deal.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;valuation-theory-1&#34;&gt;Valuation Theory
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Financial Reporting:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies need to assess the fair value of their assets and liabilities to ensure the accuracy and transparency of financial statements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please note that valuation results are influenced by various factors, including market conditions, company operations, macroeconomic indicators, etc. Therefore, when conducting a valuation, it is necessary to consider all factors comprehensively and combine qualitative and quantitative analysis to obtain a more accurate assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and even if you’re anxious, it won’t help.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs. My ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prompt: Write an article: Addressing the psychological issues in stock trading investment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from the initial entry into the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my investments focused primarily on blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, HK Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Expecting an annualized return of parlaying with hype about matching bank three-year fixed deposits,” in reality, it was driven by greed wanting more, rushing to add positions early on, and then exhausting cash flow later. Purchases of insurance, buying a house, and getting married all represented significant outflows of capital, leading to insufficient liquidity overall due to a lack of sufficient funds allocated within the broader plan. Buying blue chips is like aligning with “old money”—&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When Evergrande ran into trouble, bank stocks plummeted dramatically, successfully capitalizing on the opportunity to clear out positions. This reflects a deficiency in understanding for the broader economic market. The real estate sector accounts for too much of China’s economy, and any issues within it have far-reaching implications; it cannot be “force-landed,” leading to continued downward pressure on the stock market. Red-chip stocks like &lt;strong&gt;Industrial Bank&lt;/strong&gt; continued to rise for about two years after that.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, &lt;strong&gt;Zhongxing Telecom&lt;/strong&gt; was severely impacted, and its stock price also fell sharply. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HSPE (Hubei Hongyu Precision Electronics)&lt;/strong&gt; is a legacy company; after Ant Financial withdrew, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock had a controlling shareholder manipulating it, allowing it to surge several times per year. With reasonable position control, losses can be minimized.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;greed-the-monster-devouring-reason&#34;&gt;Greed: The “Monster” Devouring Reason
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Greed is the most common problem in a stock trading mentality.&lt;/strong&gt; When stock prices rise steadily, and investors’ account profits continuously increase, greed quietly takes root. Many people still fantasize about continued price increases even when stocks are already at high levels, craving more gains and unwilling to cut their profits. They are blinded by greed, forgetting the existence of market rules and risks. For example, during the hype of certain hot-topic stocks, some investors see prices double or even multiply within a short period, falling into it, constantly adding to their positions, hoping to be the last winner. However, the market will not always go crazy; when the bubble bursts and stock prices plummet sharply, these investors driven by greed often suffer heavy losses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fear-the-chains-that-restrict&#34;&gt;Fear: The “Chains” That Restrict
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fear is the counterpart to greed. It possesses a powerful destructive force in the stock market as well. When market conditions suddenly reverse and stock prices plummet dramatically, investors are prone to panic. This fear erodes their confidence in the market, even when the fundamentals of their holdings are sound, leading them to hastily sell off their shares out of a fear of further losses. For example, during periods of global financial crises, even high-quality blue-chip stocks saw significant declines alongside the broader market. Some investors were consumed by fear and failed to recognize the long-term value of these companies, selling their stock at extremely low prices and missing out on the substantial returns that came with subsequent market rebounds and company performance growth. Fear not only causes short-term losses for investors but can also create a lasting psychological shadow over the stock market, causing them to be reluctant to re-enter investments, thereby losing opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;blind-following-losing-direction-in-the-fog&#34;&gt;Blind Following: Losing Direction in the &amp;ldquo;Fog&amp;rdquo;
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In stock trading and wealth management, blindly following trends is another psychological pitfall that investors easily fall into. In an era of information explosion, all kinds of investment advice, market rumors, and hot topics are rampant. Many investors lack independent thinking and judgment abilities, blindly following others&amp;rsquo; operations. When they see their peers making money by buying a particular stock, they immediately follow suit without further thought; when they hear so-called &amp;ldquo;insider news,&amp;rdquo; they readily share it. This blind following behavior ignores the research and analysis of the underlying stocks, causing investors to be like lost ships in the fog, losing their own direction. For example, some momentum stocks can generate short-term gains for followers during the initial market hype. However, as the hype fades and stock prices plummet, those investors who don’t understand the situation and blindly follow become “pickup operators.” They fail to realize that each investor&amp;rsquo;s risk tolerance, investment objectives, and investment horizon are different; an investment strategy that works for others may not be suitable for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;overconfidence-the-hidden-rocks&#34;&gt;Overconfidence: The Hidden “Rocks”
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Overconfidence is also a significant issue in the investment and financial mindset. Some investors, after achieving several successful investments, begin to inflate their egos, believing they have mastered market patterns and can accurately predict stock movements. They ignore the complexity and uncertainty of the market, engage in excessive trading, blindly expand their investment scale, and even use high leverage for speculation. However, the market is ever-changing, and overconfident investors often suffer severe setbacks in a single unexpected market fluctuation. For example, some investors with limited experience who achieved an initial victory believe they possess professional investment capabilities and begin to frequently buy and sell stocks, constantly increasing their investment amount. When systemic risks or sudden negative news about individual stocks emerge, they fail to cut their losses promptly due to overconfidence, resulting in a significant reduction in their principal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-stable-financial-planning&#34;&gt;How to Adjust Your Mindset for Stable Financial Planning
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Establish the Correct Investment Philosophy: Investors should clearly understand that stock investing and wealth management are aimed at achieving long-term, stable asset appreciation, not overnight riches. By learning investment knowledge, understanding market rules, adopting value investing and long-term investment philosophies, and avoiding being swayed by short-term profits and market sentiment, you can make informed decisions. For example, thoroughly research a company’s fundamentals, paying attention to its profitability, industry position, management team, and other factors, choosing stocks with long-term investment potential rather than blindly chasing short-term trends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a Reasonable Investment Plan: Based on your financial situation, risk tolerance, and investment goals, create a scientific and reasonable investment plan. Clearly define key elements such as the amount invested, the investment period, expected returns, and stop-loss points, and strictly execute according to the plan. This can help avoid impulsive decisions made due to emotional fluctuations during investment. For example, set the investment proportion of each stock to no more than a certain percentage of total assets, and promptly take profits when the price rises to reach the expected return, and decisively cut losses when it falls to the stop-loss point.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Control emotions and remain calm: When facing market volatility, you need to learn to control your own emotions, maintain calmness and rationality. You can relieve investment pressure by diverting attention, engaging in physical exercise, or communicating with others, avoiding negative impacts of emotion on investment decisions. When the market experiences a significant fluctuation, first calmly analyze the reasons, combine them with your investment strategy and stock fundamentals, and make rational judgments instead of blindly following trends or panic selling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-to-adjust-your-mindset-for-steady-wealth-management&#34;&gt;How to Adjust Your Mindset for Steady Wealth Management
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Learning and Reflection: The stock market is constantly evolving, and investors need to continuously learn new investment knowledge and skills, paying attention to macroeconomic trends, industry dynamics, and company information, and constantly improving their investment level. At the same time, it’s important to regularly reflect on your investment behavior, summarize experiences and lessons learned, identify problems in your mindset and decision-making, and promptly adjust and improve them. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze the reasons for success and failure, and think about how to avoid similar mistakes in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in stocks and wealth management is a long and challenging journey, and mindset plays a crucial role. Only by maintaining a rational, calm, humble, and independent-thinking mindset can you steadily progress through the waves of the stock market and achieve the preservation and appreciation of your wealth. ## How to Adjust Your Mindset for Steady Financial Planning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Continuous Learning and Reflection: The stock market is constantly evolving, and investors need to continuously learn new investment knowledge and skills, paying attention to macroeconomic trends, industry dynamics, and company information, and constantly improving their investment level. At the same time, it’s important to regularly reflect on your investment behavior, summarize experiences and lessons learned, identify problems in your mindset and decision-making, and promptly adjust and improve them. For example, after each investment, review the entire process, analyze the reasons for success and failure, and think about how to avoid similar mistakes in future investments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in stocks and financial planning is a long and challenging journey, and mindset plays a crucial role. Only by maintaining a rational, calm, humble, and independent-thinking mindset can you steadily progress through the stock market’s fluctuations and achieve the preservation and appreciation of wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fixed Income Funds / Bond Funds</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/fund-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 90s, we didn’t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis – after all, we were young and hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet started to focus on finance. The roaring bull market of 2015 came with a lot of fanfare, and when it ended, it made quite a stir, ultimately requiring government intervention to stabilize the markets. Simultaneously, this brought the concept of “funds” into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Alipay, as a natural traffic entry under Ant Financial, was born with the positioning of a payment tool. When purchasing funds, most people chose Alipay like WeChat did. Alipay successfully transformed fund sales into an ordinary shopping experience. Starting in 2019, with the small bull market, fund managers’ “warming up” recruitment, ultimately stemmed from the monetary loosening guided by the COVID-19 pandemic. Those who entered made money, those who didn&amp;rsquo;t enter were envious and rushed to join in. The scale of new funds broke through the hundred billion mark at an increasingly rapid pace, and a trillion-fund market was not far off, even in scenarios where “grandmothers” (older investors) started buying funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Ant Financial’s explosive rise as a code-based internet fund sales platform, ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s contact with fund sales was primarily through depositing money at banks, where the bank manager would enthusiastically introduce various investment products. The packaging of the internet, promotional pages guiding information, and exorbitant advertising fees paid by fund sales institutions completely detached Alipay’s fund advertisements from reason.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal bank fixed-term investment returns are 4%, P2P investments that were played wildly in recent years reached 8%, credit card repayment interest rates are 12%. Our protagonist, Alipay&amp;rsquo;s promoted funds of 150% and 250% are trending, making insiders happy. The market declines? Alipay is playing with fire.&lt;/strong&gt; The advertised growth figures only show the three-year returns, while traditional fund companies only provide annualized average returns. Why don’t they dare to present the annual average returns separately? It&amp;rsquo;s not because it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to calculate – the answer is no, because unfavorable data doesn’t encourage customers to buy funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investments&#34;&gt;Fixed Income Investments
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entered a negative interest rate era, making bank deposits and government bonds the most secure fixed-income products. Pure credit funds are also a good option. You can refer to the data published by local statistical bureaus to find China’s average wage levels. Here’s a simple scenario: with an asset size of 2 million (CNY), a yearly yield of 4% converted, the annual income would exceed most cities&amp;rsquo; average wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s much more to say. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading a variety of economic books yourself – don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow. For ordinary families, the core of financial planning is preservation, not chasing risky dreams of getting rich quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right thing at the right time has the greatest value; study diligently when you’re studying, and earning a good degree is better than making pocket money by distributing flyers; work seriously when you first graduate, and your salary increases can bring you substantial returns; and when you start a family, learn to take care of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue-1&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those interested can take a look at this speech transcript: “On Time,” you’ll need to read many books to find the answers – the text of the speech is available on our site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
