<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/categories/investment/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Investment on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 21:19:42 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/categories/investment/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Premium Whole Life Insurance Policy Interpretation</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:13:58 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/premium-whole-life-insurance-policy-interpretation/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s difficult for ordinary people to understand a policy document, and traditional financial planning is based on understanding annualized returns. However, the calculation method of an increasing term life insurance policy is Internal Rate of Return (IRR), and there&amp;rsquo;s a difference between these two – what’s the difference and why does it exist?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When funds are invested in one go, &lt;strong&gt;Internal Rate of Return (IRR)&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return (Annualized Return)&lt;/strong&gt; produce the same results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;laymans-explanation&#34;&gt;Layman&amp;rsquo;s Explanation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Imagine you planted a tree.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Lump Sum Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; You invested the money to buy the sapling and the fertilizer for the first year all at once.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt; This is like measuring how much your tree grows each year, then calculating the average percentage it grows by per year. It measures how much your money grew on average over one year.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRR (Internal Rate of Return):&lt;/strong&gt; The IRR concept is broader and can handle situations with multiple cash inflows and outflows. However, in a simple scenario where you have a single investment and a single return, IRR also seeks to find an “average annual growth rate” that makes the money grow at this percentage over time, exactly equaling the amount you finally receive back.
Because in a single investment, single return scenario, there are no intermediate cash flows (like regular dividends or additional investments), the calculation of IRR is simplified into finding a compound annual growth rate, which is exactly what the annualized return expresses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example&#34;&gt;An Example
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Initial Investment:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2024, you invested &lt;strong&gt;10,000 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investment Term:&lt;/strong&gt; 3 years.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Final Return:&lt;/strong&gt; On January 1st, 2027, you received back &lt;strong&gt;13,310 yuan&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;1-annualized-return&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Annualized Return:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The formula for calculating annualized return is:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{\text{Ending Value}}{\text{Beginning Value}} \right)^{\frac{1}{\text{Investment Period}}} - 1$$
&lt;p&gt;
Substituting the data:
&lt;/p&gt;
$$\text{Annualized Return} = \left( \frac{13310}{10000} \right)^{\frac{1}{3}} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = (1.331)^{0.3333} - 1$$
$$\text{Annualized Return} = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
&lt;p&gt;
Therefore, the annualized return on this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;. This means your money grew an average of 10% per year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;2-internal-rate-of-return-irr&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Internal Rate of Return (IRR):&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;IRR is the discount rate that makes the net present value (NPV) of all cash flows zero. In this example, the cash flows include:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2024: -10,000 (Cash outflow – investment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;January 1, 2027: +13,310 (Investment recovery)
We need to find a discount rate &lt;em&gt;r&lt;/em&gt; such that:
$$-10000 + \frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 0$$
$$\frac{13310}{(1+r)^3} = 10000$$
$$(1+r)^3 = \frac{13310}{10000} = 1.331$$
$$1+r = (1.331)^{\frac{1}{3}}$$
$$1+r = 1.1$$
$$r = 1.1 - 1 = 0.1 = 10\%$$
Therefore, the internal rate of return (IRR) for this investment is &lt;strong&gt;10%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In this simple example of a one-time investment and one-time recovery, you will find that the results of calculating the annualized yield and internal rate of return are identical. This is because in this specific case, the IRR calculation logic is equivalent to the compound interest calculation logic used to determine the annualized yield.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;IRR truly comes into play when an investment involves &lt;strong&gt;multiple cash flows&lt;/strong&gt;, such as investing in a fund where you contribute money each month, or investing in a project that pays dividends at different points in time and ultimately recovers a final sum of money. In this complex cash flow pattern, the annualized yield may not accurately measure the true return on investment, while IRR can better reflect the time value of money and the overall rate of return for the investment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Where can I find backtest data?</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/where-can-i-find-backtest-data/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 27 Jun 2025 19:33:56 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/where-can-i-find-backtest-data/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Backtesting requires: proportionate method (price-weighted return method), a simple explanation, and examples. Also, why cannot use add-subtract method for adjustment, and recommendations for Python historical data sources using the proportionate method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, let&amp;rsquo;s explain the “proportionate method (price-weighted return method)” in an easy-to-understand way, along with why the &amp;ldquo;add-subtract method&amp;rdquo; is not suitable, and we’ll recommend some Python historical data sources using the proportionate method.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-concepts-why-is-time-weighting-necessary&#34;&gt;Core Concepts: Why is Time-Weighting Necessary?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the world of investing, stock prices don&amp;rsquo;t just fluctuate due to buying and selling. Corporate actions, such as &lt;strong&gt;dividends, stock splits, and cash dividends&lt;/strong&gt;, directly impact share prices, but these changes don’t reflect the company’s true value growth or decline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imagine that yesterday your stock closed at a price of 100 yuan. Today, the company decides to pay out a dividend of 5 yuan per share. This process is called “ex-dividend.”  When the dividend is paid, the company&amp;rsquo;s total value decreases, so the exchange will lower the stock price by 5 yuan, opening at 95 yuan.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you directly used 95 yuan and yesterday’s 100 yuan to calculate the percentage change, you would arrive at a &lt;code&gt;-5%&lt;/code&gt; conclusion. This is clearly incorrect because you now have 5 yuan in your account, and your total assets haven&amp;rsquo;t decreased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time-Weighting (Reinvestment/Adjustment)&lt;/strong&gt; aims to fill in these price “gaps” caused by non-market transactions (such as dividends, stock splits) and restore the true trend of the stock price, allowing you to accurately calculate returns and perform strategy backtesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;percentage-method-earnings-per-share-adjusted-method-a-simple-example-explanation&#34;&gt;Percentage Method (Earnings Per Share Adjusted Method): A Simple Example Explanation
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Idea:&lt;/strong&gt; The percentage method assumes that all dividends and stock splits you receive are immediately repurchased at the prevailing price on the date they are received. It focuses on &lt;strong&gt;“the growth rate of total assets”&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
Assume you bought 1 share of “Magic Company” stock for &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt; on &lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt;. Your total asset is &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt;.
&lt;strong&gt;On Day 2&lt;/strong&gt;, the market hasn’t changed, but Magic Company announces a &amp;ldquo;cash dividend&amp;rdquo; of &lt;strong&gt;$2&lt;/strong&gt; per share.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;After the dividend payout, the price automatically drops from $100 to &lt;strong&gt;$98&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At this point, your holding is: 1 share stock (valued at $98) + $2 cash.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your &lt;strong&gt;total assets&lt;/strong&gt; remain at $98 + $2 = &lt;strong&gt;$100&lt;/strong&gt;, unchanged.
&lt;strong&gt;On Day 3&lt;/strong&gt;, the market rises, and Magic Company’s stock price increases from $98 to &lt;strong&gt;$102.9&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the increase? It&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;(102.9 - 98) / 98 = 5%&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How much are your total assets now worth?
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you didn’t reinvest the dividend: 1 share stock (valued at $102.9) + $2 cash = &lt;strong&gt;$104.9&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If we use the &lt;strong&gt;percentage method&lt;/strong&gt; to calculate a “adjusted” price, we assume that the $2 cash was bought back on day 2 at $98. But for simplicity, the percentage method directly multiplies the previous price by today’s rise or fall.
&lt;strong&gt;Percentage Method Calculation Logic:&lt;/strong&gt;
It assumes that the total assets (100) on Day 2 and Day 1 compared to each other have a growth rate of 0%. The total assets on Day 3 compared to Day 2 have a growth rate of 5%.
So, it will construct a continuous, adjusted price sequence:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1 Adjusted Price:&lt;/strong&gt; $100&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2 Adjusted Price:&lt;/strong&gt; Since the total asset hasn’t changed, it will “discount” yesterday’s closing price to reflect today&amp;rsquo;s actual situation. The method is to multiply yesterday’s adjusted price by today’s real rise or fall. On the dividend payout day, the real rise or fall is 0 (because the total assets haven’t changed), so the adjusted price remains unchanged, or we directly look at Day 3.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3 Adjusted Price:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;Day 1 Adjusted Price * (1 + 0%) * (1 + 5%)&lt;/code&gt; is inaccurate. The correct logic is that it will use the pre-dividend price as a baseline and then perform a “discounting”.
Let’s understand a more clear &lt;strong&gt;pre-adjusted&lt;/strong&gt; perspective:&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3&lt;/strong&gt; closing price is &lt;strong&gt;$102.9&lt;/strong&gt;. (Baseline)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2&lt;/strong&gt; closing price is &lt;strong&gt;$98&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt; closing price is $100, but because Day 2 has a dividend payout (the price drops from $100 to $98, equivalent to a discount of &lt;code&gt;98/100 = 0.98&lt;/code&gt;), we need to adjust the first day’s price according to this proportion.
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adjusted first day price = &lt;code&gt;102.9 / (1 + 5%) / (100/98)&lt;/code&gt; … This calculation is very complex.
&lt;strong&gt;The simplest way to understand (Percentage Method):&lt;/strong&gt;
The core of the percentage method is to ensure that the rise and fall of any two adjusted prices in a period equals the total return rate you would have obtained if you had reinvested all dividends.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;From Day 1 closing price to Day 3 closing price, your real total return is &lt;code&gt;(104.9 - 100) / 100 = 4.9%&lt;/code&gt;. (Assuming you didn’t reinvest).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If the dividend is immediately invested, on Day 3 your total assets will be &lt;code&gt;100 * (1 + 5%) = 105&lt;/code&gt; (because all $100 are in stocks and enjoy a 5% growth).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;So, the adjusted price sequence’s rise and fall should be 5%.
&lt;strong&gt;Conclusion:&lt;/strong&gt; The percentage method (Earnings Per Share Adjusted Method) adjusts historical prices to ensure that any period&amp;rsquo;s price rises and falls precisely correspond to the total return rate you would have obtained if you had reinvested all dividends. This is the most accurate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-cannot-use-add-subtract-reconciliation&#34;&gt;Why Cannot Use “Add-Subtract Reconciliation”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Core Idea:&lt;/strong&gt; Add-subtract reconciliation attempts to simply add the dividend amounts back into the pre-dividend stock price through addition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Example (Using the previous text):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 1&lt;/strong&gt; Closing Price: 100 yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 2&lt;/strong&gt; Dividend payout of 2 yuan, Closing Price: 98 yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Day 3&lt;/strong&gt; Increases by 5%, Closing Price: 102.9 yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Flawed Logic of Add-Subtract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It will assume that the 98 yuan on Day 2 is because of a 2 yuan dividend deduction, so it should add this 2 yuan “back.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It calculates the second day’s “adjusted price” as 98 + 2 = 100 yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It calculates the third day’s “adjusted price” as 102.9 + 2 = 104.9 yuan.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now, let&amp;rsquo;s use this “adjusted price” sequence to calculate the percentage change on Day 3:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Percentage Change = &lt;code&gt;(104.9 - 100) / 100 = 4.9%&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Where Does the Error Lie?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This 4.9% percentage change is incorrect! As we analyzed earlier, the actual percentage increase in the stock price is &lt;code&gt;(102.9 - 98) / 98 = 5%&lt;/code&gt;. The add-subtract method underestimates the true growth potential of the stock.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why Does It Underestimate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because add-subtract does not consider the “compound interest” effect.  The proportional method assumes that your 2 yuan dividend also grows at a rate of 5%, while add-subtract crudely assumes this 2 yuan is always 2 yuan, without participating in subsequent investment appreciation. Over time and with increasing dividend payments, this error will become larger, seriously distorting your backtesting results, especially for high-dividend stocks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;In one sentence:&lt;/strong&gt; Add-subtract destroys the “growth rate” information of the price sequence, leading to incorrect yield calculations; proportional method preserves the true “yield,” making it the correct choice for backtesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;python-getting-historical-data-ratio-method-data-source-recommendations&#34;&gt;Python Getting Historical Data “Ratio Method” Data Source Recommendations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;In practice, we often don&amp;rsquo;t need to calculate the adjustments ourselves. Professional data providers directly offer already adjusted prices. You simply select the correct price type when calling the API. This is commonly referred to as &amp;ldquo;&lt;strong&gt;Adjusted Price&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;rdquo; (Adjusted Pricing).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are some highly-rated and effective data sources for obtaining back-adjusted historical data through Python:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;yfinance (Yahoo Finance)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Completely free, easy to use, the preferred choice for individual developers and beginners. The data it provides is already back-adjusted using the ratio method (forward-adjusted).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Data may have occasional cleaning issues or delays. For very rigorous business strategies, a more professional data source might be needed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Usage Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TuShare&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; A very popular financial data interface in China, providing rich data for A-shares, Hong Kong shares, US stocks, etc. Data quality is high, with a points system, but basic data is free. It offers clear adjustment factors and back-adjusted行情 (market data) interfaces.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Requires registration to obtain a token; some advanced data or high frequency calls require points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Usage Example (Requires first registering for a token):&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;baostock&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Free, open-source Chinese A-share securities data platform. Data is relatively stable and accurate, and it also provides back-adjustment options.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Primarily covers the A-share market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python Usage Example:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Commercial-Grade Data Sources (Quandl/FactSet, Refinitiv, Bloomberg)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Advantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Highest data quality, widest coverage, and most up-to-date updates, providing professional APIs and technical support.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Disadvantages:&lt;/strong&gt; Expensive, primarily aimed at financial institutions and corporate users.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Recommendations for Beginners:&lt;/strong&gt; Start with &lt;strong&gt;yfinance&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;TuShare&lt;/strong&gt;. They can fully meet the needs of learning, research, and personal backtesting projects, and will help you understand and apply the “ratio method” back-adjusted data effectively.  Be sure to select the &amp;ldquo;Adjusted&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Back-Adjusted&amp;rdquo; option when calling the API.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>“Making an investment and making money isn’t urgent, and getting anxious won’t help either.”</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 20:30:24 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/investing-takes-time/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on years of stock trading experiences, although I didn’t make a fortune, I also didn&amp;rsquo;t lose too much. The biggest issue was an unreasonable allocation of funds and an unstable mindset. Currently, my primary source of income is work, earning a fixed salary each day through part-time jobs, and my ability to withstand financial fluctuations remains at the level of bonds and bank deposits. However, people are inherently greedy; if you buy too little, even when prices rise, you won’t make money; and if you buy too much, you will lose money. At this point, maintaining a stable mindset is particularly important, as it can help us keep our wealth afloat.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;historical-loss-cases&#34;&gt;Historical Loss Cases
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from when I first entered the market, I’ve encountered small-cap and near-new stocks. Later, my focus shifted to blue-chip large-cap stocks: Industrial Bank, China Unicom, Hisense Electronics, ZTESC, and various large index funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Investing in blue chips is like aligning with “old money”:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Evergrande’s problems arose, bank stocks plummeted alongside it, successfully identifying the exit point. This reflected a lack of understanding regarding the broader economic market; real estate accounted for too much of China&amp;rsquo;s economy, and the implications were too extensive to simply “land” – the subsequent continued decline in the stock market saw blue-chip stocks like Industrial Bank continue to rise for about two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During the initial stages of the trade war, ZTESC suffered a severe blow, with its share price also falling dramatically. It has since gradually recovered.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hisense Electronics is an old veteran; after Ant Financial withdrew, its stock price also plummeted significantly. However, this stock had a controlling shareholder manipulating it, and it could surge several times each year. With reasonable position sizing, you wouldn’t lose much.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;bond-investment&#34;&gt;Bond Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s just say it was a lucky outcome, essentially benefiting from falling interest rates. There were changes at my job in Hangzhou, leading me to abandon the idea of buying a house and liquidate my existing bank term deposits. I then focused on reinvesting previously held bonds, significantly increasing my bond investment ratio. Fortunately, interest rates have been declining for several years, allowing me to capitalize on the “bull market” in bonds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my six months back in Hangzhou, I had plenty of time to reflect and gain clarity. Real estate isn’t a necessity, nor is staying in a particular location – my ability to handle stress was thus improved. If I were to lose my job, the mortgage would be like a mountain to climb.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;investment-return-expectations&#34;&gt;Investment Return Expectations
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;“The expected annualized oral commitment is comparable to a three-year fixed bank deposit,” but in reality, it’s greedy and wants more. From the initial frantic increase (adding positions), to later exhausting cash flow. Purchases of insurance, real estate, and weddings represent significant outflows of capital, and overall, there wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough capital flow left over, leading to insufficient funds later on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The subsequent plan is to long-term hold &lt;strong&gt;brokerage ETFs&lt;/strong&gt; and the &lt;strong&gt;Hang Seng Tech Index&lt;/strong&gt;, with an asset allocation that still includes insurance as a base, medium-to-long term bonds, and stock funds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>Fixed Income Funds / Bond Funds</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 09 Jul 2021 11:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/funds-and-fixed-income-wealth-management/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Those of us born in the 90s, we didn’t really feel the impact of the 2008 financial crisis – after all, we were young and hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet started to focus on finance. The roaring bull market of 2015 came with a lot of fanfare, and when it ended, it made quite a stir, ultimately requiring government intervention to stabilize the markets. Simultaneously, this brought the concept of “funds” into the view of ordinary people.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ant-financial-and-alipay&#34;&gt;Ant Financial and Alipay
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;As a natural traffic entry for Ant Financial, Alipay was born with the positioning of a payment tool. When purchasing funds, Alipay and WeChat both saw widespread adoption – most people chose Alipay. Alipay has successfully transformed fund sales into an ordinary shopping experience. Starting in 2019, during the small bull market, fund managers’ “warming up” recruitment, ultimately driven by the monetary easing guided by the COVID-19 pandemic. Those who entered made a profit, those who didn&amp;rsquo;t enter envied them and rushed to join. The scale of new funds broke through the hundred billion mark at an increasingly rapid pace, and with grandmothers starting to buy funds, another trillion fund is not far off.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to Alipay’s explosive rise as a code-driven internet fund sales platform, ordinary people&amp;rsquo;s contact with fund sales was primarily when depositing money in banks, where the branch manager would enthusiastically introduce various investment products. The internet packaging and promotional page information guidance, the exorbitant advertising fees given by fund sales institutions, completely detached Alipay’s fund advertisements from rationality.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal bank fixed-term investment returns are 4%, P2P investments that played wildly in recent years were 8%, credit card repayment interest rates are 12%. Our protagonist, Alipay&amp;rsquo;s promoted funds – 150% and 250% – were popular in the market, making everyone happy, both inside and outside the market? Alipay was playing with fire.&lt;/strong&gt; The advertised returns only showed the three-year cumulative yield chart, while traditional fund companies only presented annualized average yields. Why didn’t they dare to present the annual average yield alone? Because it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t look good, and it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t guide customers to purchase funds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;fixed-income-investment&#34;&gt;Fixed Income Investment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;China hasn&amp;rsquo;t yet entered a negative interest rate era, making bank deposits and government bonds the most secure fixed-income products. Pure credit funds are also a good option. You can refer to the data published by local statistical bureaus to find China’s average wage levels. I’ll present a simple scenario: with an asset size of 2 million (CNY), an annualized yield of 4%, the annual income will exceed most cities&amp;rsquo; average wages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is largely based on my personal experiences, and there’s much more I could write. If you want to learn more, I recommend reading a variety of economic books yourself – don&amp;rsquo;t blindly follow. For ordinary families, the core of financial planning is preservation, not chasing risky dreams of getting rich quick.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My uncle often says:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The right thing at the right time has the greatest value; study diligently when you’re studying, and getting a good degree is better than earning pocket money by distributing flyers; work seriously when you first graduate, and the growth in your salary will bring you substantial returns; and when you start a family, learn to take care of your home.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;epilogue-1&#34;&gt;Epilogue
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Those interested can take a look at this speech transcript: On Time, you need to read many books to find the answer. The text transcript is available on our site.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
