<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Embedded-Systems on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/embedded-systems/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Embedded-Systems on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/embedded-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Embedded Systems – Getting Started Part 1 – Technical Terms</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/embedded-entry-professional-terms/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 13:42:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/embedded-entry-professional-terms/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s the English translation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When I think of embedded systems, my mind immediately goes back to the 51-pin single-chip microcomputers and Texas Instruments we used in university labs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LPA3399Pro is a visual host developed on the HiSilicon RK3399Pro platform, designed for portable computing hosts that require extensive visual computation. It features an integrated NPU compute unit with 3.0 TOPS of processing power and supports various algorithm models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RV1109 is HiSilicon’s SoC for machine vision within its AI branch, featuring a dedicated NPU. RV1109 provides 1TOPS of processing power.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;system-on-chip&#34;&gt;System on Chip
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SoC stands for System on a Chip, meaning “chiplet system.” It’s a technology that integrates multiple electronic systems onto a single chip. This technology can significantly reduce the size and weight of electronic products while simultaneously improving performance and lowering power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoC (System on a Chip) and CPU (Central Processing Unit) are both important components of computer systems, but they have some distinctions between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU is the core processor within a computer system, responsible for executing program instructions. It typically only contains basic components such as arithmetic logic units, control units, and registers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SoC, on the other hand, integrates multiple electronic systems onto a single chip, including a CPU, along with other components like memory, graphics processors, and input/output interfaces. This allows for significant reductions in product size and weight while boosting performance and reducing power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, the CPU is a component of an SoC, whereas the SoC represents a more complex and highly integrated electronic system.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microcontroller-unit&#34;&gt;Microcontroller Unit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SoC (System on a Chip) and MCU (Microcontroller Unit) are technologies that integrate multiple electronic systems onto a single chip, but there are also some differences between them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An MCU is a microcontroller, typically containing a CPU, memory, input/output interfaces, and other basic components. It’s commonly used to control other electronic devices such as household appliances and automotive electronics systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An SoC, on the other hand, integrates more electronic systems onto a single chip, in addition to the basic components of an MCU, it can also integrate other components like graphics processors and wireless communication modules. This significantly reduces the size and weight of electronic products while improving performance and reducing power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In essence, an MCU is a simple microcontroller, whereas an SoC is a more complex and highly integrated electronic system.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
