<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Embedded-Systems on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/embedded-systems/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Embedded-Systems on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/embedded-systems/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Embedded Systems: Introduction 1 - Professional Terminology</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/embedded-introduction-professional-terms/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Mar 2023 13:42:36 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/embedded-introduction-professional-terms/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mentioning embedded systems, I still think of the 51 microcontroller and Freescale from my school lab days&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The LPA3399Pro is a visual host system developed on the Rockchip RK3399Pro platform, designed for portable computing in scenarios requiring extensive vision processing. It features an integrated NPU unit with 3.0 TOPS of computing power and supports various algorithm models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The RV1109 is a SoC from Realtek Semiconductor&amp;rsquo;s AI-driven machine vision branch, featuring an integrated NPU. It offers 1 TOPS of computing power.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;system-on-chip&#34;&gt;System on Chip
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;SoC is an abbreviation for &amp;ldquo;System on a Chip,&amp;rdquo; referring to a technology that integrates multiple electronic systems onto a single chip. This reduces the size and weight of electronic products while improving performance and reducing power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SoCs (System on a Chip) and CPUs (Central Processing Units) are both important components of computer systems, but they have some differences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The CPU is the core processor in a computer system, responsible for executing program instructions. It typically consists of basic components such as an arithmetic unit, control unit, and registers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System-on-a-Chip (SoC) integrates multiple electronic systems onto a single chip, including components like CPU, memory, graphics processors, and input/output interfaces. This reduces the size and weight of electronic products while improving performance and reducing power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, the CPU is a component of the SoC, while the SoC is a more complex and highly integrated electronic system&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;microcontroller-unit&#34;&gt;Microcontroller Unit
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Both SoCs (Systems on a Chip) and MCUs (Microcontrollers) integrate multiple electronic systems onto a single chip, but they differ in several ways&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An MCU (Microcontroller Unit) typically includes basic components such as a CPU, memory, and input/output interfaces. It is commonly used to control other electronic devices like home appliances and automotive electronics systems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;System-on-Chip (SoC) integrates more electronic systems onto a single chip, including basic MCU components and additional elements like graphics processors and wireless communication modules. This significantly reduces the size and weight of electronic products while improving performance and reducing power consumption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short, an MCU is a simple microcontroller, while a SoC is a more complex, highly integrated electronic system&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
