<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Google on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/google/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Google on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:36:31 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/google/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Gemini CLI installation and deployment, Google is catching up.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/gemini-cli-installation-and-deployment-google-is-catching-up/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 00:13:49 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/gemini-cli-installation-and-deployment-google-is-catching-up/</guid>
        <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s been almost half a month, and MiniMax and GLM4.6 in China have both had paid trials – the difference is still noticeable. The cc tool is quite useful. Last night I was messing around with optimizing the front-end interface, you know… as a writer, I basically don&amp;rsquo;t understand front-end development; Vibe Coding will be next, and I’m starting to get into the front-end technology stack. Domestic large models haven’t been figured out; I tried the newly released Gemini3, and it was done in five minutes. Switching to the site’s archived pages, you can see “the bookshelf.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Having spent years doing back-end C++ development, Google&amp;rsquo;s influence in this area is huge. You can default to assuming that Google products won’t be bad – large models were initially lagging behind, but within two years, they’ve caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The AI search on the homepage, Baidu doesn’t know when it will get out; it’s not saying that Baidu isn&amp;rsquo;t capable, it’s that domestic products haven’t thought about embedding AI in search – most importantly, speed. Google did it right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;installation--deployment&#34;&gt;Installation &amp;amp; Deployment
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Since the Google models are so good, they’ve provided free credits and haven&amp;rsquo;t notified anyone about cancellations – let’s just use them first. For individual users, you get 1000 free credits daily, while Pro users receive 1500. Essentially, Google hasn’t yet figured out how to monetize this from a coding perspective.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Similar to cc’s installation deployment, the official documentation is quite detailed – we won&amp;rsquo;t go into specifics: &lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://geminicli.com/docs/&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;https://geminicli.com/docs/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key point for domestic users is that you need to add a proxy to your current terminal when logging in; it will access Google’s servers, and you also need to maintain the proxy after logging in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For remote server logins, without a browser or interface, execute &lt;code&gt;gemini login&lt;/code&gt;, accessing the corresponding URL to obtain a login code.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gemini3 requires joining a queue for application. Gemini2-Pro and other models can be used freely.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After logging in with your Google account, you need to bind your Google Cloud project ID. Free is free, but if it transitions to a paid process, don’t go through the API flow – that&amp;rsquo;s where the charges occur. For personal accounts, set the environment variable &lt;code&gt;GOOGLE_CLOUD_PROJECT&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Regarding Google Cloud, neither Douyin nor domestic influencers have mentioned it, and they say you can use it for free. The question is how those videos are generated – there’s a suspicion of plagiarism. The process hasn&amp;rsquo;t been fully traversed.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;usage&#34;&gt;Usage
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;There’s a gap in functionality compared to cc, it&amp;rsquo;s being iterated on weekly, and remember to update regularly. Switching between the basic usage and cc types doesn’t incur much cost.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interactively, it differs somewhat; the terminal screen is divided into two sections with the input box at the bottom and the conversation process above – this is expanded by default.  Scrolling the mouse isn&amp;rsquo;t possible to flip pages in the upper area; instead, you need to use the “Pages” key on the keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon the end of each session, a summary of the task will be displayed by default.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34;&gt;   ░░░            ░░░░░░░░░  ░░░░░░░░░░ ░░░░░░   ░░░░░░ ░░░░░ ░░░░░░   ░░░░░ ░░░░░
     ░░░         ░░░     ░░░ ░░░        ░░░░░░   ░░░░░░  ░░░  ░░░░░░   ░░░░░  ░░░
       ░░░      ░░░          ░░░        ░░░ ░░░ ░░░ ░░░  ░░░  ░░░ ░░░  ░░░    ░░░
 ███     ░░░    █████████░░██████████ ██████ ░░██████░█████░██████ ░░█████ █████░
   ███ ░░░     ███░    ███░███░░      ██████  ░██████░░███░░██████  ░█████  ███░░
     ███      ███░░░     ░░███░░      ███░███ ███ ███░░███░░███░░███  ███░░  ███░░
   ░░░ ███    ███ ░░░█████░██████░░░░░███░░█████  ███░░███░░███░░███ ███░░░ ███░░░
     ███      ███      ███ ███        ███   ███   ███  ███  ███   ██████    ███
   ███         ███     ███ ███        ███         ███  ███  ███    █████    ███
 ███            █████████  ██████████ ███         ███ █████ ███     █████  █████

Tips for getting started:
1. Ask questions, edit files, or run commands.
2. Be specific for the best results.
3. Create GEMINI.md files to customize your interactions with Gemini.
4. /help for more information.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
