<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war abruptly called a pause</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of trade war tariffs in 2025 presented a “escalation – counter-repressive measures – negotiations” cycle, with the US-China rivalry shifting from tariff confrontation to competition over rules. Despite short-term easing that alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty persists, and it’s crucial to monitor WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical shifts&amp;rsquo; ongoing impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t earn money beyond their own perception; the stock market crash triggered by the launch of the trade war this year has largely recovered, but countless small investors have been buried along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 Trade War Tariff Timeline Overview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is a timeline of the trade war tariff events, combining key events involving the US and China, and other countries, to present the dynamic evolution of tariff policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;one-april-2025--comprehensive-tariff-upgrade-and-countermeasures&#34;&gt;One: April 2025 – Comprehensive Tariff Upgrade and Countermeasures
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Tariffs on China&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2nd:&lt;/strong&gt; The Trump administration signed Executive Order No. 14257, announcing the imposition of a 34% “retaliatory tariff” on goods shipped from China to the U.S., covering products originating from Hong Kong and Macau.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 8th:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States further increased the “retaliatory tariff” rate on Chinese goods from 34% to 84%, signing Executive Orders No. 14259 and 14266 to impose tariffs on additional products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 10th:&lt;/strong&gt; The White House amended the executive order, increasing the total tariff amount on Chinese goods to 145% and raising the rate on small packages (such as goods priced below $800 from 90% to 120%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China’s Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 4th:&lt;/strong&gt; China announced a 34% tariff on all goods originating in the United States, covering sectors such as agricultural products, automobiles, and energy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 10th:&lt;/strong&gt; China raised the retaliatory tariff rate from 34% to 84%, synchronizing with the U.S. side’s escalation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 12th:&lt;/strong&gt; China cancelled the 91% tariffs imposed on US goods (corresponding to some of the tariffs cancelled by the US side) and suspended the implementation of the 24% tariff for 90 days, retaining a 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Other Countries’ Tariff Game&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S.-Canada Trade War:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States imposed 25% tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum products, and Canada retaliated by imposing taxes on US goods worth $2.98 billion CAD, and filed a WTO dispute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU and Japan:&lt;/strong&gt; The EU imposed maximum 25% tariffs on U.S. goods, while Japan expressed concern about auto tariffs on the United States, calling the trade war “harming both sides.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-de-escalation&#34;&gt;II. May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff De-escalation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US-China High-Level Trade Talks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 10-11&lt;/strong&gt;: The US and China held a 16-hour meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, reaching the “Joint Statement on the US-China Economic Talks.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 12&lt;/strong&gt;: Both sides announced a suspension of some tariffs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The United States suspended its 24% tariff on Chinese goods (90 days), retaining 10%, and rescinded the additional tariffs imposed on April 8th and 9th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China simultaneously suspended its 24% retaliatory tariffs, retaining 10%, and lifted non-tariff measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishment of a Consultation Mechanism&lt;/strong&gt;: Both sides agreed to hold regular trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reduction and rulemaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic Impact &amp;amp; Policy Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Domestic Pressure&lt;/strong&gt;: High tariffs led to the closure of small and medium-sized enterprises (such as Amazon sellers forced to close due to tariff surges) and fueled inflationary expectations (core PCE is expected to rise to 3.3%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China Rare Earth Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt;: China strengthened controls on rare earth exports, cracked down on smuggling, impacting US defense and new energy industries, which were granted exemptions on tariffs for key minerals such as rare earths.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WTO and Multilateral Reactions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China both lodged WTO disputes against the U.S. steel and aluminum tariffs and “retaliatory tariffs,” alleging violations of non-discrimination principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Azevedo warned that U.S. tariffs could cause a 1% contraction in global trade volumes by 2025, exacerbating difficulties for developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exemption Lists and Industry Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Excluded Goods:&lt;/strong&gt; A 37-page list covering strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT balls exposed supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Tariffs:&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. imposed 25% tariffs on imported automobiles, leading to an estimated 2% decline in global auto production and a 9% reduction in North American output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political and Strategic Maneuvering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through “retaliatory tariffs,” but was criticized as unilateral bullying, triggering backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China responded to protectionism with efforts to expand market access (such as the Cross-Border e-Commerce Expo and zero-tariff commitments), attracting cooperation from developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States imposes additional tariffs of 34% on goods from Hong Kong and Macau.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-1&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 8th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States raised tariffs on Chinese goods to 84%, and added new executive orders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-2&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 10th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China retaliates by imposing 34% tariffs, later raised to 84%; the US adjusts tariffs to 145%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-3&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States waived some goods (such as technology products), China lifted 91% of the counter-rebalancing tariffs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-4&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 10-11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US-China talks in Geneva, reaching a joint statement on suspending tariffs of 24% (90 days).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iv-timeline-summary&#34;&gt;IV. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both sides announced a suspension of tariffs and the establishment of a consultation mechanism, easing trade tensions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;five-trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Five. Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-Term Relief and Long-Term Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; The suspension of U.S.-China tariffs sent positive signals, but structural issues (such as high technology and energy) remain, with midterm elections or policy continuity impacting the medium term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Supply Chain Restructuring:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies are accelerating adjustments to their supply chains, with Mexico and Southeast Asia benefiting from “nearshoring,” but rising costs could dampen recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multilateral Mechanism Dilemmas:&lt;/strong&gt; The WTO dispute resolution mechanism is limited, regional trade agreements (such as the U.S.-UK agreement) are emerging as alternative options, but this exacerbates fragmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points, the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism. From the mouths of the older generation, we heard that to get rich, you first needed to build roads. China&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure construction – these things are all funded by the state, and in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there’s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. Talking too much is getting off-topic, and ordinary people might feel that trade wars don&amp;rsquo;t have much impact on their lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. The IT industry I work in – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – the core configuration of assembling a computer comes from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost, and high-end manufacturing is undoubtedly essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war (often referred to as the “China–United States trade war,” “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” or “US-China trade war”) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China is stealing US intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, imposing tariffs on goods imported from China totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States. The Ministry of Commerce of China retaliated in kind with a 25% additional tariff on $340 billion worth of U.S. goods exported to China, including soybeans, the largest export product from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides had temporarily reached an agreement to pause the trade war in May 2018 and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative subsequently released its first list of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States on June 16, raising the existing 10% tariff to 25%. The China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) then retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S. products exported to China. On July 6, the Trump administration formally implemented tariffs on the first list of $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, marking the formal implementation of Trump’s trade policy towards China (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently added with a 25% tariff on August 23). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; The General Administration of Customs of China (GACC) indicated that China’s counter-measures were implemented immediately after the U.S. imposed tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump agreed to hold a nine-month negotiation and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the U.S. side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on approximately $200 billion, totaling $250 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, which took effect on June 1. On May 13, the China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) announced that tariffs on $600 billion worth of imported U.S. products would be raised to a range of 5% to 25%, starting from June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced that the implementation date for tariffs of 25% on U.S. goods would be postponed to June 15, and SAFE stated that China’s tariff measures took effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Trump held a meeting at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart economic consultations, with the United States ceasing to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to concerns about China’s purchasing process of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that tariffs of 10% would be imposed on the remaining $300 billion worth of all Chinese goods shipped to the United States starting September 1, 2019. On August 5, the Renminbi exchange rate against the US dollar fell below 7 yuan. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that China was designated as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and parts, while the U.S. side responded by increasing the tariff rates on its existing $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and its current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as retaliation, but these measures were subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
