<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:59:56 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Black Swan Goose Returns</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:10:18 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/black-swan-goose-returns/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Previously, investors focused on financial news. Since Trump’s return, they also needed to pay attention to his Twitter (a private version). The trade war continued to escalate, leading to a sharp decline on April 7th, which was quickly followed by a rebound. This time, though, are people still willing to jump in?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;background-review&#34;&gt;Background Review
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On April 7, 2025, following the impact of the U.S. implementation of an “equivalency tariff” policy, global stock markets experienced a “Black Monday.” The A-share market plunged, with the Shanghai Composite Index falling by 7.34% and the Shenzhen Component Index plummeting by 12.5%, with over 4,300 stocks declining by more than 9%. The Hang Seng Index in Hong Kong also fell by 13.22%, along with European and U.S. stock indices exceeding declines of 4%. China subsequently stabilized the market through state-owned enterprise (SOE) purchases and intervention by Huishang Securities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On October 10th, U.S. stocks suffered another significant decline, with Chinese HShares falling by 6%, driven primarily by expectations of escalation in the U.S.-China trade war. Trump signaled a further increase in tariffs on China, and the U.S. would also impose hefty fees on Chinese ships. China announced retaliatory measures and levied special port fees, compounded by a government shutdown, declining consumer confidence, and market panic selling for safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://truthsocial.com/@realDonaldTrump/posts/115351840469973590&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Original Link&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://ttf248.life/p/black-swan-goose-returns/20251011142053.png&#34;
	width=&#34;586&#34;
	height=&#34;766&#34;
	
	loading=&#34;lazy&#34;
	
		alt=&#34;realDonaldTrump&#34;
	
	
		class=&#34;gallery-image&#34; 
		data-flex-grow=&#34;76&#34;
		data-flex-basis=&#34;183px&#34;
	
&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;position-control&#34;&gt;Position Control
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;Currently, the state of short selling in A-shares isn&amp;rsquo;t a complete short position; there’s a small portion invested in index funds within Fixed Income Plus, but the bulk is still in the Hong Kong market. Xiaomi has already incurred principal losses, and Meituan remains a shareholder. The position control is somewhat unbalanced. Should we jump in and gamble on Monday? It&amp;rsquo;s a question to consider – currently, we don’t have enough cash flow. If we need to enter, we would rely on old friends like Alipay’s Jiebei for bridging funds. &lt;strong&gt;Greedy snakes swallow elephants&lt;/strong&gt; – the position control is extremely unreasonable, and we should look for opportunities to reduce our holdings later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Compared to April 7th, the current position isn&amp;rsquo;t considered a low-level one; many stocks are at relatively high levels, particularly the technology stocks within the Heng Seng Tech index. If we were to add to positions, it would be more appropriate to use an ETF rather than individual stocks – for example: &lt;strong&gt;Turned around and couldn’t find anything suitable; gains were 20%-30%&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Regarding the domestic market, long-term trends point towards a period of consolidation and decline, with potential for significant rallies in the short term. To make profits, it&amp;rsquo;s best to execute profit-taking operations within this timeframe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;associated-term-definitions&#34;&gt;Associated Term Definitions
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;h3 id=&#34;black-swan&#34;&gt;Black Swan
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;Black Swan&amp;rdquo; originates from Nassim Nicholas Taleb’s book &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to events that are &lt;strong&gt;extremely unlikely&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;unpredictable&lt;/strong&gt;, but upon occurring, they generate &lt;strong&gt;extreme impact and disruptive consequences&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rarity/Unpredictability:&lt;/strong&gt; These events have no precedent or warning signs before they occur, exceeding all conventional expectations and model predictions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Extreme Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once they happen, they can cause catastrophic effects on markets, economies, and even societies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-hoc Rationalization:&lt;/strong&gt; Despite being impossible to predict beforehand, people tend to find reasons and explanations after the event occurs, making it appear “understandable.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Legend:&lt;/strong&gt; Before the discovery of Australia, Europeans believed all swans were white until black swans were discovered in Australia, completely overturning thousands of years of knowledge. Therefore, the Black Swan symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;unforeseen and cognitive breakthroughs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Examples:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &amp;ldquo;9/11&amp;rdquo; terrorist attack in 2001 (a short-term shock to global markets).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The initial impact of &lt;strong&gt;COVID-19&lt;/strong&gt; on the global economy and markets (although some argued it had grey rhino characteristics, its sudden outbreak and global spread, as well as the extent of its impact, were largely considered Black Swans).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;gray-rhino&#34;&gt;Gray Rhino
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;The term “Gray Rhino” was coined by Michele Wucker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Concept:&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to a potential crisis that is &lt;strong&gt;highly probable&lt;/strong&gt;, has a &lt;strong&gt;significant impact&lt;/strong&gt;, and yet is &lt;strong&gt;ignored&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;selectively delayed in addressing&lt;/strong&gt; due to its &lt;strong&gt;obvious warning signs&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Characteristics:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;High Probability/Predictability:&lt;/strong&gt; The event has clear indicators and evidence before it occurs, making it a &lt;strong&gt;known&lt;/strong&gt; risk.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easily Ignored:&lt;/strong&gt; Because it’s not sudden but rather long-term or slowly developing, people become numb, exhibit optimism bias, or procrastinate, failing to take timely action.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Significant Impact:&lt;/strong&gt; Once it erupts, due to the lack of effective responses beforehand, it triggers a chain reaction and causes severe destructive consequences.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Source Allusion:&lt;/strong&gt; A gray rhino is large in size and has a slow reaction time; people can see it from afar, but often fail to avoid it because of negligence or indifference. Once it charges towards you, it will cause a fatal collision. Therefore, the gray rhino symbolizes &lt;strong&gt;obvious yet ignored&lt;/strong&gt; major threats.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stock Market Example:&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 2008 &lt;strong&gt;Global Financial Crisis&lt;/strong&gt; (many experts had already warned about the high risk of the US subprime mortgage market, but were largely ignored).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sovereign Debt Crises&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;severe asset bubbles&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;systemic risks from climate change&lt;/strong&gt; (these are long-accumulated, traceable major risks).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points, the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism. From the mouths of the older generation, we heard that to get rich, you first needed to build roads. China&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure construction – these things are all funded by the state, and in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there’s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. Talking too much is getting off-topic, and ordinary people might feel that trade wars don&amp;rsquo;t have much impact on their lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. The IT industry I work in – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – the core configuration of assembling a computer comes from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost, and high-end manufacturing is undoubtedly essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war (often referred to as the “China–United States trade war,” “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” or “US-China trade war”) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China is stealing US intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, imposing tariffs on goods imported from China totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States. The Ministry of Commerce of China retaliated in kind with a 25% additional tariff on $340 billion worth of U.S. goods exported to China, including soybeans, the largest export product from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides had temporarily reached an agreement to pause the trade war in May 2018 and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative subsequently released its first list of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States on June 16, raising the existing 10% tariff to 25%. The China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) then retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S. products exported to China. On July 6, the Trump administration formally implemented tariffs on the first list of $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, marking the formal implementation of Trump’s trade policy towards China (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently added with a 25% tariff on August 23). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; The General Administration of Customs of China (GACC) indicated that China’s counter-measures were implemented immediately after the U.S. imposed tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump agreed to hold a nine-month negotiation and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the U.S. side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on approximately $200 billion, totaling $250 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, which took effect on June 1. On May 13, the China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) announced that tariffs on $600 billion worth of imported U.S. products would be raised to a range of 5% to 25%, starting from June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced that the implementation date for tariffs of 25% on U.S. goods would be postponed to June 15, and SAFE stated that China’s tariff measures took effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Trump held a meeting at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart economic consultations, with the United States ceasing to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to concerns about China’s purchasing process of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that tariffs of 10% would be imposed on the remaining $300 billion worth of all Chinese goods shipped to the United States starting September 1, 2019. On August 5, the Renminbi exchange rate against the US dollar fell below 7 yuan. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that China was designated as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and parts, while the U.S. side responded by increasing the tariff rates on its existing $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and its current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as retaliation, but these measures were subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
