<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war put on hold</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The 2025 trade war tariff evolution showed a cycle of &amp;ldquo;escalation — retaliation — consultation,&amp;rdquo; shifting the US-China competition from tariff confrontation to rules-based competition. While short-term easing alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty remains; monitor the WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical changes&amp;rsquo; continued impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People cannot earn money beyond their understanding. The stock market crash triggered by the trade war this year, even with a partial recovery now, has claimed countless retail investors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Timeline of Trade War Tariffs in 2025&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a breakdown of the 2025 trade war tariff timeline, incorporating key events from China, the US, and other countries to illustrate the evolution of tariff policies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-tariff-escalation-and-retaliation&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Tariff Escalation and Retaliation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration signed order 14257, announcing a 34% tariff on Chinese goods imported into the US, covering products from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The U.S. is further raising tariffs on China from 34% to 84%, and has signed Executive Orders 14259 and 14266, imposing additional tariffs on more goods.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The White House revised an executive order, raising the total tariffs on China to 145%, and increasing duties on small parcels (e.g., raising the tariff rate on goods under $800 from 90% to 120%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China announced a 34% tariff on all goods originating from the United States, covering sectors like agriculture, automobiles, and energy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China will retaliate by raising tariffs from 34% to 84%, matching the US escalation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is removing 91% of tariffs on US goods (corresponding to the portion agreed upon by the US) and suspending the implementation of 90% of the remaining 24% tariffs, while retaining 10%&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US imposed a 25% tariff on Canadian steel and aluminum products, prompting Canada to retaliate with tariffs on $2.98 billion worth of US goods and file a complaint with the WTO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The EU is imposing tariffs of up to 25% on US goods, while Japan expressed concerns over tariffs on US cars, calling the trade war &amp;ldquo;lose-lose.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-easing&#34;&gt;May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff Easing
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China and the United States held 16 hours of talks in Geneva, Switzerland, resulting in the China-U.S. Geneva Trade Talks Joint Statement.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sides announce suspension of some tariffs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US has suspended 24% of tariffs on China (for 90 days), retained 10%, and canceled additional duties scheduled for April 8th and 9th&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China will suspend 24% of retaliatory tariffs, retain 10%, and remove non-tariff measures&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both sides agreed to hold regular economic and trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reductions and rule-making&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High tariffs are causing small and medium-sized enterprises to fail (e.g., Amazon sellers forced to close due to surging tariffs), and inflation expectations are rising (core PCE is projected to rise to 3.3%)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China has tightened controls on rare earth exports, cracked down on smuggling, and impacted US military and new energy industries, forcing them to seek waivers for tariffs on key minerals like rare earths&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China have both filed disputes with the WTO against the US steel and aluminum tariffs and &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; alleging violations of the non-discrimination principle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Ngozi Okonjo-Iweala warned that U.S. tariffs could cause a 1% decline in global trade volume by 2025, exacerbating the difficulties faced by developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The 37-page list covers strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT tubes, exposing supply chain vulnerabilities&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US imposed a 25% tariff on imported cars, leading to a projected 2% drop in global auto production and a 9% reduction in North America&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through &amp;ldquo;reciprocal tariffs,&amp;rdquo; but was criticized as unilateral bullying, prompting a backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China is responding to protectionism by expanding market access (such as through import fairs and zero-tariff commitments) to attract cooperation from developing countries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;timeline-summary&#34;&gt;Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;The quick brown fox jumps over the lazy dog&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US is imposing 34% retaliatory tariffs on China, covering goods from Hong Kong and Macau&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US will raise tariffs on China to 84% and introduce new tax orders&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China retaliates with tariffs, initially 34%, later raised to 84%; US modifies tariffs to 145%&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The US waived tariffs on some goods (like tech products), and China canceled 91% of its retaliatory tariffs&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China, US, and Japan Geneva talks result in a joint statement agreeing to suspend 24% tariffs (for 90 days)&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both sides announced suspension of tariffs and a consultation mechanism, easing trade tensions&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tariff suspension between China and the US sends a positive signal, but structural issues (such as high technology and energy) remain, and midterm elections may affect policy continuity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Companies are accelerating supply chain adjustments; Mexico and Southeast Asia benefit from &amp;ldquo;nearshoring,&amp;rdquo; but rising costs may curb recovery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The WTO dispute settlement mechanism is limited, and regional trade agreements (such as the US-UK agreement) have become alternative options, but this exacerbates fragmentation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>us-china-trade-war</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a tangent: the differences between socialism with Chinese characteristics and capitalism. Older generations often say, &amp;ldquo;To get rich, first build roads.&amp;rdquo; Infrastructure construction in China is funded by the state; in a capitalist society, these projects would be contracted out. In remote areas where there’s no profit to be made, companies wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be willing to take on such work. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stray too far from the article&amp;rsquo;s main topic, but ordinary people may not feel much impact from the trade war. However, China&amp;rsquo;s high-end manufacturing has consistently been relatively weak. In my IT industry, memory, hard drives, CPUs, and graphics cards – the core components of a computer – all come from foreign factories. These parts account for 50% of the total cost of a machine. The development of high-end manufacturing is essential. A collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sino-American trade war (also known as the China–United States trade war, or Sino-American trade dispute/friction/dispute) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming &amp;ldquo;China steals American intellectual property and business secrets&amp;rdquo; and directing the United States Trade Representative to impose tariffs on goods imported from China under Section 301 of the 1974 Trade Act, involving an estimated total value of $60 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed a 25% tariff on Chinese goods exported to the U.S., valued at $340 billion. The Ministry of Commerce of China responded with retaliatory measures, imposing a 25% tariff on U.S. goods exported to China, valued at $340 billion, including soybeans, a major U.S. export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US and China previously reached a consensus in May 2018 to suspend the trade war, issuing a joint statement seeking resolution. However, the USTR subsequently announced the first batch of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods on June 16, raising the original 10% rate to 25%. In response, China’s State Council Tariff Commission implemented retaliatory measures, and the Ministry of Commerce restarted anti-dumping investigations on multiple US products. On July 6, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% tariff on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods (with an additional $160 billion subject to tariffs on August 23), marking the formal implementation of Trump’s China tariffs. The Ministry of Commerce stated that the US had violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history. Customs authorities confirmed that China&amp;rsquo;s retaliatory measures were implemented after the US tariffs took effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1st at the G20 Buenos Aires summit, Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Donald Trump reached a consensus to initiate 90-day negotiations and suspend new trade measures during that period. After the March 1, 2019 deadline expired, the U.S. announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on Chinese goods entering the United States valued at approximately $200 billion, bringing the total subject to tariffs to $250 billion. The measure took effect on June 1 for goods arriving at U.S. ports. On May 13, China’s State Council Tariff Commission announced that it would raise tariffs by 5% to 25% on certain imports from the United States valued at $60 billion, effective June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative delayed the imposition of its 25% tariffs until June 15, while China’s State Council Tariff Commission stated that its tariff measures would take effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump met at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart trade negotiations and for the US not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1st, due to the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the progress of China’s purchases of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced via Twitter that a 10% tariff would be imposed on all remaining Chinese goods imported into the United States starting September 1, 2019, amounting to $300 billion. On August 5th, the yuan-dollar exchange rate fell below 7. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department declared China a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and on August 24th announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $75 billion worth of U.S. goods, as well as restoring tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; the United States responded by increasing the tariff rate on the previously levied $300 billion in Chinese goods to 15%, and raising the existing 25% tariff on $250 billion in Chinese goods to 30%, but this was later suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2020, China and the United States signed the Phase One trade agreement&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
