<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Trade-War on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/trade-war/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Trade war abruptly called a pause</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</link>
        <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2025 19:07:35 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/trade-war-pauses/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The evolution of trade war tariffs in 2025 presented a “escalation – counter-repressive measures – negotiations” cycle, with the US-China rivalry shifting from tariff confrontation to competition over rules. Despite short-term easing that alleviated market pressure, long-term uncertainty persists, and it’s crucial to monitor WTO rulings, supply chain adjustments, and geopolitical shifts&amp;rsquo; sustained impact on the global economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People don’t earn money beyond their own perception; the stock market crash triggered by the launch of the trade war this year has largely recovered, but countless retail investors have been buried along the way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2025 Trade War Tariff Timeline Overview&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here’s a timeline of the trade war tariff events, combining key events involving the US and China, and other countries, illustrating the dynamic evolution of tariff policies:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-upgrade-and-countermeasures-on-tariffs&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Upgrade and Countermeasures on Tariffs
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Tariff Measures Against China&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2nd:&lt;/strong&gt; The Trump administration signed Executive Order No. 14257, announcing the imposition of a 34% “retaliatory tariff” on goods shipped from China to the U.S., covering products originating in Hong Kong and Macao.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 8th:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States further increased the “retaliatory tariff” rate on Chinese goods from 34% to 84%, and signed Executive Orders No. 14259 and 14266, imposing tariffs on additional products.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 10th:&lt;/strong&gt; The White House amended the executive order, increasing the total tariff amount against China to 145%, and raising the tariff rate on small packages (such as goods priced below $800 from 90% to 120%).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;China’s Countermeasures&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 4th:&lt;/strong&gt; China announced the imposition of a 34% tariff on all goods originating in the United States, covering sectors such as agricultural products, automobiles, and energy. - &lt;strong&gt;April 10th&lt;/strong&gt;: China will retaliate against the tariff rate increase from 34% to 84%, in sync with the US side.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 12th&lt;/strong&gt;: China cancels the additional tariffs imposed on U.S. goods by 91% (corresponding to part of the cancellation by the US side) and suspends the implementation of 24% tariffs for 90 days, retaining 10%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;i-april-2025-comprehensive-tariff-upgrade-and-countermeasures&#34;&gt;I. April 2025: Comprehensive Tariff Upgrade and Countermeasures
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tariff Games Involving Other Countries&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US-Canada Trade War:&lt;/strong&gt; The United States imposes 25% tariffs on Canadian steel and aluminum products, and Canada retaliates by taxing goods worth $298 billion from the US, as well as filing a WTO dispute.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;EU &amp;amp; Japan:&lt;/strong&gt; The EU imposes maximum 25% tariffs on US goods, while Japan expresses concern over auto tariffs imposed by the US, calling the trade war “harming both sides.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;ii-may-2025-geneva-talks-and-tariff-de-escalation&#34;&gt;II. May 2025: Geneva Talks and Tariff De-escalation
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US-China High-Level Trade Talks&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 10-11:&lt;/strong&gt; The US and China held a 16-hour meeting in Geneva, Switzerland, reaching the “Joint Statement on the US-China Economic Talks.”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;May 12:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides announced a suspension of some tariffs:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The United States paused its 24% tariff on Chinese goods (90 days), retaining 10%, and rescinded the additional tariffs imposed on April 8th and 9th.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;China simultaneously suspended its 24% retaliatory tariffs, retaining 10%, and lifted non-tariff measures.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Establishment of a Consultation Mechanism:&lt;/strong&gt; Both sides agreed to hold regular trade consultations in China, the United States, or a third country, focusing on tariff reduction and rulemaking.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Economic Impact and Policy Adjustments&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;US Domestic Pressure:&lt;/strong&gt; High tariffs led to the closure of small and medium-sized enterprises (such as Amazon sellers forced to close due to tariff surges) and rising inflation expectations (core PCE is expected to rise to 3…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;iii-other-key-events-and-long-term-impacts&#34;&gt;III. Other Key Events and Long-Term Impacts
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WTO and Multilateral Responses&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Canada and China both lodged WTO disputes against the U.S. steel and aluminum tariffs and “retaliatory tariffs,” alleging violations of non-discrimination principles.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WTO Director-General Azevedo warned that U.S. tariffs could cause a 1% contraction in global trade volumes by 2025, exacerbating difficulties for developing countries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exemption Lists and Industry Impacts&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;U.S. Excluded Goods:&lt;/strong&gt; A 37-page list covering strategic materials such as rare earths, graphite, and medical CT balls exposed supply chain vulnerabilities.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Auto Tariffs:&lt;/strong&gt; The U.S. imposed 25% tariffs on imported automobiles, leading to an estimated 2% decline in global auto production and a 9% reduction in North American output.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Political and Strategic Maneuvering&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Trump administration attempted to reshape the international trade order through “retaliatory tariffs,” but was criticized as unilateral bullying, triggering backlash from allies (such as the EU and Japan).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;&lt;strong&gt;April 2, 2025&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States imposes additional tariffs of 34% on goods from Hong Kong and Macau.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-1&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 8th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States raised tariffs on Chinese imports to 84% and added new executive orders.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-2&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 10th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;China retaliates by imposing a 34% tariff, later raised to 84%; the US adjusts tariffs to 145%.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-3&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;April 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;The United States waived some goods (such as technology products), China lifted 91% of the counter-tariffs.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-4&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 10-11&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;US-China talks in Geneva, reaching a joint statement agreeing to suspend tariffs of 24% (for 90 days).&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;four-timeline-summary-5&#34;&gt;Four. Timeline Summary
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Time&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Event&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;May 12th&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Both sides announced a suspension of tariffs and the establishment of a consultation mechanism, easing trade tensions.&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;five-trends-and-challenges&#34;&gt;Five. Trends and Challenges
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Short-Term Relief and Long-Term Competition:&lt;/strong&gt; The suspension of US-China tariffs sent positive signals, but structural issues (such as high technology and energy) remain, with mid-term elections or policy continuity impacting the outlook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Supply Chain Restructuring:&lt;/strong&gt; Companies are accelerating adjustments to their supply chains, with Mexico and Southeast Asia benefiting from “nearshoring,” but rising costs may dampen recovery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multilateral Mechanism Dilemmas:&lt;/strong&gt; The WTO dispute resolution mechanism is constrained, regional trade agreements (such as the US-UK agreement) are emerging as alternative options, but this could exacerbate fragmentation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points – the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism, from the perspective of older generations who always said you need to build roads before getting rich. China’s infrastructure development – these things are all funded by the state, whereas in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there&amp;rsquo;s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. We’ve gone off-topic a bit, and many people might think trade wars don’t significantly impact their daily lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. As someone working in the IT industry, I can tell you that the core configurations of computers – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – come from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost of a finished computer, and it’s clear that high-end manufacturing is essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war, often referred to as the “China–United States trade war” (English: China–United States trade war), or simply “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” “US–China trade conflict,” or “trade war” between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China was stealing American intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and invoking Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 to impose tariffs on goods imported from China, totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-1&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States and China had reached a consensus in May 2018 to temporarily suspend the trade war, and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced its first list of tariffs on Chinese goods shipped to the US on June 16th, raising the existing 10% tariff rate to 25%. The China Tariff Committee subsequently retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S.-bound products. On July 6th, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% customs duty on $34 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the US from the first list of tariffs, marking the formal implementation of Trump&amp;rsquo;s trade policy towards China (the remaining $16 billion in goods were subsequently subject to a 25% tariff on August 23rd). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that “The United States has violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.” According to the General Administration of Customs of China, the Chinese side immediately implemented counter-measures following the implementation of US tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1st, during the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump reached an agreement to hold a 90-day negotiation and suspend new trade measures during that period. After the deadline of March 1st, 2019 expired, the US side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-2&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced the imposition of a 25% tariff on approximately $200 billion in Chinese goods, totaling $250 billion, as part of a trade war. The measure took effect on June 1st. On May 13th, China’s State Council Tariff Commission announced that starting June 1st, tariffs ranging from 5% to 25% would be levied on select imported goods originating in the United States valued at $60 billion. On June 1st, the U.S. Trade Representative&amp;rsquo;s Office announced a postponement of the imposition of a 25% tariff on U.S. products until June 15th. China’s State Council Tariff Commission stated that China’s retaliatory tariffs would take effect as scheduled on June 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 29th, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump held talks at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to resume economic negotiations. The United States agreed not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-3&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On August 1st, due to the Trump administration’s dissatisfaction with China’s purchasing process of American agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that starting September 1st, 2019, tariffs of 10% would be imposed on all US goods imported from China worth $300 billion. On August 5th, the Renminbi exchange rate against the dollar fell below the 7-yuan mark. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that it was designating China as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of American agricultural products and on August 24th announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of US goods, and restored tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; while the U.S. increased the tariff rate on its $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and the current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as a countermeasure, but it was subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16th, 2020, China and the United States signed a Phase One trade agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
