<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 20:54:02 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Let’s assume you have $1,000 USD and want to sell these dollars to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
1000 \, \text{USD} \times 7.0 \, \text{CNY/USD} = 7000 \, \text{CNY}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7,000 CNY. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling USD to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing US dollars from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the decline in the A-share market may be related to the dynamics of global central banks, the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank, the performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors jointly acted on the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to fluctuations in the Renminbi and the decline in the A-share market.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant volatility. Here’s a detailed breakdown:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through:&lt;/strong&gt; At opening, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar-offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and the on-shore RMB rising to a high of 7.22360, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of release by Lianhe Chat, the dollar-offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 mark, with the lowest reported at 7.2639 and the trend remained unchanged.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Exchange Rate Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the Renminbi’s midpoint exchange rate against the dollar at 7.1004, a devaluation of 62 basis points, with the adjustment magnitude expanded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened low and continued to fall, with declines exceeding 1% overall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Foreign Exchange Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment institution stated that the volatility in the foreign exchange market was mainly due to the unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss Central Bank boosting the dollar, coupled with strong U.S. economic data and the potential persistence of inflation delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics:&lt;/strong&gt; This week is the “Super Central Bank Week” for global markets, with the central banks of the United States, Japan, Britain, Australia, and other countries all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss Central Bank unexpectedly announced a cut in interest rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, which broke the market balance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forecast for Renminbi Trend:&lt;/strong&gt; Zhou Miaohua, researcher at Light Industry Bank’s Financial Market Department, stated that despite some fluctuations in the Renminbi recently, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies such as the dollar, and short-term volatility will not change the RMB&amp;rsquo;s trend of steady appreciation throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points, the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism. From the mouths of the older generation, we heard that to get rich, you first needed to build roads. China&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure construction – these things are all funded by the state, and in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there’s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. Talking too much is getting off-topic, and ordinary people might feel that trade wars don&amp;rsquo;t have much impact on their lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. The IT industry I work in – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – the core configuration of assembling a computer comes from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost, and high-end manufacturing is undoubtedly essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war (often referred to as the “China–United States trade war,” “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” or “US-China trade war”) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China is stealing US intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and under Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974, imposing tariffs on goods imported from China totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States. The Ministry of Commerce of China retaliated in kind with a 25% additional tariff on $340 billion worth of U.S. goods exported to China, including soybeans, the largest export product from the United States to China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The two sides had temporarily reached an agreement to pause the trade war in May 2018 and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative subsequently released its first list of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States on June 16, raising the existing 10% tariff to 25%. The China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) then retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S. products exported to China. On July 6, the Trump administration formally implemented tariffs on the first list of $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, marking the formal implementation of Trump’s trade policy towards China (the remaining $160 billion was subsequently added with a 25% tariff on August 23). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that &amp;ldquo;The United States violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.&amp;rdquo; The General Administration of Customs of China (GACC) indicated that China’s counter-measures were implemented immediately after the U.S. imposed tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1, at the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump agreed to hold a nine-month negotiation and suspend new trade measures during the negotiation period. After the deadline of March 1, 2019, the U.S. side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on approximately $200 billion, totaling $250 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States, which took effect on June 1. On May 13, the China’s State Administration of Foreign Exchange (SAFE) announced that tariffs on $600 billion worth of imported U.S. products would be raised to a range of 5% to 25%, starting from June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced that the implementation date for tariffs of 25% on U.S. goods would be postponed to June 15, and SAFE stated that China’s tariff measures took effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Trump held a meeting at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart economic consultations, with the United States ceasing to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1, due to concerns about China’s purchasing process of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that tariffs of 10% would be imposed on the remaining $300 billion worth of all Chinese goods shipped to the United States starting September 1, 2019. On August 5, the Renminbi exchange rate against the US dollar fell below 7 yuan. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that China was designated as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of U.S. goods, and resumed tariffs on U.S. automobiles and parts, while the U.S. side responded by increasing the tariff rates on its existing $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and its current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as retaliation, but these measures were subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
