<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 19:00:25 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding “buy rate” and “sell rate” in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-buy-and-sell-exchange-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like “buy rate” and “sell rate.” Many people may not be clear about these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, let’s help everyone understand the meaning of these rates and their functions through a simple example.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;1-what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;1. What are “Buy Rate” and “Sell Rate”?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to purchase foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you sell your foreign currency (such as US dollars) to the bank, the bank will pay you RMB according to the buy rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank or currency exchange institution is willing to sell foreign currencies at this rate, meaning when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell you the foreign currency at the sell rate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply put:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank buys foreign currency from you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The price at which the bank sells foreign currency to you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It is important to note that the buy and sell rates of banks are usually different, and the sell rate is generally higher than the buy rate. This difference is the source of profit for the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;2-specific-case-analysis&#34;&gt;2. Specific Case Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let’s look at a specific example:
Assume you go to a bank to exchange dollars, and the bank provides the following exchange rate:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buy Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.0 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sell Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; 1 US Dollar = 7.2 RMB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You Sell US Dollars to a Bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have $1000 and want to sell it to a bank. The bank will calculate the transaction using the buying rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1000 \times 7.0 \, \text{Renminbi/USD} = 7000 \, \text{Renminbi}
\]
&lt;p&gt;This means the bank will give you 7000 RMB. The exchange rate is the &lt;strong&gt;buying rate&lt;/strong&gt; because you are selling US dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-two-you-buy-us-dollars-with-renminbi&#34;&gt;Scenario Two: You Buy US Dollars with Renminbi
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assume you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars. The bank will calculate the amount in USD based on the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
7000 \, \text{RMB} \div 7.2 \, \text{RMB/USD} = 972.22 \, \text{USD}
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, you can exchange 7,000 RMB for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate here is the &lt;strong&gt;selling rate&lt;/strong&gt;, because you are purchasing USD from the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;3-why-buying-and-selling-currency-differ&#34;&gt;3. Why Buying and Selling Currency Differ?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that a bank’s buying rate (7.0 RMB/USD) is lower than its selling rate (7.2 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from this exchange rate spread when engaging in foreign exchange transactions. In other words, banks earn profits by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank’s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
\text{Selling Rate} (7.2) - \text{Buying Rate} (7.0) = 0.2 \, RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference in price is the source of the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;4-summary&#34;&gt;4. Summary
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Buying Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank buys foreign currency from you at this rate (the same rate you sold the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selling Rate:&lt;/strong&gt; The bank sells foreign currency to you at this rate (the same rate you bought the foreign currency for).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Exchange Rate Difference:&lt;/strong&gt; The difference between the buying and selling rates is the bank’s profit margin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these two rate concepts allows us to clearly know how much foreign currency we will receive, or how much Renminbi we need to spend to buy foreign currency when conducting foreign exchange transactions. We hope this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has experienced significant fluctuations, breaking above 7.26.</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the exchange rate of the Renminbi and a decline in the Shanghai Composite Index may be related to developments at global central banks, an unexpected interest rate cut by the Swiss National Bank, performance of U.S. economic data, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors interact together in the foreign exchange market and stock market, leading to volatility in the Renminbi and a decline in A-shares.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Based on the provided link content, on March 22, 2024, the Renminbi experienced significant fluctuations. Here&amp;rsquo;s the detailed information:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dollar/Offshore RMB Exchange Rate Breaks Through&lt;/strong&gt;: At the opening of trading, the Renminbi weakened, with the dollar to offshore RMB rising to a high of 7.24926 and 7.22360 respectively during intraday trading, both breaking new highs since November 17, 2023. As of the time of reporter release by Lianhe Finance, the dollar to offshore RMB broke through the 7.26 level, with a lowest reported price of 7.2639, and the trend remained strong.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Central Bank Mid-Price Adjustment:&lt;/strong&gt; On March 22nd, the central bank announced the RMB/USD midpoint quotation at 7.1004, a depreciation of 62 basis points, expanding the adjustment magnitude.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A-Share Market Reaction:&lt;/strong&gt; Affected by various factors, the three major A-share indices opened lower and continued to decline, with declines exceeding 1%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reasons for Volatility in the Forex Market:&lt;/strong&gt; A senior foreign exchange trader from a Hong Kong investment firm stated that volatility in the forex market was primarily due to the Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cutting interest rates, which boosted the dollar, coupled with strong US economic growth and the potential for inflationary persistence delaying rate cuts, leading to an increase in the Dollar Index.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Global Central Bank Dynamics&lt;/strong&gt;: This week is a “super central bank week” for global markets, with the U.S., Japan, UK, Australia, and other countries’ central banks all announcing interest rate decisions this week. The Swiss National Bank unexpectedly cut rates, becoming the first G10 currency central bank to cut rates since the outbreak of the pandemic, breaking market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RMB Trend Forecast&lt;/strong&gt;: Guotai Securities Financial Markets Department Researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent fluctuations in the RMB, the overall amplitude is significantly smaller than that of the U.S. dollar and other major currencies. Short-term volatility will not change the RMB’s steady uptrend this year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>US-China Trade War</title>
        <link>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let’s start with some tangential points – the differences between Chinese-style socialism and capitalism, from the perspective of older generations who always said you need to build roads before getting rich. China’s infrastructure development – these things are all funded by the state, whereas in a capitalist society, they would be contracted out. In remote areas, there&amp;rsquo;s no profit motive, so companies wouldn’t willingly take on those projects. We’ve gone off-topic a bit, and many people might think trade wars don’t significantly impact their daily lives. However, China’s high-end manufacturing has always been relatively weak. As someone working in the IT industry, I can tell you that the core configurations of computers – memory, hard drives, CPUs, graphics cards – come from factories abroad. These components account for 50% of the total cost of a finished computer, and it’s clear that high-end manufacturing is essential. The collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/zh-hans/2018%EF%BC%8D2020%E5%B9%B4%E4%B8%AD%E7%BE%8E%E8%B4%B8%E6%98%93%E6%88%98&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Trade War Between the US and China Starting in 2018&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a class=&#34;link&#34; href=&#34;https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E4%B8%AD%E5%9B%BD%E5%88%B6%E9%80%A02025&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;
    &gt;Made in China 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;2018-2020 China–United States trade war, often referred to as the “China–United States trade war” (English: China–United States trade war), or simply “US–China trade dispute,” “US–China trade friction,” “US–China trade conflict,” or “trade war” between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming that &amp;ldquo;China was stealing American intellectual property and trade secrets,&amp;rdquo; and invoking Section 301 of the Trade Act of 1974 to impose tariffs on goods imported from China, totaling an estimated $600 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed additional tariffs of 25% on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the United States.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-1&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The United States and China had reached a consensus in May 2018 to temporarily suspend the trade war, and issued a joint statement seeking reconciliation. However, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative announced its first list of tariffs on Chinese goods shipped to the US on June 16th, raising the existing 10% tariff rate to 25%. The China Tariff Committee subsequently retaliated with equivalent measures, and the Ministry of Commerce of China also restarted anti-dumping investigations into various U.S.-bound products. On July 6th, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% customs duty on $34 billion worth of Chinese goods shipped to the US from the first list of tariffs, marking the formal implementation of Trump&amp;rsquo;s trade policy towards China (the remaining $16 billion in goods were subsequently subject to a 25% tariff on August 23rd). The Ministry of Commerce of China stated afterward that “The United States has violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history.” According to the General Administration of Customs of China, the Chinese side immediately implemented counter-measures following the implementation of US tariffs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1st, during the G20 Buenos Aires Summit, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump reached an agreement to hold a 90-day negotiation and suspend new trade measures during that period. After the deadline of March 1st, 2019 expired, the US side announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-2&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced the imposition of a 25% tariff on approximately $200 billion in Chinese goods, totaling $250 billion, as part of a trade war. The measure took effect on June 1st. On May 13th, China’s State Council Tariff Commission announced that starting June 1st, tariffs ranging from 5% to 25% would be levied on select imported goods originating in the United States valued at $60 billion. On June 1st, the U.S. Trade Representative&amp;rsquo;s Office announced a postponement of the imposition of a 25% tariff on U.S. products until June 15th. China’s State Council Tariff Commission stated that China’s retaliatory tariffs would take effect as scheduled on June 1st.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;June 29th, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump held talks at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to resume economic negotiations. The United States agreed not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia-3&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;On August 1st, due to the Trump administration’s dissatisfaction with China’s purchasing process of American agricultural products, Trump announced on Twitter that starting September 1st, 2019, tariffs of 10% would be imposed on all US goods imported from China worth $300 billion. On August 5th, the Renminbi exchange rate against the dollar fell below the 7-yuan mark. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department announced that it was designating China as a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of American agricultural products and on August 24th announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $750 billion worth of US goods, and restored tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; while the U.S. increased the tariff rate on its $300 billion Chinese goods to 15%, and the current $250 billion Chinese goods to 25% as a countermeasure, but it was subsequently shelved.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16th, 2020, China and the United States signed a Phase One trade agreement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
