<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Exchange-Rate on Uncle Xiang&#39;s Notebook</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 09:47:38 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.ttf248.life/en/tags/exchange-rate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
        <title>Understanding buy rate and sell rate in exchange rates</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 22:32:10 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/understanding-exchange-rates-buy-and-sell-rates/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the foreign exchange market, particularly at banks or currency exchange points, we often see terms like &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate.&amp;rdquo; Many people may not be clear on these concepts, or even confuse them. Today, we will use a simple example to help everyone understand the meaning and function of these rates.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-are-buy-rate-and-sell-rate&#34;&gt;What are &amp;ldquo;buy rate&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;sell rate&amp;rdquo;?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to buy foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you sell foreign currency (like US dollars) to a bank, the bank will pay you in RMB according to the buying rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Banks or currency exchange institutions are willing to sell foreign currency at this rate; that is, when you buy foreign currency with RMB, the bank will sell it to you at the selling rate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In short:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The exchange rate at which the bank buys foreign currency from you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The price the bank offers you for foreign currency&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to note that banks&amp;rsquo; buying and selling exchange rates are typically different, with the selling rate generally higher than the buying rate. This difference is how banks make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;case-study-analysis&#34;&gt;Case Study Analysis
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help everyone better understand the practical application of these exchange rates, let&amp;rsquo;s take a specific example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suppose you go to a bank to exchange for US dollars, and the bank&amp;rsquo;s exchange rate is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.0 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1 US dollar = 7.2 Chinese yuan&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-1-you-sell-us-dollars-to-a-bank&#34;&gt;Scenario 1: You sell US dollars to a bank
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have $1,000 and want to sell it to a bank, the bank will calculate using its buy rate&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$1,000 USD x 7.0 CNY/USD = 7,000 CNY
\]
&lt;p&gt;That means the bank will give you 7,000 RMB. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;买入汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are selling dollars to the bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;scenario-2-you-buy-us-dollars-with-rmb&#34;&gt;Scenario 2: You buy US dollars with RMB
&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Assuming you have 7,000 RMB and want to exchange it for US dollars, the bank will calculate using the selling rate:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
$972.22 USD
\]
&lt;p&gt;In this case, 7000 RMB can be exchanged for approximately 972.22 USD. The exchange rate is &lt;strong&gt;卖出汇率&lt;/strong&gt;, as you are purchasing dollars from a bank.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-is-the-buy-rate-different-from-the-sell-rate&#34;&gt;Why is the buy rate different from the sell rate?
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed that the bank&amp;rsquo;s selling exchange rate (7.2 RMB/USD) is higher than its buying exchange rate (7.0 RMB/USD). This is because banks typically profit from foreign exchange transactions by exploiting this difference. In other words, banks make a profit by charging a higher selling rate and paying a lower buying rate.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, in the above case, the bank&amp;rsquo;s spread is:&lt;/p&gt;
\[
Selling exchange rate (7.2) - Buying exchange rate (7.0) = 0.2 RMB
\]
&lt;p&gt;This difference is the bank&amp;rsquo;s source of profit&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank buys foreign currency from you at this exchange rate (the rate when you sell foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The bank sells foreign currency to you at this exchange rate (the rate when you buy foreign currency)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The difference between the buying and selling exchange rates is the bank&amp;rsquo;s profit margin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding these exchange rate concepts allows us to better know how much foreign currency we will receive or how much Chinese Yuan is needed to purchase it when exchanging currencies. Hopefully, this simple example helps everyone better understand the basic principles of foreign exchange rates!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>The Renminbi exchange rate has seen significant volatility, breaking through 7.26</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:31:13 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/renminbi-exchange-rate-volatility/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Fluctuations in the Renminbi exchange rate and the broader market decline are likely linked to global central bank policies, the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise interest rate cut, US economic data performance, and adjustments in market expectations regarding inflation and interest rate cuts. These factors collectively impacted the foreign exchange and stock markets, leading to Renminbi volatility and A-share declines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to the link provided, the Renminbi exchange rate experienced a significant fluctuation on March 22, 2024. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The yuan weakened at opening, with the dollar exceeding 7.24 against the offshore RMB to 7.24926 and surpassing 7.22 against the onshore RMB to 7.22360, both breaking highs seen since November 17, 2023. At the time of this report, the dollar has broken past 7.26, reaching a low of 7.2639, and the trend continues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On March 22, the central bank set the midpoint of the yuan against the dollar at 7.1004, a decrease of 62 basis points, with an expanded adjustment range&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Affected by multiple factors, China&amp;rsquo;s three major A-share indices opened and closed lower, with declines exceeding 1%&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A senior currency trader at a Hong Kong investment firm stated that foreign exchange market volatility is primarily due to the Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s unexpected rate cut boosting the dollar, combined with a strong US economy and persistent inflation potentially delaying interest rate cuts, leading to an increase in the dollar index&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This week is a &amp;ldquo;super central bank week&amp;rdquo; for global markets, with interest rate decisions to be announced by central banks in the US, Japan, UK, Australia, and more. The Swiss National Bank&amp;rsquo;s surprise rate cut marks the first such action among G10 central banks since the pandemic began, disrupting market equilibrium.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Guangda Bank financial market researcher Zhou Maohua stated that despite recent RMB fluctuations, the overall magnitude is significantly smaller than that of major currencies like the US dollar, and short-term volatility will not alter the year&amp;rsquo;s upward trend&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
        </item>
        <item>
        <title>us-china-trade-war</title>
        <link>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 19:52:41 +0800</pubDate>
        
        <guid>https://blog.ttf248.life/en/p/us-china-trade-war/</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s start with a tangent: the differences between socialism with Chinese characteristics and capitalism. Older generations often say, &amp;ldquo;To get rich, first build roads.&amp;rdquo; Infrastructure construction in China is funded by the state; in a capitalist society, these projects would be contracted out. In remote areas where there’s no profit to be made, companies wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be willing to take on such work. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stray too far from the article&amp;rsquo;s main topic, but ordinary people may not feel much impact from the trade war. However, China&amp;rsquo;s high-end manufacturing has consistently been relatively weak. In my IT industry, memory, hard drives, CPUs, and graphics cards – the core components of a computer – all come from foreign factories. These parts account for 50% of the total cost of a machine. The development of high-end manufacturing is essential. A collision between China and the United States is inevitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;references&#34;&gt;References
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please provide the Chinese text you want me to translate. I am ready when you are! Just paste the text here.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;wikipedia&#34;&gt;Wikipedia
&lt;/h2&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Sino-American trade war (also known as the China–United States trade war, or Sino-American trade dispute/friction/dispute) was a trade war between the People&amp;rsquo;s Republic of China and the United States&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trade dispute originated when U.S. President Donald Trump signed a memorandum on March 22, 2018, claiming &amp;ldquo;China steals American intellectual property and business secrets&amp;rdquo; and directing the United States Trade Representative to impose tariffs on goods imported from China under Section 301 of the 1974 Trade Act, involving an estimated total value of $60 billion. On July 6, 2018, the U.S. imposed a 25% tariff on Chinese goods exported to the U.S., valued at $340 billion. The Ministry of Commerce of China responded with retaliatory measures, imposing a 25% tariff on U.S. goods exported to China, valued at $340 billion, including soybeans, a major U.S. export.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The US and China previously reached a consensus in May 2018 to suspend the trade war, issuing a joint statement seeking resolution. However, the USTR subsequently announced the first batch of tariffs on $500 billion worth of Chinese goods on June 16, raising the original 10% rate to 25%. In response, China’s State Council Tariff Commission implemented retaliatory measures, and the Ministry of Commerce restarted anti-dumping investigations on multiple US products. On July 6, the Trump administration formally imposed a 25% tariff on $340 billion worth of Chinese goods (with an additional $160 billion subject to tariffs on August 23), marking the formal implementation of Trump’s China tariffs. The Ministry of Commerce stated that the US had violated WTO rules and launched the largest trade war in economic history. Customs authorities confirmed that China&amp;rsquo;s retaliatory measures were implemented after the US tariffs took effect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On December 1st at the G20 Buenos Aires summit, Chinese President Xi Jinping and U.S. President Donald Trump reached a consensus to initiate 90-day negotiations and suspend new trade measures during that period. After the March 1, 2019 deadline expired, the U.S. announced significant progress and extended the suspension of new trade measures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On May 5, 2019, U.S. President Donald Trump announced tariffs of 25% on Chinese goods entering the United States valued at approximately $200 billion, bringing the total subject to tariffs to $250 billion. The measure took effect on June 1 for goods arriving at U.S. ports. On May 13, China’s State Council Tariff Commission announced that it would raise tariffs by 5% to 25% on certain imports from the United States valued at $60 billion, effective June 1. On June 1, the Office of the U.S. Trade Representative delayed the imposition of its 25% tariffs until June 15, while China’s State Council Tariff Commission stated that its tariff measures would take effect as scheduled on June 1.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On June 29, leaders Xi Jinping and Donald Trump met at the G20 Osaka Summit, agreeing to restart trade negotiations and for the US not to impose new tariffs on Chinese products&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 1st, due to the Trump administration&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the progress of China’s purchases of U.S. agricultural products, Trump announced via Twitter that a 10% tariff would be imposed on all remaining Chinese goods imported into the United States starting September 1, 2019, amounting to $300 billion. On August 5th, the yuan-dollar exchange rate fell below 7. The same day, the U.S. Treasury Department declared China a currency manipulator. Subsequently, the Chinese government announced a suspension of purchases of U.S. agricultural products and on August 24th announced tariffs of 10% or 5% on approximately $75 billion worth of U.S. goods, as well as restoring tariffs on U.S. automobiles and their parts; the United States responded by increasing the tariff rate on the previously levied $300 billion in Chinese goods to 15%, and raising the existing 25% tariff on $250 billion in Chinese goods to 30%, but this was later suspended.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On January 16, 2020, China and the United States signed the Phase One trade agreement&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
